<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>The Asian Biomass Market: Challenges and Opportunities Ahead.

Chemicals
The Asian <NODE id="83" />Biomass<NODE id="90" /> Market: Challenges and Opportunities Ahead
The <NODE id="138" />bioenergy<NODE id="147" /> market in Asia Pacific is still fairly immature compared to the European market. However, recent developments have led to expectations of significant <NODE id="298" />biomass<NODE id="305" /> demand.
By Pedro Campilho    | November 30, 2017
The <NODE id="359" />bioenergy<NODE id="368" /> market in Asia Pacific is still fairly immature compared to the European market. However, recent developments have led to expectations of significant demand  that could lead to this region quickly surpassing the European market in terms of traded volumes. As of March 2017, the amount of certified capacity under “general wood and agriculture waste” has, with 11.4 GW, already far surpassed the <NODE id="764" />bioenergy<NODE id="773" /> targets initially defined by the Japanese government (2.7 to 4.0 GWe). If all the projects awarded feed-in tariff (FIT) contracts under this category go ahead, <NODE id="934" />biomass<NODE id="941" /> demand could reach 47 million oven dry metric tons (ODMT) by 2021. Announced <NODE id="1019" />bioenergy<NODE id="1028" /> projects in South Korea are also expected to increase current wood <NODE id="1096" />biomass<NODE id="1103" /> import demand from 2 million ODMT to up to 12 million ODMT by 2024.
<NODE id="1172" />Biomass<NODE id="1179" /> Sourcing Strategies
<NODE id="1200" />Bioenergy<NODE id="1209" /> projects in Asia Pacific are mainly targeting <NODE id="1256" />industrial wood pellets<NODE id="1279" />, <NODE id="1281" />woodchips<NODE id="1290" /> and <NODE id="1295" />palm kernel shells<NODE id="1313" /> (<NODE id="1315" />PKS<NODE id="1318" />) as <NODE id="1323" />biomass<NODE id="1330" /> fuel. As these feedstocks all have different characteristics, the technical design of each <NODE id="1422" />bioenergy<NODE id="1431" /> plant will need to be tailored according to the <NODE id="1480" />biomass<NODE id="1487" /> feedstock mix, in order to maximize efficiencies and minimize operating costs. Detailed trade-off analysis, covering different <NODE id="1615" />biomass<NODE id="1622" /> supply chains and technical designs, will afford developers and their investors a better understanding of expected returns and underlying risks, and help define risk mitigation strategies. Even though some project developers have already formulated <NODE id="1872" />biomass<NODE id="1879" /> sourcing strategies, the actual implementation of these strategies may yet change in reaction to future market conditions and requirements brought forward by investors. The Japanese market is especially characterized by a high level of uncertainty regarding preferred <NODE id="2148" />biomass<NODE id="2155" /> fuel assortments, and stakeholders will have to develop in-depth market knowledge and prepare strategies covering a range of potential future market scenarios.
Despite a theoretical potential of approximately 15 million metric tons of <NODE id="2391" />PKS<NODE id="2394" /> in Indonesia and Malaysia, only a limited share of these volumes will be available in the long run to meet demand from Japan and South Korea. The <NODE id="2541" />PKS<NODE id="2544" /> market will experience considerable changes going forward; increased mobilization efforts from international buyers in combination with often challenging inland logistics, and further increasing domestic demand for <NODE id="2760" />PKS<NODE id="2763" /> as <NODE id="2767" />biomass<NODE id="2774" /> fuel, are likely to result in considerable price increases.
The majority of <NODE id="2851" />biomass<NODE id="2858" /> fuel imports into Japan and South Korea will need to come in the form of <NODE id="2932" />industrial wood pellets<NODE id="2955" /> or <NODE id="2959" />wood chips<NODE id="2969" />, both of which largely come from the same fiber resource base. Thus, before defining long-term <NODE id="3065" />biomass<NODE id="3072" /> sourcing strategies, a detailed understanding of current and future wood fiber availability in potential supply regions is required, in order to develop a clear understanding of the risk of upcoming fiber shortages and price increases. Such assessments will also need to consider competing demand from and market expectations of other wood consuming industries, such as <NODE id="3443" />pulp<NODE id="3447" /> and <NODE id="3452" />paper<NODE id="3457" />, and <NODE id="3463" />wood products<NODE id="3476" />. For example, the Japanese and Chinese <NODE id="3516" />pulp<NODE id="3520" /> and <NODE id="3525" />paper<NODE id="3530" /> industries, both of which are currently importing around 10 million ODMT of <NODE id="3607" />wood chips<NODE id="3617" /> per year, might be wary of the increasing demand pressure, and its effect on international <NODE id="3709" />wood chip<NODE id="3718" /> markets.
Supply Chain Opportunity
Additional challenges come from the short timelines for developing and implementing sourcing strategies, as projects in Japan have a window of only three years from receiving a FIT contract to the start of operations. This does not allow for the development of significant additional forest plantation resources, and buyers will have to contend for the existing resource base in the short- to medium-term. Competition for existing supply opportunities will be intense, and buyers will have to mobilize resources from further afield, with associated higher transport costs. Not only could this increase supply costs, at least initially, it could also lead to less favorable carbon footprints, negating some of the positive impact <NODE id="4482" />bioenergy<NODE id="4491" /> can have on net carbon emissions in the power sector. Project cancellations can also be expected, as developers are likely to struggle to secure long-term supply contracts for the required <NODE id="4681" />biomass<NODE id="4688" /> assortments at affordable price levels.
The expectation of significant demand increases in Japan and South Korea offers interesting opportunities for a range of stakeholders across <NODE id="4870" />wood pellet<NODE id="4881" /> and <NODE id="4886" />wood chip<NODE id="4895" /> supply chains. Indonesia, Malaysia, Thailand and Vietnam are attractive supply sources where production capacity can be expanded, drawing on a mixture of roundwood from fast-growing forestry plantations, residues from wood processing industries, and other residue sources such as rubber wood plantations. Other regions, such as the Russian Far East, western Canada, Brazil and Australia are also expected to play important roles as potential supply regions, due to an existing <NODE id="5373" />biomass<NODE id="5380" /> surplus and the potential for establishment of new plantations.
Several developers of <NODE id="5467" />bioenergy<NODE id="5476" /> projects in Japan and South Korea have also shown intent to invest upstream, by acquiring or co-investing in existing <NODE id="5595" />biomass<NODE id="5602" /> supply projects, or by developing their own greenfield projects. However, any upstream integration strategy that does not cover the full supply chain still leaves the risk of increasing <NODE id="5789" />biomass<NODE id="5796" /> raw material prices, or even supply shortages, potentially increasing investors’ exposure to risk. Only full upstream integration strategies, similar to strategies employed by Japanese <NODE id="5982" />pulp<NODE id="5986" /> and <NODE id="5991" />paper<NODE id="5996" /> producers, can provide a high level of supply and price security. In any case, such ventures will require comprehensive project due diligence covering all aspects of the supply chain, followed by a sound implementation strategy to successfully secure financing.
The Japanese and South Korean <NODE id="6289" />biopower<NODE id="6297" /> sectors are set to be the driving force behind substantial changes in dynamics for international <NODE id="6395" />biomass<NODE id="6402" /> markets, and stakeholders will have to tackle considerable uncertainties. Resource owners, <NODE id="6494" />biomass<NODE id="6501" /> suppliers, and <NODE id="6517" />bioenergy<NODE id="6526" /> producers need to develop a sound understanding of short-, medium- and long-term price trends for each <NODE id="6630" />biomass<NODE id="6637" /> assortment to avoid entering into unfavorable or unsustainable long-term fuel supply agreements.
 

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="http://biomassmagazine.com/articles/14854/the-asian-biomass-market-challenges-and-opportunities-ahead@2017-11-30T21:06:00.000+01:00" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://biomassmagazine.com/articles/14854/the-asian-biomass-market-challenges-and-opportunities-ahead" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="83" endPos="90" type="product" surface="Biomass" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="138" endPos="147" type="product" surface="bioenergy" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="298" endPos="305" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="359" endPos="368" type="product" surface="bioenergy" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="764" endPos="773" type="product" surface="bioenergy" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="934" endPos="941" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1019" endPos="1028" type="product" surface="bioenergy" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1096" endPos="1103" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1172" endPos="1179" type="product" surface="Biomass" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="1200" endPos="1209" type="product" surface="Bioenergy" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="1256" endPos="1279" type="product" surface="industrial wood pellets" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1281" endPos="1290" type="product" surface="woodchips" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1295" endPos="1313" type="product" surface="palm kernel shells" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="1315" endPos="1318" type="product" surface="PKS" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="1323" endPos="1330" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="1422" endPos="1431" type="product" surface="bioenergy" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="1480" endPos="1487" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="1615" endPos="1622" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="1872" endPos="1879" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2148" endPos="2155" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="2391" endPos="2394" type="product" surface="PKS" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="2541" endPos="2544" type="product" surface="PKS" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="2760" endPos="2763" type="product" surface="PKS" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="2767" endPos="2774" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="2851" endPos="2858" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="2932" endPos="2955" type="product" surface="industrial wood pellets" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="2959" endPos="2969" type="product" surface="wood chips" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="3065" endPos="3072" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="3443" endPos="3447" type="product" surface="pulp" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="3452" endPos="3457" type="product" surface="paper" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="3463" endPos="3476" type="product" surface="wood products" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="3516" endPos="3520" type="product" surface="pulp" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="3525" endPos="3530" type="product" surface="paper" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="3607" endPos="3617" type="product" surface="wood chips" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="3709" endPos="3718" type="product" surface="wood chip" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="4482" endPos="4491" type="product" surface="bioenergy" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="4681" endPos="4688" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="4870" endPos="4881" type="product" surface="wood pellet" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="4886" endPos="4895" type="product" surface="wood chip" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="5373" endPos="5380" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="5467" endPos="5476" type="product" surface="bioenergy" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="5595" endPos="5602" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="5789" endPos="5796" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="5982" endPos="5986" type="product" surface="pulp" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="5991" endPos="5996" type="product" surface="paper" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="6289" endPos="6297" type="product" surface="biopower" />
<Entity id="46" startPos="6395" endPos="6402" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="47" startPos="6494" endPos="6501" type="product" surface="biomass" />
<Entity id="48" startPos="6517" endPos="6526" type="product" surface="bioenergy" />
<Entity id="49" startPos="6630" endPos="6637" type="product" surface="biomass" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="50" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="39" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
<Entity id="41" label="target" />
<Entity id="42" label="target" />
<Entity id="49" label="target" />
<Entity id="23" label="target" />
<Entity id="27" label="target" />
<Entity id="47" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
<Entity id="18" label="target" />
<Entity id="24" label="target" />
<Entity id="36" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="19" label="target" />
<Entity id="46" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="51" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="40" label="target" />
<Entity id="35" label="target" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="45" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="52" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="10" label="source" />
<Entity id="37" label="target" />
<Entity id="25" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="53" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="11" label="source" />
<Entity id="38" label="target" />
<Entity id="26" label="target" />
<Entity id="34" label="target" />
<Entity id="33" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="54" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="12" label="source" />
<Entity id="20" label="target" />
<Entity id="21" label="target" />
<Entity id="13" label="target" />
<Entity id="22" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="55" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="28" label="source" />
<Entity id="43" label="target" />
<Entity id="31" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="56" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="29" label="source" />
<Entity id="44" label="target" />
<Entity id="32" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
