<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>DISCLAIMER
You are now leaving <NODE id="31" />Devon Energy<NODE id="43" />’s website and are going to a website that is not operated by <NODE id="105" />Devon Energy<NODE id="117" />. <NODE id="119" />We<NODE id="121" /> are not responsible for the content or availability of linked sites.
ABOUT THIRD PARTY LINKS ON OUR SITE
<NODE id="227" />Devon Energy<NODE id="239" /> offers links to other third party websites that may be of interest to our website visitors. When you click on these links you will leave <NODE id="377" />Devon Energy<NODE id="389" />’s website and will be redirected to another site. These sites are not under the control of <NODE id="481" />Devon Energy<NODE id="493" />.
<NODE id="495" />Devon Energy<NODE id="507" /> is not responsible for the content of linked third party websites. <NODE id="575" />We<NODE id="577" /> are not an agent for these third parties nor do <NODE id="626" />we<NODE id="628" /> endorse or guarantee any of their opinions, ideas, products, or content . We make no representation or warranty regarding the accuracy of the information contained in the linked sites. <NODE id="814" />We<NODE id="816" /> suggest that you always verify the information obtained from linked websites before acting upon this information.
Also, please be aware that that the security and privacy policies on these sites may be different from <NODE id="1034" />Devon Energy<NODE id="1046" />’s policies, so please read third party privacy and security policies closely.
If you have any questions or concerns about the products and services offered on linked third party websites, please contact the third party directly.
Click “CONTINUE” to acknowledge this disclosure and view the selected website. If you click “CANCEL”, you are acknowledging this disclosure, but you will not be able to view the information.
Cancel

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/iter03/95" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.devonenergy.com/" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="31" endPos="43" type="organization" surface="Devon Energy" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="105" endPos="117" type="organization" surface="Devon Energy" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="119" endPos="121" type="organization" surface="We" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="227" endPos="239" type="organization" surface="Devon Energy" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="377" endPos="389" type="organization" surface="Devon Energy" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="481" endPos="493" type="organization" surface="Devon Energy" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="495" endPos="507" type="organization" surface="Devon Energy" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="575" endPos="577" type="organization" surface="We" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="626" endPos="628" type="organization" surface="we" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="814" endPos="816" type="organization" surface="We" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="1034" endPos="1046" type="organization" surface="Devon Energy" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="11" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
