<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT><NODE id="0" />Tire<NODE id="4" /> manufacturing is a complex operation that consists of many steps, with stringent requirements for quality control throughout the process. Quality control of <NODE id="162" />tires<NODE id="167" /> involves inspecting many components, with each component having to satisfy precise location and finished tire specifications. Given the complexity of this process, machine vision systems used for inspection need to be as simple as possible and operate with a high level of efficiency. Integration and Installation Simplification One of the most effective ways to minimize system complexity is by simplifying  integration and installation. You can do this by implementing factory calibrated <NODE id="658" />3D smart all-in-one sensors<NODE id="685" /> into your <NODE id="696" />tire<NODE id="700" /> inspection system. “Smart” <NODE id="728" />sensors<NODE id="735" /> provide tightly integrated  acquisition and control logic  inside the <NODE id="806" />sensor<NODE id="812" />, and eliminate the need for external hardware and related development. The result is reduced cost and lower maintenance, with the added bonus of increased system reliability. Built-In Measurement Tools Yet another challenge for <NODE id="1041" />tire<NODE id="1045" /> inspection technicians is the the need to develop custom software development for analyzing profile images for geometric parameters such as grooves, found on many components in the <NODE id="1227" />tire<NODE id="1231" /> building process. This is a very specialized  and time consuming task. Again <NODE id="1309" />3D smart sensors<NODE id="1325" /> offer an elegant solution with built-in, application-specific measurement tools. The smartest of today’s <NODE id="1431" />3D sensors<NODE id="1441" /> include tools to measure width, depth and centerline position of U shaped, V shaped and open grooves, and have the ability to measure multiple grooves over the width of a profile with measurement compensation for product tilt. These tools also make it easy for users to generate recipes for new product designs through a simple browser interface. Better Connectivity Communications with other machine elements can also be complex, particularly with the broad variety of <NODE id="1912" />PLCs<NODE id="1916" /> and <NODE id="1921" />robot interfaces<NODE id="1937" /> today. Communication issues can be simplified by selecting a <NODE id="1999" />smart 3D sensor<NODE id="2014" /> with built-in standard protocols  for common industrial <NODE id="2071" />PLCs<NODE id="2075" /> as well as general Gigabit Ethernet output. Product Changeover Simplification Many <NODE id="2159" />tire<NODE id="2163" /> manufacturers will change recipes several times per shift, and must accomplish changes rapidly to achieve required throughput. <NODE id="2291" />3D sensors<NODE id="2301" /> deliver the required accuracy, as well as a large enough range and field-of-view to cover the full range of part geometries, which eliminates the need to reposition <NODE id="2467" />sensors<NODE id="2474" /> on changeover. For wide field-of-view applications, several <NODE id="2535" />sensors<NODE id="2542" /> can be mounted side-by-side for complete high resolution profiling. This task is simplified by using <NODE id="2644" />sensors<NODE id="2651" /> that can be easily scaled to provide a single synchronized profile output. Changeover can also be simplified with <NODE id="2766" />sensors<NODE id="2773" /> that can store multiple jobs or recipes. The ability to store multiple geometry configurations in the <NODE id="2876" />sensor<NODE id="2882" /> makes changes between different recipes quick and simple, which is critical to minimizing downtime for operations that make model changes multiple times per shift. Conclusion Integrating, installing and operating <NODE id="3096" />3D sensors<NODE id="3106" /> in <NODE id="3110" />tire<NODE id="3114" /> manufacturing can be complicated and expensive, but today’s <NODE id="3175" />3D smart sensors<NODE id="3191" /> can dramatically simplify these issues and minimize system complexity to produce optimal results. Tags:  3D scanning 3D inspection 3D <NODE id="3326" />tire<NODE id="3330" /> inspection systems minimizing system complexity Date:  Thursday, January 28, 2016 - 09:30 Thumbnail:  Author:  Walt Pastorius Featured:  Category:  Quality Control Homepage Thumbnail: 
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/51d35d9e-20f6-340d-b9c3-f98a30bee4c7" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-28T18:43:14Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:06:10.415Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://blog.lmi3d.com/blog/minimizing-system-complexity-rubber-and-tire-inspection" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="0" endPos="4" type="product" surface="Tire" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="162" endPos="167" type="product" surface="tires" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="658" endPos="685" type="product" surface="3D smart all-in-one sensors" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="696" endPos="700" type="product" surface="tire" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="728" endPos="735" type="product" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="806" endPos="812" type="product" surface="sensor" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1041" endPos="1045" type="product" surface="tire" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1227" endPos="1231" type="product" surface="tire" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1309" endPos="1325" type="product" surface="3D smart sensors" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="1431" endPos="1441" type="product" surface="3D sensors" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="1912" endPos="1916" type="product" surface="PLCs" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1921" endPos="1937" type="product" surface="robot interfaces" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1999" endPos="2014" type="product" surface="smart 3D sensor" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="2071" endPos="2075" type="product" surface="PLCs" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="2159" endPos="2163" type="product" surface="tire" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="2291" endPos="2301" type="product" surface="3D sensors" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="2467" endPos="2474" type="product" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="2535" endPos="2542" type="product" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="2644" endPos="2651" type="product" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2766" endPos="2773" type="product" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="2876" endPos="2882" type="product" surface="sensor" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="3096" endPos="3106" type="product" surface="3D sensors" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="3110" endPos="3114" type="product" surface="tire" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="3175" endPos="3191" type="product" surface="3D smart sensors" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="3326" endPos="3330" type="product" surface="tire" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="25" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="24" label="target" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="22" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="26" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="2" label="source" />
<Entity id="18" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="23" label="target" />
<Entity id="19" label="target" />
<Entity id="21" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="20" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="27" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="10" label="source" />
<Entity id="13" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
