<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT><NODE id="0" />BACnet International<NODE id="20" /> Welcomes New Slate of Members to Board of Directors (January 26, 2016) Atlanta, GA (<NODE id="105" />PRWEB<NODE id="110" />) January 26, 2016 <NODE id="129" />BACnet International<NODE id="149" /> is pleased to announce the results of <NODE id="188" />its<NODE id="191" /> recent board of directors elections. The new board is comprised of eight industry executives, including: Roland Laird, Andy McMillan, Jonathan Fulton, Brad Hill, Dennis Swoboda, Raymond Rae, Nancy Stein and Michael Wilson. The board of <NODE id="428" />BACnet International<NODE id="448" /> will continue to focus on expanding the successful use of the <NODE id="511" />BACnet<NODE id="517" /> building automation protocol<NODE id="546" />. The following individuals will serve on the 2016 <NODE id="597" />BACnet International<NODE id="617" /> Board of Directors: Roland Laird, Reliable Controls Chair Roland Laird is the founder and president of Reliable Controls Corporation. Since 1986, Reliable Controls has grown to more than 120 professionals, providing a comprehensive <NODE id="850" />BACnet<NODE id="856" /> building automation<NODE id="876" /> <NODE id="877" />system<NODE id="883" />. In his current role as president, Laird maintains an active involvement in product development with special emphasis on quality assurance. Through 2005 to 2010, he was an active participant in <NODE id="1078" />BACnet Internationals<NODE id="1099" /> <NODE id="1100" />BACnet<NODE id="1106" /> Testing Labs<NODE id="1119" /> working group and the ASHRAE SSPC 135 <NODE id="1158" />BACnet<NODE id="1164" /> Committee. Laird graduated with honors in instrumentation technology from the <NODE id="1243" />British Columbia Institute of Technology<NODE id="1283" /> in 1980. Andy McMillan, <NODE id="1308" />BACnet International<NODE id="1328" /> President &amp; Managing Director Andy McMillan is president of <NODE id="1389" />BACnet International<NODE id="1409" />, where he works with users and suppliers to expand and enhance the BACnet community. Formerly he served as president and general manager of an building automation unit of <NODE id="1581" />Philips Lighting<NODE id="1597" />. McMillans background includes broad open systems industry development and marketing experience, as well as strong technical knowledge of distributed automation and information management systems. McMillan has co-founded several companies and has been a featured speaker on open systems and automation at conferences in North America, Europe, Japan and Australia. McMillan co-authored a book on open systems networking and holds a dozen patents in <NODE id="2046" />sensors<NODE id="2053" />, automation and software. He has MBA and BSEE degrees from the <NODE id="2117" />University of Michigan<NODE id="2139" /> and is a member of ASHRAE, AEE, IEEE. Jonathan Fulton, <NODE id="2195" />Building Control Integrators<NODE id="2223" /> (<NODE id="2225" />BCI<NODE id="2228" />) Jonathan Fulton is the founder of an Ohio-based integration firm called <NODE id="2302" />Building Control Integrators<NODE id="2330" /> (<NODE id="2332" />BCI<NODE id="2335" />), which specializes in high-level <NODE id="2370" />BACnet<NODE id="2376" /> integrations. He has been actively involved in designing, implementing and servicing <NODE id="2462" />BACnet<NODE id="2468" /> based systems since 1995. As a state of Ohio licensed HVAC and electrical contractor, he regularly deals with multiple facets of the automation industry. Fulton attended <NODE id="2639" />DeVry University<NODE id="2655" />, <NODE id="2657" />Moody Bible Institute<NODE id="2678" /> and <NODE id="2683" />Western Theological Seminary<NODE id="2711" /> in pursuit of technological and theological studies. He is passionate about open protocols, the spiritual development of others, and personal higher learning. Fulton is happily married with three children and concurrently serves as a pastor of a central Ohio church. Brad Hill, <NODE id="2990" />Honeywell International<NODE id="3013" /> Brad Hill is working as a project management office leader for <NODE id="3077" />Honeywell Environmental and Energy Solutions<NODE id="3121" /> where he is involved in leading the new product development of commercial building offerings. Hill joined <NODE id="3228" />Honeywell<NODE id="3237" /> in 1990 where he was involved in the design and programming of complex integrated control solutions for large projects. He began involvement with <NODE id="3384" />BACnet<NODE id="3390" /> in 1996 through the need to integrate <NODE id="3429" />BACnet<NODE id="3435" /> devices into building management systems. In 1999, Hill began product development work which included the development of a <NODE id="3559" />BACnet<NODE id="3565" /> operator workstation, where he acquired a deep knowledge of the <NODE id="3630" />BACnet<NODE id="3636" /> standard, after which time he continued on to manage and then lead building management product developments. Hill holds an MBA, MES (Energy Studies), BCompSc (Hons), and a DipElecEng, and is a certified Six Sigma Black Belt and PMP®. Dennis Swoboda, <NODE id="3887" />Blue Ridge Technologies<NODE id="3910" /> Dennis Swoboda is the vice president of sales and marketing for <NODE id="3975" />Blue Ridge Technologies<NODE id="3998" />, a <NODE id="4002" />manufacturer<NODE id="4014" /> of Native <NODE id="4025" />BACnet<NODE id="4031" /> lighting control<NODE id="4048" /> <NODE id="4049" />solutions<NODE id="4058" /> designed for open communication with most building automation systems. In his role, Swoboda oversees global sales and marketing initiatives for the <NODE id="4207" />sale<NODE id="4211" /> and <NODE id="4216" />installation<NODE id="4228" /> of <NODE id="4232" />Blue Ridge Technologies<NODE id="4255" /> lighting control<NODE id="4272" /> <NODE id="4273" />systems<NODE id="4280" />. In addition, he works with engineers, end users, owners and controls contractors to help lower life cycle costs, increase energy savings, and reduce carbon emissions by taking control of the largest energy loads in a building. Swoboda has over 20 years of lighting control experience, and gives frequent talks and presentations on energy codes, lighting, and <NODE id="4641" />BACnet<NODE id="4647" />. He has been a member of <NODE id="4673" />BACnet International<NODE id="4693" /> for almost a decade, and has previously served as the <NODE id="4748" />BACnet International<NODE id="4768" /> marketing committee chair. Raymond Rae, <NODE id="4809" />Delta Controls, Inc.<NODE id="4829" /> Raymond Rae is the vice president of <NODE id="4867" />Delta Controls Inc.<NODE id="4886" />, a full line <NODE id="4900" />manufacturer<NODE id="4912" /> of native <NODE id="4923" />BACnet<NODE id="4929" /> Direct Digital Control<NODE id="4952" /> (<NODE id="4954" />DDC<NODE id="4957" />) <NODE id="4959" />systems<NODE id="4966" /> for building automation systems. Rae co-founded the <NODE id="5019" />Delta Controls Group<NODE id="5039" /> in 1980, which now has thousands of installations worldwide. Rae has enjoyed more than 35 years in the HVAC industry and has an extensive background, which includes: energy auditing, computerized building simulations, system commissioning, controls, engineering, product certifications, design and marketing. Rae has been a member of ASHRAE since 1984. Nancy Stein, <NODE id="5406" />Siemens<NODE id="5413" /> Industry Inc.<NODE id="5427" /> Nancy Stein is director of product management for <NODE id="5478" />Siemens<NODE id="5485" /> Building Technologies<NODE id="5507" />, Control Products and Systems (CPS) Business Unit. In her role, Stein is responsible for strategic direction of all CPS products. She also monitors the development of business plans and manages product lifecycles and market positioning. Stein has been with <NODE id="5765" />Siemens<NODE id="5772" /> for over 22 years in product marketing and solution sales positions. Stein has a bachelors in mechanical engineering from Purdue University and a masters in business administration from DePaul University. Michael R. Wilson, <NODE id="5997" />Automated Logic<NODE id="6012" /> Michael has worked for <NODE id="6036" />Automated Logic<NODE id="6051" /> since 2003, and is presently the product marketing manager. In this role, Wilson gathers VOC, competitive and market analysis in order to support product roadmap. Wilson has served as the marketing committee chair, as well as a member of the steering committee. Wilsons leadership and contributions have been recognized by <NODE id="6375" />BACnet International<NODE id="6395" /> on many occasions, where he has won awards for always coming to the rescue, for being, an individual who exhibits outstanding leadership, and as Volunteer of the Year. Wilson has a strategy and information technology background and has also served as the presentation consultant to CIOs of <NODE id="6686" />Delta Air Lines<NODE id="6701" /> and <NODE id="6706" />The Home Depot<NODE id="6720" />. We have a great team of leaders on the board of directors for <NODE id="6784" />BACnet International<NODE id="6804" />, said McMillan. This <NODE id="6826" />group<NODE id="6831" /> has experience in all areas of building technology and automation. As the industry continues to evolve, <NODE id="6936" />BACnet International<NODE id="6956" /> remains committed to providing educational programs and opportunities to help building owners/operators, building engineers and facility managers take full advantage of the <NODE id="7130" />BACnet<NODE id="7136" /> protocol<NODE id="7145" />. About <NODE id="7153" />BACnet International<NODE id="7173" /> <NODE id="7174" />BACnet International<NODE id="7194" /> is an industry association that facilitates the successful use of the <NODE id="7265" />BACnet<NODE id="7271" /> protocol<NODE id="7280" /> in building automation and control systems through interoperability testing, educational programs and promotional activities. <NODE id="7407" />BACnet International<NODE id="7427" /> oversees operation of the <NODE id="7454" />BACnet<NODE id="7460" /> Testing Labs<NODE id="7473" /> (<NODE id="7475" />BTL<NODE id="7478" />) and maintains a global listing of tested products . The <NODE id="7536" />BACnet<NODE id="7542" /> standard was developed by the American Society of Heating, Refrigerating and Air-Conditioning Engineers (ASHRAE) and has been made publicly available so that manufacturers can create interoperable systems of products. <NODE id="7761" />BACnet International<NODE id="7781" /> complements the work of the ASHRAE standards committee and <NODE id="7841" />BACnet<NODE id="7847" />-related interest groups around the world. <NODE id="7890" />BACnet International<NODE id="7910" /> members include building owners, consulting engineers and facility managers, as well as companies involved in the design, manufacturing, installation, commissioning and maintenance of control equipment that uses <NODE id="8123" />BACnet<NODE id="8129" /> for communication. For more information, please visit http://www.bacnetinternational.org . Read the full story at http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/01/prweb13181364.htm . Page: 1 Related Keywords:
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/38ee9506-1673-3cf6-b03c-d350b89a848c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-26T22:12:49Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:56:46.559Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://presentationmaster.digitalmedianet.com/article/BACnet-International-Welcomes-New-Slate-of-Members-to-Board-of-Directors-4262035" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="0" endPos="20" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="105" endPos="110" type="organization" surface="PRWEB" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="129" endPos="149" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="188" endPos="191" type="organization" surface="its" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="428" endPos="448" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="511" endPos="517" type="organization" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="511" endPos="546" type="product" surface="BACnet building automation protocol" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="597" endPos="617" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="850" endPos="856" type="organization" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="850" endPos="876" type="product" surface="BACnet building automation" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="877" endPos="883" type="trigger" surface="system" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1078" endPos="1099" type="organization" surface="BACnet Internationals" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1100" endPos="1106" type="organization" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="1100" endPos="1119" type="organization" surface="BACnet Testing Labs" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="1158" endPos="1164" type="organization" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="1243" endPos="1283" type="organization" surface="British Columbia Institute of Technology" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="1308" endPos="1328" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="1389" endPos="1409" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="1581" endPos="1597" type="organization" surface="Philips Lighting" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2046" endPos="2053" type="product" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="2117" endPos="2139" type="organization" surface="University of Michigan" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="2195" endPos="2223" type="organization" surface="Building Control Integrators" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="2225" endPos="2228" type="organization" surface="BCI" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="2302" endPos="2330" type="organization" surface="Building Control Integrators" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="2332" endPos="2335" type="organization" surface="BCI" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="2370" endPos="2376" type="product" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="2462" endPos="2468" type="product" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="2639" endPos="2655" type="organization" surface="DeVry University" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="2657" endPos="2678" type="organization" surface="Moody Bible Institute" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="2683" endPos="2711" type="organization" surface="Western Theological Seminary" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="2990" endPos="3013" type="organization" surface="Honeywell International" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="3077" endPos="3121" type="organization" surface="Honeywell Environmental and Energy Solutions" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="3228" endPos="3237" type="organization" surface="Honeywell" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="3384" endPos="3390" type="product" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="3429" endPos="3435" type="product" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="3559" endPos="3565" type="product" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="3630" endPos="3636" type="product" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="3887" endPos="3910" type="organization" surface="Blue Ridge Technologies" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="3975" endPos="3998" type="organization" surface="Blue Ridge Technologies" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="4002" endPos="4014" type="trigger" surface="manufacturer" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="4025" endPos="4031" type="organization" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="4025" endPos="4048" type="product" surface="BACnet lighting control" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="4049" endPos="4058" type="trigger" surface="solutions" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="4207" endPos="4211" type="trigger" surface="sale" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="4216" endPos="4228" type="trigger" surface="installation" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="4232" endPos="4255" type="organization" surface="Blue Ridge Technologies" />
<Entity id="46" startPos="4232" endPos="4272" type="product" surface="Blue Ridge Technologies lighting control" />
<Entity id="47" startPos="4273" endPos="4280" type="trigger" surface="systems" />
<Entity id="48" startPos="4641" endPos="4647" type="product" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="49" startPos="4673" endPos="4693" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="50" startPos="4748" endPos="4768" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="51" startPos="4809" endPos="4829" type="organization" surface="Delta Controls, Inc." />
<Entity id="52" startPos="4867" endPos="4886" type="organization" surface="Delta Controls Inc." />
<Entity id="53" startPos="4900" endPos="4912" type="trigger" surface="manufacturer" />
<Entity id="54" startPos="4923" endPos="4929" type="organization" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="55" startPos="4923" endPos="4952" type="product" surface="BACnet Direct Digital Control" />
<Entity id="56" startPos="4954" endPos="4957" type="product" surface="DDC" />
<Entity id="57" startPos="4959" endPos="4966" type="trigger" surface="systems" />
<Entity id="58" startPos="5019" endPos="5039" type="organization" surface="Delta Controls Group" />
<Entity id="59" startPos="5406" endPos="5413" type="organization" surface="Siemens" />
<Entity id="60" startPos="5406" endPos="5427" type="organization" surface="Siemens Industry Inc." />
<Entity id="61" startPos="5478" endPos="5485" type="organization" surface="Siemens" />
<Entity id="62" startPos="5478" endPos="5507" type="organization" surface="Siemens Building Technologies" />
<Entity id="63" startPos="5765" endPos="5772" type="organization" surface="Siemens" />
<Entity id="64" startPos="5997" endPos="6012" type="organization" surface="Automated Logic" />
<Entity id="65" startPos="6036" endPos="6051" type="organization" surface="Automated Logic" />
<Entity id="66" startPos="6375" endPos="6395" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="67" startPos="6686" endPos="6701" type="organization" surface="Delta Air Lines" />
<Entity id="68" startPos="6706" endPos="6720" type="organization" surface="The Home Depot" />
<Entity id="69" startPos="6784" endPos="6804" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="70" startPos="6826" endPos="6831" type="organization" surface="group" />
<Entity id="71" startPos="6936" endPos="6956" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="72" startPos="7130" endPos="7136" type="organization" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="73" startPos="7130" endPos="7145" type="product" surface="BACnet protocol" />
<Entity id="74" startPos="7153" endPos="7173" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="75" startPos="7174" endPos="7194" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="76" startPos="7265" endPos="7271" type="organization" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="77" startPos="7265" endPos="7280" type="product" surface="BACnet protocol" />
<Entity id="78" startPos="7407" endPos="7427" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="79" startPos="7454" endPos="7460" type="organization" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="80" startPos="7454" endPos="7473" type="organization" surface="BACnet Testing Labs" />
<Entity id="81" startPos="7475" endPos="7478" type="organization" surface="BTL" />
<Entity id="82" startPos="7536" endPos="7542" type="product" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="83" startPos="7761" endPos="7781" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="84" startPos="7841" endPos="7847" type="product" surface="BACnet" />
<Entity id="85" startPos="7890" endPos="7910" type="organization" surface="BACnet International" />
<Entity id="86" startPos="8123" endPos="8129" type="product" surface="BACnet" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="87" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="6" label="product" />
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="88" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
<Entity id="10" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="89" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="41" label="product" />
<Entity id="38" label="company" />
<Entity id="39" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="90" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="41" label="product" />
<Entity id="40" label="company" />
<Entity id="42" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="91" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="46" label="product" />
<Entity id="45" label="company" />
<Entity id="44" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="47" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="43" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="92" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="55" label="product" />
<Entity id="52" label="company" />
<Entity id="53" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="93" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="55" label="product" />
<Entity id="54" label="company" />
<Entity id="57" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="94" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="73" label="product" />
<Entity id="72" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="95" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="77" label="product" />
<Entity id="76" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="96" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="76" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="70" label="target" />
<Entity id="75" label="target" />
<Entity id="83" label="target" />
<Entity id="66" label="target" />
<Entity id="78" label="target" />
<Entity id="69" label="target" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="49" label="target" />
<Entity id="54" label="target" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="71" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="72" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="40" label="target" />
<Entity id="85" label="target" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="79" label="target" />
<Entity id="74" label="target" />
<Entity id="50" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="97" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="6" label="source" />
<Entity id="73" label="target" />
<Entity id="34" label="target" />
<Entity id="82" label="target" />
<Entity id="35" label="target" />
<Entity id="26" label="target" />
<Entity id="25" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="86" label="target" />
<Entity id="33" label="target" />
<Entity id="48" label="target" />
<Entity id="84" label="target" />
<Entity id="77" label="target" />
<Entity id="36" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="98" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="13" label="source" />
<Entity id="81" label="target" />
<Entity id="80" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="99" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="21" label="source" />
<Entity id="24" label="target" />
<Entity id="22" label="target" />
<Entity id="23" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="100" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="30" label="source" />
<Entity id="32" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="101" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="37" label="source" />
<Entity id="45" label="target" />
<Entity id="38" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="102" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="51" label="source" />
<Entity id="52" label="target" />
<Entity id="58" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="103" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="55" label="source" />
<Entity id="56" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="104" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="59" label="source" />
<Entity id="63" label="target" />
<Entity id="61" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="105" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="64" label="source" />
<Entity id="65" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
