<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>* Your First Name: * Your Last Name: * Subject: Press Release Spread Pune, Maharashtra, India Pune, Maharashtra -- Jan 21, 2016 / ( http://www.myprgenie.com ) -- The <NODE id="166" />report<NODE id="172" /> <NODE id="173" />IoT Healthcare Market by Components (Medical Device, System and Software, Service, and Connectivity Technology), Application (Telemedicine, Workflow Management, Connected Imaging, Medication Management), End-User - Global Forecast to 2020<NODE id="411" />, the global <NODE id="424" />IoT in healthcare<NODE id="441" /> market is expected to grow from USD 32.47 Billion in 2015 to USD 163.24 Billion by 2020, at a Compound Annual Growth Rate (CAGR) of 38.1% during the forecast period. In the current scenario, North America is expected to be the largest market on the basis of market size and technological advancements. Browse 75 market data tables and 44 figures spread through 146 pages and in-depth TOC on '<NODE id="834" />IoT Healthcare Market - Global Forecast to 2020<NODE id="881" />' http://www.marketsandmarkets.com/Market-Reports/iot-healthcare-market-160082804.html Early buyers will receive 10% customization on this <NODE id="1020" />report<NODE id="1026" />. Inquiry before Buying @ http://www.marketsandmarkets.com/Enquiry_Before_Buying.asp?id=160082804 The <NODE id="1128" />IoT in healthcare<NODE id="1145" /> terminology is used to define the implementation of the IoT-based technology solutions and associated services into the various applications healthcare sector. The solutions are primarily aimed at achieving the integration of connected medical devices and intelligent data analysis to enhance the operational efficiency of healthcare organizations. It also improvises the healthcare outcomes with reduced cost of care, using efficient tools and techniques. It imparts benefits to the various end-to-end needs, such as real-time patient engagement, remote monitoring, chronic disease management, inpatient monitoring, medication management, efficient clinical operations, and workflow management. The evolution of high speed networking technologies in healthcare organizations and the rise in demand for remote patient monitoring across the world are expected to drive the <NODE id="2018" />IoT in healthcare<NODE id="2035" /> market in the coming years. Patient data security and privacy is one of the challenges currently faced by healthcare organizations. As a result, solution providers are shifting focus towards IoT security solutions to safeguard the connected devices and patient data generated using those devices. IoT-based solutions are further enabling companies to increase operational efficiency. Innovation in next generation sensors is another major factor driving the <NODE id="2494" />IoT in healthcare<NODE id="2511" /> market. However, insufficient IoT technology skills and lack of governance standards act as restraining growth factors of the market. Furthermore, the <NODE id="2663" />IoT in healthcare<NODE id="2680" /> market is still in the growing phase. Major <NODE id="2725" />vendors<NODE id="2732" /> in the <NODE id="2740" />IoT in healthcare<NODE id="2757" /> market are <NODE id="2769" />Medtronic, Inc.<NODE id="2784" /> (U.S.), <NODE id="2793" />Philips<NODE id="2800" /> (the Netherlands), <NODE id="2820" />IBM Corporation<NODE id="2835" /> (U.S.), <NODE id="2844" />Cisco Systems<NODE id="2857" /> (U.S.), and <NODE id="2870" />GE Healthcare<NODE id="2883" /> (U.K.). The global <NODE id="2903" />IoT Healthcare<NODE id="2917" /> Market has been segmented on the basis of types of medical devices, systems and software, connectivity technologies, services, applications, end users, and regions. The <NODE id="3087" />report<NODE id="3093" /> includes various types of medical devices, namely, wearable external medical devices, implanted medical devices, and stationary medical devices. Systems and software include remote device management, network bandwidth management, data analytics, application security, and network security. Connectivity technologies have been segmented into Wi-Fi, BLE, NFC, ZigBee, cellular, and satellite technologies. The services have been segmented into system integration, professional services, and support and maintenance. In addition, the <NODE id="3625" />report<NODE id="3631" /> classifies the market into the regions such as North America, Europe, Asia-Pacific (APAC), Middle East and Africa (MEA), and Latin America. About <NODE id="3778" />MarketsandMarkets<NODE id="3795" />
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/c39ad060-9276-3eac-b5e9-4d94d30eae52" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-21T23:14:09Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:49:30.044Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.myprgenie.com/view-publication/iot-healthcare-market-expected-to-reach-163-24-billion-usd-by-2020" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="166" endPos="172" type="product" surface="report" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="173" endPos="411" type="product" surface="IoT Healthcare Market by Components (Medical Device, System and Software, Service, and Connectivity Technology), Application (Telemedicine, Workflow Management, Connected Imaging, Medication Management), End-User - Global Forecast to 2020" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="424" endPos="441" type="product" surface="IoT in healthcare" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="834" endPos="881" type="product" surface="IoT Healthcare Market - Global Forecast to 2020" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1020" endPos="1026" type="product" surface="report" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1128" endPos="1145" type="product" surface="IoT in healthcare" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="2018" endPos="2035" type="product" surface="IoT in healthcare" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="2494" endPos="2511" type="product" surface="IoT in healthcare" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="2663" endPos="2680" type="product" surface="IoT in healthcare" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2725" endPos="2732" type="trigger" surface="vendors" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2740" endPos="2757" type="product" surface="IoT in healthcare" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="2769" endPos="2784" type="organization" surface="Medtronic, Inc." />
<Entity id="12" startPos="2793" endPos="2800" type="organization" surface="Philips" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="2820" endPos="2835" type="organization" surface="IBM Corporation" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="2844" endPos="2857" type="organization" surface="Cisco Systems" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="2870" endPos="2883" type="organization" surface="GE Healthcare" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="2903" endPos="2917" type="product" surface="IoT Healthcare" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="3087" endPos="3093" type="product" surface="report" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="3625" endPos="3631" type="product" surface="report" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="3778" endPos="3795" type="organization" surface="MarketsandMarkets" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="20" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="10" label="product" />
<Entity id="13" label="company" />
<Entity id="9" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="21" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="10" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="company" />
<Entity id="9" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="22" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="10" label="product" />
<Entity id="11" label="company" />
<Entity id="9" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="23" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="10" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
<Entity id="9" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="24" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="10" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
<Entity id="9" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="25" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="3" label="source" />
<Entity id="18" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="0" label="target" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="26" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="2" label="source" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
