<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Press Releases Global <NODE id="22" />Photonic IC<NODE id="33" /> Market - Industry Analysis, Size, Share, Growth and Forecast 2022 : <NODE id="102" />Acute Market<NODE id="114" /> <NODE id="115" />Photonic IC<NODE id="126" /> Market India, 28 January 2016 -- <NODE id="160" />Acute Market Reports<NODE id="180" /> has <NODE id="185" />Added<NODE id="190" /> latest <NODE id="198" />Report<NODE id="204" /> on Global <NODE id="215" />Photonic IC<NODE id="226" /> Market Size, share,Strategies And Forecasts in <NODE id="274" />their<NODE id="279" /> <NODE id="280" />Market Research Reports<NODE id="303" /> in database. <NODE id="317" />Photonic integrated circuit<NODE id="344" /> is a equipment that combines numerous photonic operations into a single optical package. Unlike <NODE id="441" />electronic integrated circuits<NODE id="471" /> that makes use of electrons as information carriers and <NODE id="528" />photonic integrated circuits<NODE id="556" /> make use of photons. Since photons travel with the same speed as the speed with which light travels and so they are able to transfer information at greater speed than speed of electrons. Enhanced demand for high data speed and communication ability, generally in applications of data centers have resulted in significant growth of the <NODE id="892" />photonic IC<NODE id="903" /> market globally. The global <NODE id="932" />photonic IC<NODE id="943" /> market sector was evaluated at 191 million US dollars in year 2013 and is predicted to touch the revenue of 1300 million US dollars by the end of year 2022 growing at a CAGR rate of 26% during the forecasted period. Browse Full <NODE id="1172" />Report<NODE id="1178" /> With TOC @ http://www.acutemarketreports.com/report/photonic-ic-market-size The global <NODE id="1266" />photonic IC<NODE id="1277" /> market is emerging at an exceptional rate as it offers significant enhancements in energy consumption, system size, costs and reliability. The growth and expansion of the silicon photonics technique has helped in large scale production of <NODE id="1517" />photonic integrated circuits<NODE id="1545" /> at lesser costs. Also substantial advantages provided by <NODE id="1603" />photonic integrated circuits<NODE id="1631" /> in terms of efficacy, speed transfer ,volume, transmission capability, use of power and costs is predicted to enhance and increase their acceptance as well as market penetration across different end use business verticals like telecommunications, healthcare, metrology, aerospace, data communications, industrial and defense. However, the packaging threats as well as the issues of design related with the photonic integration and lack of digitization have to some extent inhibited the extensive acceptance of <NODE id="2142" />photonic integrated circuits<NODE id="2170" />. But the utilization of photons to provide high speed data or information transfer and data processing for purpose of computations offers a good business avenue for the growth and expansion of the <NODE id="2368" />photonic IC<NODE id="2379" /> market globally. Also commercial utilization of quantum computing is projected to provide business growth avenues for the global <NODE id="2509" />photonic IC<NODE id="2520" /> market. The global <NODE id="2540" />photonic IC<NODE id="2551" /> market is bifurcated into different market sections based on types, parts, raw materials, applications and geographical locations. Depending upon the integrated types, the universal <NODE id="2734" />photonic IC<NODE id="2745" /> market is divided into hybrid integration, monolithic integration and module integration. Hybrid integration was the key integration method utilized for photonic integration and contributing about 57% to the total market revenue share in year 2013. Method of Monolithic integration is predicted to display optimum growth during the projected period. Based on the parts , the global <NODE id="3128" />photonic IC<NODE id="3139" /> market is divided into <NODE id="3163" />detectors<NODE id="3172" />, <NODE id="3174" />lasers<NODE id="3180" />, <NODE id="3182" />optical amplifiers<NODE id="3200" />, <NODE id="3202" />modulators<NODE id="3212" />, <NODE id="3214" />attenuators<NODE id="3225" />, <NODE id="3227" />de-multiplexers<NODE id="3242" /> and <NODE id="3247" />multiplexers<NODE id="3259" />. Among different <NODE id="3277" />photonic integrated circuit<NODE id="3304" /> parts, <NODE id="3312" />lasers<NODE id="3318" /> contributed to major portion of the revenue share of about 29% to worldwide <NODE id="3395" />photonic IC<NODE id="3406" /> market in year 2013. <NODE id="3428" />Optical amplifiers<NODE id="3446" /> helping in realization of high level photonic amalgamation by recompensing for visual losses from individual photonic elements is predicted to display optimum market growth during the forecasted period. Based on the raw materials the global <NODE id="3688" />photonic IC<NODE id="3699" /> market sector is bifurcated into silicon, indium phosphide, lithium niobate, silicon on insulator, gallium arsenide and others that comprise of silicon nitride, silica on silicon and silicon dioxide. Silicon on insulator and insulin phosphide together contributed to about more than 61% of the universal market revenue share in year 2013. The domination of indium phosphide is generally due to its capability to combine opto electronic operations into an <NODE id="4155" />optical system chip<NODE id="4174" /> monolithically. Further, the advantages provided in terms of energy efficacy, volume, momentum, packaging and fabrication cost has further strengthened its position as a market leader. Depending upon the applications the global <NODE id="4403" />photonic IC<NODE id="4414" /> market is bifurcated into biophotonics, optical communications, optical signal processing and sensing. Biophotonics application is further divided into optical biosensors, medical instrumentations, analytics, diagnostics and photonic lab on a chip application. Optical communications is also bifurcated into optical datacom, fittx &amp; access networks, RF photonics, long haul networks and transport networks. Optical signal processing application comprises of various applications like quantum optics, optical metrology, quantum computing and optical instrumentation. Also sensing application includes <NODE id="5015" />chemical sensors<NODE id="5031" />, medicine, energy, utilities, structural engineering, aerospace sector and transport industry. Optical communications was the biggest application section in the global <NODE id="5200" />photonic IC<NODE id="5211" /> market contributing for more than 59% of the total market revenue share in year 2013. It is predicted to remain the biggest application section during the forecasted period as a result of growing demand from data center uses and applications. Today, biophotonics and sensing are the other key application sections jointly contributing for about 36% of the total revenue of the worldwide <NODE id="5599" />photonic IC<NODE id="5610" /> market. Though the recent contribution from the optical signal processing section is minimum, it is predicted to observe healthy growth after quantum computing services are available at commercial costs or business rates. Based on the geographical locations , the global <NODE id="5882" />photonic IC<NODE id="5893" /> market is divided into sub continent of North America, continent of Europe, APAC region and region of rest of the world that includes middle east region, region of Latin America and African zone. Browse All Reports of This Category @ http://www.acutemarketreports.com/category/ict-market Sub continent of North America was the biggest global <NODE id="6236" />photonic IC<NODE id="6247" /> market contributing about 38.56% of the total market revenue share in year 2013. It was followed by continent of Europe and APAC zone. During the predicted period, it is projected to remain the leading market section due to high level of penetration of <NODE id="6501" />photonic integrated circuit<NODE id="6528" /> based equipments in the area of fiber optic communications, generally data center uses and applications. APAC region is predicted to observe rapid expansion during the forecasted period surpassing sub continent of North America and continent of Europe. This growth can be primarily credited to enhanced demand from biophotonics uses &amp; applications and data center. Also detailed information about macro economic factors as well as micro economic factors affecting the global <NODE id="7004" />photonic IC<NODE id="7015" /> market is provided in the market report. This comprehensive information helps the new market players as well as the existing ones to take accurate business decisions. It thus facilitates their business growth and expansion by contributing largely to their revenues. All these concepts are explained in a simple and lucid language by using the graphical pictorial tools of data representation like charts, bars, diagrams, graphs, tables and spreadsheets. Key market players profiled in this <NODE id="7506" />market report<NODE id="7519" /> includes <NODE id="7529" />Luxtera Incorporation<NODE id="7550" />, <NODE id="7552" />JDS Uniphase Corporation<NODE id="7576" />, <NODE id="7578" />Kotura Incorporation<NODE id="7598" />, <NODE id="7600" />Alcatel-Lucent S.A.<NODE id="7619" />, <NODE id="7621" />M/A-COM Technology Solutions Holdings Incorporation<NODE id="7672" />, <NODE id="7674" />OneChip Photonics Limited<NODE id="7699" />, <NODE id="7701" />Kaiam Corporation<NODE id="7718" />, <NODE id="7720" />Infinera Corporation<NODE id="7740" />, <NODE id="7742" />Finisar Corporation<NODE id="7761" />, <NODE id="7763" />Mellanox Technologies Limited<NODE id="7792" />, <NODE id="7794" />Avago Technologies Limited<NODE id="7820" />, <NODE id="7822" />NeoPhotonics Corporation<NODE id="7846" />, <NODE id="7848" />Aifotec AG<NODE id="7858" />, <NODE id="7860" />Huawei Technologies Corporation Limited<NODE id="7899" />, <NODE id="7901" />TE Connectivity Limited<NODE id="7924" />, <NODE id="7926" />Oclaro Incorporation<NODE id="7946" />, <NODE id="7948" />Ciena Corporation<NODE id="7965" />, <NODE id="7967" />Intel Corporation<NODE id="7984" />, <NODE id="7986" />Hewlett Packard<NODE id="8001" />, <NODE id="8003" />Enablence Technologies Incorporation<NODE id="8039" /> and <NODE id="8044" />Agilent Technologies<NODE id="8064" />. These market participants have played key part in shaping the market dynamics and thus contributing towards the growth of the global <NODE id="8199" />photonic IC<NODE id="8210" /> market. About <NODE id="8225" />Acute Market Reports<NODE id="8245" /> <NODE id="8246" />Acute Market Reports<NODE id="8266" /> is the most sufficient <NODE id="8290" />collection<NODE id="8300" /> of <NODE id="8304" />market intelligence services<NODE id="8332" /> online. <NODE id="8341" />Acute Market Reports<NODE id="8361" /> <NODE id="8362" />provide<NODE id="8369" /> <NODE id="8370" />online reports<NODE id="8384" /> from over 100 best publishers and upgrade <NODE id="8427" />Acute Market Reports<NODE id="8447" /> collection regularly to offer direct online access to the world's most comprehensive and recent database with expert perceptions on worldwide industries, products, establishments and trends. <NODE id="8639" />Acute Market Reports<NODE id="8659" /> <NODE id="8660" />database<NODE id="8668" /> consists of 200,000+ <NODE id="8690" />market research reports<NODE id="8713" /> with detailed &amp; minute market research. For More Information, Visit <NODE id="8782" />Acute Market Reports<NODE id="8802" /> Contact: Chris Paul Office No 01, 1st Floor, Aditi Mall, Baner, Pune, MH, 411045 India Phone (India): +91 7755981103 Toll Free (US/Canada): +1-855-455-8662 Email: # # # Submitted by Ganesh Kumar , <NODE id="9000" />Acute Market Reports<NODE id="9020" /> on Thursday, 28 January 2016 at 9:23 PM Category: Business
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/a5c16575-aa8c-37cb-93cd-7751585039a2" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-29T06:34:50Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:38:02.01Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://news.scoopasia.com/index.php/news/global_photonic_ic_market_industry_analysis_size_share_growth_and_forecast_/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="22" endPos="33" type="product" surface="Photonic IC" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="102" endPos="114" type="organization" surface="Acute Market" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="115" endPos="126" type="product" surface="Photonic IC" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="160" endPos="180" type="organization" surface="Acute Market Reports" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="185" endPos="190" type="trigger" surface="Added" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="198" endPos="204" type="product" surface="Report" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="215" endPos="226" type="product" surface="Photonic IC" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="274" endPos="279" type="organization" surface="their" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="280" endPos="303" type="product" surface="Market Research Reports" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="317" endPos="344" type="product" surface="Photonic integrated circuit" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="441" endPos="471" type="product" surface="electronic integrated circuits" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="528" endPos="556" type="product" surface="photonic integrated circuits" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="892" endPos="903" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="932" endPos="943" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="1172" endPos="1178" type="product" surface="Report" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="1266" endPos="1277" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="1517" endPos="1545" type="product" surface="photonic integrated circuits" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="1603" endPos="1631" type="product" surface="photonic integrated circuits" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="2142" endPos="2170" type="product" surface="photonic integrated circuits" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2368" endPos="2379" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="2509" endPos="2520" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="2540" endPos="2551" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="2734" endPos="2745" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="3128" endPos="3139" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="3163" endPos="3172" type="product" surface="detectors" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="3174" endPos="3180" type="product" surface="lasers" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="3182" endPos="3200" type="product" surface="optical amplifiers" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="3202" endPos="3212" type="product" surface="modulators" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="3214" endPos="3225" type="product" surface="attenuators" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="3227" endPos="3242" type="product" surface="de-multiplexers" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="3247" endPos="3259" type="product" surface="multiplexers" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="3277" endPos="3304" type="product" surface="photonic integrated circuit" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="3312" endPos="3318" type="product" surface="lasers" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="3395" endPos="3406" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="3428" endPos="3446" type="product" surface="Optical amplifiers" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="3688" endPos="3699" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="4155" endPos="4174" type="product" surface="optical system chip" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="4403" endPos="4414" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="5015" endPos="5031" type="product" surface="chemical sensors" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="5200" endPos="5211" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="5599" endPos="5610" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="5882" endPos="5893" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="6236" endPos="6247" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="6501" endPos="6528" type="product" surface="photonic integrated circuit" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="7004" endPos="7015" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="7506" endPos="7519" type="product" surface="market report" />
<Entity id="46" startPos="7529" endPos="7550" type="organization" surface="Luxtera Incorporation" />
<Entity id="47" startPos="7552" endPos="7576" type="organization" surface="JDS Uniphase Corporation" />
<Entity id="48" startPos="7578" endPos="7598" type="organization" surface="Kotura Incorporation" />
<Entity id="49" startPos="7600" endPos="7619" type="organization" surface="Alcatel-Lucent S.A." />
<Entity id="50" startPos="7621" endPos="7672" type="organization" surface="M/A-COM Technology Solutions Holdings Incorporation" />
<Entity id="51" startPos="7674" endPos="7699" type="organization" surface="OneChip Photonics Limited" />
<Entity id="52" startPos="7701" endPos="7718" type="organization" surface="Kaiam Corporation" />
<Entity id="53" startPos="7720" endPos="7740" type="organization" surface="Infinera Corporation" />
<Entity id="54" startPos="7742" endPos="7761" type="organization" surface="Finisar Corporation" />
<Entity id="55" startPos="7763" endPos="7792" type="organization" surface="Mellanox Technologies Limited" />
<Entity id="56" startPos="7794" endPos="7820" type="organization" surface="Avago Technologies Limited" />
<Entity id="57" startPos="7822" endPos="7846" type="organization" surface="NeoPhotonics Corporation" />
<Entity id="58" startPos="7848" endPos="7858" type="organization" surface="Aifotec AG" />
<Entity id="59" startPos="7860" endPos="7899" type="organization" surface="Huawei Technologies Corporation Limited" />
<Entity id="60" startPos="7901" endPos="7924" type="organization" surface="TE Connectivity Limited" />
<Entity id="61" startPos="7926" endPos="7946" type="organization" surface="Oclaro Incorporation" />
<Entity id="62" startPos="7948" endPos="7965" type="organization" surface="Ciena Corporation" />
<Entity id="63" startPos="7967" endPos="7984" type="organization" surface="Intel Corporation" />
<Entity id="64" startPos="7986" endPos="8001" type="organization" surface="Hewlett Packard" />
<Entity id="65" startPos="8003" endPos="8039" type="organization" surface="Enablence Technologies Incorporation" />
<Entity id="66" startPos="8044" endPos="8064" type="organization" surface="Agilent Technologies" />
<Entity id="67" startPos="8199" endPos="8210" type="product" surface="photonic IC" />
<Entity id="68" startPos="8225" endPos="8245" type="organization" surface="Acute Market Reports" />
<Entity id="69" startPos="8246" endPos="8266" type="organization" surface="Acute Market Reports" />
<Entity id="70" startPos="8290" endPos="8300" type="trigger" surface="collection" />
<Entity id="71" startPos="8304" endPos="8332" type="product" surface="market intelligence services" />
<Entity id="72" startPos="8341" endPos="8361" type="organization" surface="Acute Market Reports" />
<Entity id="73" startPos="8362" endPos="8369" type="trigger" surface="provide" />
<Entity id="74" startPos="8370" endPos="8384" type="product" surface="online reports" />
<Entity id="75" startPos="8427" endPos="8447" type="organization" surface="Acute Market Reports" />
<Entity id="76" startPos="8639" endPos="8659" type="organization" surface="Acute Market Reports" />
<Entity id="77" startPos="8660" endPos="8668" type="trigger" surface="database" />
<Entity id="78" startPos="8690" endPos="8713" type="product" surface="market research reports" />
<Entity id="79" startPos="8782" endPos="8802" type="organization" surface="Acute Market Reports" />
<Entity id="80" startPos="9000" endPos="9020" type="organization" surface="Acute Market Reports" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="81" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="5" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
<Entity id="4" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="82" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="71" label="product" />
<Entity id="69" label="company" />
<Entity id="70" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="83" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="74" label="product" />
<Entity id="72" label="company" />
<Entity id="73" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="84" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="78" label="product" />
<Entity id="76" label="company" />
<Entity id="77" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="85" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="39" label="target" />
<Entity id="31" label="target" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="67" label="target" />
<Entity id="40" label="target" />
<Entity id="21" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="44" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="23" label="target" />
<Entity id="37" label="target" />
<Entity id="35" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
<Entity id="19" label="target" />
<Entity id="43" label="target" />
<Entity id="41" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="22" label="target" />
<Entity id="13" label="target" />
<Entity id="18" label="target" />
<Entity id="42" label="target" />
<Entity id="33" label="target" />
<Entity id="20" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="86" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="75" label="target" />
<Entity id="69" label="target" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="80" label="target" />
<Entity id="76" label="target" />
<Entity id="72" label="target" />
<Entity id="79" label="target" />
<Entity id="68" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="87" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="5" label="source" />
<Entity id="45" label="target" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="88" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="8" label="source" />
<Entity id="74" label="target" />
<Entity id="78" label="target" />
<Entity id="71" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="89" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="25" label="source" />
<Entity id="32" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="90" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="26" label="source" />
<Entity id="34" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
