<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2013 (13) - BMW 1 Series 116d Sport 3dr £13,995 Reduced by £1,000 was £14,995 Loading Images... Date Registered: Mar 2013 Mileage: 14,125 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £13,995 Colour: Black Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: Sport EC Combined (mpg) 65.7 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 74.3 EC Urban (mpg) 53.3  &gt; 65 MPG 16 Insurance Group 116 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 114 CO2 (g/km) £30 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Sport Insurance Group 16, 1 Registered Keeper, 12 months BMW approved used car warranty, 12 months FREE breakdown cover, Tracks cloth upholstery, 17 light star spoke alloy wheels - style 382, Bluetooth, Rain sensor including auto headlights activation, Run flat indicator (RFI) - tyre puncture warning system, Multifunction leather steering wheel, Thatcham alarm, Front centre armrests with storage, High gloss shadow line, Front sport seats, Front fog lights, DAB digital radio, BMW professional radio with CD player, Engine start/stop button, Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices, Electric front windows + one touch + anti-pinch, Isofix rear child seat preparation, 60/40 split rear seats Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0141 413 9591 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Beauty may be in the eye of the beholder but you would have to be a bit of BMW fan to believe the original 1-Series was a good looking hatchback. read more Better looking than the previous model Fun to drive Superb fuel economy with diesel engines Cramped in the rear Deals will be few and far between Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Passenger airbag Radio/CD Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0141 413 9591 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power socket in centre console 12V power socket in passenger footwell 2 cupholders 4 grab handles 60/40 split rear seats ABS/EBD Automatic Stability Control (ASC) CBC - (Cornering brake control) Door armrests Drive Performance Control DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric front windows + one touch + anti-pinch Electrically adjustable door mirrors Engine start/stop button Folding rear seat head rests Front door sill finishers in Sport designation Front door storage bins Front folding/sliding centre armrest with storage Front head restraints Front isofix attachment + airbag deactivation Front sports seats with electric side bolster adjustment Glovebox Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated door mirrors Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist Isofix rear child seat preparation Leather gear knob and handbrake grip 'Lights On' warning buzzer Load restraint lashing eyes Multifunction steering wheel with audio controls Oil level indicator On board computer On board diagnostics Outside temperature display Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear wash/wipe Run flat indicator (RFI) - tyre puncture warning system Service interval indicator Speed limiter Storage compartments in front/rear door panels Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio with CD player Digital Audio Broadcast (DAB) Tuner Exterior / Styling Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Brake force display Chrome exhaust tailpipe Follow me home headlights Front fog lights High gloss black kidney grille Run flat tyres Safety / Security Child locks on rear doors Crash sensor Driver/Passenger airbags (Impact dependent) Drivers knee airbag Electronic immobiliser Front side airbags ITS head airbags for front/rear Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Remote central locking Seat belt force limiter Thatcham Cat.1 alarm Three 3 point rear seatbelts Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0141 413 9591 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 114
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/cebf08d8-c867-3c87-a01a-be61a743055e" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-29T23:24:35Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:53:43.471Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39015441/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
