<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT><NODE id="0" />Future Market Insights<NODE id="22" /> Impact of Existing and Emerging Electronic Toll Collection Market - Trends and Forecast <NODE id="111" />Future Market Insights<NODE id="133" /> has announced the addition of the Electronic Toll Collection Market: Global Industry Analysis and Opportunity Assessment 2014 - 2020 report to their offering. Valley Cottage, NY -- ( <NODE id="317" />SBWIRE<NODE id="323" /> ) -- 02/10/2016 -- Electronic toll collection system is an automated system, eliminating manual operations by toll payers and receivers. The global ETC market is expected to steer towards a strong double-digit growth rate in the coming five years (2015-2020). The primary drivers of the upcoming growth comprise the need to save travel time, cashless travel facility, the need to stop/minimize the traffic congestion and fast toll transaction. However, factors like high installation cost and a high dependence on government are hindering the growth of this market to some extent. The ETC market is expected to continue its rapid expansion to meet the surging demand for an improved, safe and secure infrastructure. The ETC system provides fast, efficient and cost-effective services. They have easy to operate buttons with a user-friendly design. They are also beneficial for traffic agencies and companies as these systems eliminate the need for multiple toll plazas, acting as a cost-saving factor for road operator agencies. Electronic toll collection systems have a positive impact on the environment as it reduces the amount of exhaust emitted from <NODE id="1479" />vehicles<NODE id="1487" /> during start-up and stop at manual toll booths. The ETC market can be categorised into products, technologies, applications and geographies. <NODE id="1629" />Transponders<NODE id="1641" />, <NODE id="1643" />antennae<NODE id="1651" />, communication systems, <NODE id="1676" />treadles<NODE id="1684" />, inductive loops, scanning devices, weigh-in-motion devices, <NODE id="1746" />cameras<NODE id="1753" /> and film storage devices are some of the major products of the system. An electronic toll collection system consists of various subsystems, such as automatic <NODE id="1912" />vehicle<NODE id="1919" /> identification (AVI), automatic <NODE id="1952" />vehicle<NODE id="1959" /> classification (AVC), back-office &amp;integration and violation enforcement system (VES). These subsystems are useful for specific functions -AVI for <NODE id="2107" />vehicle<NODE id="2114" /> identification, AVC for <NODE id="2139" />vehicle<NODE id="2146" /> classification, toll collection transaction by integrating the back-office and payment system and VES to reduce unpaid tolls, by <NODE id="2276" />vehicle<NODE id="2283" /> imaging. Request Free Report Sample@ http://www.futuremarketinsights.com/reports/sample/rep-gb-76 On the basis of technologies, the ETC market can be segmented into various categories, such as radio-frequency identification (RFID), dedicated short-range communications (DSRC), video analytics, global navigation satellite system (GNSS) and global positioning system (GPS).Currently RFID and DSRC are the leading technologies. On the other hand, the GNSS and GPS are expected to show a high growth rate in following five years (2015-2020). Based on applications, the ETC market can be categorized into segments like highway, urban and bridges. Undoubtedly, ETC systems have been installed majorly on highways, but installation in urban areas and on bridges has a bright future opportunity. Geographically, the ETC market can be segmented into North America, Latin America, Asia Pacific, Japan, Western Europe, Eastern Europe, and Middle East &amp; Africa. Present market scenario represents a strong presence of ETC system in the US, Canada and Mexico in North America, South Korea, Taiwan, Thailand, Malaysia, Hong Kong, Philippines and Singapore in Asia Pacific, and the UK, Ireland, Portugal, France, Germany, Italy and Spain in Europe. Request For TOC@ http://www.futuremarketinsights.com/toc/rep-gb-76 Some of the key players in the ETC market are <NODE id="3632" />Honeywell International, Inc.<NODE id="3661" />, <NODE id="3663" />Transurban<NODE id="3673" />, <NODE id="3675" />Transtoll Pty Ltd.<NODE id="3693" />, <NODE id="3695" />Transcore Holdings, Inc.<NODE id="3719" />, <NODE id="3721" />Toll Collect GmbH<NODE id="3738" />, <NODE id="3740" />TRMI Systems Integration<NODE id="3764" />, <NODE id="3766" />Sensor Dynamics<NODE id="3781" />, <NODE id="3783" />Xerox Corporation<NODE id="3800" />, <NODE id="3802" />3M<NODE id="3804" />, <NODE id="3806" />Connect East<NODE id="3818" />, <NODE id="3820" />EFKON<NODE id="3825" />, <NODE id="3827" />SAIC<NODE id="3831" />, <NODE id="3833" />DENSO<NODE id="3838" />, <NODE id="3840" />Q-Free<NODE id="3846" />, <NODE id="3848" />Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, Ltd.<NODE id="3881" />, <NODE id="3883" />Perceptics<NODE id="3893" />, <NODE id="3895" />Thales Group<NODE id="3907" /> and <NODE id="3912" />Kapsch TrafficCom AG<NODE id="3932" />. The ETC ecosystem participants offer a wide range of solutions, such as software services and system integration and toll system operations including maintenance, payment handling and revenue assurance. It is the future solution to alleviating traffic congestion problems. Media Relations Contact
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/466d8f56-06dd-3d10-8705-22f91212f267" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-11T03:34:20Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:01:51.416Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.sbwire.com/press-releases/impact-of-existing-and-emerging-electronic-toll-collection-market-trends-and-forecast-664148.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="0" endPos="22" type="organization" surface="Future Market Insights" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="111" endPos="133" type="organization" surface="Future Market Insights" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="317" endPos="323" type="organization" surface="SBWIRE" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1479" endPos="1487" type="product" surface="vehicles" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1629" endPos="1641" type="product" surface="Transponders" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1643" endPos="1651" type="product" surface="antennae" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1676" endPos="1684" type="product" surface="treadles" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1746" endPos="1753" type="product" surface="cameras" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1912" endPos="1919" type="product" surface="vehicle" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="1952" endPos="1959" type="product" surface="vehicle" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2107" endPos="2114" type="product" surface="vehicle" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="2139" endPos="2146" type="product" surface="vehicle" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="2276" endPos="2283" type="product" surface="vehicle" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="3632" endPos="3661" type="organization" surface="Honeywell International, Inc." />
<Entity id="14" startPos="3663" endPos="3673" type="organization" surface="Transurban" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="3675" endPos="3693" type="organization" surface="Transtoll Pty Ltd." />
<Entity id="16" startPos="3695" endPos="3719" type="organization" surface="Transcore Holdings, Inc." />
<Entity id="17" startPos="3721" endPos="3738" type="organization" surface="Toll Collect GmbH" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="3740" endPos="3764" type="organization" surface="TRMI Systems Integration" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="3766" endPos="3781" type="organization" surface="Sensor Dynamics" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="3783" endPos="3800" type="organization" surface="Xerox Corporation" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="3802" endPos="3804" type="organization" surface="3M" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="3806" endPos="3818" type="organization" surface="Connect East" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="3820" endPos="3825" type="organization" surface="EFKON" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="3827" endPos="3831" type="organization" surface="SAIC" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="3833" endPos="3838" type="organization" surface="DENSO" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="3840" endPos="3846" type="organization" surface="Q-Free" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="3848" endPos="3881" type="organization" surface="Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, Ltd." />
<Entity id="28" startPos="3883" endPos="3893" type="organization" surface="Perceptics" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="3895" endPos="3907" type="organization" surface="Thales Group" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="3912" endPos="3932" type="organization" surface="Kapsch TrafficCom AG" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="31" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="32" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="3" label="source" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
