<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Full Description <NODE id="17" />Lam Research Corporation<NODE id="41" /> (<NODE id="43" />Lam Research<NODE id="55" />), incorporated on September 8, 1989, is a <NODE id="98" />supplier<NODE id="106" /> of <NODE id="110" />wafer fabrication equipment<NODE id="137" /> and <NODE id="142" />services to the semiconductor industry<NODE id="180" />. The <NODE id="186" />Company<NODE id="193" />'s customers include <NODE id="214" />semiconductor<NODE id="227" /> manufacturers that make <NODE id="252" />memory<NODE id="258" />, <NODE id="260" />microprocessors<NODE id="275" />, and other <NODE id="287" />logic integrated circuits<NODE id="312" /> for a range of electronics, including <NODE id="351" />cell phones<NODE id="362" />, <NODE id="364" />computers<NODE id="373" />, <NODE id="375" />tablets<NODE id="382" />, <NODE id="384" />storage devices<NODE id="399" /> and <NODE id="404" />networking equipment<NODE id="424" />. The <NODE id="430" />Company<NODE id="437" /> maintains a network of facilities throughout Asia, Europe, and the United States. The <NODE id="524" />Company<NODE id="531" /> <NODE id="532" />designs<NODE id="539" />, <NODE id="541" />manufactures<NODE id="553" />, <NODE id="555" />markets<NODE id="562" />, <NODE id="564" />refurbishes<NODE id="575" />, and <NODE id="581" />services<NODE id="589" /> <NODE id="590" />semiconductor<NODE id="603" /> processing systems<NODE id="622" /> <NODE id="623" />that<NODE id="627" /> are used in the fabrication of <NODE id="659" />integrated circuits<NODE id="678" /> (<NODE id="680" />ICs<NODE id="683" />). The <NODE id="690" />Company<NODE id="697" /> operates in seven geographic regions: the United States, Europe, Japan, Korea, Taiwan, China and Southeast Asia. The <NODE id="815" />Company<NODE id="822" />'s customer base includes <NODE id="848" />semiconductor memory<NODE id="868" />, <NODE id="870" />foundry<NODE id="877" />, and <NODE id="883" />integrated device<NODE id="900" /> manufacturers (IDMs) that make products, such as <NODE id="950" />dynamic random access memory<NODE id="978" /> (<NODE id="980" />DRAM<NODE id="984" />), <NODE id="987" />NAND memory<NODE id="998" />, and <NODE id="1004" />logic devices<NODE id="1017" />. <NODE id="1019" />Semiconductor<NODE id="1032" /> manufacturing, <NODE id="1048" />its<NODE id="1051" /> customers' business, involves the fabrication of multiple <NODE id="1110" />die<NODE id="1113" /> or <NODE id="1117" />ICs<NODE id="1120" /> on a <NODE id="1126" />wafer<NODE id="1131" />. The <NODE id="1137" />Company<NODE id="1144" />'s products are used primarily in front-end <NODE id="1188" />wafer<NODE id="1193" /> processing, which involves the steps that create the active components of a device (<NODE id="1278" />transistor<NODE id="1288" />, <NODE id="1290" />capacitor<NODE id="1299" />) and their wiring (interconnect). The <NODE id="1338" />Company<NODE id="1345" /> also addresses processes for back-end wafer-level packaging (WLP), which is an alternative to traditional wire bonding. In addition, <NODE id="1479" />its<NODE id="1482" /> products are offered for related markets that rely on <NODE id="1537" />semiconductor<NODE id="1550" /> processes and require production-proven manufacturing capability, such as <NODE id="1625" />micro-electromechanical systems<NODE id="1656" /> (<NODE id="1658" />MEMS<NODE id="1662" />). The <NODE id="1669" />Company<NODE id="1676" />'s<NODE id="1678" /> <NODE id="1679" />thin film deposition systems<NODE id="1707" /> form a device's sub-microscopic layers of conducting (metal) or insulating (dielectric) materials. The <NODE id="1811" />Company<NODE id="1818" /> is a <NODE id="1824" />provider<NODE id="1832" /> of <NODE id="1836" />plasma etch<NODE id="1847" />, a process step that selectively removes materials from the <NODE id="1908" />wafer<NODE id="1913" /> to create the features and patterns of a device. The <NODE id="1967" />Company<NODE id="1974" />'s<NODE id="1976" /> <NODE id="1977" />wet spin clean<NODE id="1991" /> and <NODE id="1996" />plasma-based bevel clean<NODE id="2020" /> <NODE id="2021" />products<NODE id="2029" /> remove particles, residues and film from the <NODE id="2075" />wafer<NODE id="2080" /> surface before or after adjacent processes. <NODE id="2125" />Thin Film Deposition<NODE id="2145" /> The <NODE id="2150" />Company<NODE id="2157" /> <NODE id="2158" />offers<NODE id="2164" /> <NODE id="2165" />thin film depositions<NODE id="2186" /> for Copper Metal Films, including the <NODE id="2225" />SABRE<NODE id="2230" /> Product Family; Tungsten Metal Films, consisting of <NODE id="2283" />ALTUS<NODE id="2288" /> Product Family; plasma-enhanced chemical vapor deposition (PECVD) dielectric Films, including <NODE id="2383" />VECTOR<NODE id="2389" /> Product Family; <NODE id="2406" />Gapfill Dielectric Films<NODE id="2430" />, such as <NODE id="2440" />SPEED<NODE id="2445" /> Product Family, and <NODE id="2466" />Film Treatment<NODE id="2480" />, including <NODE id="2492" />SOLA<NODE id="2496" /> Product Family. The <NODE id="2517" />SABRE electrochemical deposition<NODE id="2549" /> (<NODE id="2551" />ECD<NODE id="2554" />) product family consists of a platform for copper damascene manufacturing. <NODE id="2630" />Its<NODE id="2633" /> system capabilities include deposition of copper directly on various liner materials. The number of yielding <NODE id="2743" />ICs<NODE id="2746" /> per <NODE id="2751" />wafer<NODE id="2756" /> is optimized by increasing the usable <NODE id="2795" />die<NODE id="2798" /> area through process edge exclusion engineering. The <NODE id="2852" />SABRE ECD<NODE id="2861" /> product family's applications include copper deposition for both logic and memory interconnect. <NODE id="2958" />It<NODE id="2960" /> also offers the <NODE id="2977" />SABRE third dimension (3D) system<NODE id="3010" /> to address through-silicon via (TSV) and wafer-level packaging (WLP), applications, such as copper pillar, redistribution layer (RDL), high-density fanout, underbump metallization, bumping, and microbumps used in post-TSV processing. The <NODE id="3249" />Company<NODE id="3256" />'s<NODE id="3258" /> <NODE id="3259" />ALTUS systems<NODE id="3272" /> deposit highly conformal atomic layer films for tungsten metallization applications. Pulsed Nucleation Layer (PNL), its atomic layer deposition (ALD) technology, is used in the deposition of tungsten nitride films to achieve high step coverage with reduced thickness relative to conventional barrier films. PNL is also used to reduce thickness and alter CVD bulk fill grain growth, lowering the overall resistivity of thin tungsten films. The ExtremeFill CVD tungsten technology provides extendibility to fill the structures at technology nodes. The <NODE id="3823" />ALTUS<NODE id="3828" /> product family's applications include tungsten plug and via fill, 3D NAND wordlines, low-stress composite interconnects, and tungsten nitride barrier for via and contact metallization. The <NODE id="4018" />Company<NODE id="4025" />'s<NODE id="4027" /> <NODE id="4028" />VECTOR<NODE id="4034" /> family of <NODE id="4045" />PECVD<NODE id="4050" /> and <NODE id="4055" />ALD systems<NODE id="4066" /> delivers wafer-to-wafer uniformity. <NODE id="4103" />VECTOR<NODE id="4109" /> products include specialized systems for logic and memory applications with multiple platform options. <NODE id="4213" />VECTOR Express<NODE id="4227" /> offers a small footprint with around four processing stations. <NODE id="4291" />VECTOR Excel<NODE id="4303" /> is a modular tool for technology nodes where pre-and-post film deposition treatments are needed. <NODE id="4401" />VECTOR Extreme<NODE id="4415" /> accommodates up to 12 processing stations for high-throughput applications. <NODE id="4492" />VECTOR Q<NODE id="4500" /> accommodates up to 16 processing stations for depositing multi-stack films. The <NODE id="4581" />VECTOR<NODE id="4587" /> product family's applications include deposition of oxides, nitrides, and carbides for hardmasks; multiple patterning films; anti-reflective layers; multi-layer stack films, and diffusion barriers. The <NODE id="4790" />SPEED HDP-CVD<NODE id="4803" /> products provide void-free gap fill of dielectric films. The <NODE id="4865" />SPEED<NODE id="4870" /> Product Family's applications include shallow trench isolation (STI), pre-metal dielectrics, inter-layer dielectrics, inter-metal dielectrics, and passivation layers. The <NODE id="5042" />SOLA ultraviolet thermal processing (UVTP)<NODE id="5084" /> product family is used for the treatment of back-end-of-line (BEOL) low-k dielectric films and front-end-of-line (FEOL) silicon nitride strained films. The systems incorporate a treatment process that modifies the physical characteristics of a deposited film through exposure to ultraviolet light, gases and vapors, and heat. The Multi-Station Sequential Processing (MSSP) architecture allows independent control of temperature, wavelength, and intensity at each station of the wafer path. <NODE id="5575" />Plasma Etch<NODE id="5586" /> The <NODE id="5591" />Company<NODE id="5598" /> <NODE id="5599" />provides<NODE id="5607" /> <NODE id="5608" />Conductor Etch<NODE id="5622" />, including <NODE id="5634" />Kiyo<NODE id="5638" /> Product Family and <NODE id="5658" />Versys Metal<NODE id="5670" /> Product Family; <NODE id="5687" />Dielectric Etch<NODE id="5702" />, such as <NODE id="5712" />Flex<NODE id="5716" /> Product Family, and <NODE id="5737" />TSV Etch Syndion<NODE id="5753" /> Product Family. The <NODE id="5774" />Kiyo<NODE id="5778" /> product family delivers for conductor etch applications. In addition, <NODE id="5849" />Kiyo<NODE id="5853" /> systems can be configured to perform atomic layer etching (ALE), which delivers atomic-scale variability control to enable <NODE id="5977" />wafer<NODE id="5982" /> processing. The <NODE id="5999" />Kiyo<NODE id="6003" /> Product Family's applications include FinFET gate, fin definition, STI, high-k/metal gate and multiple patterning. The <NODE id="6123" />Versys metal<NODE id="6135" /> product family provides a flexible platform for BEOL metal etch processes. The <NODE id="6215" />Versys metal<NODE id="6227" /> product family's applications include <NODE id="6266" />metal hardmask<NODE id="6280" />, multiple patterning, <NODE id="6303" />high-density aluminum line<NODE id="6329" /> and <NODE id="6334" />aluminum pad<NODE id="6346" />. The <NODE id="6352" />Flex<NODE id="6356" /> product family offers technologies and application-focused capabilities for dielectric etch applications. <NODE id="6463" />Its<NODE id="6466" /> systems has in situ multi-step etch and continuous plasma capability. The <NODE id="6541" />Flex<NODE id="6545" /> product family's applications include low-k and ultra low-k dual damascene, self-aligned contacts, capacitor cell, mask open, 3D NAND HAR hole, trench, and contact. Based on <NODE id="6720" />its<NODE id="6723" /> production-proven <NODE id="6742" />conductor etch<NODE id="6756" /> <NODE id="6757" />products<NODE id="6765" />, the <NODE id="6771" />Syndion TSV etch<NODE id="6787" /> family provides flexible solutions to address multiple TSV etch applications. The <NODE id="6870" />Syndion<NODE id="6877" /> products support both conventional single-step etch and rapidly alternating process (RAP). <NODE id="6969" />It<NODE id="6971" /> <NODE id="6972" />offers<NODE id="6978" /> <NODE id="6979" />Syndion<NODE id="6986" /> Product Family for metal-oxide-semiconductor 3D IC and image sensor applications. <NODE id="7069" />Single-Wafer Clean<NODE id="7087" /> The <NODE id="7092" />Company<NODE id="7099" /> <NODE id="7100" />offers<NODE id="7106" /> <NODE id="7107" />single-wafer clean<NODE id="7125" /> during the <NODE id="7137" />semiconductor<NODE id="7150" /> manufacturing process, from device fabrication through packaging. <NODE id="7217" />Its<NODE id="7220" /> <NODE id="7221" />single-wafer clean<NODE id="7239" /> <NODE id="7240" />offerings<NODE id="7249" /> include <NODE id="7258" />Wet Clean<NODE id="7267" />, including <NODE id="7279" />EOS<NODE id="7282" />, <NODE id="7284" />Da Vinci<NODE id="7292" />, <NODE id="7294" />DV-Prime<NODE id="7302" /> and <NODE id="7307" />SP Series<NODE id="7316" />, and <NODE id="7322" />Plasma Bevel Clean<NODE id="7340" />, including <NODE id="7352" />Coronus<NODE id="7359" /> Product Family. <NODE id="7376" />It<NODE id="7378" /> is engaged in single-wafer wet processing. <NODE id="7422" />Its<NODE id="7425" /> wet clean services' applications include particle, polymer, and residue removal; photoresist removal; and <NODE id="7532" />wafer<NODE id="7537" /> backside/bevel cleaning and film removal. <NODE id="7580" />Its<NODE id="7583" /> <NODE id="7584" />wet clean systems<NODE id="7601" /> are also used for multiple wet etch and clean applications for WLP, including silicon substrate thinning, <NODE id="7708" />wafer<NODE id="7713" /> stress relief, underbump metallization etch, and photoresist removal. The <NODE id="7788" />Coronus<NODE id="7795" /> plasma-based bevel clean products enhance <NODE id="7838" />die<NODE id="7841" /> yield by removing particles, residues and unwanted films from the <NODE id="7908" />wafer<NODE id="7913" />'s edge that can impact the device area. The <NODE id="7958" />Coronus<NODE id="7965" /> Product Family's system combines the ability of plasma to selectively remove a range of materials with a confinement technology that protects the <NODE id="8112" />die<NODE id="8115" /> area. The <NODE id="8126" />Coronus<NODE id="8133" /> Product Family's applications include post-etch, pre- and post-deposition, pre-lithography, and metal film removal to prevent arcing during plasma etch or deposition steps. <NODE id="8307" />It<NODE id="8309" /> also removes carbon-rich residues and films. Legacy Products The <NODE id="8375" />Company<NODE id="8382" /> provides refurbished and newly built legacy products for <NODE id="8440" />semiconductor<NODE id="8453" /> manufacturers. The <NODE id="8473" />Company<NODE id="8480" /> also <NODE id="8486" />provides<NODE id="8494" /> <NODE id="8495" />solutions for the MEMS<NODE id="8517" /> and <NODE id="8522" />light emitting diode<NODE id="8542" /> (<NODE id="8544" />LED<NODE id="8547" />) markets. The <NODE id="8562" />Company<NODE id="8569" /> competes with <NODE id="8584" />Applied Materials, Inc.<NODE id="8607" />, <NODE id="8609" />ASM International<NODE id="8626" />, <NODE id="8628" />Wonik IPS<NODE id="8637" />, <NODE id="8639" />Tokyo Electron, Ltd.<NODE id="8659" />, <NODE id="8661" />Screen Holding Co., Ltd.<NODE id="8685" /> and <NODE id="8690" />Semes Co., Ltd.<NODE id="8705" /> » Full Overview of <NODE id="8725" />LRCX.OQ<NODE id="8732" />
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/f0a3cebe-aaa6-31c4-a982-6ca40f6bba2b" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-27T14:24:51Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:06:39.038Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/companyProfile?symbol=LRCX.OQ" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="17" endPos="41" type="organization" surface="Lam Research Corporation" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="43" endPos="55" type="organization" surface="Lam Research" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="98" endPos="106" type="trigger" surface="supplier" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="110" endPos="137" type="product" surface="wafer fabrication equipment" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="142" endPos="180" type="product" surface="services to the semiconductor industry" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="186" endPos="193" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="214" endPos="227" type="product" surface="semiconductor" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="252" endPos="258" type="product" surface="memory" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="260" endPos="275" type="product" surface="microprocessors" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="287" endPos="312" type="product" surface="logic integrated circuits" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="351" endPos="362" type="product" surface="cell phones" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="364" endPos="373" type="product" surface="computers" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="375" endPos="382" type="product" surface="tablets" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="384" endPos="399" type="product" surface="storage devices" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="404" endPos="424" type="product" surface="networking equipment" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="430" endPos="437" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="524" endPos="531" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="532" endPos="539" type="trigger" surface="designs" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="541" endPos="553" type="trigger" surface="manufactures" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="555" endPos="562" type="trigger" surface="markets" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="564" endPos="575" type="trigger" surface="refurbishes" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="581" endPos="589" type="trigger" surface="services" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="590" endPos="603" type="product" surface="semiconductor" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="590" endPos="622" type="product" surface="semiconductor processing systems" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="623" endPos="627" type="product" surface="that" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="659" endPos="678" type="product" surface="integrated circuits" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="680" endPos="683" type="product" surface="ICs" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="690" endPos="697" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="815" endPos="822" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="848" endPos="868" type="product" surface="semiconductor memory" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="870" endPos="877" type="product" surface="foundry" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="883" endPos="900" type="product" surface="integrated device" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="950" endPos="978" type="product" surface="dynamic random access memory" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="980" endPos="984" type="product" surface="DRAM" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="987" endPos="998" type="product" surface="NAND memory" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="1004" endPos="1017" type="product" surface="logic devices" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="1019" endPos="1032" type="product" surface="Semiconductor" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="1048" endPos="1051" type="organization" surface="its" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="1110" endPos="1113" type="product" surface="die" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="1117" endPos="1120" type="product" surface="ICs" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="1126" endPos="1131" type="product" surface="wafer" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="1137" endPos="1144" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="1188" endPos="1193" type="product" surface="wafer" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="1278" endPos="1288" type="product" surface="transistor" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="1290" endPos="1299" type="product" surface="capacitor" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="1338" endPos="1345" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="46" startPos="1479" endPos="1482" type="organization" surface="its" />
<Entity id="47" startPos="1537" endPos="1550" type="product" surface="semiconductor" />
<Entity id="48" startPos="1625" endPos="1656" type="product" surface="micro-electromechanical systems" />
<Entity id="49" startPos="1658" endPos="1662" type="product" surface="MEMS" />
<Entity id="50" startPos="1669" endPos="1676" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="51" startPos="1676" endPos="1678" type="trigger" surface="'s" />
<Entity id="52" startPos="1679" endPos="1707" type="product" surface="thin film deposition systems" />
<Entity id="53" startPos="1811" endPos="1818" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="54" startPos="1824" endPos="1832" type="trigger" surface="provider" />
<Entity id="55" startPos="1836" endPos="1847" type="product" surface="plasma etch" />
<Entity id="56" startPos="1908" endPos="1913" type="product" surface="wafer" />
<Entity id="57" startPos="1967" endPos="1974" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="58" startPos="1974" endPos="1976" type="trigger" surface="'s" />
<Entity id="59" startPos="1977" endPos="1991" type="product" surface="wet spin clean" />
<Entity id="60" startPos="1996" endPos="2020" type="product" surface="plasma-based bevel clean" />
<Entity id="61" startPos="2021" endPos="2029" type="trigger" surface="products" />
<Entity id="62" startPos="2075" endPos="2080" type="product" surface="wafer" />
<Entity id="63" startPos="2125" endPos="2145" type="product" surface="Thin Film Deposition" />
<Entity id="64" startPos="2150" endPos="2157" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="65" startPos="2158" endPos="2164" type="trigger" surface="offers" />
<Entity id="66" startPos="2165" endPos="2186" type="product" surface="thin film depositions" />
<Entity id="67" startPos="2225" endPos="2230" type="product" surface="SABRE" />
<Entity id="68" startPos="2283" endPos="2288" type="product" surface="ALTUS" />
<Entity id="69" startPos="2383" endPos="2389" type="product" surface="VECTOR" />
<Entity id="70" startPos="2406" endPos="2430" type="product" surface="Gapfill Dielectric Films" />
<Entity id="71" startPos="2440" endPos="2445" type="product" surface="SPEED" />
<Entity id="72" startPos="2466" endPos="2480" type="product" surface="Film Treatment" />
<Entity id="73" startPos="2492" endPos="2496" type="product" surface="SOLA" />
<Entity id="74" startPos="2517" endPos="2549" type="product" surface="SABRE electrochemical deposition" />
<Entity id="75" startPos="2551" endPos="2554" type="product" surface="ECD" />
<Entity id="76" startPos="2630" endPos="2633" type="product" surface="Its" />
<Entity id="77" startPos="2743" endPos="2746" type="product" surface="ICs" />
<Entity id="78" startPos="2751" endPos="2756" type="product" surface="wafer" />
<Entity id="79" startPos="2795" endPos="2798" type="product" surface="die" />
<Entity id="80" startPos="2852" endPos="2861" type="product" surface="SABRE ECD" />
<Entity id="81" startPos="2958" endPos="2960" type="product" surface="It" />
<Entity id="82" startPos="2977" endPos="3010" type="product" surface="SABRE third dimension (3D) system" />
<Entity id="83" startPos="3249" endPos="3256" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="84" startPos="3256" endPos="3258" type="trigger" surface="'s" />
<Entity id="85" startPos="3259" endPos="3272" type="product" surface="ALTUS systems" />
<Entity id="86" startPos="3823" endPos="3828" type="product" surface="ALTUS" />
<Entity id="87" startPos="4018" endPos="4025" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="88" startPos="4025" endPos="4027" type="trigger" surface="'s" />
<Entity id="89" startPos="4028" endPos="4034" type="product" surface="VECTOR" />
<Entity id="90" startPos="4045" endPos="4050" type="product" surface="PECVD" />
<Entity id="91" startPos="4055" endPos="4066" type="product" surface="ALD systems" />
<Entity id="92" startPos="4103" endPos="4109" type="product" surface="VECTOR" />
<Entity id="93" startPos="4213" endPos="4227" type="product" surface="VECTOR Express" />
<Entity id="94" startPos="4291" endPos="4303" type="product" surface="VECTOR Excel" />
<Entity id="95" startPos="4401" endPos="4415" type="product" surface="VECTOR Extreme" />
<Entity id="96" startPos="4492" endPos="4500" type="product" surface="VECTOR Q" />
<Entity id="97" startPos="4581" endPos="4587" type="product" surface="VECTOR" />
<Entity id="98" startPos="4790" endPos="4803" type="product" surface="SPEED HDP-CVD" />
<Entity id="99" startPos="4865" endPos="4870" type="product" surface="SPEED" />
<Entity id="100" startPos="5042" endPos="5084" type="product" surface="SOLA ultraviolet thermal processing (UVTP)" />
<Entity id="101" startPos="5575" endPos="5586" type="product" surface="Plasma Etch" />
<Entity id="102" startPos="5591" endPos="5598" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="103" startPos="5599" endPos="5607" type="trigger" surface="provides" />
<Entity id="104" startPos="5608" endPos="5622" type="product" surface="Conductor Etch" />
<Entity id="105" startPos="5634" endPos="5638" type="product" surface="Kiyo" />
<Entity id="106" startPos="5658" endPos="5670" type="product" surface="Versys Metal" />
<Entity id="107" startPos="5687" endPos="5702" type="product" surface="Dielectric Etch" />
<Entity id="108" startPos="5712" endPos="5716" type="product" surface="Flex" />
<Entity id="109" startPos="5737" endPos="5753" type="product" surface="TSV Etch Syndion" />
<Entity id="110" startPos="5774" endPos="5778" type="product" surface="Kiyo" />
<Entity id="111" startPos="5849" endPos="5853" type="product" surface="Kiyo" />
<Entity id="112" startPos="5977" endPos="5982" type="product" surface="wafer" />
<Entity id="113" startPos="5999" endPos="6003" type="product" surface="Kiyo" />
<Entity id="114" startPos="6123" endPos="6135" type="product" surface="Versys metal" />
<Entity id="115" startPos="6215" endPos="6227" type="product" surface="Versys metal" />
<Entity id="116" startPos="6266" endPos="6280" type="product" surface="metal hardmask" />
<Entity id="117" startPos="6303" endPos="6329" type="product" surface="high-density aluminum line" />
<Entity id="118" startPos="6334" endPos="6346" type="product" surface="aluminum pad" />
<Entity id="119" startPos="6352" endPos="6356" type="product" surface="Flex" />
<Entity id="120" startPos="6463" endPos="6466" type="product" surface="Its" />
<Entity id="121" startPos="6541" endPos="6545" type="product" surface="Flex" />
<Entity id="122" startPos="6720" endPos="6723" type="organization" surface="its" />
<Entity id="123" startPos="6742" endPos="6756" type="product" surface="conductor etch" />
<Entity id="124" startPos="6757" endPos="6765" type="trigger" surface="products" />
<Entity id="125" startPos="6771" endPos="6787" type="product" surface="Syndion TSV etch" />
<Entity id="126" startPos="6870" endPos="6877" type="product" surface="Syndion" />
<Entity id="127" startPos="6969" endPos="6971" type="organization" surface="It" />
<Entity id="128" startPos="6972" endPos="6978" type="trigger" surface="offers" />
<Entity id="129" startPos="6979" endPos="6986" type="product" surface="Syndion" />
<Entity id="130" startPos="7069" endPos="7087" type="product" surface="Single-Wafer Clean" />
<Entity id="131" startPos="7092" endPos="7099" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="132" startPos="7100" endPos="7106" type="trigger" surface="offers" />
<Entity id="133" startPos="7107" endPos="7125" type="product" surface="single-wafer clean" />
<Entity id="134" startPos="7137" endPos="7150" type="product" surface="semiconductor" />
<Entity id="135" startPos="7217" endPos="7220" type="organization" surface="Its" />
<Entity id="136" startPos="7221" endPos="7239" type="product" surface="single-wafer clean" />
<Entity id="137" startPos="7240" endPos="7249" type="trigger" surface="offerings" />
<Entity id="138" startPos="7258" endPos="7267" type="product" surface="Wet Clean" />
<Entity id="139" startPos="7279" endPos="7282" type="product" surface="EOS" />
<Entity id="140" startPos="7284" endPos="7292" type="product" surface="Da Vinci" />
<Entity id="141" startPos="7294" endPos="7302" type="product" surface="DV-Prime" />
<Entity id="142" startPos="7307" endPos="7316" type="product" surface="SP Series" />
<Entity id="143" startPos="7322" endPos="7340" type="product" surface="Plasma Bevel Clean" />
<Entity id="144" startPos="7352" endPos="7359" type="product" surface="Coronus" />
<Entity id="145" startPos="7376" endPos="7378" type="organization" surface="It" />
<Entity id="146" startPos="7422" endPos="7425" type="organization" surface="Its" />
<Entity id="147" startPos="7532" endPos="7537" type="product" surface="wafer" />
<Entity id="148" startPos="7580" endPos="7583" type="organization" surface="Its" />
<Entity id="149" startPos="7584" endPos="7601" type="product" surface="wet clean systems" />
<Entity id="150" startPos="7708" endPos="7713" type="product" surface="wafer" />
<Entity id="151" startPos="7788" endPos="7795" type="product" surface="Coronus" />
<Entity id="152" startPos="7838" endPos="7841" type="product" surface="die" />
<Entity id="153" startPos="7908" endPos="7913" type="product" surface="wafer" />
<Entity id="154" startPos="7958" endPos="7965" type="product" surface="Coronus" />
<Entity id="155" startPos="8112" endPos="8115" type="product" surface="die" />
<Entity id="156" startPos="8126" endPos="8133" type="product" surface="Coronus" />
<Entity id="157" startPos="8307" endPos="8309" type="product" surface="It" />
<Entity id="158" startPos="8375" endPos="8382" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="159" startPos="8440" endPos="8453" type="product" surface="semiconductor" />
<Entity id="160" startPos="8473" endPos="8480" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="161" startPos="8486" endPos="8494" type="trigger" surface="provides" />
<Entity id="162" startPos="8495" endPos="8517" type="product" surface="solutions for the MEMS" />
<Entity id="163" startPos="8522" endPos="8542" type="product" surface="light emitting diode" />
<Entity id="164" startPos="8544" endPos="8547" type="product" surface="LED" />
<Entity id="165" startPos="8562" endPos="8569" type="organization" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="166" startPos="8584" endPos="8607" type="organization" surface="Applied Materials, Inc." />
<Entity id="167" startPos="8609" endPos="8626" type="organization" surface="ASM International" />
<Entity id="168" startPos="8628" endPos="8637" type="organization" surface="Wonik IPS" />
<Entity id="169" startPos="8639" endPos="8659" type="organization" surface="Tokyo Electron, Ltd." />
<Entity id="170" startPos="8661" endPos="8685" type="organization" surface="Screen Holding Co., Ltd." />
<Entity id="171" startPos="8690" endPos="8705" type="organization" surface="Semes Co., Ltd." />
<Entity id="172" startPos="8725" endPos="8732" type="organization" surface="LRCX.OQ" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="173" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="2" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="174" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="23" label="product" />
<Entity id="16" label="company" />
<Entity id="19" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="17" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="18" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="20" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="21" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="175" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="52" label="product" />
<Entity id="50" label="company" />
<Entity id="51" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="176" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="55" label="product" />
<Entity id="53" label="company" />
<Entity id="54" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="177" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="60" label="product" />
<Entity id="59" label="product" />
<Entity id="57" label="company" />
<Entity id="58" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="61" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="178" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="68" label="product" />
<Entity id="66" label="product" />
<Entity id="67" label="product" />
<Entity id="71" label="product" />
<Entity id="73" label="product" />
<Entity id="69" label="product" />
<Entity id="64" label="company" />
<Entity id="65" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="179" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="85" label="product" />
<Entity id="83" label="company" />
<Entity id="84" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="180" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="90" label="product" />
<Entity id="91" label="product" />
<Entity id="89" label="product" />
<Entity id="87" label="company" />
<Entity id="88" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="181" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="105" label="product" />
<Entity id="106" label="product" />
<Entity id="108" label="product" />
<Entity id="104" label="product" />
<Entity id="109" label="product" />
<Entity id="107" label="product" />
<Entity id="102" label="company" />
<Entity id="103" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="182" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="123" label="product" />
<Entity id="122" label="company" />
<Entity id="124" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="183" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="129" label="product" />
<Entity id="127" label="company" />
<Entity id="128" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="184" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="133" label="product" />
<Entity id="131" label="company" />
<Entity id="132" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="185" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="138" label="product" />
<Entity id="136" label="product" />
<Entity id="144" label="product" />
<Entity id="142" label="product" />
<Entity id="143" label="product" />
<Entity id="141" label="product" />
<Entity id="140" label="product" />
<Entity id="139" label="product" />
<Entity id="135" label="company" />
<Entity id="137" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="186" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="149" label="product" />
<Entity id="148" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="187" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="162" label="product" />
<Entity id="163" label="product" />
<Entity id="160" label="company" />
<Entity id="161" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="188" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="83" label="target" />
<Entity id="127" label="target" />
<Entity id="122" label="target" />
<Entity id="165" label="target" />
<Entity id="158" label="target" />
<Entity id="160" label="target" />
<Entity id="148" label="target" />
<Entity id="53" label="target" />
<Entity id="64" label="target" />
<Entity id="41" label="target" />
<Entity id="45" label="target" />
<Entity id="50" label="target" />
<Entity id="102" label="target" />
<Entity id="145" label="target" />
<Entity id="87" label="target" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
<Entity id="172" label="target" />
<Entity id="37" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="46" label="target" />
<Entity id="57" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="131" label="target" />
<Entity id="135" label="target" />
<Entity id="27" label="target" />
<Entity id="146" label="target" />
<Entity id="28" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="189" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="6" label="source" />
<Entity id="159" label="target" />
<Entity id="47" label="target" />
<Entity id="36" label="target" />
<Entity id="134" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="190" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="23" label="source" />
<Entity id="24" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="191" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="25" label="source" />
<Entity id="26" label="target" />
<Entity id="77" label="target" />
<Entity id="39" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="192" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="32" label="source" />
<Entity id="33" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="193" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="38" label="source" />
<Entity id="152" label="target" />
<Entity id="155" label="target" />
<Entity id="79" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="194" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="40" label="source" />
<Entity id="112" label="target" />
<Entity id="78" label="target" />
<Entity id="42" label="target" />
<Entity id="62" label="target" />
<Entity id="56" label="target" />
<Entity id="153" label="target" />
<Entity id="147" label="target" />
<Entity id="150" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="195" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="48" label="source" />
<Entity id="49" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="196" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="52" label="source" />
<Entity id="63" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="197" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="55" label="source" />
<Entity id="101" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="198" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="74" label="source" />
<Entity id="80" label="target" />
<Entity id="81" label="target" />
<Entity id="76" label="target" />
<Entity id="67" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="199" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="68" label="source" />
<Entity id="86" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="200" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="69" label="source" />
<Entity id="97" label="target" />
<Entity id="92" label="target" />
<Entity id="89" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="201" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="71" label="source" />
<Entity id="98" label="target" />
<Entity id="99" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="202" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="73" label="source" />
<Entity id="100" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="203" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="105" label="source" />
<Entity id="113" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="204" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="106" label="source" />
<Entity id="115" label="target" />
<Entity id="114" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="205" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="108" label="source" />
<Entity id="119" label="target" />
<Entity id="120" label="target" />
<Entity id="121" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="206" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="109" label="source" />
<Entity id="126" label="target" />
<Entity id="129" label="target" />
<Entity id="125" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="207" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="144" label="source" />
<Entity id="151" label="target" />
<Entity id="157" label="target" />
<Entity id="154" label="target" />
<Entity id="156" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="208" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="163" label="source" />
<Entity id="164" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
