<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>The following features are fitted to this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Alloy wheels Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Central locking Cruise control Electric door mirrors Front electric windows Front fog lights Headlight washers Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment fitted to this car... This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0117 321 0490 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle Comfort / Convenience 2 rear headrests + integral centre headrest 3 spoke leather sports steering wheel ABS Adjustable front seat head restraints Analogue instruments Anti dazzle rear view mirror Anti-roll bars Armrests on doors with integral closing Auto air recirculation Automatic air conditioning Body colour exterior mirrors Car/key memory CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre rear armrest Check control system Cruise control+multi-function steering wheel Digital clock Door sill trims with chrome inserts DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Electric + heated aspheric door mirrors Electric front + rear windows - anti trap + one touch Front armrests Fully lined luggage compartment Heat insulated glass Heated washer nozzles Instrument panel illumination control Isofix child seat attachment Laminated windscreen Lights on warning Lockable/illuminated glovebox Luggage net Manual adj of belt anchorage on B-pillar On board computer Outside temperature gauge Parking protection all round PAS Rain sensor Rear park distance control Service interval indicator Storage space Toolkit mounted under luggage comp Traction control Entertainment BMW Business radio cassette with CD preparation Exterior / Styling 17 Seven star alloy wheels Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Fog lights Headlight range control-electric Headlight wash system Home safe lighting Smoker's kit Space saver spare wheel Third brake light Safety / Security Anti theft alarm+remote Central locking including fuel flap Centre lock switch Driver and passenger airbags Driver and passenger side airbags Ergonomic belt system at the rear Front and rear crumple zones Front seatbelt pretensioners with force limiters Height adjustable front seatbelts Immobiliser ITS head airbag for driver/front passenger Locking luggage and engine compartments Occupancy sensor for passenger seat Remote control key/auto recharge battery Safety steering column Side impact protection Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications... The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. 178 CO2 (g/km) 184 Performance (BHP) 42 MPG £68 Cost to fill 582 Tank range (miles) 31 Insurance group £225 Road tax 5 Seats 4 Doors Diesel Dec 2001 Manual Saloon Red Emissions CO2 (g/km) 178 Engine and Drive Train Camshaft DOHC Cylinder Layout IN-LINE Cylinders 6 Engine Layout NORTH SOUTH Fuel Delivery DIRECT INJECTION Gears 5 SPEED Transmission MANUAL Fuel Consumption EC Combined (mpg) 42.2 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 53.3 EC Urban (mpg) 30.7 General Insurance Group 1 15 Insurance Group 1 - 50 Effective January 07 31E Manufacturers Corrosion Perforation Guarantee - Years 6 Manufacturers Paintwork Guarantee - Years 3 Standard manufacturers warranty - Mileage 60000 Standard manufacturers warranty - Years 3 Performance 0 to 60 mph (secs) False 0 to 62 mph (secs) 7.8 Engine Power - BHP 184 Engine Torque - NM 390 Top Speed 141 Tyres Wheel Style STAR SPOKE Wheel Type 8JX17 ALLOY Vehicle Dimensions Height 1415 Length 4471 Wheelbase 2725 Width 1739 Width (including mirrors) 1932 Weight and Capacities Fuel Tank Capacity (Litres) 63 Gross Vehicle Weight 2020 Luggage Capacity (Seats Up) 440 Max. Loading Weight 500 Max. Roof Load 75 Max. Towing Weight - Braked 1800 Max. Towing Weight - Unbraked 750 Minimum Kerbweight 1595 No. of Seats 5 Turning Circle - Kerb to Kerb 10.5 Finance to suit your monthly budget. Adjust finance options Preferred Term Optional Deposit (£) Annual Mileage Finance terms &amp; conditions
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/d7979b16-4e9a-30c7-ab01-5ab3dca4fb5c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-06T10:50:44Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:57:05.29Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.motors.co.uk/car-40040353/3/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" />
</Meta>
<Entities></Entities>
<Relations></Relations>
</Document>
