<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Rising costs have become increasingly unsustainable, driving health care systems and payers to seek new approaches that emphasize value. Over 20,000 health care <NODE id="161" />smart phone<NODE id="172" /> apps are available, with more on the way. These apps and wirelessly connected medical devices are creating real-time data and enabling real-time interventions. Mobile health These pressures are being exacerbated by aging populations, increasingly sedentary lifestyles in emerging markets and an imminent chronic disease epidemic. Meanwhile, the rapid rise of digital health — apps, wearables, big data, analytics and more — is enabling real-time, cost-effective interventions. Companies beyond health care are entering the fray, providing new sources of competition and collaboration. These trends are driving a once-in-a-lifetime transformation from 'sick care' by traditional health care companies to 'Health 2.0' — a more active management of health by an increasingly diverse set of players, including entrants from sectors such as tech, telecoms, retail and more. Social media channels will generate 25,000 petabytes of significant health care data by 2020. This data is being analysed to improve the efficiency of everything from drug R&amp;D to care coordination. Health insurance for Health 2.0 To remain relevant in Health 2.0, health insurers will need new business models that are patient-centric, behaviorally driven, grounded in pay-for-performance, and empowered by mobile health and data analytics. In 2015, <NODE id="1492" />EY<NODE id="1494" /> <NODE id="1495" />launched<NODE id="1503" /> a new service — <NODE id="1520" />Health insurer of the future<NODE id="1548" /> — to help clients build a new business model that approaches health insurance in a fundamentally different way. This model transforms insurance from a short-term contractual relationship to a longer-term collaborative one by laying the foundation for ongoing engagement with customers. The model is powered by mobile-health (m-health) technologies, which help influence customer behavior and also generate valuable data. It is delivered by a consortium of health care-related entities — including providers, patient groups, m-health companies and retailers — that collaborate to improve outcomes and share success. This model allows the insurer and its partners to create best-in-class health data — an extremely valuable asset in increasingly outcomes-focused health care systems. Most importantly, the model recognizes that the health insurer of the future will need to be in a very different core business. So far, insurers have been in the business of pricing and underwriting risk — risk that has been static and, unfortunately, quantified using relatively little information. With this new approach, the insurer would leapfrog the competition and enter a very different business — not just pricing and underwriting risk, but influencing and reducing risk as well, and doing so with a much better understanding of customers' behaviors and risk factors. The global <NODE id="2918" />mobile health<NODE id="2931" /> and <NODE id="2936" />fitness sensor<NODE id="2950" /> market will grow at 40% CAGR between 2013 and 2018. Increased pulse The algorithm will see you now A number of years ago I started seeing a lot of interest in health care from large telecom companies in markets such as India, China and Japan, says Jacques Mulder, <NODE id="3215" />EY<NODE id="3217" /> Global Health Leader. These firms were expecting a significant portion of their future growth and revenue to come from health and wellness. For example <NODE id="3370" />SoftBank<NODE id="3378" />, the Japanese telecom giant, and <NODE id="3412" />Fitbit<NODE id="3418" />, <NODE id="3420" />worked<NODE id="3426" /> together to bring a subscription-based <NODE id="3466" />activity tracker service<NODE id="3490" /> to Japanese customers. Today we're seeing similar interest from technology companies. Their strengths – advanced analytics reporting, cloud and web-enabled capabilities — will become increasingly critical in the provision of health care. That's because we're moving to a world where diagnosis, decision and prescription can all be done by an algorithm on a <NODE id="3848" />chip<NODE id="3852" />. For example, a physician treating a cancer patient needs to make several decisions for which he or she has limited information. Decisions such as: 'What tests do I need to determine the optimal drug cocktail and what is the upfront cost of these tests? How can I use those results to pick a course of treatment and how do I understand the economics of that decision?' This is far too complicated for an individual physician to figure out. What's needed is for someone to do the calculations and guide the doctor to the best prescription based on the patient's genotype/phenotype and other variables. That's where health care is headed, thanks in part to major advances in testing capabilities and analytics. Of course, these exciting developments in health care raise crucially important issues around patient privacy, data ownership, risks and accountability, not to mention regulatory approval. If an app is performing dosage calculations, someone has to be accountable for the correctness of the algorithm used. Companies from new sectors are entering the healthcare business. Technology companies are tackling the challenge of data analytics and telecom firms are empowering patients in managing their health. Branching out Jacques Mulder
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/70d290d8-3768-39ed-975a-78fb966e2846" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-29T19:02:01Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:17:52.504Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.ey.com/GL/en/About-us/Our-global-approach/Global-review/global-review-2015-health" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="161" endPos="172" type="product" surface="smart phone" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1492" endPos="1494" type="organization" surface="EY" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1495" endPos="1503" type="trigger" surface="launched" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1520" endPos="1548" type="product" surface="Health insurer of the future" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="2918" endPos="2931" type="product" surface="mobile health" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="2936" endPos="2950" type="product" surface="fitness sensor" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="3215" endPos="3217" type="organization" surface="EY" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="3370" endPos="3378" type="organization" surface="SoftBank" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="3412" endPos="3418" type="organization" surface="Fitbit" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="3420" endPos="3426" type="trigger" surface="worked" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3466" endPos="3490" type="product" surface="activity tracker service" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="3848" endPos="3852" type="product" surface="chip" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="12" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
<Entity id="2" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="13" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="10" label="product" />
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
<Entity id="9" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="14" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
