<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2011 (11) - MINI Hatch 1.6 Cooper D 3dr £11,990 1.6 litre 0 4 0 1 6 7 Mileage Diesel Jun 2011 Manual Hatchback 74 MPG £42 Cost to fill 651 Tank range (miles) 18 Insurance group £0 Road tax 4 Seats Vehicle Overview Vehicle Trim / Variant: Cooper Insurance Group 18, 1 Registered Keeper, Leather Gravity-Polar Beige, 17'' Infinite Stream Alloys, Additional Decor Rings, Alloy Wheels in White, Auto dimming ext/int mirrors, Bluetooth hands free function with USB a, CHILI Pack, Chrome Line exterior, Colour Line Polar Beige, Elec Fold Exterior Mirrors, Harman Kardon - Hi-Fi, Headlight wash, Interior Trim Piano Black, Interior World Polar Beige, Leather interior, Metallic paint, Rear-view mirror. auto dimming, Roof and mirrors caps in white, Seat heating. front, White Bonnet Stripes, White Indicator Lenses, Xenon Headlights, Alarm system (Thatcham 1), Heated Mirrors/Washer Jets, Passenger airbag deactivation. front, Radio BOOST CD, DAB digital radio, 2nd Remote Key Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted to this car... ABS Alarm DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Equipment fitted to this car... This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 2 rear head restraints 2 speed wipers+intermittent wipe 3rd sun visor on driver side 4 boot load lashing points 50/50 split folding rear seats ABS/EBD Acoustic seat-belt warning Active carbon filter Air recirculation system Anti trapping/one touch open close front windows ASC+T Auxiliary socket in centre console storage compartment Brake fluid level warning light Brake pad wear indicator warning light CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console storage Driver's footrest Driver's seat height adjuster DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Easy entry seats Electric front windows Electrically adjustable door mirrors Exterior temperature gauge Front and rear cupholders Front head restraints Front passenger grab handle Front seat backrest storage nets Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated door mirrors/heated windscreen washers Heated rear window with auto timer Internal chrome door handles Isofix child seat preparation Oil level indicator Push button starter Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear grab handles Rear storage trays Rear wiper Service interval indicator Speed sensitive power steering Storage compartments in doors Toolkit in luggage compartment Entertainment Auxiliary input socket DAB digital radio module Radio BOOST + single slot CD Exterior / Styling Body colour lip spoiler Body coloured bumpers Chrome bezels around rear lights and headlights Chrome door handles Chrome exhaust tailpipe Chrome plated radiator grille Chrome plated trim on bottom edge of window Chrome strip on lower grille Chrome tailgate handle Flared wheel arches Follow me home headlights Side air inlets Safety / Security 3 point seatbelts Anti-theft wheel bolts Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Drive away door locking Driver and passenger airbags Driver/front passenger side airbags Electronic immobiliser Fuel cut off safety device Head airbags Locking wheel bolts Passenger airbag deactivation system Remote central locking/doors+fuel cap+tailgate Remote control alarm Seatbelt pretensioners Second remote key Tyre pressure warning Technical Specifications... The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. 74 MPG £42 Cost to fill 651 Tank range (miles) 18 Insurance group £0 Road tax 4 Seats 1.6 litre Diesel Jun 2011 Manual Hatchback Green Emissions CO2 (g/km) 99
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/e06564e9-4632-3861-aed5-04330b235632" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-26T01:56:25Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:00:26.015Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.sunmotors.co.uk/car-39300366/rlw" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" />
</Meta>
<Entities></Entities>
<Relations></Relations>
</Document>
