<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>CES Market update: Still searching for the Next Big Thing January 6, 2016 By Kurt Marko SUMMARY: The CES market update provides depressing news for those looking at spend trends but there are some rays of hope, especially in the auto tech sector. Like swallows returning to San Juan Capistrano, New Year’s revelers have barely cleaned out their rooms before hoards of tech execs, entrepreneurs, marketeers, journalists, PR flacks, technophiles and gawkers descend upon Las Vegas for the annual gala to gadgetry that is CES. Now before anyone gets hissy about why we're talking about consumer tech trends, remember that delivery is enabled by big ass business vendors with supply chains and what not. In short, what is happening in consumer has an impact on how tech vendors respond. Most years, it’s a testament to the  wisdom of Macbeth , full of overwrought product announcements for things of little ultimate significance. However there are always a few major themes worth watching that measure the pulse of what the event’s organizing body, the <NODE id="1049" />Consumer Technology Association (CTA)<NODE id="1086" /> now terms the Global Technology Market. Perhaps the most accurate barometer of the CES ecosystem is the annual technology spending forecast and analysis provided by <NODE id="1252" />CTA<NODE id="1255" />’s Senior Director of Market Research, Steve Koenig.  His 2016 presentation  was full of mostly discouraging data interspersed with bright spots designed to temper the stark numbers with rays of hope. The backdrop to CES is a world where technology spending and unit sales are in steady decline. According to the <NODE id="1568" />CTA<NODE id="1571" />’s latest forecast, global technology spending will drop two percent this year while unit sales are essentially flat. Looking at the longer trend, since 2011, both units and revenues are declining just over one percent annually. Extrapolate this out a couple years and we’ll see total tech revenue about $90 billion less than in 2011. The major culprit is declining ASPs across the board in big spend categories: down seven percent for smartphones, four percent for laptops and two percent for TVs in the last year. It’s a mobile and more diverse world The overriding theme of <NODE id="2148" />CTA<NODE id="2151" />’s data is how mobile has taken over the industry (surprise anyone?), however the spread of technology from developed countries to emerging markets has notably crimped technology spending. The situation is similar to the effect globalization and the ready availability of low-skill workers has had on wages. As mobile technology spreads to low-wage emerging market countries, the pressure to reduce prices is extreme. The <NODE id="2573" />CTA<NODE id="2576" /> estimates that emerging markets will account for 71 percent of smartphone units this year, up from 40 percent in 2010. Indeed, across all tech spending, the revenue split between developed and emerging markets has reached near parity: 51 percent versus 49 percent. The expanding <NODE id="2856" />smartphone<NODE id="2866" /> market has been a boon to sales volumes, increasing over 5-fold since 2010, however ASPs have been slashed by over a third. Indeed, the long-term rate of price decline is over seven percent. But at least <NODE id="3071" />smartphones<NODE id="3082" /> keep selling in greater numbers. Pity the poor <NODE id="3130" />tablet<NODE id="3136" /> market where both units  and prices are in free-fall. From 2014’s peak, the number of <NODE id="3223" />tablets<NODE id="3230" /> sold this year will be down 21 percent. From 2010, when the iPad created the tablet market with prices well over $500, ASPs are expected to be just $228 this year, a 17 percent annual decline over five years. Clearly the <NODE id="3452" />smartphone<NODE id="3462" /> and <NODE id="3467" />tablet<NODE id="3473" /> market trends are linked. As the former spreads throughout the world, it’s often one’s only computing and communication device, which has driven the market to screen sizes. <NODE id="3647" />Phablets<NODE id="3655" />, in turn, have obviated the need for <NODE id="3693" />tablets<NODE id="3700" /> in many situations with a resulting race to the bottom as everyone but <NODE id="3772" />Apple<NODE id="3777" /> turns <NODE id="3784" />tablets<NODE id="3791" /> into cheap secondary devices for kids, schools and occasional media consumption. Rays of hope In a  separate presentation , <NODE id="3916" />CTA’s<NODE id="3921" /> Chief Economist Shawn Dubravac offered his trends to watch for 2016. The backdrop is five megatrends shaping the tech industry: ubiquitous computing: epitomized by <NODE id="4086" />smartphones<NODE id="4097" /> cheap digital storage: flash following Moore’s Law to exponential improvements in capacity/price connectivity: wireless everywhere with  LTE penetration exceeding 50%  in most of the world proliferation of digital devices: wearables, smart appliances, IoT ‘sensor'ization of tech: the proliferation of low-cost sensors beyond smartphones to everyday appliances and special-purpose gadgets Three themes emerge in 2016 according to Dubravac: ambient sensing: things like baby monitors, diet/food sensors, environmental aggregated learning or predictive customization: think <NODE id="4670" />Netflix<NODE id="4677" /> recommendations or the Nest thermostat learning your behavior and preferences maturing of five nascent ecosystems: VR: From <NODE id="4802" />Oculus<NODE id="4808" /> Rift<NODE id="4813" /> on the high-end to <NODE id="4833" />Google<NODE id="4839" /> Cardboard<NODE id="4849" /> at the bottom, <NODE id="4865" />CTA<NODE id="4868" /> estimates it as a $540M market growing over 4x this year. 4K TV: With $10.7B in revenue, 4K now accounts for 21% of the TV market <NODE id="4999" />Wearables<NODE id="5008" />: Split between <NODE id="5024" />smart watches<NODE id="5037" /> with $3.7B in sales and <NODE id="5062" />fitness trackers<NODE id="5078" /> at $1.3B, if  <NODE id="5093" />Fitbit<NODE id="5099" />’s<NODE id="5101" /> <NODE id="5102" />Blaze<NODE id="5107" />  is an indication, expect to see a broader spectrum of health and fitness data. <NODE id="5188" />Drones<NODE id="5194" />: Now almost a $1B market, with 2.9M units sold and growing over 100% this year <NODE id="5274" />3D printers<NODE id="5285" />: Still relatively tiny at $152M in revenue, like drones these seem destined to be a niche consumer product, but hugely important to manufacturers Smart homes: Another billion-dollar business, but it’s unclear whether it develops into a standalone market or the technology gets absorbed into existing devices (appliances, HVAC equipment, lighting). A final trend that Dubravac lumps under the aggregated learning category, but which deserves special mention; is <NODE id="5747" />autonomous vehicle<NODE id="5765" /> technology. The new car chop shop With <NODE id="5805" />NVIDIA<NODE id="5811" />  <NODE id="5813" />announcing<NODE id="5823" /> a <NODE id="5826" />virtual supercomputer<NODE id="5847" />  to analyze sensor data and power machine learning algorithms,  <NODE id="5912" />Ford<NODE id="5916" />’s CEO saying  the industry will put full Level 4, fully <NODE id="5973" />autonomous cars<NODE id="5988" /> on the market by 2020 and  <NODE id="6016" />Volvo<NODE id="6021" /> partnering with <NODE id="6038" />Microsoft<NODE id="6047" />  to allow voice control of the car’s entertainment and control systems using a <NODE id="6127" />Band 2 fitness tracker<NODE id="6149" />, automotive  technology is becoming a major catalyst of tech innovation and spending. (cue fresh media dedicated to said topic?) Although initial applications target consumers, the implications of <NODE id="6347" />autonomous vehicles<NODE id="6366" /> on the transportation and logistics business are profound, as evidenced by  <NODE id="6443" />GM<NODE id="6445" />’s investment of $500M in <NODE id="6471" />Lyft<NODE id="6475" /> . My take Although the macro environment for technology spending is ugly and CES itself is again littered with tchotchkes that are soon forgotten, the show demonstrates the ongoing osmosis of technology throughout every industry and object. Some of these trends will remain niches, however things like <NODE id="6778" />autonomous vehicles<NODE id="6797" />, <NODE id="6799" />smart sensors<NODE id="6812" />/IoT (particularly applied to industrial settings) and machine learning/predictive analytics will reshape industries and disrupt unprepared companies throughout the rest of this decade. Image credit: via <NODE id="7016" />CTA<NODE id="7019" /> Filed Under: Event reports
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/f8435b76-1cec-3ab6-a841-66489aefe96d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-20T14:40:24Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:09:33.409Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://diginomica.com/2016/01/06/ces-market-update-still-searching-for-the-next-big-thing/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1049" endPos="1086" type="organization" surface="Consumer Technology Association (CTA)" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1252" endPos="1255" type="organization" surface="CTA" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1568" endPos="1571" type="organization" surface="CTA" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="2148" endPos="2151" type="organization" surface="CTA" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="2573" endPos="2576" type="organization" surface="CTA" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="2856" endPos="2866" type="product" surface="smartphone" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="3071" endPos="3082" type="product" surface="smartphones" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="3130" endPos="3136" type="product" surface="tablet" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="3223" endPos="3230" type="product" surface="tablets" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="3452" endPos="3462" type="product" surface="smartphone" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3467" endPos="3473" type="product" surface="tablet" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="3647" endPos="3655" type="product" surface="Phablets" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="3693" endPos="3700" type="product" surface="tablets" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="3772" endPos="3777" type="organization" surface="Apple" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="3784" endPos="3791" type="product" surface="tablets" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="3916" endPos="3921" type="organization" surface="CTA’s" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="4086" endPos="4097" type="product" surface="smartphones" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="4670" endPos="4677" type="organization" surface="Netflix" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="4802" endPos="4808" type="organization" surface="Oculus" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="4802" endPos="4813" type="product" surface="Oculus Rift" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="4833" endPos="4839" type="organization" surface="Google" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="4833" endPos="4849" type="product" surface="Google Cardboard" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="4865" endPos="4868" type="organization" surface="CTA" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="4999" endPos="5008" type="product" surface="Wearables" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="5024" endPos="5037" type="product" surface="smart watches" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="5062" endPos="5078" type="product" surface="fitness trackers" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="5093" endPos="5099" type="organization" surface="Fitbit" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="5099" endPos="5101" type="trigger" surface="’s" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="5102" endPos="5107" type="product" surface="Blaze" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="5188" endPos="5194" type="product" surface="Drones" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="5274" endPos="5285" type="product" surface="3D printers" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="5747" endPos="5765" type="product" surface="autonomous vehicle" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="5805" endPos="5811" type="organization" surface="NVIDIA" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="5813" endPos="5823" type="trigger" surface="announcing" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="5826" endPos="5847" type="product" surface="virtual supercomputer" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="5912" endPos="5916" type="organization" surface="Ford" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="5973" endPos="5988" type="product" surface="autonomous cars" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="6016" endPos="6021" type="organization" surface="Volvo" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="6038" endPos="6047" type="organization" surface="Microsoft" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="6127" endPos="6149" type="product" surface="Band 2 fitness tracker" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="6347" endPos="6366" type="product" surface="autonomous vehicles" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="6443" endPos="6445" type="organization" surface="GM" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="6471" endPos="6475" type="organization" surface="Lyft" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="6778" endPos="6797" type="product" surface="autonomous vehicles" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="6799" endPos="6812" type="product" surface="smart sensors" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="7016" endPos="7019" type="organization" surface="CTA" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="46" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="19" label="product" />
<Entity id="18" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="47" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="21" label="product" />
<Entity id="20" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="48" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="28" label="product" />
<Entity id="26" label="company" />
<Entity id="27" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="49" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="22" label="target" />
<Entity id="45" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="50" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="5" label="source" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="51" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="7" label="source" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="52" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="31" label="source" />
<Entity id="43" label="target" />
<Entity id="36" label="target" />
<Entity id="40" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
