<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Close (X) Set up related e-mail alerts _ FREE! AutoGrid Is Named to the 2015 Global Cleantech 100 AutoGrid Recognized as One of the Top Private Companies in Clean Technology January 25, 2016 8:05 PM EST REDWOOD CITY, CA -- (Marketwired) -- 01/25/16 -- AutoGrid Systems , a leader in big data analytics and predictive control software for the electricity and energy industry, today announced it was named in the prestigious 2015 Global Cleantech 100 , produced by Cleantech Group . The Global Cleantech 100 represents the most innovative and promising ideas in cleantech. Featuring companies that are best positioned to solve tomorrow's clean technology challenges, Global Cleantech 100 is a comprehensive list of private companies with the highest potential to make the most significant market impact. The global need for more sustainable, more affordable and more reliable energy is transforming the electric grid -- from a rigid, centralized system that just transports electrons into a flexible, distributed system for balancing electricity supply and demand, said Dr. Amit Narayan, CEO of AutoGrid. Our inclusion on the 2015 Global Cleantech 100 list demonstrates that AutoGrid continues to be a leader in accelerating this transformation, with a scalable and intelligent software-as-a-service platform that enables our customers to optimize and manage a diverse portfolio of connected energy assets across the Energy Internet. The Global Cleantech 100 is collated by combining proprietary Cleantech Group research data, with weighted qualitative judgments of hundreds of nominations, and specific inputs from a global 100-person Expert Panel. To qualify for the list, companies must be independent, for-profit, cleantech companies that are not listed on any major stock exchange. The 2015 Global Cleantech 100 recognition adds to a long list of accolades for AutoGrid. AutoGrid has been named: About Cleantech Group Founded in 2002, Cleantech Group's mission is to accelerate sustainable innovation. Core to this mission is i3, an online platform that connects corporates with innovation, at scale, by allowing them to find, vet, and connect with start-ups -- efficiently building an innovation pipeline. The i3 platform comes to life at our global Events, which convene corporates and start-ups, along with other players shaping the future of sustainable innovation. Cleantech Group is headquartered in San Francisco and has offices in London. For more information, visit; www.cleantech.com About AutoGrid AutoGrid transforms data into the cleanest, cheapest source of power. The company's Energy Data Platform (EDP) and suite of Energy Internet applications help global utilities, energy service providers and Internet-of-Things (IoT) vendors improve customer engagement, enhance grid reliability, drive resource flexibility and increase profitability. EDP leverages petabytes of smart meter, sensor and third party data along with powerful data science algorithms to generate a dynamic, real-time portrait of energy consumption and implement actionable programs across connected assets and residential, commercial and enterprise customers. Utilities such as E.ON, Bonneville Power Administration, Florida Power &amp; Light, Southern California Edison, Eneco, Portland General Electric, and the City of Palo Alto Utilities are using AutoGrid's big data analytics technology to improve the reliability and productivity of their operations. AutoGrid technology is also embedded in software products from leading vendors, such as Schneider Electric, Silver Spring Networks and NTT Data. AutoGrid was named a World Economic Forum Technology Pioneer for 2015. Source: AutoGrid Systems
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/d299dfe5-6ae7-31f5-a5e6-2bd2146a91a4" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-26T02:58:02Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:55:11.323Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.streetinsider.com/Press+Releases/AutoGrid+Is+Named+to+the+2015+Global+Cleantech+100/11245033.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" />
</Meta>
<Entities></Entities>
<Relations></Relations>
</Document>
