<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (65) - Mazda 3 Sport Nav 4-Door £17,999 Loading Images... Date Registered: Sep 2015 Mileage: 50 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Petrol Price: £17,999 Colour: Silver Body Style: Saloon Vehicle Trim / Variant: Sport EC Combined (mpg) 55.4 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 65.7 EC Urban (mpg) 43.5  &gt; 55 MPG 18 Insurance Group 120 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 119 CO2 (g/km) £30 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Sport Insurance Group 18, 1 Registered Keeper, This is a Mazda Approved Demonstration Vehicle at Brindley Mazda, Stourbridge, Grange Lane, Lye, DY97HH 01384 849190. Part exchanges are welcome as well as low rate Finance packages to help with your purchase. Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01384 500803 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Alloy wheels Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Climate control Cruise control Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Headlight washers Heated door mirrors Heated front seat Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Ipod Connection Isofix child seat anchor points Navigation system PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01384 500803 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 3 speed front intermittent wipe and electric wash 5 headrests 60/40 split rear seat back 7 touch screen ABS+Electronic Brake force Distribution Active Traction Control (TRC) Auto dimming interior mirror Auxilliary 12V power socket Bluetooth system Body colour electric adjustable heated door mirrors with integral indicators Cigar lighter Cloth upholstery Colour satellite navigation Cruise control Cupholders - 2 in rear centre armrest Digital clock Digital exterior temperature gauge Driver seat lumbar adjustment Driver's seat height adjustment Dual zone climate control Dynamic stability control Electric folding door mirrors Electric front/rear windows Electric heated rear glass window Electric hydraulic power assisted steering Emergency brake assist Emergency stop signal system Front and rear parking sensors Front centre console with storage box with tray, lid + 2 cupholders Front door pockets Front grab handles Head up Display Heated front seats Hill hold assist Illuminated glovebox Isofix child seat attachment Leather gearknob Leather handbrake Leather wrapped steering wheel 'Lights On' warning buzzer Mobile App interface Multi function display Passenger seat back pocket Pollen filter Privacy glass Rain and light sensors Rear centre armrest Rear grab handles with coathooks Remote fuel cap release Service indicator Silver interior door handles Silver interior trim Smart City Brake Support - SCBS Sunglasses holder Tachometer Tilt/telescopic adjust steering wheel Trip computer Entertainment 9 speakers Auxiliary input socket Bose Premium Audio system Single play CD/radio with MP3 compatability Steering wheel audio controls USB/iPod connection Exterior / Styling 18 alloy wheels Adaptive front lighting system Bi-Xenon headlamp with auto levelling + Headlamp Wash Body colour door handles Body colour lip spoiler Body colour side mouldings Body coloured bumpers Dual exhaust pipes Dusk sensitive headlamps Front fog lights LED daytime running lights Tyre repair kit Safety / Security 3 point ELR front seatbelts with pretensioners 3 rear 3 point seatbelts with ELR Crash sensor Deadlocking system Driver and passenger airbags Front and rear curtain airbags Front side airbags Immobiliser Keyless Start Passenger airbag deactivate switch Remote central door locking Seatbelt reminder front and rear Smart entry Thatcham Cat.1 alarm Tyre pressure monitoring system Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01384 500803 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 119
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/83861825-343f-354d-8b9d-5ceadb04bd5d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-07T19:20:06Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:24:57.415Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39384468/av" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
