<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2013 (63) - MINI Countryman 1.6 Cooper S ALL4 5dr [Chili Pack] £16,490 1.6 litre 0 1 3 2 1 5 Mileage Petrol Sep 2013 Manual Hatchback 42 MPG £50 Cost to fill 434 Tank range (miles) 28 Insurance group £180 Road tax 5 Seats Vehicle Overview Vehicle Trim / Variant: Cooper S Insurance Group 28, Cloth/Leather Parallel-Light Tobacco, CHILI Pack, Colour Line - Carbon Black, Dashboard Trim Dark Anthracite, Interior World Carbon Black, Run-flat tyres, Silver alloy wheels, Sport Steering Wheel, Alarm system (Thatcham 1), Heated Mirrors/Washer Jets, Bike Rack Preparation, Passenger airbag deactivation. front, Park Distance Control (PDC). rear, Basic Bluetooth with USB, Radio BOOST CD, DAB digital radio, 2nd Remote Key, White Indicator Lenses Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted to this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Cruise control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Headlight washers Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Roof rails Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment fitted to this car... This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 2 cupholders in front centre console 3 rear seats 3 spoke sport leather steering wheel 4 lashing points to secure luggage 60/40 split sliding rear seats ABS Adjustable headrests Anthracite interior trim Anti dazzle mirror Automatic air conditioning Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Brake fluid level warning light Brake pad wear indicator warning light CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console storage Chrome interior door handles Driver/passenger sunvisors Driver's seat height adjuster DSC-Dynamic Stability Control DTC - Dynamic traction control Electric front + rear windows - anti trap + one touch Electric power steering Electrically adjustable door mirrors Electronic brake force distribution Engine start/stop button Exterior temperature gauge Front seat backrest storage nets Front sports seats Gear knob with chrome ring Gear/selector and handbrake in artificial leather Heated door mirrors/heated windscreen washers Heated rear window with automatic switch off Height/reach adjustable steering column Hill start assist Isofix child seat preparation MINI centre rail Multifunction steering wheel inc cruise control Oil level indicator On board computer Passenger seat height adjuster Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Rear grab handles Rear park distance control Rear wiper Run flat indicator Service interval indicator Side sunvisor for driver Sports button Stainless steel foot rest Stainless steel pedals Storage compartments in doors Entertainment Auxiliary input socket DAB Digital radio Radio BOOST + single slot CD Exterior / Styling Anthracite roof rails Bi-Xenon headlights / auto height adjust/ headlight washers Body colour bumpers Body coloured air scoops Chrome bezels around rear lights and headlights Chrome door handles Chrome exhaust tailpipes Chrome plated trim on bottom edge of window Chrome-plated radiator grille surround Follow me home headlights Front fog lights Honeycomb radiator grille Interior lights pack - Countryman Metal look door sill finishers Roof spoiler in roof colour Run flat tyres Storage Compartment Pack - Countryman White indicator lights Safety / Security 3-point rear centre seat belt Automatic door locking Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Driver and passenger airbags Driver and passenger side airbags Electronic immobiliser Front head airbags Front seatbelt pretensioners with force limiters Locking wheel bolts Passenger airbag deactivation system Remote central locking + boot release Second remote key Thatcham Cat.1 alarm Tyre pressure warning Technical Specifications... The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. 42 MPG £50 Cost to fill 434 Tank range (miles) 28 Insurance group £180 Road tax 5 Seats 1.6 litre Petrol Sep 2013 Manual Hatchback White Emissions CO2 (g/km) 157
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/88fba65c-bd85-3721-b4dc-55b5bc9f6e80" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-05T00:19:46Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:27:06.153Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.driving.co.uk/car-39300690/rlw" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
