<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (65) - BMW 2 Series F22 Auto 2-Door £40,950 Loading Images... Date Registered: Dec 2015 Mileage: 0 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Petrol Price: £40,950 Colour: White Body Style: Coupe Vehicle Trim / Variant: M235i EC Combined (mpg) 37.2 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 56.5 EC Urban (mpg) 27.4  &gt; 37 MPG 39 Insurance Group 326 Performance (BHP) 4 Seats 176 CO2 (g/km) £225 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: M235i Insurance Group 39, Adaptive headlights, Air Conditioning, Bluetooth handsfree system, BMW Online services, BMW Professional navigation system, Cruise control with brake function, DAB, Dakota Leather interior , Full black panel display, Heated front seats, High beam assistant, Park distance control PDC, Real time traffic information, Reversing assist camera, Sport automatic transmission, Sports seats, Sun protection glass, Windscreen with green shade band Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0117 321 5758 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Just as BMW has renamed the 3 Series Coupe the 4 Series, the same fate has befallen the 1 Series Coupe. read more Great engines Comfortable yet sharp handling High level of equipment Excellent M235i model Emissions could be lower No grab handles on roof Average Owner Review Large boot, comfortable seats - easy to enter and exit. Read more Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Alloy wheels Audio remote control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Front electric windows Headlight washers Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Leather seat trim PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0117 321 5758 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V sockets in front centre console and passenger footwell 2 speed adjustable intermittent wipers with wash/wipe function 4 grab handles ABS/EBD Anthracite headlining Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic Stability Control (ASC) BMW emergency call BMW teleservices Brake pad wear indicator warning light CBC - (Cornering brake control) Check control system Dakota leather upholstery Door/boot open warning Drive Performance Control DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric adjustable heated door mirrors Electric front windows/one touch facility Ferric grey mirror caps Folding storage compartment with glasses holder + coin tray Front cupholders x 2 Front door storage bins Front head restraints Front sliding armrest Front/rear armrests within door panels Full black panel display Glovebox with lid Heat insulating tinted glass Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist ISOFIX child seat preparation+airbag deactivation Lashing eyelets in boot Leather gearknob Lights on warning M Sport braking system M Sport multifunction leather steering wheel Oil temperature gauge On board computer Outside temperature display Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear centre armrest Rear coat hooks Service interval indicator Speed limiter Sports function on gearbox with steering wheel mounted gearshift paddles Stop/start button Storage compartment in rear centre console Variable sport steering Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio/CD/MP3 DAB Digital radio Exterior / Styling 18 light alloy wheels - M Double spoke style 436M Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Body colour roof mouldings Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Door sill finishers Dual dark chrome exhaust tailpipes Follow me home headlights Interior comfort pack - 2 Series/M2 M aerodynamic body styling M rear spoiler Shark fin roof aerial Xenon headlight pack - 2 Series/M2 Safety / Security Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Drive away door locking Driver seatbelt warning indicator Driver/Front Passenger airbags Electronic immobiliser Front and rear curtain airbags Front seatbelt force limiters Front seatbelt pretensioner Front side airbags Remote central locking Remote control Thatcham category 1 alarm Tyre pressure monitoring system Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0117 321 5758 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 176
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/ec965016-5ca4-3f9a-844c-596a7ac33d81" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-05T16:44:12Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:05:06.574Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-40090388/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" />
</Meta>
<Entities></Entities>
<Relations></Relations>
</Document>
