<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (65) - Ford Focus 1.5 TDCi 120 Zetec Navigation 5dr [AP] [RPA] £13,499 Loading Images... Date Registered: Sep 2015 Mileage: 8,606 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £13,499 Colour: White Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: Zetec EC Combined (mpg) 74.3 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 83.1 EC Urban (mpg) 65.7  &gt; 74 MPG 16 Insurance Group 120 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 98 CO2 (g/km) £0 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Zetec Insurance Group 16, SAVE 7616 off new list price, Sat. Nav.,Air Conditioning,Reversing Sensors Rear,17 inch Wheels,Heated Windscreen,Privacy Glass,Bluetooth,DAB Radio,Alloy Wheels,Cloth Trim,Appearance pack1 - Focus,Special solid paint,Rear Park assist, 0 Annual Tax, 74.3 MPG,All vehicles come with the balance of the manufacturer's warranty, are inspected by trained technicians and are history checked. Test drives and part-exchange are available, and you can choose, buy and drive away the same day. For more details on this or one of over 4000 other cars at Motorpoint, the UKs leading Car Supermarket, search Motorpoint.co.uk. (If you wish to enquire about this vehicle please quote 677834) Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01733 821936 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating The Ford Focus is the perfect all-round car, especially for a young family. read more Excellent ride and handling Spacious Strong petrol and diesels Poor steering feedback Counter-intuitive Powershift Seats lack lateral support Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Bluetooth Connection DAB digital radio DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Navigation system Navigation system PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Radio/CD Remote central locking Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01733 821936 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 3 spoke leather steering wheel 60/40 split back and cushion rear seats with 2 height adjustable headrests ABS+Electronic Brake force Distribution Air conditioning - CFC-free Body colour door mirrors Centre console storage box/armrest Cloth upholstery Digital clock Driver's seat manual height adjust Driver's seat with adjustable lumbar support Easy fuel capless refuelling system Eco mode Electric adjustable heated door mirrors Electric boot release ESP with traction control + emergency brake assist Front variable intermittent wipers with electric wash Heated rear window Height adjustable front headrests Hill start assist Isofix child seat preparation PAS 'Quickclear' heated windscreen/heated washer jets Reach + rake adjustable steering column Sports style front seats SYNC 2 nav system SYNC 2 nav system with DAB radio/CD, 8 colour touch screen, bluetooth, emergency assistance, advanced voice control and 6 speakers Tailgate wash/wipe TFT cluster screen Trip computer Entertainment Aux input Steering column with mounted audio controls SYNC 2 DAB radio/CD, 8 colour touch screen, emergency assistance, Bluetooth connection, advanced voice control USB connection Exterior / Styling Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Body colour rear spoiler Chrome finish on upper door line Chrome radiator grille and surround Front fog lights Safety / Security Driver airbag Front inertia reel height adjustable seatbelts with pre-tensioners Front passenger airbag Front side airbags Immobiliser-Passive Anti-Theft System (PATS) MyKey system Remote central double locking Side curtain airbags Thatcham Cat.1 alarm Three rear inertia reel lap/diagonal seatbelts Tyre pressure monitoring system Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01733 821936 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 98
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/7cc683bc-134e-337a-9ecb-9be6d659db08" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-31T17:40:23Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:22:24.399Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39870358/nnw" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
