<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2013 (13) - MINI Roadster Diesel 2.0 Cooper S D 2dr £15,995 Loading Images... Date Registered: May 2013 Mileage: 9,143 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £15,995 Colour: White Body Style: Convertible Vehicle Trim / Variant: Cooper S EC Combined (mpg) 62.8 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 70.6 EC Urban (mpg) 53.3  &gt; 62 MPG 24 Insurance Group 143 Performance (BHP) 2 Seats 118 CO2 (g/km) £30 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Cooper S Insurance Group 24, 0 Registered Keepers, Franchise Approved, MINI Roadster Diesel Finished in Pepper White Specification Includes Clth/Lea Ray Carbon Black, Armrest - front. centre, Black headlights, Chrome Line interior, Colour Line - Carbon Black, Enhanced Bluetooth with USB audio, Headlight wash, Interior Trim Piano Black, MINI JCW CHILI pack, Run-flat tyres, Telephone USB audio interface, Wind deflector, Dynamic Stability Control, Multi-function controls for s'wheel, Security Wheel Bolts, Alarm system (Thatcham 1), Heated Mirrors/Washer Jets, Pass. seat height adjustment, Sport Button, Park Distance Control (PDC). rear, Passenger airbag deactivation. front, DAB digital radio, Semi Automatic Soft-Top Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01205 535786 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating The MINI Cooper S has an historic name stretching all the way back to the early days of the small car’s history. read more Strong performance Retro styling Great fun to drive Funky interior Few bargains for the used buyer Air con wasn't standard on earlier models Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Cruise control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Front electric windows Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01205 535786 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 2 speed wipers+intermittent wipe 4 boot load lashing points ABS/EBD Acoustic seat-belt warning Active carbon filter Additional silver Decor rings Air recirculation system Anthracite headlining Anti trapping/one touch open close front windows ASC+T Brake fluid level warning light Brake pad wear indicator warning light CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console storage Cup holders Driver's seat height adjuster DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Electrically adjustable door mirrors Exterior temperature gauge Front head restraints Front passenger seat height adjust Front sports seats Heated door mirrors/heated windscreen washers Heated rear window with auto timer Interior world - Carbon black Internal chrome door handles Multifunction steering wheel inc cruise control Oil level indicator Push button starter Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear park distance control Sensatec gearshift and handbrake Service interval indicator Speed sensitive power steering Sports button Stainless steel foot rest Stainless steel pedals Through load facility Entertainment Auxiliary input socket DAB digital radio module Radio BOOST + single slot CD Exterior / Styling Adaptive rear spoiler Body colour scoop integrated into engine- compartment lid Body colour tailgate handle Body coloured bumpers Chrome bezels around rear lights and headlights Chrome door handles Chrome exhaust tailpipes Chrome plated trim on bottom edge of window Chrome side air inlets with S badge Follow me home headlights Honeycomb radiator grille Metal look door sill finishers Safety / Security 3 point seatbelts Anti-theft wheel bolts Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Drive away door locking Driver and passenger airbags Driver/front passenger side airbags Electronic immobiliser Fuel cut off safety device Head airbags Locking wheel bolts Passenger airbag deactivation system Remote central locking/doors+fuel cap+tailgate Remote control alarm Seatbelt pretensioners Second remote key Tyre pressure warning Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01205 535786 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 118
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/33afa4b1-9179-30de-a0a3-f0b9c02931aa" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-31T14:07:27Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:54:47.371Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39978447/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
