<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (65) - Audi Q3 1.4 T FSI S Line (150PS) CoD S Tronic Auto 5-Door £27,990 Reduced by £800 was £28,790 Loading Images... Date Registered: Sep 2015 Mileage: 3,490 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Petrol Price: £27,990 Colour: Grey Body Style: Estate Vehicle Trim / Variant: S Line EC Combined (mpg) 47.9 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 53.3 EC Urban (mpg) 39.8  &gt; 47 MPG 20 Insurance Group 150 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 138 CO2 (g/km) £130 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: S Line Insurance Group 20, Franchise Approved, Anti lock brake system + Electronic Brake force Distribution,Electronic Stability Programme,Cruise control,18 inch 5 twin spoke design alloy wheels,Dual zone climate control,On board computer,Acoustic parking system - rear,Curtain airbags,DAB digital radio module,Audi music interface,Comfort pack - Q3,3 spoke multi-function Q design steering wheel with paddle shift,Dynamic suspension,Space saver spare wheel,8 speakers,Electric adjustable/heated/folding door mirrors,Concert radio/single CD player with MP3 facility,Towbar preparation,Sprint cloth/leather upholstery,Electronic Differential Lock + Anti-slip regulation,6.5 inch colour display screen,Acoustic windscreen,Audi drive select,Audi parking system plus,Bluetooth hands free telephone connection,Driver and passenger airbags,Driver and passenger side airbags,Driver's information system,Electric front lumbar adjustment,Electrically operated child locks on rear doors,First aid kit,Front fog lights,Front passenger airbag deactivation,Front sports seats,Heated windscreen washer jets,High beam assist,ISOFIX on front passenger and rear outer seats,Jack and tool kit,LED daytime running lights,LED headlights with headlight washers,Light and rain sensor for auto activation of lights and windscreen wipers,Locking wheel bolts,Low washer fluid indicator,Metallic paint,MMI - Multi Media Interface control system,Remote electric tailgate opening/closing,Service interval indicator,Sunband for windscreen,Thatcham category 1 alarm+immobiliser,Voice control system,Warning triangle,Sprint Cloth/Leather interior Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01223 633594 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating With the success of the Q7 and Q5 models, it was almost inevitable that Audi would introduce a smaller entry-level to the Q range. read more Affordable entry to Q models Available with two- or four-wheel drive Stylish looks Fails to match rivals for driver engagement Options can make it pricey Interior space is a little tight Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Climate control DAB digital radio Electrically adjustable drivers seat Electrically adjustable passenger seat Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Headlight washers Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Rear electric windows Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01223 633594 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V socket in rear centre console 3 spoke multi-function Q design steering wheel with paddle shift 6.5 colour display screen ABS+Electronic Brake force Distribution Acoustic windscreen Aluminium door sill trims Audi drive select Black cloth headlining Body colour door mirrors Door mirror integrated indicators Dual zone climate control EDL + ASR Electric front lumbar adjustment Electromechanical parking brake ESP Front and rear electric windows Front and rear headrests Front centre armrest with storage compartment and angle adjustment Heated windscreen washer jets Height adjustable front seats Height/reach adjust steering wheel ISOFIX on front passenger and rear outer seats Jack and tool kit Light and rain sensor for auto activation of lights and windscreen wipers Low washer fluid indicator Matt brushed aluminium fascia and door trim inlays MMI - Multi Media Interface control system On board computer PAS Perforated leather gearknob Rear wiper Remote electric tailgate opening/closing Retractable luggage cover Service interval indicator Split fold rear seat Sunband for windscreen Under floor storage in luggage area Voice control system Entertainment Audi music interface DAB digital radio module
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/72a6e38c-240b-37ab-b51a-3a54c07c227f" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-22T09:11:31Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:18:34.516Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39763819/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
