<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2011 (11) - MINI Convertible 1.6 Cooper D 2dr [Chili Pack] £9,654 Reduced by £667 was £10,321 Loading Images... Date Registered: Jun 2011 Mileage: 33,297 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £9,654 Colour: Red Body Style: Convertible Vehicle Trim / Variant: Cooper EC Combined (mpg) 70.6 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 76.3 EC Urban (mpg) 62.8  &gt; 70 MPG 19 Insurance Group 112 Performance (BHP) 4 Seats 105 CO2 (g/km) £20 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Cooper Insurance Group 19, Black Leather, Bluetooth Telephone Preparation, 17 Alloys, Chili Pack, Automatic Air Conditioning, TLC, Sport Button, Multi Function Steering Wheel, Sport Steering Wheel, Wind Deflector, Floor Mats, Sport Seats, Extended Storage, Front Foglights, Radio Boost CD, DAB Digital Radio, ''We Can Guarantee The Future Value Of This Car Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01246 642063 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating With its retro-inspired styling and funky image, the MINI Convertible has proved a real hit. read more Stylish image Huge fun to drive Refined and quiet with hood up Speedy roof Restricted rear visibility Not as attractive as the standard hatch Tiny rear seats Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642063 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 2 rear head restraints 4 boot load lashing points 50/50 split folding rear seats ABS/EBD Acoustic seat-belt warning Active carbon filter Air recirculation system Anti trapping/one touch open close front windows ASC+T Auxiliary socket in centre console storage compartment Brake fluid level warning light Brake pad wear indicator warning light CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console storage Driver's footrest Driver's seat height adjuster DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Easy entry seats Electric front windows Electrically adjustable door mirrors Exterior temperature gauge Front and rear cupholders Front head restraints Front passenger grab handle Front seat backrest storage nets Heated door mirrors/heated windscreen washers Heated rear window with auto timer Internal chrome door handles Isofix child seat preparation Lockable glovebox Oil level indicator Push button starter Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear park distance control Run flat indicator Service interval indicator Speed sensitive power steering Storage compartments in doors Toolkit in luggage compartment Entertainment Auxiliary input socket DAB digital radio module Radio BOOST + single slot CD Exterior / Styling Body coloured bumpers Chrome bezels around rear lights and headlights Chrome door handles Chrome exhaust tailpipe Chrome plated radiator grille Chrome plated trim on bottom edge of window Chrome strip on lower grille Chrome tailgate handle Follow me home headlights Fully electric convertible soft top with sunroof function Metal look door sill finishers Side air inlets Safety / Security 3 point seatbelts Anti-theft wheel bolts Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Drive away door locking Driver and passenger airbags Driver/front passenger side airbags Electronic immobiliser Fuel cut off safety device Head airbags Passenger airbag deactivation system Remote central locking/doors+fuel cap+tailgate Remote control alarm Seatbelt pretensioners Second remote key Tyre pressure warning Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642063 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 105
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/771f2992-38ae-33bb-8135-5f1863fe18f5" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-21T14:41:27Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:20:17.406Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39698620/ds" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
