<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (65) - MINI Hatch 1.2 One 3-Door Call for Price 1.2 litre 0 0 0 0 0 0 Mileage Diesel Oct 2015 Manual Hatchback 61 MPG £44 Cost to fill 536 Tank range (miles) 12 Insurance group £20 Road tax 4 Seats Vehicle Overview Vehicle Trim / Variant: One Insurance Group 12, Cloth Firework Carbon Black/Carbon Black, 15'' Heli Spoke alloy wheels in silver, Chrome Line exterior, Chromed Mirror Caps, Interior Trim Piano Black, Metallic paint, MINI Connected, PEPPER Pack, Sport Steering Wheel, Visual Boost Radio, Servotronic Steering, Alarm system (Thatcham 1), Roof in body colour, ISOFIX Child Seat System, Colour Line - Carbon Black, Foglights. front, On-Board Computer Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted to this car... ABS Alarm DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment fitted to this car... This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 2 rear head restraints 2 speed wipers+intermittent wipe 3rd sun visor on driver side 4 boot load lashing points 4 way manually adjustable passenger seat 6-way manually adjustable driver's seat ABS/EBD Acoustic seat-belt warning Active carbon filter Air recirculation system Anti dazzle mirror Anti trapping/one touch open close front windows ASC+T Auxiliary socket in centre console storage compartment Brake fluid level warning light Brake pad wear indicator warning light CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console storage Driver/passenger sunvisors Driver's seat height adjuster DSC-Dynamic Stability Control DTC - Dynamic traction control Easy entry seats Electric front windows Electrically adjustable door mirrors Electronic differential lock Exterior temperature gauge Front and rear cupholders Front head restraints Front passenger grab handle Gear/selector and handbrake in artificial leather Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated door mirrors/heated windscreen washers Heated rear window with auto timer Hill start assist Internal chrome door handles Isofix child seat preparation Oil level indicator On board computer Push button starter Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear grab handles Rear storage trays Rear wiper Service interval indicator Servotronic PAS Split folding rear seats Storage compartments in doors Toolkit in luggage compartment Ventilated front disc brakes Entertainment Auxiliary input socket DAB digital radio module Exterior / Styling Black tailgate handle Body colour roof Body coloured bumpers Chrome bezels around rear lights and headlights Chrome door handles Chrome exhaust tailpipe Chrome plated radiator grille Chrome plated trim on bottom edge of window Chrome strip on lower grille Flared wheel arches Follow me home headlights Metal look door sill finishers Roof spoiler in roof colour Safety / Security 3 point seatbelts Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Drive away door locking Driver and passenger airbags Driver/front passenger side airbags Fuel cut off safety device Head airbags Locking wheel bolts Passenger airbag deactivation system Remote central locking/doors+fuel cap+tailgate Seatbelt pretensioners Second remote key Thatcham category 1 alarm+immobiliser Tyre pressure warning Technical Specifications... The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. 61 MPG £44 Cost to fill 536 Tank range (miles) 12 Insurance group £20 Road tax 4 Seats 1.2 litre Diesel Oct 2015 Manual Hatchback Black Emissions CO2 (g/km) 108
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/8a8d9ecc-8459-3bb4-81e7-b35ff5764091" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-10T19:12:42Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:27:41.622Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.driving.co.uk/car-39329523/rlw" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
