<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2012 (62) - Audi Q3 2.0 T FSI quattro SE (170ps) 5-Door £20,500 Loading Images... Date Registered: Sep 2012 Mileage: 12,129 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Petrol Price: £20,500 Colour: White Body Style: Estate Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE EC Combined (mpg) 38.7 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 46.3 EC Urban (mpg) 29.7  &gt; 38 MPG 20 Insurance Group 170 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 174 CO2 (g/km) £205 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE Insurance Group 20, Franchise Approved, Anti Lock Brake System + Electronic Brake Force Distribution,SD card satellite navigation system,Electronic Stability Programme,18 inch 5 Double Spoke Design Alloy Wheels,Dual Zone Climate Control,Acoustic Parking System - Rear,Audi Music Interface,12V Power In Rear Centre Console,3 Spoke Leather Multifunction Sports Steering Wheel,S Line Body Styling,3X3 Point Rear Seatbelts,Height/Reach Adjust Steering Wheel,Split Folding Rear Seat,8 Speakers,Concert Radio/Single CD Player With MP3 Facility,Aluminium Roof Rails,Sprint Cloth/Leather Upholstery,6.5 inch Colour Display Screen,Aluminium Door Sill Trims,Aluminium Window Surround,Bluetooth Hands Free Telephone Connection,Chrome Exhaust Tailpipe,Chrome Fog Light Surround,Chrome Grille,Coming Home Function,Driver's Information System,Electric Front Lumbar Adjustment,Electrically Adjustable And Heated Door Mirrors,Electrically Operated Child Locks On Rear Doors,Electromechanical Parking Brake,Front Fog Lights,Front Passenger Airbag Deactivation,Front Sports Seats,Full Paint Finish,Heated Windscreen Washer Jets,ISOFIX On Front Passenger And Rear Outer Seats,LED Daytime Running Lights,Light And Rain Sensor For Auto Activation Of Lights And Windscreen Wipers,MMI - Multi Media Interface Control System,Service Interval Indicator,Thatcham Category 1 Alarm+Immobiliser,Voice Control System,Xenon Plus Headlights + Washers + Automatic Range Adjustment,Cloth &amp; Leather interior Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0843 778 2668 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating With the success of the Q7 and Q5 models, it was almost inevitable that Audi would introduce a smaller entry-level to the Q range. read more Affordable entry to Q models Available with two- or four-wheel drive Stylish looks Fails to match rivals for driver engagement Options can make it pricey Interior space is a little tight Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Bluetooth Connection Climate control Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0843 778 2668 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power in rear centre console 6.5 colour display screen ABS+Electronic Brake force Distribution Acoustic windscreen Bluetooth hands free telephone connection Body colour door mirrors Door mirror integrated indicators Dual zone climate control Dynamic suspension EDL + ASR Electromechanical parking brake ESP Front and rear electric windows Front and rear headrests Front centre armrest with storage compartment and angle adjustment Heated windscreen washer jets Height/reach adjust steering wheel ISOFIX on front passenger and rear outer seats Light and rain sensor for auto activation of lights and windscreen wipers Low washer fluid indicator MMI - Multi Media Interface control system On board computer PAS Rear wiper Service interval indicator Split fold rear seat Sunband for windscreen Voice control system Entertainment Audi music interface Concert radio/single CD player with MP3 facility Speed dependent audio volume control Exterior / Styling Aluminium window surround Body coloured bumpers Coming home function Daytime running lights Front fog lights Headlight range control Safety / Security 3x3 point rear seatbelts Driver and passenger airbags Driver and passenger side airbags Electrically operated child locks on rear doors First aid kit Front passenger airbag deactivation Locking wheel bolts Remote central locking Seatbelt warning light Thatcham category 1 alarm+immobiliser Warning triangle Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0843 778 2668 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 174
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/bcec3a88-35b3-305a-a04c-6f0ff7d9dc7b" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-01T10:47:57Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:46:57.916Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39706860/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
