<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2012 (12) - BMW 1 Series 116d Urban 5dr £13,825 Loading Images... Date Registered: Aug 2012 Mileage: 5,675 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £13,825 Colour: White Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: Urban EC Combined (mpg) 62.8 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 72.4 EC Urban (mpg) 52.3  &gt; 62 MPG 16 Insurance Group 116 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 117 CO2 (g/km) £30 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Urban Insurance Group 16, Bluetooth Telephone Preparation, 17 Alloys, Park Distance Control, Front Centre Armrest, Front Foglights, BMW Professional Radio, Multi Function Steering Wheel, Alarm, Leather Trim, Sport Steering Wheel, Electric Windows, Airbags, Anti-Lock Braking System ( ABS), Power Assisted Steering ( PAS), ''We Can Guarantee The Future Value Of This Car Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01246 642175 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Beauty may be in the eye of the beholder but you would have to be a bit of BMW fan to believe the original 1-Series was a good looking hatchback. Better looking than the previous model Fun to drive Superb fuel economy with diesel engines Cramped in the rear Deals will be few and far between Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642175 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power socket in centre console 12V power socket in passenger footwell 2 cupholders 3 spoke sports leather steering wheel 4 grab handles 60/40 split rear seats ABS/EBD Automatic Stability Control (ASC) CBC - (Cornering brake control) Drive Performance Control DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric front windows + one touch + anti-pinch Electric rear windows Electrically adjustable door mirrors Engine start/stop button Folding rear seat head rests Front door sill finishers in Urban designation Front door storage bins Front folding/sliding centre armrest with storage Front head restraints Front isofix attachment + airbag deactivation Glovebox Heated door mirrors Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist Isofix rear child seat preparation Leather gear knob and handbrake grip 'Lights On' warning buzzer Load restraint lashing eyes Multifunction steering wheel with audio controls Oil level indicator On board computer On board diagnostics Outside temperature display Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear wash/wipe Run flat indicator (RFI) - tyre puncture warning system Service interval indicator Storage compartments in front/rear door panels Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio with CD player Exterior / Styling Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Brake force display Chrome exhaust tailpipe Chrome kidney grille with high gloss white slat sides Follow me home headlights Front fog lights Run flat tyres Safety / Security Child locks on rear doors Crash sensor Driver/Passenger airbags (Impact dependent) Drivers knee airbag Electronic immobiliser Front side airbags ITS head airbags for front/rear Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Remote central locking Seat belt force limiter Thatcham Cat.1 alarm Three 3 point rear seatbelts Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642175 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 117
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/f3b965a9-be7e-3e22-a6a8-4b79f3fc65ce" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-25T16:57:21Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:07:48.792Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39432736/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" />
</Meta>
<Entities></Entities>
<Relations></Relations>
</Document>
