<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Featured Company Aflac Recognized for Technology Excellence and Leadership PR Newswire Monday, January 25th 2016 Company Receives Two Top Honors from IDG Enterprise/Computerworld COLUMBUS, Ga. , Jan. 25, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- Aflac, the leading provider of voluntary insurance at the work site in the United States , announced today that the company has received IDG Enterprise's 2016 Digital Edge 25 Award for its innovative One Day Pay S M initiative. With One Day Pay S M , when an eligible claim is submitted via SmartClaim by 3 p.m. ET , Monday-Friday, with all supporting documentation, Aflac processes, approves and disburses payment for the claim within one business day. This marks the second consecutive year <NODE id="718" />Aflac<NODE id="723" /> has received the Digital Edge 25 Award. In addition, IDG Enterprise has awarded Julia Davis , Aflac senior vice president and chief information officer, with the 2016 Computerworld Premier 100 Technology Leaders Award. She was recognized for her exceptional technology leadership and innovative approach in helping lead to the success of Aflac's groundbreaking One Day PaySM initiative, fostering collaboration between several key departments and ensuring Aflac's position as the leading provider of voluntary insurance at the work site in the United States . We are extremely pleased that IDG Enterprise has honored Aflac, and we are so proud of Julia for her diligence and leadership, Aflac U.S. President Teresa White said. The strides we achieved through our One Day Pay initiative have helped us make our already fast claims payment process even faster so our policyholders can focus on recovery, not their bills. The 2016 Digital Edge 25 Award recognizes 25 organizations for their advances toward digital transformation initiatives, and the 2016 Computerworld Premier 100 Technology Leaders Award honors personal leadership excellence among senior IT executives. The Digital Edge awards were extremely competitive this year given the volume of innovative entries with measurable business impact, said Anne McCrory , vice president of Marketing and Content Strategy for the IDG Enterprise events team. In both the B2B and B2C space, organizations are doing incredible things with data, mobile, cloud and sensors and showing great progress in scaling their digital efforts. About IDG Enterprise IDG Enterprise, an International Data Group (IDG) company, brings together the leading editorial brands (CIO, Computerworld, CSO, InfoWorld, ITworld and Network World) to serve the information needs of its technology and security-focused audiences. As the premier hi-tech B2B media company, they leverage the strengths of their premium owned and operated brands, while simultaneously harnessing their collective reach and audience affinity. The company provides market leadership and converged marketing solutions for their customers to engage IT and security decision-makers across their portfolio of award-winning websites, events, magazines, products and services. For more information, visit www.idgenterprise.com . About Aflac When a policyholder gets sick or hurt, Aflac pays cash benefits fast. For nearly six decades, Aflac insurance policies have given policyholders the opportunity to focus on recovery, not financial stress. In the United States , Aflac is the leading provider of voluntary insurance at the work site. Through its trailblazing One Day PaySM initiative, Aflac U.S. can receive, process, approve and disburse payment for eligible claims in one business day. In Japan , Aflac is a leading provider of medical and cancer insurance and insures 1 in 4 households. Aflac individual and group insurance products help provide protection to more than 50 million people worldwide. For nine consecutive years, Aflac has been recognized by Ethisphere magazine as one of the World's Most Ethical Companies. In 2015, Fortune magazine recognized Aflac as one of the 100 Best Companies to Work For in America for the 17th consecutive year. Also, in 2015, Fortune magazine included Aflac on its list of Most Admired Companies for the 14th time, ranking the company No. 1 in innovation for the insurance, life and health category. Aflac Incorporated is a Fortune 500 company listed on the New York Stock Exchange under the symbol AFL. To find out more about Aflac and One Day PaySM, visit aflac.com or espanol.aflac.com.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/15173f7b-022a-3faa-b445-0f2c3c9f5ad6" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-25T16:40:33Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:43:15.8Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.virtual-strategy.com/2016/01/25/aflac-recognized-technology-excellence-and-leadership" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="718" endPos="723" type="organization" surface="Aflac" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
