<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Archives Industry News Login | Don't have an account? Register now » January 27, 2016 <NODE id="86" />TE Connectivity<NODE id="101" />’s <NODE id="104" />Micro-MaTch cable assemblies<NODE id="132" /> now available from <NODE id="152" />Newark element14<NODE id="168" /> Prevents fretting corrosion while offering a variety of wire-to-board and board-to-board interconnections for industrial applications CHICAGO – Jan. 27, 2016 –– <NODE id="330" />Newark element14<NODE id="346" /> expanded their inventory with <NODE id="377" />Micro-MaTch cable assemblies<NODE id="405" /> from <NODE id="411" />TE Connectivity<NODE id="426" /> (<NODE id="428" />TE<NODE id="430" />), a world leader in <NODE id="451" />connectivity<NODE id="463" />. These cable assemblies are the newest edition to <NODE id="514" />TE<NODE id="516" />'s <NODE id="519" />Micro-MaTch connector series<NODE id="547" />' product portfolio. The Micro-MaTch contact spring system provides a fretting corrosion resistant solution, designed to limit movement between mating parts and establish gas tight connections, unlike tin-plated designs which wear more easily and quickly. The connector utilizes an additional positioning spring in the female part that absorbs movements caused by vibrations and thermal expansion. This stops movement on the contact spot and allows a secure connection to form. The system reduces free motion by equalizing tight, positional tolerances. This also applies the high contact force necessary for tin-plated systems and offers robust housings with and without latches. These cable assemblies can be used for a variety of applications across a wide range of industries. Uses for the automotive market, for example, include motors, radios, GPS, climate controls, navigation systems and airbag units. Other applications include production and material handling equipment, alarm equipment, building surface control, AV equipment, set top boxes and more. This sturdy and multi-functional product gives engineers the flexibility to build out the projects they imagined. <NODE id="1722" />TE<NODE id="1724" /> <NODE id="1725" />Micro-MaTch cable assemblies<NODE id="1753" /> are available from <NODE id="1773" />Newark element14<NODE id="1789" /> in <NODE id="1793" />North America<NODE id="1806" />, <NODE id="1808" />Farnell element14<NODE id="1825" /> in <NODE id="1829" />Europe<NODE id="1835" /> and <NODE id="1840" />element14<NODE id="1849" /> in <NODE id="1853" />Asia<NODE id="1857" /> in a variety of position plugs and sizes. For more information about <NODE id="1927" />TE<NODE id="1929" />'s <NODE id="1932" />Micro-MaTch cable assemblies<NODE id="1960" />, visit www.newark.com/te-connectivity-amp. About the <NODE id="2014" />Premier Farnell Group<NODE id="2035" /> <NODE id="2036" />Premier Farnell plc<NODE id="2055" /> (LSE:<NODE id="2061" />pfl<NODE id="2064" />) is a global leader in high service <NODE id="2101" />distribution of technology products and solutions<NODE id="2150" /> for electronic system design, production, maintenance and repair. Trading as <NODE id="2228" />Farnell element14<NODE id="2245" /> in <NODE id="2249" />Europe<NODE id="2255" />, <NODE id="2257" />Newark element14<NODE id="2273" /> in <NODE id="2277" />North America<NODE id="2290" /> and <NODE id="2295" />element14<NODE id="2304" /> across <NODE id="2312" />Asia Pacific<NODE id="2324" />, it had sales last year of <NODE id="2352" />£960m<NODE id="2357" />, the <NODE id="2363" />Group<NODE id="2368" /> is supported by a global supply chain of more than 3,000 suppliers and an inventory profile developed to anticipate and meet its customers' needs. <NODE id="2516" />Premier Farnell<NODE id="2531" /> works to bring to market development kits in a variety of applications, enabling it to support the customer from design concept through to production. The latest products, software, services and solutions from trusted supplier partners are all available through 43 local language transactional websites. The element14 Community allows buyers and engineers to access a wide range of independent technical information, tools and the latest resources and the Design Center enables design engineers to compare kits from the world's greatest range of development tools. About <NODE id="3103" />TE Connectivity<NODE id="3118" /> <NODE id="3119" />TE Connectivity<NODE id="3134" /> (NYSE: <NODE id="3142" />TEL<NODE id="3145" />) is a <NODE id="3152" />$12 billion<NODE id="3163" /> global technology leader. Our connectivity and sensor solutions are essential in today's increasingly connected world. We collaborate with engineers to transform their concepts into creations – redefining what's possible using intelligent, efficient and high-performing <NODE id="3434" />TE<NODE id="3436" /> products and solutions proven in harsh environments. Our 72,000 people, including over 7,000 engineers, partner with customers in close to 150 countries across a wide range of industries. We believe EVERY CONNECTION COUNTS – www.TE.com. Channels
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/acc7a333-06d1-35f5-ac5a-8c788639ff28" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-28T18:22:21Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:40:41.271Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://eejournal.com/archives/news/20160127-10/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="86" endPos="101" type="organization" surface="TE Connectivity" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="104" endPos="132" type="product" surface="Micro-MaTch cable assemblies" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="152" endPos="168" type="organization" surface="Newark element14" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="330" endPos="346" type="organization" surface="Newark element14" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="377" endPos="405" type="product" surface="Micro-MaTch cable assemblies" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="411" endPos="426" type="organization" surface="TE Connectivity" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="428" endPos="430" type="organization" surface="TE" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="451" endPos="463" type="industry" surface="connectivity" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="514" endPos="516" type="organization" surface="TE" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="519" endPos="547" type="product" surface="Micro-MaTch connector series" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="1722" endPos="1724" type="organization" surface="TE" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1722" endPos="1753" type="product" surface="TE Micro-MaTch cable assemblies" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1725" endPos="1753" type="head" surface="Micro-MaTch cable assemblies" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="1773" endPos="1789" type="organization" surface="Newark element14" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="1793" endPos="1806" type="location" surface="North America" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="1808" endPos="1825" type="organization" surface="Farnell element14" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="1829" endPos="1835" type="location" surface="Europe" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="1840" endPos="1849" type="organization" surface="element14" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="1853" endPos="1857" type="location" surface="Asia" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="1927" endPos="1929" type="organization" surface="TE" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="1932" endPos="1960" type="product" surface="Micro-MaTch cable assemblies" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="2014" endPos="2035" type="organization" surface="Premier Farnell Group" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="2036" endPos="2055" type="organization" surface="Premier Farnell plc" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="2061" endPos="2064" type="organization" surface="pfl" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="2101" endPos="2150" type="industry" surface="distribution of technology products and solutions" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="2228" endPos="2245" type="organization" surface="Farnell element14" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="2249" endPos="2255" type="location" surface="Europe" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="2257" endPos="2273" type="organization" surface="Newark element14" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="2277" endPos="2290" type="location" surface="North America" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="2295" endPos="2304" type="organization" surface="element14" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="2312" endPos="2324" type="location" surface="Asia Pacific" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="2352" endPos="2357" type="number" surface="£960m" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="2363" endPos="2368" type="organization" surface="Group" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="2516" endPos="2531" type="organization" surface="Premier Farnell" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="3103" endPos="3118" type="organization" surface="TE Connectivity" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="3119" endPos="3134" type="organization" surface="TE Connectivity" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="3142" endPos="3145" type="organization" surface="TEL" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="3152" endPos="3163" type="number" surface="$12 billion" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="3434" endPos="3436" type="organization" surface="TE" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="39" NAME="company_facility">
<Entity id="13" label="company" />
<Entity id="14" label="location" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="40" NAME="company_facility">
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
<Entity id="16" label="location" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="41" NAME="company_facility">
<Entity id="17" label="company" />
<Entity id="18" label="location" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="42" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
<Entity id="7" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="43" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="22" label="company" />
<Entity id="24" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="44" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="45" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="46" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="47" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="48" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="13" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="49" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="50" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="17" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="51" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="19" label="organization" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="52" NAME="company_relationship">
<Entity id="32" label="parent" />
<Entity id="26" label="location" />
<Entity id="25" label="child" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="53" NAME="company_relationship">
<Entity id="32" label="parent" />
<Entity id="28" label="location" />
<Entity id="27" label="child" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="54" NAME="company_relationship">
<Entity id="32" label="parent" />
<Entity id="30" label="location" />
<Entity id="29" label="child" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="55" NAME="company_turnover">
<Entity id="32" label="company" />
<Entity id="31" label="turnover" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="56" NAME="company_turnover">
<Entity id="35" label="company" />
<Entity id="37" label="turnover" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="57" NAME="entity_head">
<Entity id="12" label="head" />
<Entity id="11" label="full_extent" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
