<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (64) - Volvo V40 D2 SE Nav 5dr Powershift [WP] [RPA] Auto £14,999 Loading Images... Date Registered: Jan 2015 Mileage: 11,534 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £14,999 Colour: Blue Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE Nav EC Combined (mpg) 72.4 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 78.5 EC Urban (mpg) 64.2  &gt; 72 MPG 17 Insurance Group 115 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 102 CO2 (g/km) £20 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE Nav Insurance Group 17, SAVE 11326 off new list price, Sat. Nav.,Heated Seats,Cruise Control,Climate Control,Leather Trim,Reversing Sensors Rear,16 inch Wheels,Heated Windscreen,Electric Folding Mirrors,Privacy Glass,Bluetooth,DAB Radio,Alloy Wheels,Metallic paint,Rear Park assist,Winter pack - V40, 20 Annual Tax, 72.4 MPG,All vehicles come with the balance of the manufacturer's warranty, are inspected by trained technicians and are history checked. Test drives and part-exchange are available, and you can choose, buy and drive away the same day. For more details on this or one of over 4000 other cars at Motorpoint, the UKs leading Car Supermarket, search Motorpoint.co.uk. (If you wish to enquire about this vehicle please quote 678655) Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01332 426682 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Volvo, sick of BMW and Audi taking the limelight in the medium hatchback segment, has thrown down a gauntlet in the form of its V40. read more Most eco-friendly version emits just 94g/km of CO2 Averages a claimed 78.8mpg Standout styling Numb steering Not as good to drive as a BMW 1 Series Cluttered centre console Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Climate control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Navigation system PAS Passenger airbag Rear electric windows Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01332 426682 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V socket in front + rear tunnel console 5 headrests 60/40 split folding rear seat ABS+EBA Automatic folding door mirrors with ground lights Blond headlining Bluetooth hands free telephone kit Body colour door mirrors Chronograph instrument dials DSTC-Dynamic Stability and Traction Control Easy fuel capless refuelling system Electrically adjustable and heated door mirrors Electronic climate control (ECC) Forward folding front passenger seat Front and rear electric windows Front centre armrest Front cupholders Front storage box Graphite aluminium trim Height adjustable drivers seat with lumbar support Height adjustable passenger seat Height/reach adjustable steering column Hill start assist Information centre Intelligent driver information system (IDIS) Isofix attachments on rear seats Leather gear knob Leather steering wheel with chrome inserts Lockable cooled glovebox PAS Passenger lumbar support Pollen filter Rain sensor windscreen wipers Rear armrest with cupholder Rear wiper Sensus navigation system Service interval indicator Speed limiter Ticket holder WHIPS - Whiplash Protection System Entertainment DAB Digital radio Steering wheel audio controls
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/7cb096a6-b318-3f53-8b9a-eb52bf27070f" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-01T02:42:17Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:22:22.31Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39869109/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
