<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>news » eu-proposes-stricter-vehicle-emissions-tests 0 ▲ Compare clear all 27.1.2016 EU proposes stricter vehicle emissions tests New and stricter regulations for car emissions testing have been proposed by the European Commission (EC) today (Wednesday 27th January) which aim to prevent the repeat of the <NODE id="305" />VW<NODE id="307" /> emissions scandal in the future. The main points of focus are on the type approval process and on-going testing of cars already on the road. The executive body for the European Union (EU) wants vehicle testing to be carried out by independent assessors and for there to be a greater level of EU-level checks in the type approval process. The EC also wants to reduce the financial connection between type approval regulators and the vehicle manufacturers to prevent a conflict of interest occurring. Currently assessors test vehicles at a national level and, once a type approval certificate has been awarded to a model, that is then valid in all EU member states. This cross-border approval will remain, being tied into the EU single market system, but there will be greater regulation from a European level. New plans would also allow member states to carry out spot-checks on cars already on the market, with proposals for strict and quickly-implemented measures should vehicles be found to be non-compliant. This on-going checking process will help the authorities prevent the late discovery of systems such as <NODE id="1422" />VW<NODE id="1424" />'s 'defeat device', that turned on emissions control systems when it detected the car being tested. Linked to this is the EC's desire to order recalls at a European level and to impose heavy fines on manufacturers that allow illegal vehicles to be sold. The proposals are planned to coincide with the implementation of Real-World Driving Emissions (RDE) testing and tighter NOx emissions levels which could still be months or years away. A recent plan to introduce stricter NOx limits was successfully fought by EU Member States with large automotive manufacturing industries for example, and there is still the issue of how the type approval testing process will be funded if there is a break with manufacturer's payments. Independent environmental transport campaigners Transport and Environment's (T&amp;E) clean vehicles director, Greg Archer, commented: This good proposal addresses many flaws in the current car testing system but lacks teeth. The principal reason why Volkswagen managed to get away with cheating in Europe was the lack of independence of national authorities, which were compromised by their cosy relationship with car makers. Without the threat of future EU sanctions, it will be mission impossible to break the strong bond between national regulators and their car makers that has protected the industry but at the cost of higher emissions. Dr Ben Lane. Director of Next Green Car added: The tightening up of the relationships between testing agencies and manufacturers is to be welcomed as is the introduction of emissions checks on real vehicles being used on real roads. In partnership with NXP Semiconductors, Next Green Car is investigating how these spot-checks could be conducted at low cost on large numbers of vehicles using Continuous Vehicle Emissions Monitoring (CVEM) , which utilises existing On-Board Diagnostic (OBD) sensors to monitor emissions, and export this data to a central off-board server for reporting purposes. We are currently looking for an opportunity to trial this technology on an existing fleet to demonstrate to regulators that the rise of the connected car will offer new ways to monitor and enforce future vehicle emissions regulations.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/7963936c-08e7-3723-ad79-09961451a21e" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-28T01:18:17Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:21:07.598Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.nextgreencar.com/news/7462/eu-proposes-stricter-vehicle-emissions-tests" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="305" endPos="307" type="organization" surface="VW" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1422" endPos="1424" type="organization" surface="VW" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
