<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT><NODE id="0" />Racepoint Global<NODE id="16" /> , an intelligence-driven <NODE id="42" />marketing<NODE id="51" /> agency that delivers results for the accountability economy, announced the addition of new clients in Q4 2015, ending the year with strong momentum in the US, Asia and Europe. 'We had a fantastic 2015,' said <NODE id="260" />Peter Prodromou<NODE id="275" />, <NODE id="277" />President<NODE id="286" /> of <NODE id="290" />Racepoint Global<NODE id="306" />. 'We aimed high and we achieved our goals thanks to the right people, quality work and our integrated offer. We’ve kicked off 2016 with some great wins and an extremely impressive pipeline.' 'Our partnership with <NODE id="520" />Racepoint Global<NODE id="536" /> has been a successful one, and we are very happy with how the agency has driven awareness, leveraged and identified influencers and positioned our company in the media,' said <NODE id="712" />David Fetterolf<NODE id="727" />, <NODE id="729" />President<NODE id="738" /> of <NODE id="742" />Stratus Video Interpreting<NODE id="768" />. 'Due to our excellent working relationship matched with stellar results, we’ve been able to share a compelling story about the comprehensive solutions that Stratus has to offer.' Some of the wins include: <NODE id="975" />U.S.<NODE id="979" /> <NODE id="980" />Coalfire<NODE id="988" /> is a leading <NODE id="1002" />cybersecurity risk advisory and compliance services<NODE id="1053" /> company. <NODE id="1063" />Massachusetts Innovation Labs<NODE id="1092" /> embodies an ecosystem of innovators in its 124,000-square-foot first-class chemistry and biology space in the heart of <NODE id="1212" />Kendall Square<NODE id="1226" />. We provide comprehensive solutions for growing companies, including animal facilities, on-site CRO support, co-located CRO services and operational needs. SERMO is the global leading social network for physicians _ the virtual doctors’ lounge and the home of medical crowdsourcing _ where doctors anonymously share their true feelings about their profession and lives and talk ‘real world’ medicine. Stratus Video Interpreting is a leading provider of on-demand interpreter services by using technology to connect clients with interpreters in over 175 spoken and signed languages in less than 30 seconds. Stratus’s cloud-based video solution delivers an array of unique features to virtually any Internet-enabled PC, Mac, smartphone or tablet. Vantiv, the second-largest provider in the U.S. of payment processing services and related technology solutions, with specialties in mobile payments, payments security, eCommerce and integrated payments. Vivere is a leading fertility management and equity partner that turns successful practices into thriving businesses. The company has gained a reputation as a business innovator for its holistic examination of a practice _ from business and market forces to operational and administrative opportunities _ that provides the foundation for Vivere successful strategic partnerships. ASIA Little Freddie: Using only Europe’s finest organic fruit and veggies in their wide range of organic and natural baby food products, Little Freddie’s products have no additives, sugar, GMO or BPA packaging and are all 100% EU Certified Organic. CleanOil: Established in 2002, CleanOil is a company specialized in the re-refining of used oil. Their aim is to produce high quality performance lubricant oil with minimal impact on the environment. MACOM: A leading supplier of high-performance analog RF, microwave, millimeter wave and photonic semiconductor products that enable next-generation internet and modern battlefield applications. Netatmo: A dynamic and innovative company developing consumer electronics for a better and connect lifestyle, creating elegant and smart products designed to harmoniously blend into your lifestyle. UK E Ink: is the world’s leading innovator of electronic ink or electronic paper display technology, supplying its leading edge technology to a variety of industries including eReader, retail, digital signage, consumer technology, architecture and design, and healthcare and packaging. Rambus creates cutting-edge semiconductor and IP products across memory, security, smart sensors and lighting. Pin It
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/d0d7ee73-f7ca-3ac5-9244-46ef13a67930" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-27T14:26:07Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:54:31.334Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.bulldogreporter.com/racepoint-global-ends-2015-with-strong-momentum-several-new-clients/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="0" endPos="16" type="organization" surface="Racepoint Global" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="42" endPos="51" type="industry" surface="marketing" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="260" endPos="275" type="person" surface="Peter Prodromou" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="277" endPos="286" type="position" surface="President" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="290" endPos="306" type="organization" surface="Racepoint Global" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="520" endPos="536" type="organization" surface="Racepoint Global" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="712" endPos="727" type="person" surface="David Fetterolf" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="729" endPos="738" type="position" surface="President" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="742" endPos="768" type="organization" surface="Stratus Video Interpreting" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="975" endPos="979" type="location" surface="U.S." />
<Entity id="10" startPos="980" endPos="988" type="organization" surface="Coalfire" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1002" endPos="1053" type="industry" surface="cybersecurity risk advisory and compliance services" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1063" endPos="1092" type="organization" surface="Massachusetts Innovation Labs" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="1212" endPos="1226" type="location" surface="Kendall Square" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="14" NAME="company_headquarters">
<Entity id="9" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="15" NAME="company_headquarters">
<Entity id="13" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="16" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="1" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="17" NAME="organization_leadership">
<Entity id="2" label="person" />
<Entity id="4" label="organization" />
<Entity id="3" label="position" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
