<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2012 (62) - BMW 5 Series 520d M Sport 4dr £19,595 Loading Images... Date Registered: Dec 2012 Mileage: 26,597 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £19,595 Colour: Grey Body Style: Saloon Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport EC Combined (mpg) 57.6 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 64.2 EC Urban (mpg) 47.9  &gt; 57 MPG 33 Insurance Group 184 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 130 CO2 (g/km) £110 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport Insurance Group 33, 1 Registered Keeper, 12 months BMW approved used car warranty, 12 months FREE breakdown cover, Dakota leather upholstery, 18 light alloy M Double-Spoke style 350M, BMW Navigation pack, Enhanced bluetooth telephone functionality with USB audio interface + voice control, Drive Performance Control, Heated front sports seats, Park distance control, M suspension, M steering wheel, M aerodynamic body styling, Start stop technology, High gloss shadow line, Anthracite headlining, Tyre puncture warning system, Auto dimming rear view mirror, Thatcham alarm, Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices, Shark fin roof aerial Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0141 413 9591 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating BMW is renowned for building cars that are great to drive but sometimes at the expense of comfort. read more High-class luxury car feel Superbly refined and quiet Outstanding handling Generous passenger room Forgiving ride Amazingly frugal 520d version Steering lacks some of the feel you'd expect from a BMW Average Owner Review The size of the boot. Its incredible how much we can get in there. The 5-series is perfect for a family who (like me) doesn't want a people carrier. Read more Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Bluetooth Connection Cruise control Electric door mirrors Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Heated front seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0141 413 9591 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V socket in rear centre console 3 spoke leather M multi-function steering wheel ABS/EBD Aluminium brake calipers Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Body coloured door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Check control system Cruise control with brake function DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric + heated aspheric door mirrors Electric front and rear windows with fingertip open/close + anti-trap all round Electromechanical parking brake Enhanced bluetooth telephone functionality with USB audio interface + voice control Fogging sensor for front windscreen Front centre armrest Front cupholders x 2 Front/rear Parking distance control Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated front seats Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist iDrive controller and display with 6.5 monitor Illuminated glovebox with lock Isofix rear child seat preparation Luggage compartment release button in drivers A pillar Luggage compartment with electric unlocking via key remote control On board computer Outside temperature display Personal Profile Rain sensor with auto light activation system Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear centre armrest with 2 cupholders + storage Rear headrests Securing rings in luggage compartment Service interval indicator Speed limiter Tyre puncture warning system Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio/CD/MP3
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/b196e874-c930-3e60-b19c-b9d79b019dc9" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-21T21:35:39Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:42:40.253Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39244701/spw" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
