<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2011 (61) - Ford Focus 1.6 Tdci Titanium-X (115) 5dr £8,264 Reduced by £247 was £8,511 Loading Images... Date Registered: Nov 2011 Mileage: 62,000 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £8,264 Colour: Black Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: Titanium X EC Combined (mpg) 67.3 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 76.4 EC Urban (mpg) 55.4  &gt; 67 MPG 16 Insurance Group 115 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 109 CO2 (g/km) £20 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Titanium X Insurance Group 16, Metallic Black, Part leather interior, Alloy wheels, Cruise control, Digital radio, Radio/CD, Metallic - Panther black, Part leather - Charcoal, Alarm, Bluetooth connection, Climate control, Curtain airbags, Drivers airbag, Electric door mirrors, Folding rear seats, Front armrest, Front fog lights, Front head restraints, Front parking sensor, Headlight washers, Heated door mirrors, Heated front seat, Height adjustable drivers seat, Isofix child seat anchor points, Lumbar support, Partial leather seat trim, Passenger airbag, Rear armrest, Rear headrests, Rear parking sensor, Rear wiper, Remote central locking, Side airbags, Space saver spare wheel, Sports seats, Traction control, Trip computer, Tyre pressure monitor, USB/iPod interface, Xenon headlights. 5 seats, All our cars come with a minimum 12 month warranty and are available to view and test drive, 8,264 Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0121 514 8217 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Climate control Electric door mirrors Electrically adjustable drivers seat Electrically adjustable passenger seat Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Headlight washers Heated door mirrors Heated front seat Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0121 514 8217 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power point front/rear 4 spoke leather steering wheel with silver accents 60/40 split back and cushion rear seats with 2 height adjustable headrests ABS+Electronic Brake force Distribution Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic rain sensing wipers Bluetooth connection with voice control and USB port Body colour electric folding/heated door mirrors Centre console storage box/armrest Digital clock Door ajar warning Driver/passenger front seatback pockets Driver's seat electric height adjustment Driver's seat with adjustable lumbar support Dual electronic automatic temperature control air conditioning - CFC-free Easy fuel capless refuelling system Electric boot release Electric front and rear windows + one touch + global open/closing Electric heated front seats ESP with traction control + emergency brake assist Exterior temperature gauge 'Ford Power' starter button Front and rear parking sensors Front variable intermittent wipers with electric wash Heated rear window Height adjustable front headrests Hill start assist Isofix child seat preparation Leather gear knob Lights on warning Low screen washer fluid warning Part leather upholstery PAS Passenger seat height/lumbar adjustment Pollen/active carbon filters 'Quickclear' heated windscreen/heated washer jets Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear armrest with storage Sports style front seats Tailgate wash/wipe Trip computer Entertainment 9 speakers Steering column with mounted audio controls
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/ba1fbcbd-e8be-36e8-ad2c-6a7c0642c5a5" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-21T08:50:08Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:45:55.343Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39454363/ds" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
