<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2013 (13) - BMW 1 Series 120i Sport Plus Edition 2dr £15,303 Loading Images... Date Registered: Mar 2013 Mileage: 12,153 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Petrol Price: £15,303 Colour: Grey Body Style: Coupe Vehicle Trim / Variant: Sport Plus Edition EC Combined (mpg) 43.5 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 53.3 EC Urban (mpg) 33.2  &gt; 43 MPG 26 Insurance Group 170 Performance (BHP) 4 Seats 152 CO2 (g/km) £180 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Sport Plus Edition Insurance Group 26, Black Boston Leather, Bluetooth Telephone Preparation, 18 Alloys, Automatic Air Conditioning, Comfort Pack, Heated Front Seats, Front Sport Seats, Cruise Control, Daytime Driving Lights, Parking Distance Control - Front and Rear, Multi Function Steering Wheel, Front Foglights Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01246 642175 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Entry-level BMW motoring gets the wow factor with the arrival of the 1-Series Coupe. read more A delight to drive, good choice of efficient engines, superb build quality Tricky access to rear seats, styling ungainly from some angles Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Alloy wheels Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Leather seat trim Passenger airbag Radio/CD Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642175 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power socket in centre console 3 spoke leather M multi-function steering wheel 60/40 split folding rear seat ABS Air microfilter ASC+T Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic air conditioning + active carbon filter Black door mirrors Black door sill finishers with BMW designation Boston leather upholstery CBC - (Cornering brake control) DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric front windows - anti trap + one touch Electric internally adjustable exterior mirrors Electronic brake force distribution Engine start/stop button Front centre armrest with storage compartment Front head restraints Front passenger isofix child seat attachment Front sports seats with electric side bolster adjustment Handbrake and gear lever in sensatec Individual anthracite headlining Isofix rear child seat fastenings Leather gear lever Leather handbrake Lights on warning Luggage strap Luggage tie-down hooks Oil level indicator On board computer On-board diagnosis - OBD Outside temperature display Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear adjustable/removable head restraints Rear seat easy access Run flat tyre indicator Service interval indicator Toolkit located in luggage compartment Trip computer Tyre puncture warning system Windscreen wipers with adjustable interval Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio with CD player DAB Digital radio Exterior / Styling 18 double spoke light alloy wheels style 313M Body colour door handles Body coloured bumper strips Body coloured bumpers Brake force display Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Enhanced lighting pack - 1 Series Coupe Front fog lights/heated windscreen washer jets/heated door mirrors M Aerodynamic pack - 1 series Run flat tyres Twin matt chrome round exhaust pipes Safety / Security 2 rear 3 point inertia reel seatbelts 3 point inertia reel seatbelts on front seats Crash sensor Driver and passenger airbags Front side airbags ITS head airbags for front/rear Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Remote alarm system/immobiliser Remote central locking Seat belt force limiter Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642175 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 152
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/ba091392-69e7-34bd-a815-52067c6ac817" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-28T20:05:14Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:45:53.246Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39824243/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
