<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>printer friendly version An enclosure for every application February 2016 , Enclosures, Cabling &amp; Connectors <NODE id="109" />Elen Enclosures<NODE id="124" /> is the <NODE id="132" />South African<NODE id="145" /> <NODE id="146" />distributor<NODE id="157" /> of <NODE id="161" />Schneider Electric<NODE id="179" /> <NODE id="180" />Universal Enclosures<NODE id="200" /> (SEUE) since 1982 and remains the authorised <NODE id="246" />Schneider Electric<NODE id="264" /> partner today. <NODE id="280" />Schneider Electric<NODE id="298" /> is a leading name in <NODE id="320" />enclosure design<NODE id="336" />. Previously known by the Sarel and Himel brand names, these enclosures have been protecting automation and electrical installations for over 50 years around the world. SEUE is a specialist in enclosure design and manufacture that conforms to the highest certification standards and is adapted to applications including: • Control and automation. • Electrical distribution. • Data, electronics and network applications. SEUE’s product offering comprises several ranges categorised as follows: • ‘Spacial’: steel and stainless steel floor standing and wall mount enclosures and industrial screw-lid boxes. • ‘Thalassa’: insulating (non-metallic) floor standing, wall-mount enclosures (GRP) and industrial boxes (ABS and polycarbonate). • ‘Climasys’: efficient thermal management solutions that extend the service life of installed equipment, electrical devices and instruments. Schneider Electric enclosures offer three material solutions for the most demanding environments and applications: • Steel enclosures are recommended for indoor harsh and dirty environments, such as machine and manufacturing plants. They can also be used outdoors in applications where there are no corrosive elements in the environment. • Stainless steel enclosures are intended for use in hygienic installations or where resistance to chemicals is required. They are commonly used in the food, beverage and pharmaceutical industries. The material is also used in the oil and gas industry for its chemical resistance, although GRP is more often than not better suited for such applications. • Plastic and polyester (GRP) enclosures provide protection by total electrical insulation for people and devices. They are ideal for outdoor applications and are the number one choice and recommendation for harsh corrosive environments. <NODE id="2143" />Schneider Electric<NODE id="2161" /> and <NODE id="2166" />Elen Enclosures<NODE id="2181" /> have extensive experience as product specialists in the <NODE id="2238" />enclosure market<NODE id="2254" />. Together, they offer a wide range of enclosures and accessories according to application and supported by digital tools including selection and thermal management calculation software. For more information contact <NODE id="2470" />Elen Enclosures<NODE id="2485" />, +27 (0)11 472 2220, sales@elen.co.za , <NODE id="2526" />www.elen.co.za<NODE id="2540" /> Further reading: Distributed temperature measurement over fibre ­optic cable September 2015 , Spero Sensors &amp; Instrumentation, Enclosures, Cabling &amp; Connectors Sperosens, in partnership with AP Sensing, recently launched its first fibre optic linear heat detection (LHD) system in South Africa.       Principle of operation Distributed temperature sensing (DTS) ... Contact: Technews Publishing (Pty) Ltd 1st Floor, Stabilitas House 265 Kent Ave, Randburg, 2194 South Africa Publications by Technews Dataweek Electronics &amp; Communications Technology Electronic Buyers Guide (EBG) Hi-Tech Security Solutions Hi-Tech Security Business Directory Motion Control in Southern Africa Motion Control Buyers’ Guide (MCBG) South African Instrumentation &amp; Control South African Instrumentation &amp; Control Buyers’ Guide (IBG) Other Terms &amp; conditions of use, including privacy policy PAIA Manual classic | mobile Copyright © Technews Publishing (Pty) Ltd . All rights reserved.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/abb77427-26b4-32e0-8822-a3201ac87a4a" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-02T13:59:59Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:40:17.42Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.instrumentation.co.za/53750n" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="109" endPos="124" type="organization" surface="Elen Enclosures" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="132" endPos="145" type="location" surface="South African" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="146" endPos="157" type="provide_type" surface="distributor" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="161" endPos="179" type="organization" surface="Schneider Electric" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="161" endPos="200" type="product" surface="Schneider Electric Universal Enclosures" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="180" endPos="200" type="head" surface="Universal Enclosures" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="246" endPos="264" type="organization" surface="Schneider Electric" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="280" endPos="298" type="organization" surface="Schneider Electric" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="320" endPos="336" type="industry" surface="enclosure design" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2143" endPos="2161" type="organization" surface="Schneider Electric" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2166" endPos="2181" type="organization" surface="Elen Enclosures" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="2238" endPos="2254" type="industry" surface="enclosure market" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="2470" endPos="2485" type="organization" surface="Elen Enclosures" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="2526" endPos="2540" type="url" surface="www.elen.co.za" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="14" NAME="company_facility">
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="1" label="location" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="15" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
<Entity id="8" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="16" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="9" label="company" />
<Entity id="11" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="17" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
<Entity id="11" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="18" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="2" label="provide_type" />
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="19" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="ceremony" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="20" NAME="company_website">
<Entity id="13" label="website" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="21" NAME="entity_head">
<Entity id="5" label="head" />
<Entity id="4" label="full_extent" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
