<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2012 (12) - BMW X3 20 2.0 D X-Drive 5dr Auto £19,243 Loading Images... Date Registered: Apr 2012 Mileage: 61,000 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £19,243 Colour: White Body Style: 4 X 4 Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE EC Combined (mpg) 50.4 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 53.3 EC Urban (mpg) 46.3  &gt; 50 MPG 28 Insurance Group 184 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 147 CO2 (g/km) £145 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE Insurance Group 28, Solid White, Full leather interior, Alloy wheels, Leather seat trim, Tyre repair kit, Heated front seats, Nevada leather - Black, Solid - Alpine white, Sun protection glass, Cruise control, Curtain airbags, Drivers airbag, Electric door mirrors, Folding rear seats, Front armrest, Front electric windows, Front fog lights, Front head restraints, Front parking sensor, Heated door mirrors, Height adjustable drivers seat, Isofix child seat anchor points, Passenger airbag, Radio/CD, Rear airbags, Rear electric windows, Rear headrests, Rear parking sensor, Rear wiper, Remote central locking, Roof rails, Side airbags, Traction control, Trip computer, Tyre pressure monitor, Bluetooth, Climate control, Navigation. 5 seats, All our cars come with a minimum 12 month warranty and are available to view and test drive, 19,243 Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 024 7648 7154 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Cruise control Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Leather seat trim Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Roof rails Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 024 7648 7154 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V socket in centre console and luggage area 4 lashing points to secure luggage 60/40 split folding rear seat ABS/EBD Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Body colour electric adjust heated aspherical door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console storage tray Cruise control with brake function Cupholders in centre console DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Dual zone automatic air conditioning Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electromechanical parking brake Fingertip control / anti-trap function on electric window Folding grab handles with rear coat hooks Front and rear electric windows Front centre armrest with storage compartment Front/rear Parking distance control Heated windscreen washer jets Height adjustable front seats Height adjustable front/rear head restraints Hill descent control iDrive Controller and Display w/6.5 monitor Illuminated glovebox with lock Isofix rear child seat preparation Luggage area underfloor compartment Nevada leather upholstery On board computer Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Rake/reach adjustable steering wheel Rear wiper Removable / retractable luggage cover Storage pockets - front doors Tyre puncture warning system Entertainment Auxiliary socket for external MP3 player BMW professional radio/CD/MP3 Exterior / Styling Body colour door handles Body coloured bumpers Chrome kidney grille with black verticle slats Follow me home headlights Front fog lights Height adjustable headlamps Matt aluminium roof rails Safety / Security 3 rear 3 point seatbelts Child locks on rear doors Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Driver/front passenger airbag Driver/front passenger side airbags Engine immobiliser Front and rear head airbags Front passenger airbag deactivation Inertia reel front seatbelts+pretensioners Locking wheel nuts Remote central locking Remote control Thatcham category 1 alarm Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 024 7648 7154 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 147
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/80b3693d-0117-34cc-b354-9429909b568d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-25T23:10:06Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:23:53.175Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39580348/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
