<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (65) - BMW X1 Auto 5-Door £30,991 Loading Images... Date Registered: Oct 2015 Mileage: 3,000 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £30,991 Colour: White Body Style: Estate Vehicle Trim / Variant: xLine EC Combined (mpg) 57.6 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 64.2 EC Urban (mpg) 50.4  &gt; 57 MPG 30 Insurance Group 190 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 128 CO2 (g/km) £110 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: xLine Insurance Group 30, 18 Alloys, Sun Protection Glass, Driver Comfort Package, Multi Function Steering Wheel, Sport Steering Wheel, ISOFIX Child Seat Attachment, Front Centre Armrest, Heated Front Seats, Adaptive Headlights, Park Assist, Park Distance Control, Cruise Control, Automatic Air Conditioning, DAB Digital Radio, Auto Drive Away Locking System, X Line Package Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01482 272140 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating When we initially published our review of the original BMW X1 SUV review, we weren't exactly blown away by its good looks. read more Improved looks Great to drive Efficient engines More practical than ever Lots of safety kit Brand cache Price has increased Yet to try standard suspension Servicing and maintenance could be expensive Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Audio remote control Central locking DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Heated front seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Leather seat trim Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01482 272140 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12v power point in centre console 12V power socket in passenger footwell 3 spoke sport leather steering wheel 4 grab handles ABS/EBD Ambient temperature display Attentiveness assist Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Automatic tailgate opening BMW emergency call BMW teleservices Body colour door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console with cupholders Dakota leather upholstery Drivers folding storage compartment DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Dual zone automatic air conditioning Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electrically adjustable and heated door mirrors Electronic differential lock Electronic parking brake Fingertip control / anti-trap function on electric window Front and rear door armrests Front and rear electric windows Front centre armrest/sliding cover Front passenger isofix child seat attachment Front/rear adjustable head restraints Heat insulating tinted glass Heated front seats Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist Illuminated glovebox Isofix rear child seat preparation Leather gearknob/gaiter/handbrake grip Lights on warning Luggage area underfloor compartment Multifunction steering wheel On board computer Outside temperature gauge Performance Control Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Rake/reach adjustable steering wheel Rear park distance control Rear wiper Service interval indicator Speed limiter Stop/start button Tyre puncture warning system Entertainment Auxiliary socket for external MP3 player BMW professional radio with CD player DAB Digital radio Exterior / Styling Adaptive LED Headlights Adjustable headlights Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Exclusive door sill finishers Follow me home headlights Front fog lights LED daytime running lights Low rolling resistance tyres Storage package - X1 Twin chrome exhaust tailpipes x2 Welcome home function Safety / Security 3 rear 3 point seatbelts Audio/visual collision warning system Auto door lock when driving Central locking including boot and fuel flap with deadlocks Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Driver/Front Passenger airbags Driver/front passenger side airbags Engine immobiliser Front and rear head airbags Front passenger airbag deactivation Front seatbelt force limiters Locking wheel nuts Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Rear door child safety locks Remote control Thatcham category 1 alarm Seatbelt warning Tyre pressure monitor Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01482 272140 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 128
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/455039ee-6e08-3452-bda8-cf2866ebfda3" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-26T15:30:22Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:01:25.286Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39833623/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
