<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>ReportsnReports Anti-Collision Sensors Market to Grow at 16.89% CAGR to 2020 Global Anti-Collision Sensors Market 2016-2020 report has been prepared based on an in-depth market analysis with inputs from industry experts. This report covers the market landscape and its growth prospects over the coming years. The report also includes a discussion of the key vendors operating in this market. Pune, Maharastra -- ( SBWIRE ) -- 01/20/2016 -- According to the Global Anti-collision Sensors Market 2016-2020 report the growing concern about the rising number of accidents globally has led to increased demand for automotive safety applications that help drivers to remain alert while driving and prevent potential accidents. Luxury car and SUV manufacturers demand a large number of sensors to integrate safety features into automobiles. Complete report on anti-collision sensors market spread across 36 pages, analyzing 5 major companies and providing 12 data exhibits is now available at http://www.reportsnreports.com/reports/458698-global-anti-collision-sensors-market-2016-2020.html . The analysts forecast global anti-collision sensors market to grow at a CAGR of 16.89% during the period 2016-2020. Autonomous vehicles and 360-degree surveillance cars are among the major trends in the market. Luxury car manufacturers are planning to embed these features in their vehicles to improve the level of comfort and safety. There is also an emerging trend of vehicle-to-everything (V2X) technology in the market that helps improve fuel efficiency and traffic flow. Anti-collision sensors are mainly used to detect obstacles in the way of a vehicle and alert the driver, thus preventing a potential accident. The rising number of road accidents across the globe has led to increased awareness of the need for safety among governments, automobile manufacturers, and consumers. This has increased the demand for anti-collision sensors. Order a copy of Global Anti-collision Sensors Market 2016-2020 report @ http://www.reportsnreports.com/Purchase.aspx?name=458698 . The anti-collision sensors market report covers the present scenario and the growth prospects of the global anti-collision sensors market for the period 2016-2020. To calculate the market size, we consider revenue generated from the sales of the following anti-collision sensor technology pertaining to the automotive industry: Radar, Cameras, Ultrasound and LiDAR Key players in the <NODE id="2445" />Global Anti-Collision Sensors Market<NODE id="2481" />: <NODE id="2483" />Continental AG<NODE id="2497" />, <NODE id="2499" />Delphi Automotive<NODE id="2516" />, <NODE id="2518" />Denso<NODE id="2523" />, <NODE id="2525" />Bosch<NODE id="2530" /> and <NODE id="2535" />TRW Automotive<NODE id="2549" /> Other Prominent Vendors in the market are: <NODE id="2593" />Analog Devices<NODE id="2607" />, <NODE id="2609" />Autoliv<NODE id="2616" />, <NODE id="2618" />Freescale Semiconductor<NODE id="2641" />, <NODE id="2643" />Hella Kgaa Hueck<NODE id="2659" />, <NODE id="2661" />Hyundai Mobis<NODE id="2674" />, <NODE id="2676" />Infineon Technologies<NODE id="2697" />, <NODE id="2699" />Mobileye N.V.<NODE id="2712" />, <NODE id="2714" />Murata Manufacturing<NODE id="2734" />, <NODE id="2736" />OmniVision Technologies<NODE id="2759" />, <NODE id="2761" />Panasonic Corporation<NODE id="2782" />, <NODE id="2784" />Quanergy Systems<NODE id="2800" />, <NODE id="2802" />Sensata Technologies<NODE id="2822" />, and <NODE id="2828" />Texas Instruments<NODE id="2845" />. Further, the report states that technological setbacks related to anti-collision sensors are one of the major challenges for the market. Explore other new reports on Semiconductor and Electronics Market at http://www.reportsnreports.com/market-research/semiconductor-and-electronics/ . About ReportsnReports.com ReportsnReports.com is an online market research reports library of 500,000+ in-depth studies of over 5000 micro markets. Call +1 888 391 5441 with your research requirements or email the details at sales@reportsandreports.com and we would be happy to help you find the business intelligence that you need. ReportsnReports.com offers research studies on agriculture, energy and power, automotive, Semiconductor and Electronics, Manufacturing &amp; Construction, chemicals, environment, medical devices, healthcare, food and beverages, water and much more. Media Relations Contact
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/7ea7ae9f-1281-3f86-911d-6cbd36a8a80b" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-21T06:56:29Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:23:06.612Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.sbwire.com/press-releases/anti-collision-sensors-market-to-grow-at-1689-cagr-to-2020-658563.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="2445" endPos="2481" type="industry" surface="Global Anti-Collision Sensors Market" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="2483" endPos="2497" type="organization" surface="Continental AG" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="2499" endPos="2516" type="organization" surface="Delphi Automotive" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="2518" endPos="2523" type="organization" surface="Denso" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="2525" endPos="2530" type="organization" surface="Bosch" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="2535" endPos="2549" type="organization" surface="TRW Automotive" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="2593" endPos="2607" type="organization" surface="Analog Devices" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="2609" endPos="2616" type="organization" surface="Autoliv" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="2618" endPos="2641" type="organization" surface="Freescale Semiconductor" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2643" endPos="2659" type="organization" surface="Hella Kgaa Hueck" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2661" endPos="2674" type="organization" surface="Hyundai Mobis" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="2676" endPos="2697" type="organization" surface="Infineon Technologies" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="2699" endPos="2712" type="organization" surface="Mobileye N.V." />
<Entity id="13" startPos="2714" endPos="2734" type="organization" surface="Murata Manufacturing" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="2736" endPos="2759" type="organization" surface="OmniVision Technologies" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="2761" endPos="2782" type="organization" surface="Panasonic Corporation" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="2784" endPos="2800" type="organization" surface="Quanergy Systems" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="2802" endPos="2822" type="organization" surface="Sensata Technologies" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="2828" endPos="2845" type="organization" surface="Texas Instruments" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="19" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="0" label="industry" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="20" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
<Entity id="0" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="21" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="0" label="industry" />
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="22" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="0" label="industry" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="23" NAME="company_industry">
<Entity id="0" label="industry" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
