<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2010 (60) - BMW X1 1.8d SE X Drive 4x4 5-Door £13,695 Loading Images... Date Registered: Dec 2010 Mileage: 36,102 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £13,695 Colour: Grey Body Style: Estate Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE EC Combined (mpg) 49.6 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 55.4 EC Urban (mpg) 42.2  &gt; 49 MPG 22 Insurance Group 143 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 150 CO2 (g/km) £145 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE Insurance Group 22, 40/60 Split-folding rear seat back, Adjustable Steering Column, Anti-theft system, Automatic headlight activation, CD Player, Climate control, Electric Door Mirrors, Electric Windows, Electric Windows - Rear, Heated Mirrors, Hill Descent Control, Interior mirrors - automatic dimming, Leather seat facings, Metallic Paint, Parking Aid - Front, Parking Distance Control, Push Button Ignition, Radio, Rear Headrests, Split Rear Seats, Stop Start system, Traction Control System (TCS), Vehicle security system with engine immobiliser and alarm,Leather Interior , Front &amp; Rear Parking distance control, DTC , Stop Start , Electric Windows , 4X4 Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0161 822 8785 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Audio remote control Central locking Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Reverse parking aid Roof rails Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0161 822 8785 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12v power point in centre console 12v socket in front centre armrest storage compartment 4 foldable grab handles - rear with clothes hook 4 lashing points to secure luggage 40/20/40 split folding rear seat ABS/EBD Ambient temperature display Anti roll bar front and rear Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Body colour aspheric/tinted/electrically adjustable door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console with cupholders Dash mounted storage compartments Double hinged removeable loadspace cover DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Dual zone automatic air conditioning Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric power steering Fingertip control / anti-trap function on electric window Front and rear electric windows Front centre armrest/sliding cover Front/rear adjustable head restraints Heat insulating tinted glass Heated door mirrors Heated windscreen washer jets Hill descent control Illuminated glovebox Isofix rear child seat preparation Leather gearknob/gaiter/handbrake grip Luggage area underfloor compartment Multifunction sports leather steering wheel On board computer Rake/reach adjustable steering wheel Rear park distance control Rear wiper Service interval indicator Stop/start button Storage compartments in doors Tyre puncture warning system Entertainment Auxiliary socket for external MP3 player BMW professional radio with CD player Exterior / Styling Adjustable headlights Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Chrome tailpipe finisher Follow me home headlights Front fog lights Satin Aluminium Roof Rails Welcome home function xLine pack - X1 Safety / Security 3 rear 3 point seatbelts Central locking including boot and fuel flap with deadlocks Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Driver/Front Passenger airbags Driver/front passenger side airbags Engine immobiliser Front and rear head airbags Front passenger airbag deactivation Front seatbelt force limiters Locking wheel nuts Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Rear door child safety locks Remote control Thatcham category 1 alarm Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0161 822 8785 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 150
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/776112e5-91c9-349c-b3d8-9aa7c54f291a" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-28T04:15:51Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:20:23.127Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39852089/ds" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
