<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Bruce Power, the world's largest operating nuclear facility, has iPad and iPhone apps that feature interactive calculators and information about our site. Download through the App Store. Bruce Power App
Summer bus tour program begins
Looking for something fun to do with the family this summer? We’ve got you covered at the Bruce Power Visitors’ Centre.
As of July 1, the Visitors’ Centre will be open 7 days a week (closed on July 3 and Aug. 7 for statutory holidays) from 9 a.m. to 4 p.m. Along with our regular exhibits, we’ve got a few special treats for Summer 2017.
The first is the return of our site bus tours. If you’ve always wanted to see what our site looks like up close, this is the tour for you! Tours run twice daily at 1 and 2 p.m. Valid government-issued photo ID is required and an adult must be present to vouch for the identity of children under 18.  Pre-registration for bus tours is required.
As well, we will be featuring a live theatre performance throughout the summer!
On Wednesdays and Fridays at noon, and on selected weekends, the Visitors’ Centre auditorium will be transformed into a theatre for a 20-minute play titled ‘The Quest for the Perfect Science Fair Project,’ which was written by Development Student Cassie Davidson, who also stars in the show with fellow student Robert Colquhoun. The performance will take place July 1, 2, 5, 12, 14, 15, 16, 19, 21, 26 and 28, as well as Aug. 2, 4, 9, 11, 16, 18, 19, 20, 23, 25 and 30
“We are very excited about opening Sundays and adding more tours and our live theatre performance to the Summer Program at the Visitors’ Centre,” said Chris Mercanti, Section Manager, Community and Indigenous Relations. “Our Development Students have written a fun and educational show about nuclear power, and it complements the interactive displays throughout the Visitors’ Centre and the Bus Tour Program.”
Use the map below to get directions from where you are to us.
We hope to see you this summer!
STAY IN TOUCH
Sign up for our monthly eNewsletter
* indicates required

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/iter03/46" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.brucepower.com/" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
