<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Obama Spending Costs Revealed, Over $114 Million In Vacations And Hillary Campaigning.

Obamanomics
(<NODE id="101" />Conservative Tribune<NODE id="121" />) – Former President Barack Obama infamously spent large amounts of taxpayer dollars on vacations and family outings, but until recently, an exact amount was not available due to refusals by certain groups to disclose their records.
However, a Freedom of Information Act request and subsequent lawsuits filed by <NODE id="433" />Judicial Watch<NODE id="447" /> resulted in the disclosure of <NODE id="478" />U.S. Air Force<NODE id="492" /> and the <NODE id="501" />Secret Service<NODE id="515" /> documents showing that the Obamas spent $9,028,346.90 on non-work related travel.
When added to the previously reported tab of $105,662,975.27, the total cost of personal travel expenses during Obama’s presidency amounted to $114,691,322.17.
These additional records showed that over the course of just one weekend in February of 2014, Obama family vacations cost the <NODE id="884" />Secret Service<NODE id="898" /> $272,192.91.
Those costs included Michelle Obama’s annual trip to Aspen with daughters Sasha and Malia, which amounted to $6,970 in air/rail expenses, $5,614.99 in car rentals, and $76,078.30 in hotels for a total of $88,663.29.
Meanwhile, the former president was on a golfing trip to Palm Springs, which cost $10,951 in air/rail travel, $10,166.79 in car rentals, and $162,411.80 in hotels for a total of $183,529.62.
The records also revealed how much taxpayer funding went toward campaigning for 2016 presidential candidate Hillary Clinton.
In fact, during the campaign, the former first lady made two trips to North Carolina to stump for the Democratic candidate.
For both trips, she took a C-40C military jet, which operated at $5,312 per hour, racking up an <NODE id="1664" />Air Force<NODE id="1673" /> bill of $40,902.40.
The records also indicated that during his second term, Obama spent more than $7 million in taxpayer money to fly to his hometown of Chicago.
And, unfortunately, his taxpayer-funded trips did not end with his administration.
In fact, post-presidency, Obama has spent nearly $2 million in taxpayer money on travel expenses, according to the Secret Service documents. The details of those trips, however, were redacted due to concerns regarding “privacy” and “law enforcement.”
<NODE id="2170" />Judicial Watch<NODE id="2184" /> had to sue for these records after the <NODE id="2224" />Air Force<NODE id="2233" /> and <NODE id="2238" />Secret Service<NODE id="2252" /> did not respond to its public records requests in time, as required by law.
The organization’s president, Tom Fitton, criticized both government groups for their failure to produce the information.
“It shouldn’t require federal lawsuits to…prod the <NODE id="2502" />Secret Service<NODE id="2516" /> and <NODE id="2521" />Air Force<NODE id="2530" /> to produce information about the costs of presidential travel—whether the travel is necessary or not, it’s a massive amount of money,” he said in a statement about the report. “We will continue to monitor this spending while taxpayers continue to pay the bills for presidential travel.”
Taxpayers shouldn’t have to foot the bill for travel that isn’t necessary to carry out the duties of the presidency. With an insurmountable national debt already burdening future Americans who haven’t even been born, our leaders should be cautious about overspending, especially for personal reasons.
Like and share this article on Facebook and Twitter if you’re appalled at how much taxpayer money former President Obama spent on vacations and traveling.
conservativetribune.com/obama-spending-costs-revealed/

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="https://www.teaparty.org/obama-spending-costs-revealed-114-million-vacations-hillary-campaigning-279439/@2017-11-29T17:38:24.000+01:00" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.teaparty.org/obama-spending-costs-revealed-114-million-vacations-hillary-campaigning-279439/" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="101" endPos="121" type="organization-company" surface="Conservative Tribune" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="433" endPos="447" type="organization" surface="Judicial Watch" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="478" endPos="492" type="organization" surface="U.S. Air Force" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="501" endPos="515" type="organization" surface="Secret Service" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="884" endPos="898" type="organization" surface="Secret Service" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1664" endPos="1673" type="organization" surface="Air Force" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="2170" endPos="2184" type="organization" surface="Judicial Watch" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="2224" endPos="2233" type="organization" surface="Air Force" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="2238" endPos="2252" type="organization" surface="Secret Service" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2502" endPos="2516" type="organization" surface="Secret Service" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2521" endPos="2530" type="organization" surface="Air Force" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
