<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Lindsey Vonn second-fastest in Lake Louise downhill training.

Classifieds
Lindsey Vonn, of the United States, skis down the course during a training run for the women's World Cup downhill ski race in Lake Louise, Alberta, Thursday, Nov. 30, 2017. <NODE id="248" />The Canadian Press<NODE id="266" /> via <NODE id="271" />AP<NODE id="273" /> Frank Gunn
Lindsey Vonn, of the United States, skis down the course during a training run for the women's World Cup downhill ski race in Lake Louise, Alberta, Thursday, Nov. 30, 2017. <NODE id="458" />The Canadian Press<NODE id="476" /> via <NODE id="481" />AP<NODE id="483" /> Frank Gunn
Lindsey Vonn second-fastest in Lake Louise downhill training
<NODE id="556" />The Associated Press<NODE id="576" />
November 30, 2017 05:35 PM
UPDATED 5 MINUTES AGO
LAKE LOUISE, Alberta
Lindsey Vonn was the second-fastest in training Thursday for the season-opening women's World Cup downhill.
An 18-time winner at Lake Louise, Vonn is back at the resort west of Calgary after missing the stop last season because of a broken arm. The 33-year-old American star had a run of 1 minute, 48.29 seconds to finish 0.15 seconds behind Ester Ledecka of the Czech Republic.
Downhills are set for Friday and Saturday, followed by a super-G race Sunday.
Tina Weirather of Liechtenstein was third at 1:48.68. Weirather topped training Tuesday, and scheduled runs Wednesday were wiped out because of soft course conditions.
Never miss a local story.
Sign up today for unlimited digital access to our website, apps, the digital newspaper and more.
SUBSCRIBE NOW
Canada's Marie-Michele Gagnon, was just off Ledecka's pace coming into the final turn, but fell and crashed into the safety nets. She injured a shoulder and was removed from the course on a sled.
Vonn has a record 77 career women's World Cup victories. She is a four-time overall World Cup champion and won the 2010 Olympic women's downhill.

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="http://www.heraldonline.com/sports/article187405398.html@2017-11-30T23:35:17.000+01:00" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.heraldonline.com/sports/article187405398.html" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="248" endPos="266" type="organization-company" surface="The Canadian Press" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="271" endPos="273" type="organization-company" surface="AP" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="458" endPos="476" type="organization-company" surface="The Canadian Press" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="481" endPos="483" type="organization-company" surface="AP" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="556" endPos="576" type="organization-company" surface="The Associated Press" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
