<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>B. Braun To Showcase New Additions to Its Regional Anesthesia Portfolio at American Society of….

B. Braun To Showcase New Additions to Its Regional Anesthesia Portfolio at American Society of Anesthesiologists Annual Meeting
By GlobeNewswire,  October 20, 2017, 09:25:00 AM EDT
A A A
&quot;Infectious Disease Transmission in The Operating Room: Clinical Research Illuminates The Risk&quot; To Be Presented by Randy Loftus, M.D.
BETHLEHEM, Pa., Oct.  20, 2017  (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- B. Braun Medical Inc. will present its expanding portfolio of regional anesthesia products at ANESTHESIOLOGY 2017, the American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) Annual Meeting, Oct. 21-23, in Boston. New products designed to improve efficiency and patient outcomes will be showcased, including: Xperius® Ultrasound System; SAXA Anesthesia Disinfection Workstation with DOCit™ and HubScrub™ IPA devices; NRFit™ connectors; and Ultra 360® Nerve Block Needles.
At booth #3126 at the Boston Convention and Exhibition Center, B. Braun will feature the following products that are bringing an innovative approach to regional anesthesia:
Xperius® Ultrasound System : Xperius is designed to be mobile and fit seamlessly into the care area. Its anatomical imaging complements B. Braun&apos;s regional block needle portfolio, and its image quality promotes confident needle targeting and positioning. Xperius&apos; fully articulating arm allows for easy adjustments of the ultrasound monitor position and the angle of the screen for ergonomic use and screen view. Xperius is the first product resulting from a strategic alliance between B. Braun Melsungen AG and Royal Philips (NYSE: PHG )(AEX: PHIA ).
 
Anesthesia Disinfection Workstation: Developed by SAXA Medical Solutions and distributed by B. Braun to help organize the anesthesia workspace in the operating room, the Anesthesia Disinfection Workstation includes the new DOCit™ and HubScrub™ IPA devices. The DOCit device is intended to disinfect and clean syringe tips and male luer connectors, and the HubScrub device is intended to disinfect and clean needleless connectors and stopcocks. The devices are designed to improve intravascular device disinfection in the operating room.
B. Braun will sponsor the presentation Infectious Disease Transmission in The Operating Room: Clinical Research Illuminates The Risk on Sunday, Oct. 22, in Pacific Salons A-E, Renaissance Boston Waterfront Hotel. Randy Loftus, M.D., Associate Professor of Anesthesiology, will discuss the latest research in infectious disease transmission in the OR and innovations - like the Anesthesia Disinfection Workstation - in device handling designed to optimize compliance with disinfection of devices in the OR. Breakfast will be served between 5:30 - 6:30 a.m., and the presentation will run from 6:30 to 8 a.m. (The event is held adjunct from ANESTHESIOLOGY 2017 and is not sponsored or endorsed by ASA. The presentation does not qualify for continuing education or CMEs.) To register, visit www.BBraunKnowledge.com .
NRFit™Connectors: B. Braun offers epidural and spinal products with NRFit connectors that are designed to help avoid connections between medical devices meant for neuraxial administration and devices used for IV, enteral, and other applications. By replacing luer connectors with NRFit connectors, clinicians can reduce the risk of misconnection between applications and reduce medication errors.
 
Ultra 360® Nerve Block Needles: Intended for use in dual guidance techniques, the Ultra 360 needles feature B. Braun&apos;s new echogenic 360º x-pattern. In a study comparing four manufacturers&apos; needles (Pajunk&apos;s Sonoplex, Arrow&apos;s StimuQuick Echo, Vygon&apos;s Echoplex, and B. Braun&apos;s Stimuplex® Ultra 360), the Stimuplex Ultra 360 was ranked highest overall.1 The Ultra 360 needles are designed for nerve block injections under ultrasound visualization.
About B. Braun
B. Braun Medical Inc., a leader in infusion therapy and pain management, develops, manufactures, and markets innovative medical products and services to the healthcare industry. The company is committed to eliminating preventable treatment errors and enhancing patient, clinician and environmental safety. B. Braun Medical is headquartered in Bethlehem, Pa., and is part of the B. Braun Group of Companies in the U.S., which includes B. Braun Interventional Systems, Aesculap® and CAPS®.
Globally, the B. Braun Group of Companies employs more than 58,000 employees in 64 countries. Guided by its Sharing Expertise® philosophy, B. Braun continuously exchanges knowledge with customers, partners and clinicians to address the critical issues of improving care and lowering costs. To learn more about B. Braun Medical, visit www.BBraunUSA.com .
1Cooper, D, Van Geffen, GJ, Bruaset, 1, et. al. Regional Block Needles - A Matter of Feel and Brightness. Presented at the 35th ESRA in Maastricht, Netherlands, September 2016. Conflict of interest: Dr. Cooper is employed as a research analyst by
B. Braun and is a research fellow at Sheffield Hallam University. No other author has conflicts to declare.
Philips is the manufacturer of the Xperius ultrasound system. B. Braun Medical Inc. is the distributor of the Xperius ultrasound system.
DOCit™ and HubScrub™ are trademarks of SAXA Medical Solutions, LLC. SAXA is the manufacturer and B. Braun Medical Inc. is the distributor of the Anesthesia Disinfection Workstation, DOCit and HubScrub.
Contact:       

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="http://www.nasdaq.com/press-release/b-braun-to-showcase-new-additions-to-its-regional-anesthesia-portfolio-at-american-society-of-20171020-00562@2017-10-20T15:29:52.000+02:00" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.nasdaq.com/press-release/b-braun-to-showcase-new-additions-to-its-regional-anesthesia-portfolio-at-american-society-of-20171020-00562" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
</Meta>
<Entities></Entities>
<Relations></Relations>
</Document>
