<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Kia Telluride Concept Glimpsing a future that is grounded in reality but not bound by the present, <NODE id="99" />Kia Motors America (KMA)<NODE id="123" /> unveiled a cutting-edge vision for a full-size <NODE id="171" />SUV<NODE id="174" /> at the 2016 North American International Auto Show (NAIAS). The Telluride, a striking three-row, seven-passenger, luxury SUV concept features a modern and upright shape, muscular stance, and state-of-the-art technology to care for its occupants. Purely conceptual, the Kia Telluride is based on an existing platform and reveals the brand's interest in potentially offering a premium SUV positioned above the current hot-selling Sorento. The <NODE id="616" />Kia Telluride<NODE id="629" /> makes an aesthetic statement for the <NODE id="667" />Kia<NODE id="670" /> brand as a bold, all-new luxury SUV with an abundance of advanced technology, focusing particular attention on the experience and comfort of second-row occupants, said <NODE id="839" />Tom Kearns<NODE id="849" />, chief designer, <NODE id="867" />Kia Design Center America (KDCA)<NODE id="899" />. Longer, wider and taller than the recently redesigned Sorento CUV, Telluride allows us to envision what a full-size seven-passenger SUV from Kia could look like. Telluride's front doors and rear-hinged back doors swing open 90 degrees in opposing directions, creating an expansive and inviting portal into the panoramic interior space and revealing a technological showcase. Four beautiful black-leather captain's seats appear to float within the spacious cabin in front of a folded third-row bench. The large cabin allows the middle seats to recline nearly flat and include large fold-away footrests for sublime comfort. All four seats include a series of precise diamond-cut openings in the seatback, each embedded with Smart Sensors to capture a passenger's vital health information. Once obtained, these vitals are displayed on the interior door panel screens, which then systematically synchronize with a Light Emitted Rejuvenation (LER) system. The LER system utilizes a massive, wing-shaped LED panel mounted beneath the oversized sunroof that displays a pattern of therapeutic light to treat desynchronosis (jetlag) and improve the passengers' energy levels. Tags: car dealers detroit,car dealers in detroit,car detroit,cars in detroit,detroit car,detroit car companies,detroit car dealers,detroit car industry,detroit car makers,detroit car manufacturers,detroit cars,detroit motor cars,kia concept car,kia concept cars,kia concept sports car,kia concepts,kia gt concept,kia gt concept car price,kia gt concept price
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/2ee0e170-ded2-36c0-bb12-28e46e18c47e" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T12:34:09Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:52:58.712Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YJt6rz1LJpk" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="99" endPos="123" type="organization-company" surface="Kia Motors America (KMA)" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="171" endPos="174" type="product-class" surface="SUV" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="616" endPos="629" type="product" surface="Kia Telluride" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="667" endPos="670" type="organization-company" surface="Kia" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="839" endPos="849" type="person" surface="Tom Kearns" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="867" endPos="899" type="organization-company" surface="Kia Design Center America (KDCA)" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="6" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="7" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="2" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
