<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Wednesday, January 6, 2016 Last update: 9:03 AM FreshNews.com - Covering Large &amp; Obscure Tech Companies Since 1996 Bluetooth Announces Breakthrough Award Winners at Discover Blue, CES 2016 Submitted by admin on 1/6/2016 @ 8:00 AM Companies mentioned in this article: Bluetooth Special Interest Group LAS VEGAS -- (BUSINESS WIRE) -- The Bluetooth Special Interest Group (SIG) today announced the overall winner and four category winners for the 2016 Bluetooth Breakthrough Awards from its annual CES media and demo event, Discover Blue. Exemplifying the most innovative IoT prototypes, products, and applications from around the globe, the winners all use Bluetooth to deliver the secure, effortless connectivity that makes the Internet of Things accessible to everyone. From audio solutions to home lighting, kitchen appliances, cycling equipment, and food safety, Bluetooth is the constant that empowers developers and manufacturers to quickly create next-level IoT innovations. Overall winner Fliegl Agratechnik GmbH earned top honors for its unprecedented implementation of Bluetooth to help alleviate food safety concerns, a complex and critical global issue. The Fliegl Tracker uses advanced Bluetooth beacon technology to dramatically improve food safety by making it easier and more reliable to track food from farm to table. As the overall winner, Fliegl Agratechnik GmbH will be featured among the latest Bluetooth innovations driving IoT growth at Bluetooth World 2016 in March, and will be receiving transportation and exhibition space valued at $12,500 USD. Every year, the Bluetooth Breakthrough Awards demonstrate that the Internet of Things is not just hype. It's real and becoming more important every day. These products, applications, and prototypes represent the amazing relationships we can – and already do - create between people and technology, said <NODE id="1873" />Errett Kroeter<NODE id="1887" />, <NODE id="1889" />Vice President of Marketing<NODE id="1916" /> at <NODE id="1920" />Bluetooth SIG<NODE id="1933" />. Our winners aren't just embracing the potential of the IoT; they're creating it with the flexibility and simplicity of Bluetooth. Just take our overall winner Fliegl for example. With a tiny Bluetooth beacon, they created a product that can make our food supply much safer. Overall Winner <NODE id="2224" />Fliegl Tracker<NODE id="2238" /> (<NODE id="2240" />Fliegl Agratechnik GmbH<NODE id="2263" />) is a Bluetooth beacon-based vehicle detection system that reduces food safety concerns by making the agricultural distribution cycle more transparent and the production of foodstuffs traceable. Small and reliable, Bluetooth beacons are the linchpin of this IoT solution for agriculture and make Fliegl's long-term plans to improve food safety around the globe a possibility. Breakthrough Product Winner <NODE id="2668" />ilumi LED Smartbulb<NODE id="2687" /> (<NODE id="2689" />ilumi Solutions<NODE id="2704" />) is an advanced wireless lighting system facilitated by the effortless connectivity of Bluetooth. ilumi leverages the interoperability of Bluetooth to control lights, share lighting access with friends and family, and connect multiple lights together to cover whole home and commercial installations. Breakthrough Application Winner <NODE id="3038" />ReSound Smart App<NODE id="3055" /> (<NODE id="3057" />ReSound<NODE id="3064" />) is the first hearing aid app with a direct Bluetooth connection between your hearing aids and your Apple Watch, iPhone, or Android device. With the secure, reliable connection of Bluetooth, you can manage and personalize your hearing experience – intuitively and discretely – with programmable settings and data sharing with your healthcare professional, further embracing the benefits of connected medical devices. Breakthrough Prototype Winner <NODE id="3512" />Bioshift<NODE id="3520" /> (<NODE id="3522" />Baron Biosystems Ltd.<NODE id="3543" />) is an intelligent gear selection system that uses Bluetooth sensors to constantly determine the optimal gear for a cyclist, in real-time, based on their specific athletic characteristics and needs. The power efficiency and dynamic capabilities of Bluetooth make it possible for Bioshift to provide the ideal cycling experience. Breakthrough APAC Region Winner <NODE id="3905" />Easy Sous-vide<NODE id="3919" /> (<NODE id="3921" />KitchBot<NODE id="3929" />) is a Bluetooth enabled thermometer that allows you to control temperature and monitor cook time of your rice or slow cooker from your smart phone, making a delicious home cooked meal a reality for everyone. With a simple Bluetooth connection, anyone can perfectly braise meats or prepare seafood without expensive specialty equipment or years of cooking experience. This year's Breakthrough Awards were proudly sponsored by Platinum sponsor: Nordic Semiconductor ASA; Gold sponsor: Frontline Test Equipment, Inc.; and Silver sponsors: Anaren, Broadcom Corporation, and Qualcomm Technologies, Inc. For complete details on all winners, visit: https://www.bluetooth.com/news-events/awards . The Bluetooth Breakthrough Awards also include a student category, recognizing the most ambitious ideas from the next generation of Bluetooth pioneers. More information on our student finalists at: http://blog.bluetooth.com/meet-the-next-generation-of-bluetooth-pioneers/ . About Bluetooth® Wireless Technology Bluetooth is the global wireless standard for simple, secure connectivity. Propelled by a global community of nearly 30,000 companies, Bluetooth serves to unify, harmonize, and drive innovation in the vast range of connected devices all around us. Through collective creation and shared technical standards, Bluetooth simplifies, secures, and enriches the technology experience of users worldwide. Copyright Business Wire 2016 Contact: Americas INK Public Relations Blair Poloskey, +1-512-382-8983 blair@ink-pr.com or Europe, Middle East, Africa Octopus Group Russell Lindsey, +44 (0) 845-3707-024 bluetoothsig@weareoctopusgroup.net or Asia-Pacific CHINA Elite PR Consultants Ellen Xu, +86-21-6373-2255 ext. 128 yangyang.xu@elitepr.cn or JAPAN Actio, Inc. Seiji Arimoto, +81-3-5771-6426 sig@actioinc.jp or KOREA Strategic Marketing and Communications, Inc. MinKyung Bae, +82-2-3445-3283 mk.bae@oksmc.co.kr or TAIWAN Apex Communications Consultants Zoe Chuang, 886-2-7718-7777 ext. 517 zoe@apexpr.com.tw
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0ae53bab-70a1-34b7-afc2-6b64c89f5e61" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-06T19:10:03Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:39:24.94Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.freshnews.com/news/1171356/bluetooth-announces-breakthrough-award-winners-discover-blue-ces-2016" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1873" endPos="1887" type="person" surface="Errett Kroeter" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1889" endPos="1916" type="org-position" surface="Vice President of Marketing" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1920" endPos="1933" type="organization-company" surface="Bluetooth SIG" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="2224" endPos="2238" type="product" surface="Fliegl Tracker" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="2240" endPos="2263" type="organization-company" surface="Fliegl Agratechnik GmbH" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="2668" endPos="2687" type="product" surface="ilumi LED Smartbulb" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="2689" endPos="2704" type="organization-company" surface="ilumi Solutions" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="3038" endPos="3055" type="product" surface="ReSound Smart App" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="3057" endPos="3064" type="organization-company" surface="ReSound" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="3512" endPos="3520" type="product" surface="Bioshift" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3522" endPos="3543" type="organization-company" surface="Baron Biosystems Ltd." />
<Entity id="11" startPos="3905" endPos="3919" type="product" surface="Easy Sous-vide" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="3921" endPos="3929" type="organization-company" surface="KitchBot" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="13" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="14" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="5" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="15" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="7" label="product" />
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="16" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="17" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="18" NAME="OrganizationLeadership">
<Entity id="0" label="person" />
<Entity id="2" label="organization" />
<Entity id="1" label="position" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
