<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>| | | | | | Why don't vikings send emails? They prefer to use Norse code. Powered By <NODE id="85" />Scannable!<NODE id="95" /> | | | | Here's this week's reads. Brought to you this time by <NODE id="158" />Scannable!<NODE id="168" /> What could you do with a high quality scanning LiDAR sensor?     That's it, Enjoy! | | | | Transformations A fundamental application of electronics is transformation - from power supplies that transform AC to DC to microprocessors that transform binary code to text, graphics, and sound. While transformations at many levels may be critical to the function of a device or application, it's the high-level sensory transformations that hold the greatest potential to change the world. Read It Now! | | | | | The Flying Marbellos Click!... Whirrr... Hummm... Bang! These are the sounds of The Flying Marbellos - a rolling ball sculpture with marbles and small metal bugs to run the Stamp controlled show. Read It Now! | | | | | Psychedelia II  This color organ has both hardware and software (firmware) components. What's different about this design is that all of the frequency selectivity is provided by digital filters in the digital domain and the output devices are now low voltage super bright LEDs instead of incandescent bulbs. Read It Now! | | | | | High quality LiDAR, at a price you can afford <NODE id="1271" />Sweep<NODE id="1276" /> is a new scanning LiDAR sensor built from the ground up for consumer applications.  Imagine what you could do with accurate, long range depth information in your next project.  Find out more about our upcoming <NODE id="1487" />Kickstarter<NODE id="1498" /> campaign and sign up for our newsletter at scannable.io | | Get More Info Advertisement | | | | | Smiley's Workshop 36 C Programming * Hardware * Projects The novice-friendly serial library was built on top of two other not so novice-friendly libraries: one for storing the data (ring buffer) and another for sending and receiving the data (USART). This episode will look at ring buffers and at another software engineering tool - the <NODE id="1934" />AVRStudio Simulator<NODE id="1953" /> - that we'll use to test the ring buffer functions. Then next time, we'll look at the <NODE id="2040" />AVR USART<NODE id="2049" />. Read It Now! | | | | From The Q&amp;A Optoisolator Interface Semiconductor Sex Explained Diodes in Series | | | | | Security Electronics Systems And Circuits - Part 7 Practical Build-It-Yourself Anti-Burglary Circuits Take a look at the three basic categories of wireless burglar alarms, some basic types of intrusion sensors, and a variety of practical hard-wired build-it-yourself anti-burglary circuits.   Read It Now! | | | | | Book Pick Of The Week From the <NODE id="2510" />Nuts &amp; Volts Webstore<NODE id="2531" />   <NODE id="2534" />Beginner's Guide to Reading Schematics  3rd Edition<NODE id="2585" />   We love books that have little Tips and Tricks blurbs throughout. Usually they're filled with wisdom that's only learned at the school of hard knocks. This one's loaded with 'em, so it ranks high on our easy to read list. Totally suitable for beginners and the somewhat experienced. Navigate the roadmaps of simple electronic circuits and complex systems with help from an experienced engineer. Schematic, block, and pictorial diagrams Resistors and capacitors Inductors and transformers Switches, conductors, and cables Diodes, transistors, and logic gates Electron tubes Cells and batteries Voltage dividers and reducers Breadboards and wire wrapping Electronics troubleshooting Check It Out! | | | | Subscribe!Subscribe!Subscribe!Subscribe!Subscribe! If you're reading the articles in this newsletter and you like them, then you will certainly like our print magazines too. How do we know this you ask? Easy, because that's where these articles came from. So, it stands to reason that if you like these, you'll like those too. To order, just click one (or both) of the links below 24/7 or call 877 525-2539 between 5am and 5pm PST. Easy! Right? Don't forget, if you become a print subscriber, we'll give you access via the digital edition and mobile app for free! | | For the Electronics Hobbyist Order Nuts &amp; Volts Use Promo Code M62ENLA | For the Robotics Innovator Order SERVO Use Promo Code M62ENLA | | | | You are receiving this email because you have been a customer of the <NODE id="4071" />Nuts &amp; Volts webstore<NODE id="4092" />, a subscriber to <NODE id="4110" />Nuts &amp; Volts<NODE id="4122" /> or <NODE id="4126" />SERVO Magazine<NODE id="4140" />, or have requested to be notified of special offers and promotions. You may unsubscribe or change your email address at any time through the links provided below. | | <NODE id="4308" />T &amp; L Publications, Inc<NODE id="4331" /> | 430 Princeland Court Corona, CA 92879 951.371.8497 | reallycoolreads@nutsvolts.com | www.nutsvolts.com | | | | STAY CONNECTED: | | | | | | | | | | | Forward This Email to a Friend | | This email was sent to wd0ajg@gmail.com by reallycoolreads@nutsvolts.com |   Update Profile/Email Address | Rapid removal with SafeUnsubscribe™ | About our service provider. | | | <NODE id="4698" />T &amp; L Publications, Inc<NODE id="4721" /> | 430 Princeland Ct | Corona | CA | 92879-1300 | | |
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/65519b4e-e84d-3aa1-9e0f-fbde6e9a5bfa" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-06T23:00:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:13:31.639Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://wd0ajg.blogspot.com/2016/02/fwd-do-you-think-of-electronics-as.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="85" endPos="95" type="organization-company" surface="Scannable!" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="158" endPos="168" type="organization-company" surface="Scannable!" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1271" endPos="1276" type="product" surface="Sweep" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1487" endPos="1498" type="organization-company" surface="Kickstarter" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1934" endPos="1953" type="product" surface="AVRStudio Simulator" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="2040" endPos="2049" type="product" surface="AVR USART" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="2510" endPos="2531" type="organization-company" surface="Nuts &amp; Volts Webstore" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="2534" endPos="2585" type="product" surface="Beginner's Guide to Reading Schematics  3rd Edition" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="4071" endPos="4092" type="organization-company" surface="Nuts &amp; Volts webstore" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="4110" endPos="4122" type="organization-company" surface="Nuts &amp; Volts" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="4126" endPos="4140" type="organization-company" surface="SERVO Magazine" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="4308" endPos="4331" type="organization-company" surface="T &amp; L Publications, Inc" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="4698" endPos="4721" type="organization-company" surface="T &amp; L Publications, Inc" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
