<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>http://Howtocomparecarinsurance.net  2016 Kia Telluride concept Review Glimpsing a future that is grounded in reality but not bound by the present, Kia Motors America (KMA) unveiled a cutting-edge vision for a full-size SUV at the 2016 North American International Auto Show (NAIAS).  The Telluride, a striking three-row, seven-passenger, luxury SUV concept features a modern and upright shape, muscular stance, and state-of-the-art technology to care for its occupants. Purely conceptual, the Kia Telluride is based on an existing platform and reveals the brand's interest in potentially offering a premium SUV positioned above the current hot-selling Sorento. The <NODE id="666" />Kia Telluride<NODE id="679" /> makes an aesthetic statement for the <NODE id="717" />Kia<NODE id="720" /> brand as a bold, all-new luxury SUV with an abundance of advanced technology, focusing particular attention on the experience and comfort of second-row occupants, said Tom Kearns, chief designer, Kia Design Center America (KDCA). Longer, wider and taller than the recently redesigned <NODE id="1005" />Sorento<NODE id="1012" /> CUV, <NODE id="1018" />Telluride<NODE id="1027" /> allows us to envision what a full-size seven-passenger SUV from <NODE id="1092" />Kia<NODE id="1095" /> could look like. Telluride's front doors and rear-hinged back doors swing open 90 degrees in opposing directions, creating an expansive and inviting portal into the panoramic interior space and revealing a technological showcase. Four beautiful black-leather captain's seats appear to float within the spacious cabin in front of a folded third-row bench.  The large cabin allows the middle seats to recline nearly flat and include large fold-away footrests for sublime comfort. All four seats include a series of precise diamond-cut openings in the seatback, each embedded with Smart Sensors to capture a passenger's vital health information. Once obtained, these vitals are displayed on the interior door panel screens, which then systematically synchronize with a Light Emitted Rejuvenation (LER) system.  The LER system utilizes a massive, wing-shaped LED panel mounted beneath the oversized sunroof that displays a pattern of therapeutic light to treat desynchronosis (jetlag) and improve the passengers' energy levels. With an innovative combination of cutting-edge technologies, the Telluride's powertrain is a near-future, no-compromises propulsion system, offering both power and efficiency. A finger-print activated push-button start unleashes Telluride's tremendously potent yet extremely efficient PHEV powertrain. Utilizing a 3.5-liter gasoline direct injected (GDI) V6 engine and powerful electric motor, Telluride's transverse-mounted powertrain combines to produce 400 horsepower (270 horsepower from V6 and 130 horsepower from the electric motor) while achieving more than 30 mpg on the highway. Power is routed to all four wheels via an advanced all-wheel drive system. While there are currently no plans to bring the Telluride to production, Kia has a history of delivering production vehicles that bear strong resemblance to preceding concepts, and Kia's large SUV is anything but a utopian fantasy. Tags: 2016 Kia Telluride,2016 Kia Telluride review,2016 Kia Telluride concept,2016 Kia Telluride driving,2016 Kia Telluride video,2016 Kia,Kia,Kia 2016,Kia driving,Kia sedan,Kia cars,new cars,vehicle,car insurance,car deal,auto,automotive,sedan
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0b2f2f8a-f982-31ea-b2da-ef1d6439024d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T01:44:20Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:39:31.594Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xo3odFYZJFk" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="666" endPos="679" type="product" surface="Kia Telluride" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="717" endPos="720" type="organization-company" surface="Kia" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1005" endPos="1012" type="product" surface="Sorento" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1018" endPos="1027" type="product" surface="Telluride" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1092" endPos="1095" type="organization-company" surface="Kia" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="5" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="0" label="product" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="6" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="2" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="7" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
