<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Datalogic: Products and Technology to NRF 2016. The global leader in Automatic Data Capture and Industrial Automation markets, and world-class producer of bar code readers, mobile computers, sensors, vision systems and laser marking equipment brings an extensive display of products and technology to NRF 2016 at the Datalogic booth 3619. The NRF exhibition “Retail’s Big Show 2016” will take place January 17 – 19 at the Javits Center in New York. “We look at NRF as the best showcase to demonstrate our retail technology and solutions. This year we are planning an extensive display that illustrates our Retail 360˚ viewpoint” states <NODE id="636" />Pietro Todescato<NODE id="652" />, <NODE id="654" />CEO<NODE id="657" /> and <NODE id="662" />President<NODE id="671" /> of <NODE id="675" />Datalogic ADC<NODE id="688" />. “As a multinational company, there is no better place than NRF to meet and network with our many global customers. We make their visit worthwhile by bringing a full suite of interesting retail focused solutions.” <NODE id="903" />Datalogic<NODE id="912" /> will have ten demonstration areas each focusing on a retail application or functional area. Each demonstration area will have live demonstrations of multiple applicable products and solutions. The following list is a sample of the many products and solutions which will be on display at NRF 2016: Magellan™ 9800i &amp; 9400i scanner/scales - These multi-plane advanced imaging scanner/scales are the industry’s first fully digital imaging high performance scanner/scale product lines with features that prevent shrink, accelerate mobile interaction and help future proof the POS. These products were the first in the industry to read digital watermarks including the Digimarc® Barcode. Jade™X7 Automated Scanner – The Jade portal scanner powers the industry’s fastest automated checkout solutions. It allows shoppers to place items in any orientation onto a fast moving belt. Items are automatically read and visually recognized at speeds significantly higher than a manual checkout. Joya™ Touch Device - The Joya™ Touch device is the ideal multi-purpose retail device for Self-shopping and shop-floor applications. This state-of-the-art device, offered in handheld and gun versions, can have multiple applications resident making it the one device that can tackle any retail task. Consumer applications such as Self-Shopping, Queue-busting and Gift Registry can co-exist with operational applications such as shelf replenishment, inventory checks, mark downs, price checks and more. LaneHawk™ Loss Prevention Solution – This loss prevention solution turns the bottom-of-the-basket shrink into profits in real-time. LaneHawk cameras detect and identify items in the bottom of the basket and send product information to the POS system to include in the customer’s transaction. PowerScan™ Rugged Handheld Scanner – The world’s best-selling industrial scanner that is synonymous with warehouse data capture will soon be available in a Retail version that with the ability to decode digital watermarks, including the Digimarc® Barcode. This new scanner will be previewed at NRF 2016. <NODE id="2989" />Falcon™ X3+ Mobile Computer<NODE id="3016" /> – The <NODE id="3023" />Falcon<NODE id="3029" /> device is <NODE id="3040" />Datalogic<NODE id="3049" />’s most rugged <NODE id="3064" />mobile computer<NODE id="3079" /> with the ideal blend of ergonomics, ruggedness, computing power and data capture technologies that is at home in the stockroom, warehouse, or retail floor. Skorpio™X3 Mobile Computer – <NODE id="3265" />Datalogic<NODE id="3274" />’s bestselling <NODE id="3289" />mobile computer<NODE id="3304" /> is packed with technology and is ideally suited for most any retail or warehouse application. Cobalto™ Presentation Scanner – Omnidirectional scanning and an excellent value for retailers looking for outstanding performance in a full-featured product. Heron™ Handheld Scanner – Unmatched elegance, the latest data capture technology, and extensive customization of sounds, lighting, and labeling make it the modern point-of-sale scanner. DL-Axist™ PDA – Android based, full touch 5” HD display with an advanced 2D imager making it ideal for assisted sales, merchandising, stock management, or as a Manager’s device, all designed in a robust industrial strength enclosure. DBT6400™ Scanner – A pocket-sized innovative, wireless Bluetooth® scanner that is ideal for connection with tablets offering easy implementation of Mobile POS, Assisted Sales and other data capture within the stores. RFID Solutions – Multiple RFID reading solutions specifically designed for use in retail environments such as capturing real time inventory. Smart Dressing Room – Display technological integrating touch screens, video imaging, and RFID for retail assistance to customers deciding the correct fit and color, offering the ability to check current stock of items and sharing apparel information via social media. OEM Scan Engines – Two new miniature scan engines the Halogen engine for 2D area imager applications and the innovative Herbo engine for laser-like linear imager applications, that leverage Datalogic proprietary illumination and data capture technology will be previewed. During NRF 2016, product managers and executives will be on hand to discuss the latest products, solutions, and technologies on display in the booth. Contact your local Datalogic representative to schedule meetings and obtain more information. <NODE id="5120" />Datalogic Group<NODE id="5135" /> is a global leader in <NODE id="5158" />Automatic Data Capture<NODE id="5180" /> and <NODE id="5185" />Industrial Automation<NODE id="5206" /> markets. As a world-class <NODE id="5233" />producer<NODE id="5241" /> of <NODE id="5245" />bar code readers<NODE id="5261" />, <NODE id="5263" />mobile computers<NODE id="5279" />, <NODE id="5281" />sensors for detection, measurement and safety<NODE id="5326" />, <NODE id="5328" />vision systems<NODE id="5342" /> and <NODE id="5347" />laser marking systems<NODE id="5368" />, <NODE id="5370" />Datalogic<NODE id="5379" /> offers innovative solutions for a full range of applications in the retail, transportation &amp; logistics, manufacturing and healthcare industries. With products used in over a third of world’s supermarkets and points of sale, airports, shipping and postal services, Datalogic is in a unique position to deliver solutions that can make life easier and more efficient for people. Datalogic S.p.A., listed on the STAR segment of the Italian Stock Exchange since 2001 as DAL.MI, is headquartered in Lippo di Calderara di Reno (Bologna). Datalogic Group as of today employs about 2,400 members of staff worldwide distributed in 30 countries. In <NODE id="6018" />2014<NODE id="6022" /> <NODE id="6023" />Datalogic Group<NODE id="6038" /> achieved <NODE id="6048" />revenues<NODE id="6056" /> for <NODE id="6061" />464,5 million Euro<NODE id="6079" /> and invested over <NODE id="6098" />43 million Euro<NODE id="6113" /> in Research and Development with a portfolio of over 1,100 patents across the world. www.datalogic.com The post Datalogic: Products and Technology to NRF 2016 appeared first on BYinnovation.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/3fe20687-3978-36d2-9ee5-c51ce0baeb1c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-13T06:15:13Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:59:22.917Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://byinnovation.eu/datalogic-products-and-technology-to-nrf-2016/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="636" endPos="652" type="person" surface="Pietro Todescato" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="654" endPos="657" type="org-position" surface="CEO" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="662" endPos="671" type="org-position" surface="President" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="675" endPos="688" type="organization-company" surface="Datalogic ADC" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="903" endPos="912" type="organization-company" surface="Datalogic" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="2989" endPos="3016" type="product" surface="Falcon™ X3+ Mobile Computer" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="3023" endPos="3029" type="product" surface="Falcon" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="3040" endPos="3049" type="organization-company" surface="Datalogic" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="3064" endPos="3079" type="product-class" surface="mobile computer" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="3265" endPos="3274" type="organization-company" surface="Datalogic" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3289" endPos="3304" type="product-class" surface="mobile computer" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="5120" endPos="5135" type="organization-company" surface="Datalogic Group" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="5158" endPos="5180" type="product-class" surface="Automatic Data Capture" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="5185" endPos="5206" type="product-class" surface="Industrial Automation" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="5233" endPos="5241" type="provide-type" surface="producer" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="5245" endPos="5261" type="product-class" surface="bar code readers" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="5263" endPos="5279" type="product-class" surface="mobile computers" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="5281" endPos="5326" type="product-class" surface="sensors for detection, measurement and safety" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="5328" endPos="5342" type="product-class" surface="vision systems" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="5347" endPos="5368" type="product-class" surface="laser marking systems" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="5370" endPos="5379" type="organization-company" surface="Datalogic" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="6018" endPos="6022" type="date" surface="2014" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="6023" endPos="6038" type="organization-company" surface="Datalogic Group" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="6048" endPos="6056" type="trigger" surface="revenues" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="6061" endPos="6079" type="number" surface="464,5 million Euro" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="6098" endPos="6113" type="number" surface="43 million Euro" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="26" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="8" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="product" />
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="27" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="10" label="product" />
<Entity id="9" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="28" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="13" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="product" />
<Entity id="11" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="29" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="18" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="product" />
<Entity id="17" label="product" />
<Entity id="19" label="product" />
<Entity id="16" label="product" />
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="CompanyRevenue">
<Entity id="24" label="revenue" />
<Entity id="21" label="from" />
<Entity id="22" label="company" />
<Entity id="21" label="to" />
<Entity id="23" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="OrganizationLeadership">
<Entity id="0" label="person" />
<Entity id="3" label="organization" />
<Entity id="1" label="position" />
<Entity id="2" label="position" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
