<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Global Xenon Gas Market - Market Research Report 2015-2019 By PR Newswire Article Rating: January 7, 2016 05:06 PM EST LONDON , Jan. 7, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- About xenon gas Xenon is naturally available in the atmosphere in trace amounts and is extremely expensive to produce. Xenon is commercially extracted through atmospheric air distillation while some of its compounds are sourced from certain igneous rocks and hot springs. With about eight stable isotopes and more than 40 unstable isotopes, the gas, despite the limited availability and high price, is used for certain exclusive applications some of which are listed as follows: - Used in high resolution IMAX screens and projector screens, where xenon arc lamps act as an excellent source of short wavelength UV radiation - Forms a range of chemical compounds such as xenon chloride and xenon fluoride that are widely used in excimer lasers - Used as an efficient alternate anesthetic to nitrous oxide; it is also used as a performance stimulant by athletes Technavio's analysts forecast the global xenon gas market to grow at a CAGR of 6.12% over the period 2014-2019. Covered in this report Technavio's report, Global Xenon Gas Market 2015-2019, has been prepared based on an in-depth market analysis with inputs from various industry experts. The report includes a comprehensive discussion of the market, an extensive coverage on different end-user segments, demand-supply dynamics in various geographies, and distribution method. The report provides comments on both the existing market landscape and its growth prospects over the forecast period. The report further includes a discussion of the key vendors operating in this market. The report presents data on the following segments of the market: - End-user: aerospace and aircraft, healthcare, imaging and lightning, automotive and transportation, and other industrial uses - Geography: APAC, North America , MEA, Latin America , and Europe - Distribution method: tonnage, merchant, and packaged Key vendors - Air Liquide - Airgas - Linde - Messer Group - Praxair Other prominent vendors - Air Water - American Gas Group - BASF - Core Gas - Iceblick - Matheson Tri -gas - Proton Gas Market drivers - Scientific research enhancing cryogenic usage of xenon - For a full, detailed list, view our report Market challenges - Rise of LEDs and substitutable technologies - For a full, detailed list, view our report Market trends - Growing prominence of repackaging and customized gas formulations - For a full, detailed list, view our report Key questions answered in this report - What will the market size be in 2019 and what will the growth rate be? - What are the various end-uses and potential applications for the product? - What are the key market trends? - What is driving this market? - What are the challenges to market growth? - Who are the key vendors in this market space and what is the nature of competition between them? - What is the distribution channel structure in each geography? Download the full report: https://www.reportbuyer.com/product/3348539/ About Reportbuyer Reportbuyer is a leading industry intelligence solution that provides all market research reports from top publishers http://www.reportbuyer.com For more information: Sarah Smith Research Advisor at Reportbuyer.com Email: [email protected] Tel: +44 208 816 85 48 Website: www.reportbuyer.com To view the original version on PR Newswire, visit: http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/global-xenon-gas-market---market-research-report-2015-2019-300201299.html SOURCE ReportBuyer Published January 7, 2016 Copyright 2016 SYS-CON Media, Inc. - All Rights Reserved. Syndicated stories and blog feeds, all rights reserved by the author. Cloud Expo &amp; DevOps Summit 2015 East KEYNOTES VIEW KEYNOTE WEBCASTS VIEW KEYNOTE WEBCASTS Most Influential Technology Blogs The Application Performance Gap By Steve Brar If a slow or unresponsive application on your mobile device or PC has ever left you feeling angry, frustrated and unproductive, you're not alone. Business success in today's digital age relies on application performance. Yet according to the Riverbed Global Application Performance Survey 2015, nine out of 10 organizations suffer from poor performance on a regular basis. Executives say the poor per... Jan. 7, 2016 05:30 PM EST IoT: Wi-Fi as Leading Technology Segment By Ram Sonagara Internet-of-Things (IoT) is touted as the next big thing slated to revolutionize how we communicate online or how we work. The majority of the chatter rising from industries nowadays is focused on how to deploy machine-to-machine (M2M) communication and optimally capitalize on the technology. Simply put, IoT is built on the paradigm of cloud computing and data gathering sensors networks. Hence, ... Jan. 7, 2016 05:00 PM EST Reads: 107 Is ITIL Still Relevant in the Digital World?
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/67a0d281-20c3-30cd-9af7-a60d9f356149" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-07T23:51:18Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:14:23.629Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.sys-con.com/node/3625340" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
