<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>History: 3rd generation independent farmer of commodities (retired, lol) I can speak to the folks running around in my old neck of the woods, California's Central Valley. Technology has just recently (~10 years) started to heavily integrate into the local farming scene. I'd say the first big leap forward was the addition of smart tractors equipped with a host of sensors and GPS. The machinery can leverage the GPS to guide the equipment to pull dead straight furrows among other beautiful automations. Prior to this, I think the laser planing earth movers used to grade plots of land were pretty slick. What I see in The Valley is a farming industry still heavily rooted in the past. Folks are not overly interested in changing things up too much as this is how it's always been and I've yet to meet a more, lets say, frugal group of people. lol The part of the article that describes the notion of the lion's share of decisions being made by the farmer as a limitation might be true. However, trying to encourage folks who are typically tech-illiterate to hand over the keys to their livelihood to a machine will be met with resistance. All of this being said, none of the farmers that I associate with (and living in such a community you tend to associate with quite a large group) seem to be doing any sort of analytics from the data they are generating. I don't think any of my folks are even storing their data outside of any portal their equipment manufacturer has provided. There is a company I worked with called <NODE id="1524" />Valley Ag Services<NODE id="1542" />. <NODE id="1544" />They<NODE id="1548" /> offer a catalog programed entitled <NODE id="1584" />DairyComp305<NODE id="1596" />. This is a simple database app designed to keep track of a dairyman's heard. It tracks births, deaths, immunizations, sicknesses, etcs. It can generate some fairly static reports as the app is not very sophisticated, but to be fair, most of the dairy farmers are using the cheapest eMachine they can buy to track their most vital information so CPU horsepower is very limited.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/4f512cd6-4c7f-3e5e-a352-3feccf3b98b7" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-08T18:32:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:05:14.278Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.reddit.com/r/bigdata/comments/400kzu/big_data_in_agriculture/?limit=500#cyqsy8n" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1524" endPos="1542" type="organization-company" surface="Valley Ag Services" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1544" endPos="1548" type="organization-company" surface="They" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1584" endPos="1596" type="product" surface="DairyComp305" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="3" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
