<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 12, 2016 C O N T E N T S: Image Courtesy: link: http://www.team100.org/sponsors author: team100.org description: Harmonic Drive LLC is a KEY TOPICS <NODE id="292" />Harmonic Drive, LLC<NODE id="311" /> <NODE id="312" />engineers<NODE id="321" /> and <NODE id="326" />manufactures<NODE id="338" /> <NODE id="339" />precision servo actuators<NODE id="364" />, <NODE id="366" />gearheads<NODE id="375" /> and <NODE id="380" />gear component sets<NODE id="399" />. [1] Common unmanned systems applications for our products include robotic arms, gimbals &amp; stabilized platforms, antenna positioning, and wheel drives for mobile robots. [2] <NODE id="574" />Energid?s<NODE id="583" /> <NODE id="584" />Actin software<NODE id="598" /> drives sensor-guided manipulation, autonomous grasping and straightforward control of complex robotic systems for medical, energy, transportation, and industrial applications. [3] I am interested in making a harmonic drive for small robotic applications. [4] <NODE id="858" />Harmonic Drive<NODE id="872" /> <NODE id="873" />designs<NODE id="880" /> and <NODE id="885" />manufactures<NODE id="897" /> all key components of our actuators including the <NODE id="948" />motor<NODE id="953" />, <NODE id="955" />encoder<NODE id="962" />, <NODE id="964" />gearing<NODE id="971" /> and <NODE id="976" />cross-roller output bearing<NODE id="1003" />. [5] Hackaday Here is another version using planetary gears to deform the flexspline: ORLIN Technologies Ltd How difficult would lit be to machine the components of a small harmonic drive (25mm dia)? I think the most difficult part would be the flexspline. [4] Essentially the major components of the drive forces are due to structural damping and springiness of the flexispline deforming while the input rotates. [6] Arron Acosta CEO and Co-Founder, Rise Robotics <NODE id="1469" />Arron Acosta<NODE id="1481" /> is the <NODE id="1489" />CEO<NODE id="1492" /> and Co-founder of <NODE id="1511" />Rise Robotics<NODE id="1524" />, a company that pio-neers new, affordable ways to design and make <NODE id="1591" />robotic components<NODE id="1609" /> without sacri-ficing performance or power. [3] The limiting elements of conventional Harmonic Drives (teeth, flexspline and ball bearings) are substituted by contactless mechanical components (magnetic gear and superconducting magnetic bearings, ). [7] By using the magnetic distance force interactions of magnets and ferromagnetic materials, all the conventional mechanical elements of a Harmonic Drives (teeth, flexspline and ball bearings) are substituted by contactless mechanical components (magnetic gear and superconducting magnetic bearings). [7] <NODE id="2165" />Harmonic Drive LLC<NODE id="2183" /> is a leader in high precision gearing and motion control with our <NODE id="2250" />Harmonic DriveTM servo actuators<NODE id="2282" />, <NODE id="2284" />gearheads<NODE id="2293" /> and <NODE id="2298" />gear component sets<NODE id="2317" />. [5] The gearhead incorporates a Harmonic Drive gear component into an integral housing. [8] Bernd Wittman, Michael Krabiell and Erik Rig make up the Robotics, Handling and Automation team, bringing together years of knowledge and experience in creating robots, automation systems and high quality drive technology. [9] The new expert teams cover all of the core sectors Harmonic Drive customers operate in, including Robotics, Handling and Automation, Machine Tool, Mechanical Engineering and Medical Technology, Optics and Precision Engineering, Aerospace, Defence and Special Environments. [9] ?Dimensions Harmonic Drive LLC 38 CSF-2UH is a housed component gear set combined with a precision cross roller output bearing flange. [10] Many of the components that comprise a robot are intricate and costly, e.g., reduction gears from Nabtesco, Harmonic Drive and Sumitomo (all Japanese companies). [11] <NODE id="3222" />M axon Precision Mo tors, Inc.<NODE id="3252" /> is a leading <NODE id="3266" />manufacturer<NODE id="3278" /> and <NODE id="3283" />supplier<NODE id="3291" /> of <NODE id="3295" />precision DC drive components<NODE id="3324" />. [12] <NODE id="3331" />Harmonic Drive LLC<NODE id="3349" /> is a company that leads the high precision gearing and motion control industry with their <NODE id="3440" />servo actuators<NODE id="3455" />, <NODE id="3457" />gearheads<NODE id="3466" /> and <NODE id="3471" />gear component sets<NODE id="3490" />. [13] ?? RV Reducer, the predecessor is the mainstream product of Teijin Seiki, the 1970s began as mining equipment drive motor core components. [14] For these reasons, harmonic drives are widely used in applications requiring precision positioning, especially in robotics and semiconductor industries. [15] Harmonic Drive gearing is used extensively in high-precision applications such as robotics and satellite antenna pointing. [16] Technology in Quality RoboDrives: the high-torque, precision drive for next-generation robotic applications As electric motors and drives are integrated into robotics systems, they are bringing new levels of efficiency and productivity to compact robotic solutions for medical, aerospace, and other applications. [17] Application example: An actuator for adjusting business class seats in airplanes. 6 – www.ConvergencePromotions.com RoboDrive and Pin-Ring Drives <NODE id="4391" />TQ<NODE id="4393" /> leads a new generation of high-torque off-road <NODE id="4441" />eBikes<NODE id="4447" /> High performance technology for Pedelecs and E-Bikes Under the trademark cleanmobile <NODE id="4533" />TQ<NODE id="4535" /> <NODE id="4536" />develops<NODE id="4544" /> and <NODE id="4549" />produces<NODE id="4557" /> customer-specific <NODE id="4576" />drive systems and components for Pedelecs, E-Bikes and electric cargo vehicles.<NODE id="4655" /> [17] Headquartered in <NODE id="4678" />Clearwater<NODE id="4688" />, <NODE id="4690" />Florida<NODE id="4697" />, <NODE id="4699" />MICROMO Inc.<NODE id="4711" /> is the <NODE id="4719" />North American<NODE id="4733" /> <NODE id="4734" />source<NODE id="4740" /> for the world?s smallest <NODE id="4766" />high precision DC drive systems<NODE id="4797" />, <NODE id="4799" />components<NODE id="4809" />, and <NODE id="4815" />controls<NODE id="4823" />. [18] <NODE id="4830" />Kinova<NODE id="4836" /> <NODE id="4837" />designs<NODE id="4844" /> and <NODE id="4849" />manufactures<NODE id="4861" /> <NODE id="4862" />robotics platforms<NODE id="4880" /> and <NODE id="4885" />components<NODE id="4895" /> that are simple, sexy and safe under two divisions: Assistive Robotics empowers people with disabilities to push beyond their current boundaries and limitations while Service Robotics empowers people in industry to interact with their environment more efficiently and safely. [19] <NODE id="5177" />Harmonic Drive<NODE id="5191" /> <NODE id="5192" />designs<NODE id="5199" /> and <NODE id="5204" />manufactures<NODE id="5216" /> <NODE id="5217" />high precision servo actuators<NODE id="5247" />, <NODE id="5249" />gearheads<NODE id="5258" /> and <NODE id="5263" />gear component sets<NODE id="5282" />. [20] ADVANCED Motion Controls servo drives are compatible with ANY Motor, ANY Controller, ANY Feedback and ANY I/O which means you don't have to get locked into any particular component manufacturer when designing your system. [21] For your convenience we have compiled this list of 3 rd party component manufacturers that are known to work with our servo drives. [21] We?ve been focusing on locomotion capability because that?s currently a missing component in robotics technology. [22] Coupled with the motivational component of training provided by a novel robotic gait training regimen, the H2 allows these participants to experience kinesthetic feedback of near-normal gait patterns in over ground walking. [23] I realize that you are probably looking for help on how to fix the gearbox but really if you are willing to spend 3k on the gearbox alone, a harmonic drive (works on a similar principle) might be a better option especially if you are building a robotic arm. [24] I remembered watching my manager present the new robotic arm link solid model that was going to be used to automate the drive axle assembly? with a mouse and trackpad in hand. [25] Computer includes the following components: Antec 380 watt Power Supply Unit Zip Disc Drive(no cable) 2 Hard Drives Formatted(OS install ready) include: Primary: Seagate Barracuda 80GB and Secondary:. more Western Digital 30 GB LG Lightscribe DvD Player/Rewriter Plextor CD rewriter(included but don't know if this works; powers up) ATX Case Everything is in working order. [26] POSSIBLY USEFUL Our high-precision, zero-backlash Harmonic Drive gears and Harmonic Planetary gears have, and continue to play critical roles in robotics, spaceflight applications, semiconductor manufacturing equipment, factory automation equipment, medical diagnostics and surgical robotics. [1] Harmonic Drive Group Companies in, Japan (Harmonic Drive Systems, Inc.) and Germany (Harmonic Drive AG) provide additional products. [1] The majority of the products sold by <NODE id="7295" />Harmonic Drive, LLC<NODE id="7314" /> are proudly made at our <NODE id="7339" />manufacturing facility<NODE id="7361" /> in <NODE id="7365" />Peabody<NODE id="7372" />, <NODE id="7374" />Massachusetts<NODE id="7387" />. [1] HPG-U1 Series – The HPG Harmonic Planetary gearhead has the same high performance specifications as our standard HPG series but with an input shaft for shaft couplings or for use with motor offset with a belt drive. [8] Available in a wide range of sizes, these zero backlash, 1 arc-min accuracy Harmonic Drive® gearheads enable design engineers to pass shafts, wires, tubing, or other components directly through the center of the gear. [2] Our high-precision, zero-backlash Harmonic Drive® gears and Harmonic Planetary® gears have, and continue to play critical roles in robotics, spaceflight applications, semiconductor manufacturing equipment, factory automation equipment, medical diagnostics and surgical robotics. [27] Through this period of time, Bob has been involved with numerous applications of Harmonic Drive products in the field of motion control including factory automation and robotics. [3] Ideally suited for robotic applications, the new CSG-LW and CSF-LW gearheads are 30% lighter than previous designs without reducing the torque rating or significantly changing interface dimensions. [2] He has served on the editorial boards of the IEEE Transactions on Robotics and Automation, IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering, ASME Journal of Mechanical Design, the ASME Journal of Mechanisms and Robotics and the Springer Tract in Advanced Robotics (STAR). [3] Richard Margolin Founder and Director of Engineering, RoboKind Robotics Mr. Margolin received his BS in mechanical engineering from the University of Texas at Arlington, and studied cognitive and computational neuroscience at Trinity College, Hartford, CT. Prior to founding RoboKind he was Director of Hardware for Hanson Robotics where he designed and built the world?s most lifelike interactive robots. [3] His technical focus is on integrated robotic systems including real-time sensor processing, mobility planning, and intuitive robot control. [3] His robotics and AI practice includes workplace safety standards, privacy requirements, robot collaboration and human displacement, anti-discrimination law, and legislative and regulatory developments. [3] Brian has held numerous product development positions in an array of industries, including biotech, pharma, and now robotics. [3] Through his passion for robotics, he continues to have an eye towards identifying new opportunity and driving business growth and requirements for product development. [3] In his role at MathWorks, he focuses on robotics product management, product marketing, industry marketing, and business development. [3] He focuses his practice on intellectual property counseling, particularly in the fields of alternative energy, medical devices, consumer products, and electromechanical engineering including robotics and control systems. [3] He also directs the robotics track of the AlphaLab Gear hardware startup accelerator, which he helped launch in partnership with Innovation Works. [3] Marco Mascorro CEO and CTO, Fellow Robots With 8+ years experience in robotics, Marco worked previously with BMW, Rolls-Royce and MINI, Singularity University, as well as in Japan to develop humanoid robots for rescue and exploration. [3] John holds a B.S. degree in mechanical engineering from the University at Buffalo and has publications in robotic manipulation, granular packing, learning algorithms, and machine design. [3] Jon started his career in robotics and prototype development for the machine design industry. [3] Prior to joining Neya, Mr. Stancil served as a project manager at QinetiQ North America where he lead the development of automated capability and control for several of the military?s fielded robotic EOD platforms including QinetiQ?s DragonRunner, TALON, and MAARS unmanned systems. [3] Ofer Shochet Entrepreneur, Technologist and Founder, Golem Robotics Dr. Ofer Shochet is an entrepreneur and a technology visionary, specializing in the development and successful implementation of future technologies in various companies at various fields of technologies. [3] He originated and co-chairs Littler?s Robotics, Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Automation Practice Group, providing legal advice and representation to the robotics industry, as well as employers deploying this technology in the workplace. [3] Jeff Burnstein President, Association for Advancing Automation (A3) Jeff Burnstein is the President of the Association for Advancing Automation (A3), the parent group of the Robotic Industries Association (RIA), AIA – Advancing Vision + Imaging, and the Motion Control Association (MCA). [3] Nuzha Yakoob Product Manager, Festo Corporation Nuzha Yakoob is currently the Product Manager for the electromechanical, motion control and robotics products and solutions from Festo. [3] Eric Foellmer Marketing Manager, Rethink Robotics Eric Foellmer is the Manager of Product Marketing and Marketing Communications at Rethink Robotics, a pioneer in the Collaborative Robotics space. [3] Yanliang is the first product manager of MathWorks Robotics System Toolbox released in March 2015. [3] The advantage of being very compact with a high torque to weight ratio – exactly what is needed for robotic arms. [4] Gearing specialist <NODE id="12621" />Harmonic Drive UK<NODE id="12638" /> has <NODE id="12643" />launched<NODE id="12651" /> a new series of extremely <NODE id="12678" />lightweight and compact gears<NODE id="12707" /> for the next generation of robots. [28] HPGP Series (High Torque Inline Planetary Gearheads) – <NODE id="12803" />Harmonic Drive<NODE id="12817" /> now <NODE id="12822" />offers<NODE id="12828" /> a NEW <NODE id="12835" />high-torque planetary gearhead<NODE id="12865" /> based upon our high precision <NODE id="12896" />HPG Harmonic Drive Planetary gears<NODE id="12930" />. [8] Precision Harmonic Drive gearing products are available with gear ratios from 3:1 to 45:1 with backlash maintained below 1 arc-min. High capacity output bearings are utilized for robust and accurate support of loads. [8] The CSD series, mastered light weight and compactness inherited the excellent performance of the Harmonic Drive precision strain wave gear and have fulfilled the market demand and achieved bold form. [8] Affiliated companies in, Japan (Harmonic Drive Systems, Inc.) and Germany (Harmonic Drive AG) provide additional manufacturing capabilities. [2] Infranor is a technology leader in motion control specializing in servo motors and drives. [3] WG is the wave generator (input); fs is the flexispline (output); N is the gear ratio, then the springs and dampers are deflection and friction losses at various stages in the harmonic drive. [6] Note that here I'm using the gear ratio as input : output, as harmonic drives are reducers. [6] Building on the success of Harmonic Drive LLCs current CSF, CSG, SHG, and SHF gear units, new lightweight versions were the next logical evolution of the product lines. [2] <NODE id="14066" />Harmonic Drive LLC<NODE id="14084" />, a <NODE id="14088" />leader in<NODE id="14097" /> <NODE id="14098" />high precision motion control<NODE id="14127" /> introduces lightweight versions of select <NODE id="14170" />gearhead products<NODE id="14187" />. [2] The new website is part of <NODE id="14220" />Harmonic Drive LLCs<NODE id="14239" /> <NODE id="14240" />launch<NODE id="14246" /> of the <NODE id="14254" />HPN Harmonic Planetary® gearhead Product Line<NODE id="14299" />. [27] The Product Selector Tool enables the design engineer to quickly filter through Harmonic Drive product specifications to find the right gearhead to connect to their servomotor. [27] Z. Hui, Z. Jun, S. Rui-Peng, and H. Hong, Tungsten containing hydrogenated DLC coatings on grease lubricated harmonic drive gear for space application, in 14th European Space Mechanisms and Tribology Symposium, 2011. [7] The new and completely redesigned website offers users a quick and easy way to choose the best Harmonic Drive LLC product for their application. [27] Harmonic Drive LLC provides high precision, high performance solutions to meet customer's mission critical application requirements. [2] Harmonic Drive Gearboxes feature precision strain wave gearing which provides zero backlash, high torque, compact size, and excellent positional accuracy. [8] INTRODUCTION Harmonic Drives (HD) are transmission mechanisms able to develop high ratios, providing a high positional precision, with relatively low weight/volume ratio, high torque capability and near zero backlash. [7] C. Kennedy and J. Desai, Modeling and control of the Mitsubishi PA-10 robot arm harmonic drive system, IEEE/ASME Trans. [7] A maximum torque of 3 Nm and efficiency higher than 75% at 3000 rpm were demonstrated WORKING PRINCIPLE The working principle of the MAGDRIVE is like that of the Nonius-Vernier motors as shown in Figure 1, as very similar to the one of a conventional harmonic drive. [7] In MAGDRIVE a rotational reduction, like in an harmonic drive, of prototype was designed comprising two elementary units with 42 teeth in the stator, 40 teeth in the output obtaining a reduction ratio of i -20 (reversal of the rotation sense) as it is shown in figure 2. [7] SHD Series (Integrated Output Bearing) – Harmonic Drive SHD Series gearheads inherits the excellent performance of the SHF/SHG Series. [8] CSG-2UH Series – Harmonic Drive CSG series gearheads are improved, high-torque versions of the CSF series. [8] Harmonic Drive LLC developed this new website for its Harmonic Planetary® and Harmonic Drive® Quick Connect™ gearheads (HPN, HPG, HPGP, CSF-GH, CSG-GH, HPF and HPG-U1). [27] Known for its expert engineering and manufacturing, Harmonic Drive LLC products are relied upon every day throughout the unmanned systems community. [2] These same improvements are being made in other areas, such as marine drives, mining and construction vehicles, hand tools, motorcycles and various industrial mechanisms such as machine tools, just to name a few. [28] We work with customers of all sizes to provide both standard product and custom-engineered Harmonic DriveTM servo actuators, gearheads and gear components. [5] Gear components and gearheads are available in many configurations including hollow shaft and differential gears as well as gearheads designed to quickly connect to any servomotor meet your specific application needs. However, the easiest way to reap the benefits of these high performance gears is to use one of our performance matched servo actuators. [5] A true visionary, Daniel has designed and developed several robots, including the Bear disaster recovery robot and the QC Bot logistics solution, as well as advanced automation components, such a biomemetic muscle and machine perception technology. [3] Based on the proven reliability of our SHD component sets, this gear unit has zero backlash, exceptional position accuracy and repeatability. [8] Because these components are designed to be an optimum performance match, our actuators have extremely high torque-to weight ratio and torque-to-volume ratios. [5] He was also developer and chairman of the RoboBusiness Conference and Exposition series, the RoboDevelopment Conference and Exposition series, the RoboNexus Conference and Exposition series, and the CES Robotics TechZone. [3] RoboUniverse News Stay up to date on the incredible field of robotics! Enter your email address below to receive daily news about the robotics industry and updates on the RoboUniverse conference series, including show dates, announcements, exclusive discounts, and more. [3] In his current position with RoboUniverse, Richard is a catalyst for building community and introducing RoboUniverse events as end user focused open format world-class robotics business, technology and applications-focused trade shows. [3] Carl Vause CEO, Soft Robotics Inc. <NODE id="18699" />Carl Vause<NODE id="18709" /> is <NODE id="18713" />CEO<NODE id="18716" /> of <NODE id="18720" />Soft Robotics Inc.<NODE id="18738" /> Prior to Soft Robotics, Carl held a variety of senior positions in technology and medical device companies, most recently Vice President of Marketing at OmniGuide Surgical. [3] Alan Ludwiszewski General Manager, Vecna, Inc. <NODE id="18963" />Alan Ludwiszewski<NODE id="18980" />, <NODE id="18982" />General Manager<NODE id="18997" /> for <NODE id="19002" />Vecna?s Robotic Logistics Solutions<NODE id="19037" />, has over 20 years? experience in bringing innovative, multidisciplinary technology solutions to market. [3] After his graduation, he worked as the General Manager of a technology transfer and investment company before joining Kinova in its early days to develop the service robotics market. [3] Aadhar holds a Bachelors of Science in Electrical Engineering from the Georgia Institute of Technology, where his focus was Artificial Intelligence and Robotics, and a Masters in Business Administration from the Harvard Business School. [3] Richard Erb Executive Director, RoboUniverse Conference and Expo Richard Erb brings more than 15 years of experience organizing trade shows in the telecom, information technology and robotics industries. [3] He is the founder of LocoRobo Inc., a technology non-profit whose mission is to advance programming education using robotics. [3] While it's primarily targeted at the robotic and semiconductor market, it will perform equally as well in other demanding high precision applications such as broadcast, aerospace and machine tools. [28] Ofer is the founder of Golem Robotics, a startup in the world of Robotics, a lecturer at the COMAS Design school, serves as a Board member at Velo 3D Inc. and is an advisory board member at RoboUniverse Expo. [3] Dr. Murphy is a member of the IEEE Robotics and Automation Society Administrative Committee and co-founded the Technical Committee on Safety Security and Rescue Robotics and its annual conference. [3] Nathan's interest in robotics includes both the life-improving aspects that automation and smarter systems bring, and the fun side of things such as flying quadcopters. [3] ROBO-STOX is the first and only index tracking the global robotics and automation market. [3] Bill Culley Co-Founder and President, Empire Robotics, Inc. Bill Culley is an entrepreneur and engineer, and is cofounder of Empire Robotics, the company commercializing one of the newest technologies poised to have a significant impact across industrial robotics. [3] Bill Torrens Clearpath Robotics Bill Torrens joined Clearpath Robotics in 2014, charged with the responsibility to identify and manage opportunities in Clearpath?s industrial materials handling business vertical. [3] Prior to joining RMT Robotics, Bill was a Regional Sales Manager with Dematic Corporation, helping to foster integrated conveyor, ASRS and AGV based projects for Dematic?s industrial clients. [3] One, lower costs and increased ease of use will spur significant growth in industrial robotics over the next decade, according to a study conducted by The Boston Consulting Group (BCG). [28] David Askey Co-Founder and Chief Business Development Officer, Energid David Askey is responsible for strategic initiatives, guidance, and market development of vision-based robotic systems. [3] Brian Stancil Director Robotic Systems, Neya Systems Brian has spent the last decade developing autonomous capability for a wide range of unmanned ground vehicles from man-transportable systems to large multiple-ton platforms. [3] One of its main objectives is to turn magnetic harmonic drives useful for a wide range os space applications in different temperature regimes. [7] Bob Mullins VP of Sales, Harmonic Drive, LLC Bob started his career with Harmonic Drive as a Sales Engineer in covering the Midwest and for the past ten years has held a management role at the company?s headquarters in the Boston area. [3] Here are some great design tips for selecting harmonic drives, too, if anyone's interested. [6] The objective of the MAGDRIVE project, funded by the EU Space FP7, is to design, build and test a new concept of contactless harmonic drive. [7] J. Sensinger and R. Weir, Improved torque fidelity in harmonic drive sensors through the union of two existing strategies, IEEE/ASME Trans. [7] The system is composed of a centered magnetic harmonic drive whose corresponding floating axles are supported by two pairs of superconducting magnetic bearings. [7] The maximum tested input speed was 3000 rpm -six times the previous existing record for harmonic drives at cryogenic temperature. [7] Harmonic drives were presumably used in the wheels of the NASA rover. [4] Targeting the semiconductor electronics market, the new CSD Component Set is equipped with a heavy-duty cross roller bearing to deliver high payload performance in environments with limited space. [28] MAG SOAR Company is already providing contactless mechanical components for space applications able to operate in a wide range of temperatures. [7] Harmonic Drive LLC Item Model Drive Stroke (mm) Maximum Driving Force (N) Resolution (m) Maximum Speed (mm/s) Repeatability Outside Dimensions (mm) Total length (mm) LBC-25A-5D6K Brushless Motor 50 6000 0.32 20 5m or less/50mm stroke ?136 353 LBC-25A-5D12K Brushless Motor 50 12000 0.16 10 Precision Linear Actuators LBC Series ?LBC Series Ratings The precision lead screw provides positioning accuracy in the micron range with sub- micron repeatability. [10] The SHA-CG offers improved rotary positioning accuracy and a high precision output with surface runout less than 10 microns. ? Alternative to Direct Drive Motors ? High Accuracy Output Bearing ? Available with Mounting Base ? High Torque ? Hollow Shaft Design ? Compact ? Available in 4 sizes Hollow Shaft Brushless Actuators SHA-CG Series The table shows typical output values of actuators. [10] The RSF Mini Series is designed to operate with a wide range of third party drivers as well as Harmonic Drive LLC?s DCJ Series, DDP Series, DEP Series, and HA680 drivers. ? Exceptional positional accuracy ? Compact design ?RSF Mini Series Ratings Notes: 1 The table shows output values of the actuator. 2 All specifications are applicable for actuators mounted on an aluminum heat sink of size: 150 x 150 x 6(mm). 3 Values for saturated actuator temperature. [10] Harmonic Drive LLC 14 Brushless Actuators RSF Supermini Series These extremely small servo actuators utilize zero backlash Harmonic Drive precision gears, a brushless servo motor and an incremental encoder to deliver precision motion control. [10] Harmonic Drive LLC 16 Brushless Actuators RSF Series The RSF series is compact and includes high torque AC servo actuators with high rotational accuracy, a shaft output combining Harmonic Drive strain wave gearing for precision control and an AC servomotor. [10] ?SHA-CG Series Ratings SHA-CG high precision actuators are a great alternative for direct drive motors. [10] SHA-CG actuators offer direct drive motor performance in a compact, significantly lighter package. [10] As the trend towards developing more compact robots gains momentum, these Harmonic Drive® units are uniquely positioned to provide designers the affordability and flexibility to meet the increasing demands and performance expectations posed by the robotics industry. [29] Our high-precision, zero-backlash Harmonic Drive® gears and Harmonic Planetary ® gears have, and continue to play critical roles in robotics, spaceflight applications, semiconductor manufacturing equipment, factory automation equipment, medical diagnostics and surgical robotics. [29] Excellent Technology for Evolving Industries Harmonic Drive actuators utilize high-precision, zero-backlash Harmonic Drive precision gears and play critical roles in robotics, semiconductor manufacturing equipment, factory automation equipment, medical diagnostics and surgical robot- ics. [10] Below are links and videos compiled to give persons involved with robot building and/or investigating careers involving robotics technology a list of internet resources that will help them achieve their goals. [30] MASTER Robotics offers Preventive Maintenance service for your robots at very reasonable rates(volume discounts are available when 24 or more robots are scheduled for the same period). [31] MASTER Robotics – Robot repair and refurbishment You are using an outdated browser. [31] The consumer sector is also growing: robotic vacuums and personal/social robots are examples. [11] In 2013 he co-founded <NODE id="27103" />Robo-stox? LLC<NODE id="27117" /> (renamed to <NODE id="27130" />ROBO-Global<NODE id="27141" />) which <NODE id="27149" />developed<NODE id="27158" /> a tracking index for the robotics industry: the <NODE id="27207" />ROBO-Global? Robotics &amp; Automation Index<NODE id="27247" />. [11] <NODE id="27254" />Harmonic Drive LLC<NODE id="27272" /> <NODE id="27273" />offers<NODE id="27279" /> <NODE id="27280" />precision gears<NODE id="27295" />, <NODE id="27297" />gearheads<NODE id="27306" />, <NODE id="27308" />servo actuators<NODE id="27323" /> and <NODE id="27328" />motion control systems<NODE id="27350" />. [29] Harmonic Drive LLC15 Brushless Actuators These brushless servo actuators utilize zero backlash Harmonic Drive precision gears for precise motion control. [10] <NODE id="27516" />Harmonic Drive LLC<NODE id="27534" />, a <NODE id="27538" />leader<NODE id="27544" /> in <NODE id="27548" />high precision motion control<NODE id="27577" /> <NODE id="27578" />introduces<NODE id="27588" /> new, ultra-flat, <NODE id="27606" />zero-backlash gear unit<NODE id="27629" />. [29] <NODE id="27636" />Harmonic Drive LLC<NODE id="27654" /> (Silver Sponsor) is the <NODE id="27679" />leader<NODE id="27685" /> in the <NODE id="27693" />design<NODE id="27699" />, <NODE id="27701" />development<NODE id="27712" />, and <NODE id="27718" />manufacturing<NODE id="27731" /> of zero backlash, <NODE id="27750" />high precision motion control products<NODE id="27788" />. [12] The Machine Tool, Mechanical Engineering, and Medical Technology team, which consists of Thomas Reuber, Eric Schwenk, Sebastian Finhold, Reinhard Garstecki, and Friedrich Mann, specialises in drive solutions for a wide range of machine tools, including medical applications which require maximum precision. [9] Aerotech Motion Control Systems – Manufacturers of motion controllers, stages, drives, and positioning systems for applications worldwide. [30] Harmonic Drive LLC35 ?FB, FR Series Ratings FB FR Pancake Pancake gears consist of four main parts: Wave Generator, Flexspline, Dynamic Spline, and Circular Spline. [10] Question regarding Ultra-Flat, Zero-Backlash Gear by Harmonic Drive LLC. [29] Please contact Harmonic Drive LLC, to inquire about use with different environmental conditions. 4 Value after angular position of the HA-770 servo driver is corrected. 5 All parts, except the rotary sliding parts (oil seal), of the actuators are protected against solid bodies of superior dimensions to 1mm, and against the water sprays. [10] The RSF Supermini series is designed to operate with a wide range of third party drivers as well as Harmonic Drive LLC?s DCJ Series, DDP Series, DEP Series, and HA680 drivers. [10] Harmonic Drive products are extensively used in industrial robot, mobile robot and aerospace applications, including the Apollo Lunar Rover, Mars Exploration Rovers and the Mars Science Laboratory. [12] Complete with a housing and precision output bearing, Harmonic Drive ®gear units are lightweight and extremely compact. [29] Simplicity Gear Unit Non-housed component gearing combined with a precision cross roller output bearing. [10] CSG-2UH is a high torque housed component gear set combined with a precision cross roller output bearing flange. [10] Structure of Harmonic Drive component product Flexspline Wave Generator Circular Spline Circular Spline Flexspline Tooth engagement The strain wave gear has a unique tooth engagement which results in a Zero-backlash gear mesh that provides high positional accuracy and high torque with a compact form factor. [10] Silk Hat – High Torque SHG Series SHG is a high torque, silk hat, component set gear available with a large hollow through bore. [10] ?Dimensions HarmonicDriveComponentSet SHFSeries ?SHF Series Ratings SHF is a silk hat, component set gear available with a large hollow through bore. [10] Component Gear Sets Consisting of three basic components: flexspline, circular spline and wave generator; component gear sets offer ultimate design flexibility and can be tightly integrated in equipment sub-structures. [10] Harmonic Drive? servo actuators, gearheads, and gear components are very compact, yet deliver high torque and are capable of 30 arc-second position accuracy and +/- 5 arc-second repeatability. [12] Although a few of the startups are attempting to make reduction gears and other similar devices, the lack of these component manufacturers in China may put a cap on how low costs can go and on how much can be done in-country for the time being. [11] Chinese companies that manufacture robots and their components are also growing. [11] Send your robot component repair to us with complete confidence knowing you are getting the best value for your money. [31] Their generous donation of precision aluminum welding services is an essential aspect of our rover, and provides us with the ability to make lightweight and strong components in configurations that would otherwise not be possible. [12] We have been able to identify 47 Chinese companies and 5 startups that call themselves industrial robot makers, and another 26 which offer to provide integration services and speciality equipment. 34 more provide ancillary services, sensors and components to the robot makers. [11] MASTER Robotics provides quick, reliable repair of any part of your industrial robot. [31] Whether you are looking for new or used robotic spare parts, we can quickly provide you with a quote for even the hardest to find equipment. [31] That figure represents more than the total global sales of all types of industrial robots in 2014! The Chinese government is encouraging the development of an in-country robotics industry because currently 3/4 of all robots purchased are from off-shore companies (albeit some with manufacturing and assembly facilities in China). [11] In addition to growth in Chinese industrial robotics, progress in the service robotics sector is also healthy. [11] Overall, 107 Chinese companies are involved in industrial robotics. [11] NASA is an organization that works in a multitude of Science and Technology fields, Including: Aeronautics, Human Exploration and Operations science, Space Technology, and Robotics. [13] Dielectric strength: AC 1500V/1min. Insulation class: Class B Recommended Driver DC24V DCJ-055-09/DDP-090-09/DEP-090-09 DCJ-055-18/DDP-090-18/ DEP-090-18 DDP-090-36/DEP-090-36 AC100/200 RTL-230-18/REL-230-18 Harmonic Drive LLC 8 w w w. [10] Harmonic Drive LLC continues to develop enabling technologies for the evolving motion control market, which drives the pace of global innovation. [10] Pooling our technical knowledge means Harmonic Drive is ideally positioned to provide our customers across Europe with quality technical advice specific to their sector, said <NODE id="33097" />Graham Mackrell<NODE id="33112" />, <NODE id="33114" />managing director<NODE id="33131" /> of <NODE id="33135" />Harmonic Drive UK<NODE id="33152" />. This means that we are able to quickly identify the best solutions for our customers? needs, helping them to succeed. [9] High precision gearing expert, Harmonic Drive, has strengthened its organisational structure to support its customers with the best possible technical information. [9] The key focus of the Optics and Precision Engineering team is the move towards smaller high precision components, which places more demands on accurate machines and manufacturing. [9] The unit refurbishment consist of greater study and the possible replacement of functioning components that we suspect could fail due to age or because they are functioning only within the minimum specifications. [31] Leader Harmonious Drive Systems Co., Ltd.: The company participated in compiling national standards – Robot Harmonic Gear Reducer, and harmonic gear reducer manufactured by the company has been adopted by SIASUN Robot &amp; Automation Co., Ltd. and other companies. [32] Harmonic gear speed reducer in aerospace, energy, shipbuilding, machinery bionics, ordnance, machine tool, instrument, electronic equipment, mining and metallurgy, transportation, heavy machinery, petroleum chemical engineering machinery, textile machinery, agricultural machinery and medical devices has been more and more widely used, especially in the high dynamic performance of the servo system, the harmonic gear drive is showing its superiority. [14] The eccentric shaft is connected to the motor input and drives the wobble gear against the stationary internal gear. [15] Introduc- tion of these compact drives help in reduction of pow- er input to be supplied to the gear system. [15] January 1, 2006 Hamonake And the above introduction Nabtesco The United States subsidiary in Massachusetts established a joint venture company Drive L.L.C. Harmonic. [14] Sounds like a big industry category, in fact Drive harmonic is Drive Systems Inc. Harmonic trademark. [14] Cycloid drives should be considered for applications in robots and aerospace applications, where the need for precision and applications of back drivability are important. [15] ?The input and output shafts are coaxial hence drive becomes compact compared to other high ratio, high torque drives. [15] Complete with a housing and precision output bearing, Harmonic Drive gear units are lightweight and extremely compact. [33] Three advantages are associated with this solution: (1) the first advantage is the cost, as these reducers can be machined at a fraction of the price of a harmonic drive; (2) secondly, it is compact; and (3) finally, the gear housing and teeth can be machined directly into the main joint structure, which leads into an easier incorporation into the overall design. [34] Advantages of cycloidal and harmonic drive over con- ventional drives are ?Since power is transmitted through multiple teeth engagement harmonic gear drive offers high output torque capacity than conventional planetary gear drive having nearly twice its size and thrice its weight. [15] An example of a head designed primarily to look lifelike is by Hanson Robotics who developed a very realistic head used in the 'Albert' version of HUBO humanoid robot ( Oh et al., 2006 ), which utilizes a high number of servo motors used to mimic human muscles and deform its rubbery skin so the head is able to display emotions as well as to articulate the mouth when it speaks. [34] 'Open robot control software: the OROCOS project,' in Robotics and Automation, 2001. [34] 'Robonaut 2-the first humanoid robot in space,' in Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2011 IEEE International Conference on (Shanghai: IEEE), 2178–2183. [34] 'Development of a new humanoid robot WABIAN-2,' in Proceedings 2006 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, 2006. [34] 'Player 2.0: toward a practical robot programming framework,' in Proceedings of the Australasian Conference on Robotics and Automation (ACRA 2005) (Sydney: ARAA), 145. [34] We settled on ROS as it has a big growing community, built in support for OpenCV ( Bradski and Kaehler, 2008 ), is natively supported in Matlab, has a large selection of modules that we felt benefited Herbert, and has been shown to work successfully on numerous humanoid robots, such as NAO ( Gouaillier et al., 2009 ), Robonaut 2 ( Diftler et al., 2011 ), and the REEM ( Tellez et al., 2008 ) series of humanoids by PAL Robotics. [34] In comparison to other robots, the development of humanoid robotic systems creates unique electrical challenges. [34] ''Mask-bot 2i': an active customisable robotic head with interchangeable face,' in Proceedings of IEEE-RAS International Conference on Humanoid Robots (Humanoids 2012) (Osaka: IEEE), 520–525. [34] Unlike other well-developed robotic systems, like wheeled robots where the controllers and sensors can easily be taken off-the-shelf and then integrated, developers of humanoid systems place a higher priority on compactness and weight. [34] Let Chronos and OPT help meet your goals for size and weight reduction, consistent with high performance, with a robust mechanical solution for your robotic application. [16] 'Maccepa 2.0: adjustable compliant actuator with stiffening characteristic for energy efficient hopping,' in Robotics and Automation, 2009. [34] 'Mechatronic design of NAO humanoid,' in Conference on Robotics and Automation (Kobe: IEEE), 769–774. [34] Robotics and Automation Companies may rely on a combination of patents, copyrights, trademarks and trade secret laws to establish and protect their proprietary rights in their products and technologies. [35] Robotics and Automation Companies, especially smaller, start-up companies, tend to be more volatile than securities of companies that do not rely heavily on technology. [35] 'The development of Honda humanoid robot,' in Proceedings of the 1998 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (Leuven: IEEE), 1321–1326. [34] 'Versatile modular electronics for rapid design and development of humanoid robotic subsystems,' in Advanced Intelligent Mechatronics (AIM), 2014 IEEE/ASME International Conference on (Besancon: IEEE), 735–741. [34] Whereas other robotic heads have been designed with the main aim of looking as lifelike as possible, so that the texture of the skin and the mimicking of the muscles are the most important aspect of their design. [34] 'MABEL, a new robotic bipedal walker and runner,' in American Control Conference, 2009. [34] 'Design of the robot-cub (iCub) head,' in Robotics and Automation, 2006. [34] These risks associated with investments in Robotics and Automation Companies include, but are not limited to, small or limited markets for such securities, changes in business cycles, world economic growth, technological progress, rapid obsolescence, and government regulation. [35] To overcome the need for complex mechanical structures to display emotions and mouth movements, there is an emerging type of robotic head which uses the concept of displaying an avatar instead of relying on a complicated mechanical mechanism. [34] According to the robotics industry experts Luo Baihui introduced in 2013 the Chinese market, sales of industrial robots near the Taiwan Taiwan, accounting for global sales of 1/5, with a total sales of more than Japan, ranking first in the world. [14] NEW YORK, March 4, 2015 /PRNewswire/ - Speed reducer is one of three core parts of industrial robot, along with two others (drive and control device, servomotor), accounting for about 36% of the industrial robot's total cost. [32] The input shaft drives an eccentric bearing that in turn drives the cycloidal disk in an eccentric, cycloidal motion. [34] As discussed above, each drive can be designed inde- pendently for various applications. [15] Table 1 Comparison of various drives 1 Excellent, 2 Good and 3 Average RESULTS AND DISCUSSIONS: The above drives have been designed to check the compatibility of the current project. [15] Two core mechanical module types make up the main structural elements of Herbert: (1) small compact mechanical drive modules and (2) compliant mechanical drive modules. [34] Herbert’s mass is very evenly distributed symmetrically apart for his chest where the CoM is to the right by 12 mm due to the chest pitch joint drive mechanism not being centered due to mechanical constraints. [34] The design is based around the ball screw that drives the pulley belt. [34] ?High speed – reduction ratios from 50: 1 to 6500: 1 can be achieved using these drives. [15] Using cycloid and harmonic drives, the gear reduction ratios of upto 1:6500 (max.) are attainable. [15] Harmonic drive reducer (gear drive harmonic) Is a kind of flexible gear generated by the wave generator controllable elastic deformation, and with the rigid gear meshing, from the transmission of motion and power transmission system. [14] Present day technologies available for gear transmission are: conventional gear drives (spur gear, helical gear etc), Harmonic Drive, 2- stage Hypo- cycloid Drive, single-stage cycloid drive. [15] You use one set of gear teeth to record your PEC, but when you actually use the mount you are using a different set of teeth to guide! When the Chronos Mount is permanently mounted at a site, the same Harmonic Drive teeth are always in the same position for a given optical line of sight of your payload. [16] Harmonic Drive gearing has zero backlash, and they keep a full one third of their gear teeth engaged at all times, whereas worm drives can only keep a maximum of three teeth engaged at any one time. [16] In 1960 the United States USM company for the first time Harmonic drive reducer successfully put into use, and later Kyohko Hasegawa gear (Gear Works Hasegawa, Ltd.) obtained the production license of USM. October 1970, Kyohko Hasegawa and USM each invested 50%, in Tokyo have set up a Drive Systems Inc. Harmonic, Chinese Translation Hammer Nako. [14] This works in a similar way to a harmonic drive but with the main difference that the harmonic drive has a flexible toothed spline that rotates and the cycloidal reducer has a solid gear center. [34] All Chronos mount models come with HPO (High Precision Output), which incorporates very high resolution glass disk incremental encoders located on the payload end of the harmonic drive mount system. [16] We set out to replace the Harmonic drives that are used in most high-performance electric humanoid robots, such as HUBO ( Oh et al., 2006 ), HRP-series ( Kaneko et al., 2008 ), TORO ( Ott et al., 2010 ), iCub ( Parmiggiani et al., 2012 ), and ARMAR-4 ( Asfour et al., 2013 ). [34] Does it sound like the harmonic could be damaged an then work for 5 months? There is a high sensitivity collision detect on the robot but I dont know how effective this is at actually protecting the robots components, Id apreciate your comments. [36] 'RT-middleware: distributed component middleware for RT (robot technology),' in Intelligent Robots and Systems, 2005. (IROS 2005). 2005 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on (Alberta: IEEE), 3933–3938. [34] The cost of the actuation mechanism is one of the most costly components on any humanoid robot. [34] China is expected to become the worlds largest robot market in 2016, the amount will be more than 150 thousand units. even Nabtesco Plans to invest nearly 5 billion yen in new factories in China, starting in 2016, put into operation the core components of industrial robots, planned annual output of 100 thousand units, up to 200 thousand units in 2020. [14] Many applications call for the need of lighter mechanical components example UAVs, aerospace ve- hicles, kitchen Aid equipment, house hold machines, etc. Apart from these applications, the reduction of size of gear box results in lower payload of aerospace vehicles, such as rockets, drones, aircrafts, etc.While considering weight reduction from a machine, the re- duction of weight contributed by gears will be a huge contribution. [15] An option provides housings and components that have been built with pinned-in-place assembly techniques for the most demanding customer's applications. [16] To achieve this, we aimed to place the heaviest components of each limb, which in this case are the motors, as high as we could within the limb. [34] Figure 4 B shows different designs that have been tested in CAD using the finite element method (FEM) to compute the theoretical compliance as well as the strength of the component. [34] As we have stated, one of the main components of the head is the LED projector C112 (Acer Inc.), which is 70 ANSI lumens, has a contrast ratio of 1000:1 and weighs 138 g. [34] Considering the elastic effects of bolted joints and the motion disturbances, this paper investigates the dynamic and stability of the flexible CRA. With the kinetic energy and potential energy of the comprising components, Hamilton’s variational principle and Duhamel integral are utilized to derive the dynamic equation and vibration differential equation. [37] There are four main hardware components used to achieve this: (1) the projector; (2) the optics used to modify the light beam; and (3) the mask (4) the 3 DOF neck. [34] All these supporting components have been important in the development of the complete system. [34] If I am asking the robot to move to one position (J(1) 100% CNT100) and then move away from it in the exact opposite direction (and with same 100% CNT100 command) would it be advisable to use an ACC command of, say 50, to slow it down (protect mechanical components) or should the standard acceleration be okay on the robots mechanical parts? Thanks. [36] The harmonic drives especially can be rec- ommended for those applications in which size, iner- tia, and efficiency take precedence over backlash and torque ripple. [15] Weir, Improved Torque Fidelity in Harmonic Drive Sensors through the Union of Two Existing Strategies, IEEE/ASME Transactions on Mechatronics, vol. 11, pp. 457-461, 2006. [15] For our compact design, we elected to use acycloidal reducer instead of the standard method of using harmonic drives. [34] The main joint mechanism is compact and cheap while at the same time being functionally similar to the classical harmonic drive or planetary gearbox design. [34] To verify that the compact module was a good low-cost replacement for harmonic drives it was tested using a simple PD controller controlling the desired angular position of the waist. [34] Among the ones available, widely used drives are: single stage cycloidal drive, 2-stage cycloidal drive, harmonic drive Single stage cycloidal drive: A single-stage cycloid disk in a cycloid drive has Z1 lobes and its housing is made of Z2 rollers, where Z2 is an in- teger higher than Z1. [15] The harmonic drives used on LR mates are very accurate but not very robust. [36] <NODE id="47955" />China<NODE id="47960" /> now has no manufacturers that can provide mass-produced and reliable industrial robot speed reducers, and the market is almost completely dominated by international giants like <NODE id="48138" />Nabtesco<NODE id="48146" />, <NODE id="48148" />Harmonic Drive<NODE id="48162" /> and <NODE id="48167" />Sumitomo Heavy Industries<NODE id="48192" />, of which <NODE id="48203" />Nabtesco<NODE id="48211" /> is the world's largest <NODE id="48235" />robot RV reducer<NODE id="48251" /> <NODE id="48252" />manufacturer<NODE id="48264" /> with a market share of around 60%, and <NODE id="48304" />Harmonic Drive<NODE id="48318" /> is the largest <NODE id="48334" />robot harmonic reducer<NODE id="48356" /> <NODE id="48357" />producer<NODE id="48365" /> in the world, holding a market share of 16%. [32] Harmonic Drive gearing is an integral part of the design of the Rovers on Mars, and they keep the adaptive optics aligned on large telescopes atop Mauna Kea, Hawaii. [16] The simplicity in design and minimal number of parts make the 2-stage cycloidal drive easy to assemble and reduces the negative effects on gear contact due to the stack up of manufacturing errors. [15] Neither cycloid nor harmonic drives are universally superior for all applications and conditions. [15] The Chronos HD32HPO ruggedized equatorial mount uses custom High-tech harmonic drives instead of traditional worm or spur drives for consistently smooth operation, no meridian flip, zero backlash, and high torque operation. [16] The Chronos mount is an innovative high-performance mechanical mount system incorporating Harmonic Drive gearing. [16] Custom designed Harmonic Drive assemblies, made to ChronosMount specs, are at the heart of the Chronos mount. [16] When high precision and repeatability are required, harmonic drives are a no brainer when compared to conventional worm-and-wheel and spur gearing. [16] In combination with carefully designed tooth profiles, the 2-stage cycloidal drive is designed to provide high stiffness, low power loss, nearly zero backlash and lost motion, and smooth and quiet opera- tion. [15] While typical cycloidal drives are claimed to provide for high load-carrying capacity, quiet operation, and shock load resistance, they suffer from relatively heavy weight and high stiction due to many contact elements and bear- ings, when designed for sizes higher than 40 cm. [15] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (46 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) Related Related Articles
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/79afe6f6-054f-367a-a6b6-96a78e174fc8" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T21:18:37Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:21:14.25Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/hamonic-drive-robotics-components/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="292" endPos="311" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive, LLC" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="312" endPos="321" type="provide-type" surface="engineers" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="326" endPos="338" type="provide-type" surface="manufactures" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="339" endPos="364" type="product-class" surface="precision servo actuators" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="366" endPos="375" type="product-class" surface="gearheads" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="380" endPos="399" type="product-class" surface="gear component sets" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="574" endPos="583" type="organization-company" surface="Energid?s" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="584" endPos="598" type="product" surface="Actin software" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="858" endPos="872" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="873" endPos="880" type="provide-type" surface="designs" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="885" endPos="897" type="provide-type" surface="manufactures" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="948" endPos="953" type="product-class" surface="motor" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="955" endPos="962" type="product-class" surface="encoder" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="964" endPos="971" type="product-class" surface="gearing" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="976" endPos="1003" type="product-class" surface="cross-roller output bearing" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="1469" endPos="1481" type="person" surface="Arron Acosta" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="1489" endPos="1492" type="org-position" surface="CEO" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="1511" endPos="1524" type="organization-company" surface="Rise Robotics" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="1591" endPos="1609" type="product-class" surface="robotic components" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2165" endPos="2183" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive LLC" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="2250" endPos="2282" type="product" surface="Harmonic DriveTM servo actuators" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="2284" endPos="2293" type="product-class" surface="gearheads" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="2298" endPos="2317" type="product-class" surface="gear component sets" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="3222" endPos="3252" type="organization-company" surface="M axon Precision Mo tors, Inc." />
<Entity id="24" startPos="3266" endPos="3278" type="provide-type" surface="manufacturer" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="3283" endPos="3291" type="provide-type" surface="supplier" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="3295" endPos="3324" type="product-class" surface="precision DC drive components" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="3331" endPos="3349" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive LLC" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="3440" endPos="3455" type="product-class" surface="servo actuators" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="3457" endPos="3466" type="product-class" surface="gearheads" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="3471" endPos="3490" type="product-class" surface="gear component sets" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="4391" endPos="4393" type="organization-company" surface="TQ" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="4441" endPos="4447" type="product-class" surface="eBikes" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="4533" endPos="4535" type="organization-company" surface="TQ" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="4536" endPos="4544" type="provide-type" surface="develops" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="4549" endPos="4557" type="provide-type" surface="produces" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="4576" endPos="4655" type="product-class" surface="drive systems and components for Pedelecs, E-Bikes and electric cargo vehicles." />
<Entity id="37" startPos="4678" endPos="4688" type="location" surface="Clearwater" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="4690" endPos="4697" type="location" surface="Florida" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="4699" endPos="4711" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO Inc." />
<Entity id="40" startPos="4719" endPos="4733" type="location" surface="North American" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="4734" endPos="4740" type="trigger" surface="source" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="4766" endPos="4797" type="product-class" surface="high precision DC drive systems" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="4799" endPos="4809" type="product-class" surface="components" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="4815" endPos="4823" type="product-class" surface="controls" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="4830" endPos="4836" type="organization-company" surface="Kinova" />
<Entity id="46" startPos="4837" endPos="4844" type="provide-type" surface="designs" />
<Entity id="47" startPos="4849" endPos="4861" type="provide-type" surface="manufactures" />
<Entity id="48" startPos="4862" endPos="4880" type="product-class" surface="robotics platforms" />
<Entity id="49" startPos="4885" endPos="4895" type="product-class" surface="components" />
<Entity id="50" startPos="5177" endPos="5191" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive" />
<Entity id="51" startPos="5192" endPos="5199" type="provide-type" surface="designs" />
<Entity id="52" startPos="5204" endPos="5216" type="provide-type" surface="manufactures" />
<Entity id="53" startPos="5217" endPos="5247" type="product-class" surface="high precision servo actuators" />
<Entity id="54" startPos="5249" endPos="5258" type="product-class" surface="gearheads" />
<Entity id="55" startPos="5263" endPos="5282" type="product-class" surface="gear component sets" />
<Entity id="56" startPos="7295" endPos="7314" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive, LLC" />
<Entity id="57" startPos="7339" endPos="7361" type="facility-type" surface="manufacturing facility" />
<Entity id="58" startPos="7365" endPos="7372" type="location" surface="Peabody" />
<Entity id="59" startPos="7374" endPos="7387" type="location" surface="Massachusetts" />
<Entity id="60" startPos="12621" endPos="12638" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive UK" />
<Entity id="61" startPos="12643" endPos="12651" type="trigger" surface="launched" />
<Entity id="62" startPos="12678" endPos="12707" type="product-class" surface="lightweight and compact gears" />
<Entity id="63" startPos="12803" endPos="12817" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive" />
<Entity id="64" startPos="12822" endPos="12828" type="trigger" surface="offers" />
<Entity id="65" startPos="12835" endPos="12865" type="product-class" surface="high-torque planetary gearhead" />
<Entity id="66" startPos="12896" endPos="12930" type="product" surface="HPG Harmonic Drive Planetary gears" />
<Entity id="67" startPos="14066" endPos="14084" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive LLC" />
<Entity id="68" startPos="14088" endPos="14097" type="trigger" surface="leader in" />
<Entity id="69" startPos="14098" endPos="14127" type="product-class" surface="high precision motion control" />
<Entity id="70" startPos="14170" endPos="14187" type="product-class" surface="gearhead products" />
<Entity id="71" startPos="14220" endPos="14239" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive LLCs" />
<Entity id="72" startPos="14240" endPos="14246" type="trigger" surface="launch" />
<Entity id="73" startPos="14254" endPos="14299" type="product" surface="HPN Harmonic Planetary® gearhead Product Line" />
<Entity id="74" startPos="18699" endPos="18709" type="person" surface="Carl Vause" />
<Entity id="75" startPos="18713" endPos="18716" type="org-position" surface="CEO" />
<Entity id="76" startPos="18720" endPos="18738" type="organization-company" surface="Soft Robotics Inc." />
<Entity id="77" startPos="18963" endPos="18980" type="person" surface="Alan Ludwiszewski" />
<Entity id="78" startPos="18982" endPos="18997" type="org-position" surface="General Manager" />
<Entity id="79" startPos="19002" endPos="19037" type="organization-company" surface="Vecna?s Robotic Logistics Solutions" />
<Entity id="80" startPos="27103" endPos="27117" type="organization-company" surface="Robo-stox? LLC" />
<Entity id="81" startPos="27130" endPos="27141" type="organization-company" surface="ROBO-Global" />
<Entity id="82" startPos="27149" endPos="27158" type="provide-type" surface="developed" />
<Entity id="83" startPos="27207" endPos="27247" type="product" surface="ROBO-Global? Robotics &amp; Automation Index" />
<Entity id="84" startPos="27254" endPos="27272" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive LLC" />
<Entity id="85" startPos="27273" endPos="27279" type="trigger" surface="offers" />
<Entity id="86" startPos="27280" endPos="27295" type="product-class" surface="precision gears" />
<Entity id="87" startPos="27297" endPos="27306" type="product-class" surface="gearheads" />
<Entity id="88" startPos="27308" endPos="27323" type="product-class" surface="servo actuators" />
<Entity id="89" startPos="27328" endPos="27350" type="product-class" surface="motion control systems" />
<Entity id="90" startPos="27516" endPos="27534" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive LLC" />
<Entity id="91" startPos="27538" endPos="27544" type="trigger" surface="leader" />
<Entity id="92" startPos="27548" endPos="27577" type="product-class" surface="high precision motion control" />
<Entity id="93" startPos="27578" endPos="27588" type="trigger" surface="introduces" />
<Entity id="94" startPos="27606" endPos="27629" type="product-class" surface="zero-backlash gear unit" />
<Entity id="95" startPos="27636" endPos="27654" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive LLC" />
<Entity id="96" startPos="27679" endPos="27685" type="trigger" surface="leader" />
<Entity id="97" startPos="27693" endPos="27699" type="provide-type" surface="design" />
<Entity id="98" startPos="27701" endPos="27712" type="provide-type" surface="development" />
<Entity id="99" startPos="27718" endPos="27731" type="provide-type" surface="manufacturing" />
<Entity id="100" startPos="27750" endPos="27788" type="product-class" surface="high precision motion control products" />
<Entity id="101" startPos="33097" endPos="33112" type="person" surface="Graham Mackrell" />
<Entity id="102" startPos="33114" endPos="33131" type="org-position" surface="managing director" />
<Entity id="103" startPos="33135" endPos="33152" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive UK" />
<Entity id="104" startPos="47955" endPos="47960" type="location" surface="China" />
<Entity id="105" startPos="48138" endPos="48146" type="organization-company" surface="Nabtesco" />
<Entity id="106" startPos="48148" endPos="48162" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive" />
<Entity id="107" startPos="48167" endPos="48192" type="organization-company" surface="Sumitomo Heavy Industries" />
<Entity id="108" startPos="48203" endPos="48211" type="organization-company" surface="Nabtesco" />
<Entity id="109" startPos="48235" endPos="48251" type="product-class" surface="robot RV reducer" />
<Entity id="110" startPos="48252" endPos="48264" type="provide-type" surface="manufacturer" />
<Entity id="111" startPos="48304" endPos="48318" type="organization-company" surface="Harmonic Drive" />
<Entity id="112" startPos="48334" endPos="48356" type="product-class" surface="robot harmonic reducer" />
<Entity id="113" startPos="48357" endPos="48365" type="provide-type" surface="producer" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="114" NAME="CompanyFacility">
<Entity id="56" label="company" />
<Entity id="58" label="location" />
<Entity id="59" label="location" />
<Entity id="57" label="facility" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="115" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="5" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="2" label="type" />
<Entity id="1" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="116" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="7" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="117" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="13" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="product" />
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
<Entity id="10" label="type" />
<Entity id="9" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="118" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="18" label="product" />
<Entity id="17" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="119" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="22" label="product" />
<Entity id="21" label="product" />
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="19" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="120" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="26" label="product" />
<Entity id="23" label="company" />
<Entity id="25" label="type" />
<Entity id="24" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="121" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="28" label="product" />
<Entity id="29" label="product" />
<Entity id="30" label="product" />
<Entity id="27" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="122" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="32" label="product" />
<Entity id="31" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="123" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="36" label="product" />
<Entity id="33" label="company" />
<Entity id="34" label="type" />
<Entity id="35" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="124" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="44" label="product" />
<Entity id="42" label="product" />
<Entity id="43" label="product" />
<Entity id="39" label="company" />
<Entity id="41" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="125" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="49" label="product" />
<Entity id="48" label="product" />
<Entity id="45" label="company" />
<Entity id="46" label="type" />
<Entity id="47" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="126" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="55" label="product" />
<Entity id="53" label="product" />
<Entity id="54" label="product" />
<Entity id="50" label="company" />
<Entity id="52" label="type" />
<Entity id="51" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="127" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="62" label="product" />
<Entity id="60" label="company" />
<Entity id="61" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="128" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="66" label="product" />
<Entity id="65" label="product" />
<Entity id="63" label="company" />
<Entity id="64" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="129" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="69" label="product" />
<Entity id="70" label="product" />
<Entity id="67" label="company" />
<Entity id="68" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="130" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="73" label="product" />
<Entity id="71" label="company" />
<Entity id="72" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="131" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="83" label="product" />
<Entity id="80" label="company" />
<Entity id="82" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="132" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="86" label="product" />
<Entity id="89" label="product" />
<Entity id="87" label="product" />
<Entity id="88" label="product" />
<Entity id="84" label="company" />
<Entity id="85" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="133" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="94" label="product" />
<Entity id="90" label="company" />
<Entity id="93" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="134" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="92" label="product" />
<Entity id="90" label="company" />
<Entity id="91" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="135" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="100" label="product" />
<Entity id="95" label="company" />
<Entity id="96" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="99" label="type" />
<Entity id="97" label="type" />
<Entity id="98" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="136" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="109" label="product" />
<Entity id="108" label="company" />
<Entity id="110" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="137" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="112" label="product" />
<Entity id="111" label="company" />
<Entity id="113" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="138" NAME="OrganizationLeadership">
<Entity id="15" label="person" />
<Entity id="17" label="organization" />
<Entity id="16" label="position" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="139" NAME="OrganizationLeadership">
<Entity id="74" label="person" />
<Entity id="76" label="organization" />
<Entity id="75" label="position" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="140" NAME="OrganizationLeadership">
<Entity id="77" label="person" />
<Entity id="79" label="organization" />
<Entity id="78" label="position" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="141" NAME="OrganizationLeadership">
<Entity id="103" label="organization" />
<Entity id="101" label="position" />
<Entity id="102" label="position" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
