<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Lin Evans wrote: Roland, We had a member here who still stops by every now and then who trolled this forum for months. Every time an image from a Merrill was posted, one could almost guarantee that he would pop up and complain about purple blotching. Not once, not twice, not three times, but in nearly every post he was like clockwork. Forum rules plainly state that if you have a complaint about a particular camera, etc., that you state it once and have evidence to substantiate your view. Everyone who uses a Merrill sensor camera knows that in shadows with insufficient exposure you could extect some magenta/purple blotching. It was a subject beaten to death. The behavior was the epitome of trolling and flame baiting yet he was allowed to continue unabated. This is why some no longer post on the Sigma forum. They become sick and tired of hearing the same sermon from the same people who somehow believe that if they shout long enough and loud enough everyone will accept their point of view and pat them on the back for being so astute. That is the reason we have rules - to prevent continual bashing, flame baiting and trolling. Perhaps you believe that intent is the operant word here. It's not. The operant word is behavior. Trolling is defined by behavior not by intent. Without rules we have anarchy. Perhaps you believe that is O.K., but some of us disagree and want posters to adhere to the forum rules. Therein lies the difficulty. There is no need to analyze intent, only demonstrated behavior. If it walks like a duck, quacks like a duck and looks like a duck then it indeed is most probably a duck.... No matter, Gentlemen, Apparently, we are all insane . . . http://www.dpreview.com/forums/post/57046691 How a direct, calculated insult like that gets past moderation is a mystery to me. -- hide signature -- Ted
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/800f57a4-75fe-3445-9f29-6d59d9e2a138" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-07T01:08:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:23:39.051Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.dpreview.com/forums/thread/3945613?page=4" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
