<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (15) - Peugeot 108 1.2 VTI ALLURE 3DR - LOW MILES £8,995 Reduced by £2,000 was £10,995 Loading Images... Date Registered: Jun 2015 Mileage: 1,413 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Petrol Price: £8,995 Colour: White Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: Allure EC Combined (mpg) 65.7 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 76.3 EC Urban (mpg) 52.3  &gt; 65 MPG 11 Insurance Group 82 Performance (BHP) 4 Seats 99 CO2 (g/km) £0 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Allure Insurance Group 11, TOUCH SCREEN MULTIMEDIA BLUETOOTH ALLOY WHEELS LED DAYTIME RUNNING LIGHTS | Call 0333 2220414 | This Peugeot 108 registration number FJ15WLR was first registered on 09th June 2015. Finished in white it has a 82 BHP PETROL engine with a manual gearbox. The CO2 emissions for this vehicle are 99g/km and you should expect to achieve around 65.70 miles per gallon during normal driving and up to 76.30 MPG during long distance extra urban driving. A MINIMUM 12 MONTH COMPREHENSIVE WARRANTY IS ALSO INCLUDED. Like this 108? Call us to arrange a test drive on 0333 2220414. Part exchange welcome please get in touch for a valuation. Choose a dealer you can trust - 9/10 Pentagon customers would recommend us. You can read 1000s of customer reviews on our website. Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0843 781 5636 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alloy wheels Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Side airbags Traction control Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0843 781 5636 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 2 rear head restraints 50/50 split folding rear seat ABS+Electronic Brake force Distribution Auxilliary 12V power socket Bluetooth system Driver seat height adjust Electric front windows Electric operated/heated door mirrors EPAS ESP with Hill Assist Height adjustable steering wheel Intermittent rear wash/wipe Isofix on outer rear seats Leather gear knob Leather steering wheel Manual air conditioning Rev counter Reversing camera Speed limiter Stop/start button Tinted rear windows Touch screen display Entertainment 2 speakers + 2 tweeters DAB Digital radio Steering wheel mounted remote controls USB socket Exterior / Styling 15 Thorren alloy wheels Automatic headlights Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Chrome side window trim Front fog lights LED daytime running lights Space saver spare wheel Safety / Security Driver and passenger airbags Front and rear curtain airbags Front side airbags Keyless entry Passenger airbag deactivation system Remote central locking Seatbelt warning lamp and buzzer Thatcham Cat 2 engine immobiliser Two 3 point rear seatbelts Tyre pressure sensor Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0843 781 5636 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 99
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/3d1a6d41-335f-368b-a9ca-1b03106e5d1a" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-13T13:21:52Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:58:20.887Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-38143422/ds" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
