<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>No, the image you see above isn't R2-D2 wearing a burka. That's <NODE id="64" />Haier's<NODE id="71" /> <NODE id="72" />R2-D2 Moving Refrigerator<NODE id="97" /> unceremoniously draped in a full-body cover-up to keep it hidden from curious eyes at CES 2016. If you read our CES preview , you know I was looking forward to seeing the astromech service droid at the show. The remote-controlled R2-D2 Moving Refrigerator, first unveiled in Japan in June, is a 1:1 scale model that holds up to six 350 ml cans, emits authentic R2-D2 sound effects, comes with a 720P video projector, and travels at a speed of 1 kilometer per hour.  To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/3020056/consumer-electronics/r2-d2-moving-refrigerator-detained-on-ces-show-floor-due-to-immigration-dispute.html Consumer Technology CES Robotics The Sensorwake smell-based alarm clock has a nagging bacon deficit Tue, 05 Jan 2016 15:02:00 -0800 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips It’s called Sensorwake, it promises to wake you up from sleep with pleasant smells instead of harsh sounds, and it may be one of the most untenable gadgets you’ll find at CES 2016. That’s right: untenable. I have two main objections to the Sensorwake 'olfactory alarm clock': (1) Studies show that our sense of smell shuts down when we’re sleeping, and (2) the clock doesn’t have a bacon scent option! Seriously, there’s no bacon option. That’s almost indefensible given everything we know about about the olfactory benefits of cured pork products. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/3019347/ces/the-sensorwake-smell-based-alarm-clock-has-a-nagging-bacon-deficit.html CES Home Tech Gadgets Google Glass version 2: New photos appear in FCC filing Mon, 28 Dec 2015 14:05:00 -0800 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips Google’s Glass Explorer program may be dead, but the ill-fated face computer—now under the care of <NODE id="1898" />Nest<NODE id="1902" /> <NODE id="1903" />CEO<NODE id="1906" /> <NODE id="1907" />Tony Fadell<NODE id="1918" />—is very much alive. An  FCC filing  published on Monday shows the next version of Google Glass in precise detail, giving the world a closer glimpse at a reboot that appears destined for workplace productivity scenarios. As you can see from the FCC photos here, it appears one manifestation of the Google Glass redux lacks a nose bridge, and doesn’t wrap fully around the user’s face. Moreover, the assembly that holds the glass prism can fold down against the earpiece. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/3018444/wearable-technology/google-glass-version-2-new-photos-appear-in-fcc-filing.html Wearable Technology Hardware 7 high-tech gadgets for wine, beer and cocktail lovers Mon, 23 Nov 2015 14:00:00 -0800 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips People have been drinking wine for 8,000 years. Beer goes back 5,000 years. Distilled spirits, about 2,000 years. That’s 15,000 collective years of drink hacking, yet in 2015 we’re still finding new ways to improve the basic boozing experience. Beer pong was a bright idea, but the following seven gadgets speak to real innovation. They’re all imbued with clever engineering, and should appeal to the nerdier, geekier drinkers among us. Coravin Model Two Coravin is a must for anyone who’s serious about collecting—and drinking—wine. Using a medical grade needle, this 'wine access' system lets you pour a glass of vino without ever disturbing the cork in any meaningful (let alone negative) way. The upshot is you can enjoy a glass of your most precious wine today, and then have a second glass six months from now. And then a third glass in 2017. And so on. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/3005277/holiday/7-high-tech-gadgets-for-wine-beer-and-cocktail-lovers.html Holiday Gift Guide Home Tech New Facebook tools help you manage awkward romantic break-ups Fri, 20 Nov 2015 05:15:00 -0800 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips Wow, Facebook is getting downright emo. In a Thursday blog post  titled 'Improving the Experience When Relationships End' (and, no, that’s not a Morrissey song), Facebook introduced features that mitigate the awkwardness of break-ups in the social media age. If you’ve ended a romance in the last seven or eight years, you probably know that 'it’s complicated' barely begins to describe the weirdness of seeing your ex’s posts in your news feed—or knowing that he or she can see yours. The new tools address all that. Once you change your status to single, Facebook’s emotional-insulation agents come to the rescue. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/3006851/social-networking/new-facebook-tools-help-you-manage-awkward-romantic-break-ups.html Social Media This is why the Nexus 6P is the Android phone you want next Wed, 21 Oct 2015 06:30:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips The Nexus 6P is the first smartphone I’ve ever wanted to evangelize. I mean, literally. It makes me want to pull people aside at parties, lean in with almost uncomfortable intimacy, and tell them in my most emphatic quiet voice, You need to get this phone. I was skeptical at first. Nexus-branded phones run pure Android—the operating system as Google intends it to be—but so many previous versions have been underwhelming. Plus, the 6P is manufactured by Huawei, a company that’s still mostly known in the States for budget phones. It’s not a name that immediately inspires trust. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2995501/android-smartphone/this-is-why-the-nexus-6p-is-the-android-phone-you-want-next.html Smartphones Android What <NODE id="5630" />Ford's<NODE id="5636" /> self-parking <NODE id="5650" />Edge<NODE id="5654" /> says about the dubious future of driverless cars Thu, 08 Oct 2015 04:00:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips My hands aren’t touching the steering wheel. The car is parking itself. It’s an unsettling experience, but I’m trying to give technology a chance. Even when the 2015 Ford Edge successfully maneuvers itself booty-first into a perpendicular parking spot, all you can do is grip your seat bolsters and think about insurance deductibles. But what happens when the Edge isn’t so successful? Well, then you have to wrest control from the machine, and park your own damn self. Ford’s high-tech driver-assist features have a lot to offer in toto, but when they don’t deliver, you might as well be driving a ‘68 Ford Bronco. Dig it: If your brain is hard-wired to believe man is master of all machinery, and robots require laws, and humankind must fight to the bloody end when Skynet rains hellfire, then you won’t warmly embrace the computer-controlled driver-assist features from Ford and its competitors. Shoot, I was taught two hands on the wheel. But this? To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2990567/car-tech/what-fords-self-parking-edge-says-about-the-dubious-future-of-driverless-cars.html Car tech Shelby GT350R: <NODE id="6936" />Ford’s<NODE id="6942" /> fastest <NODE id="6951" />Mustang<NODE id="6958" /> shows high-tech can redeem American muscle Wed, 02 Sep 2015 04:15:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips Ever since it released its first all-electric <NODE id="7106" />Focus<NODE id="7111" /> in 2011, <NODE id="7121" />Ford<NODE id="7125" /> has had a vocal technology story to share—but for car enthusiasts that story has been snoozier than a Hallmark Channel marathon. On pain medication. With a box of red wine. But now all that changes with the Shelby GT350 , a car I still can’t stopping thinking about, some five days since I’ve given back the keys. <NODE id="7440" />Ford’s<NODE id="7446" /> latest halo <NODE id="7459" />Mustang<NODE id="7466" /> has all the makings of a track-day superstar, and it gets there not on brute-force horsepower—which it has to the tune of 526 pissed-off ponies—but on a high-tech makeover of every system that makes a car stick to curving geometry. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2979582/automotive/shelby-gt350r-fords-fastest-mustang-shows-high-tech-can-redeem-american-muscle.html Car tech Consumer Technology Moov Now is a $100 fitness wearable that does what Apple Watch and Fitbit cannot Thu, 16 Jul 2015 08:00:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips With Apple Watch squeezing the high end of the fitness tracking market, and the just-IPOed Fitbit looking more powerful than ever, you’d think now would be a bad time to launch the Moov Now . Another activity-tracking wearable? Doesn’t the world have enough already—especially at that commodity-level $100 price point? But take a look at the Moov Now feature set. It doesn’t look like anything we’re seeing from the big wearable players. Indeed, what’s inside the Moov platform may be just enough to make the Moov Now relevant in today’s crazy-crowded wearables space. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2949005/wearable-technology/moov-now-is-a-100-fitness-wearable-that-does-what-apple-watch-and-fitbit-cannot.html Wearable Technology Health Review: Voyce is the wellness monitor for dogs that makes wearables vividly relevant Wed, 27 May 2015 15:00:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips Even if you retired your Fitbit or Fuelband to a desk drawer long ago, you may still find room in your heart for another activity-tracking wearable. No, not for you—for your dog. The Voyce health and wellness monitor bypasses human biology entirely, and sets its sights on canis familiaris, a species with much less capricious technology habits. Yeah, it’s another canine wearable. But instead of merely recording pawsteps, the Voyce band also tracks resting heart and respiratory rates, two biometrics that can provide deep insights into a dog’s health. My border collie mix, Whiskey, has been wearing Voyce for just over a month, and I’ve gathered a wealth of interesting data about just how much activity and sleep she’s really getting—along with reports on her vital signs that would otherwise require specialized veterinary equipment. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2926744/wearable-technology/review-voyce-is-the-wellness-monitor-for-dogs-that-makes-wearables-vividly-relevant.html Wearable Technology Gadgets The Ford GT is absolutely sick with high-tech innovation and you need to know why Mon, 04 May 2015 04:15:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips Ford is done with nostalgia. The 2017 Ford GT might bear the faint silhouette of the GT40—the gorgeous endurance racer that crushed Le Mans in 1966—but this latest supercar reboot is absolutely sick with high-tech engineering. In fact, the new <NODE id="10482" />GT<NODE id="10484" /> is the most high-tech car <NODE id="10511" />Ford<NODE id="10515" /> has ever <NODE id="10525" />created<NODE id="10532" />, and it claims that tag without a single parking-assist sensor or lithium-ion propulsion pack. The story here is all about lap times, lap times, lap times: getting from start to finish on twisty race tracks as quickly possible. And to reach that goal, the Ford GT doubles down on aerodynamics and weight reduction, twin byproducts of Ford’s most advanced R&amp;D. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2917907/automotive/the-ford-gt-is-absolutely-sick-with-high-tech-innovation-and-you-need-to-know-why.html Car tech Innovation My HoloLens acid trip was fascinating, but left a funny taste in my mouth Fri, 01 May 2015 15:14:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips HoloLens was the most dazzling tech demo I’ve ever experienced—but it left me wanting more. HoloLens did much more than I expected—but made me question whether real people will actually use it in all the ways Microsoft imagines. HoloLens felt far less isolating and restrictive than the DK2 Oculus Rift headset—but I still felt trapped inside a piece of alien technology. And, yeah, strapped down tight, HoloLens wasn’t comfortable to wear. The pressure on the bridge of my nose was intense. It left a funny taste in my mouth. I collected all these experiences during a brief press demo at Build 2015 on Thursday night. You can read all about how Microsoft uses advanced sensors to project holographic images onto the user’s environment here . But if you just want to know what HoloLens is like to use, follow along and I’ll regale you with a tale of high-tech trippiness that everyone should experience at least once. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2917277/wearable-technology/my-hololens-acid-trip-was-fascinating-but-left-a-funny-taste-in-my-mouth.html Wearable Technology Deep inside the smart Swiss watches that challenge Apple Watch with analog panache Thu, 23 Apr 2015 03:30:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips Philippe Kahn is a big man with a big personality and big feelings about Swiss watches. He’s got a massive Alpina model on his wrist, and he’s bragging about how the watch is water-resistant down to 100 meters, and can last more than two years on its built-in battery. He hands me a different Alpina. This one is for women. It’s smaller and more delicate with hand-set diamonds. Next Kahn celebrates a trio of <NODE id="12941" />watches<NODE id="12948" /> from <NODE id="12954" />Frederique Constant<NODE id="12973" />, another Swiss brand. Their aesthetic is more deliberately urbane than a snifter of brandy. The fanciest of the three models has rose-gold plating that’s been polished to a concours-level shine. Kahn didn’t design the watches, but he’s helping to bring them to market—and he’s very, very eager to explain what they represent. He’s the CEO of <NODE id="13316" />Fullpower<NODE id="13325" /> , the company that <NODE id="13345" />developed<NODE id="13354" /> the <NODE id="13359" />MotionX activity-tracking algorithms<NODE id="13395" /> for the <NODE id="13404" />Nike<NODE id="13408" /> Fuelband and the first three <NODE id="13438" />Jawbone<NODE id="13445" /> UP wristbands. And now Fullpower is aiming to bring that same step- and sleep-tracking technology to real Swiss watches. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2913737/smartwatches/deep-inside-the-smart-swiss-watches-that-challenge-apple-watch-with-analog-panache.html Smartwatches Wearable Technology Alcatel Onetouch Watch review: A cheap smartwatch with training wheels Wed, 15 Apr 2015 08:00:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips The Alcatel Onetouch Watch isn’t snazzy-beautiful, and it’s not packed with features. But at only $150, it’s one of the cheapest smartwatches you can buy—and that might seal the deal if you’re merely smartwatch-curious instead of smartwatch-confirmed. It’s sort of like a clip-on tie, or a Barbie bike with training wheels. Consider it Baby’s First Smartwatch, a disposable purchase that can that give you a taste of what a $350 Apple Watch or $300 Android Wear watch is like to use. Do you even want smartphone notifications on your wrist? What about simple activity tracking? The Alcatel Watch—which pairs with any iPhone from 4S to 6 Plus, and any Android phone running 4.3 and later—can put you in the smartwatch game without a major investment. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2910227/smartwatches/alcatel-onetouch-watch-review-a-cheap-smartwatch-with-training-wheels.html Smartwatches Wearable Technology TAG Heuer has a smartwatch plan and it's full of dials, designs and ideas Wed, 18 Mar 2015 15:56:00 -0700 Jon Phillips Jon Phillips <NODE id="15043" />TAG Heuer<NODE id="15052" />, the revered <NODE id="15066" />luxury watch<NODE id="15078" /> <NODE id="15079" />maker<NODE id="15084" />, is on the verge of announcing a smartwatch that blends all its fine Swiss craftsmanship with modern digital features. Speaking to Bloomberg , Claude Biver, head of the timepiece group of <NODE id="15273" />LVMH Moet Hennessy<NODE id="15291" /> (<NODE id="15293" />TAG Heuer’s<NODE id="15304" /> <NODE id="15305" />parent<NODE id="15311" /> company), said the watch’s hardware and software will 'come from Silicon Valley,' while the case, dial, design and crown will 'of course be Swiss.' Meanwhile, Pocket-lint is reporting that TAG Heuer will announce a partnership with Google and Intel tomorrow at Basel World, the most important luxury watch show in the world. It's held in Switzerland, but of course. To read this article in full or to leave a comment, please click here http://www.cio.com/article/2899138/smartwatches/tag-heuer-has-a-smartwatch-plan-and-its-full-of-dials-designs-and-ideas.html Smartwatches Wearable Technology
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1b9161ce-32b4-3e3f-aaa7-531b6f8d37fd" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-08T05:08:30Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:45:43.904Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.cio.com/author/Jon-Phillips/index.rss" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="64" endPos="71" type="organization-company" surface="Haier's" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="72" endPos="97" type="product" surface="R2-D2 Moving Refrigerator" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1898" endPos="1902" type="organization-company" surface="Nest" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1903" endPos="1906" type="org-position" surface="CEO" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1907" endPos="1918" type="person" surface="Tony Fadell" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="5630" endPos="5636" type="organization-company" surface="Ford's" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="5650" endPos="5654" type="product" surface="Edge" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="6936" endPos="6942" type="organization-company" surface="Ford’s" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="6951" endPos="6958" type="product" surface="Mustang" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="7106" endPos="7111" type="product" surface="Focus" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="7121" endPos="7125" type="organization-company" surface="Ford" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="7440" endPos="7446" type="organization-company" surface="Ford’s" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="7459" endPos="7466" type="product" surface="Mustang" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="10482" endPos="10484" type="product" surface="GT" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="10511" endPos="10515" type="organization-company" surface="Ford" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="10525" endPos="10532" type="provide-type" surface="created" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="12941" endPos="12948" type="product-class" surface="watches" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="12954" endPos="12973" type="organization-company" surface="Frederique Constant" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="13316" endPos="13325" type="organization-company" surface="Fullpower" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="13345" endPos="13354" type="provide-type" surface="developed" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="13359" endPos="13395" type="product" surface="MotionX activity-tracking algorithms" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="13404" endPos="13408" type="organization-company" surface="Nike" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="13438" endPos="13445" type="organization-company" surface="Jawbone" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="15043" endPos="15052" type="organization-company" surface="TAG Heuer" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="15066" endPos="15078" type="product-class" surface="luxury watch" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="15079" endPos="15084" type="provide-type" surface="maker" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="15273" endPos="15291" type="organization-company" surface="LVMH Moet Hennessy" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="15293" endPos="15304" type="organization-company" surface="TAG Heuer’s" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="15305" endPos="15311" type="relation-type" surface="parent" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="29" NAME="CompanyBusinessRelationship">
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="18" label="vendor" />
<Entity id="19" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="22" label="customer" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="CompanyBusinessRelationship">
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="18" label="vendor" />
<Entity id="19" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="21" label="customer" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="32" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="6" label="product" />
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="33" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="8" label="product" />
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="34" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="35" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="36" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="13" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="company" />
<Entity id="15" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="37" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="16" label="product" />
<Entity id="17" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="38" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="18" label="company" />
<Entity id="19" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="39" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="24" label="product" />
<Entity id="23" label="company" />
<Entity id="25" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="40" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="26" label="parent" />
<Entity id="28" label="type" />
<Entity id="27" label="child" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="41" NAME="OrganizationLeadership">
<Entity id="4" label="person" />
<Entity id="2" label="organization" />
<Entity id="3" label="position" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
