<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2 litre 0 1 8 2 8 4 Mileage Diesel Sep 2014 Automatic Saloon 62 MPG £62 Cost to fill 777 Tank range (miles) 32 Insurance group £30 Road tax 5 Seats Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport Insurance Group 32, 1 Registered Keeper, 18 M Star spoke alloy wheels - Style 400M, Navigation system Business advanced, Push button starter, Check control system, DAB Digital radio, On board diagnostics, Outside temperature display, Run flat tyre indicator, Service interval indicator, Brake pad wear indicator warning light, Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices, BMW professional radio/CD/MP3, CD Changer preparation, Auto dimming rear view mirror, Chrome exhaust tailpipe, Dynamic brake lights, Front fog lights, Electric front and rear windows with one touch/convenient open/close function, Green tinted heat insulating glass, Rain sensor + automatic driving lights control, Shark fin roof aerial, 12V sockets in front centre console and passenger footwell, Automatic interior light soft on/soft off system, Folding front centre armrest + storage, Front and rear door armrests, Front sports seats with electric side bolster adjustment, Isofix system on outer rear seats, M sports leather steering wheel, Storage compartment in rear doors, Interior lights pack - 3 Series Saloon, ABS, Automatic Stability Control (ASC), CBC - (Cornering brake control), DSC+, Dynamic brake control, Dynamic Traction Control - DTC, Hill start assist, Front seatbelt pretensioners + load limiters, Three 3 point rear seatbelts, Automatic drive away locking facility, Centre lock switch, Electronic immobiliser, Remote control alarm, Electronic differential lock, Drive Performance Control, Run-flat tyres Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01942 504361 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Arnold Clark Fiat (Ashton) At Arnold Clark, it’s not all about searching our 15,000 cars, it’s about finding the right one for you. Our fantastic range of nearly new and used cars can be found across 200 dealerships in the UK, and on ArnoldClark.com. Find your perfect car today! 01942 504361 Night Owl Contact the dealer for a priority response as they open for business in the morning. Email dealer Live Chat available Other cars from this dealer: View all cars at this dealer PARKERS Review Rating This is the sixth generation of the BMW 3 Series.... read more
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/70a53d2d-f8d8-3268-bfe7-b9631a59293d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-10T21:17:53Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:17:48.293Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.motors.co.uk/car-39922166/spw" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
