<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT><NODE id="0" />Heptagon<NODE id="8" /> Introduces Next Generation <NODE id="36" />OLIVIA 3DRanger™<NODE id="52" /> Time-of-Flight Smart Sensor January 11, 2016 By LBSzone Precision Distance Measurements up to 2 meters in Normal Lighting Conditions for High-speed Auto Focus, Distance Ranging, Robotics and other HMI Devices SANTA CLARA, Calif.–<NODE id="282" />Heptagon<NODE id="290" /> introduces <NODE id="302" />OLIVIA<NODE id="308" />, an advanced Time-of-Flight (ToF) 3D Range sensor and the next generation of Heptagon’s Smart Sensor family, today at CES 2016. OLIVIA is a complete intelligent system module with an integrated microprocessor, adaptive algorithms, advanced optics, ToF sensor and light source. OLIVIA can accurately measure distance up to 2 meters in normal lighting conditions and functions reliably with constant performance independent of an object’s reflectance, compared with other solutions that are only able to reach similar distances in lower lighting. OLIVIA also requires 40% less power when ranging than alternate solutions. Heptagon continues to build on its patented 'phase modulation' ToF pixel, which has best-in-class sensitivity and speed, as well as excellent background light rejection. This allows <NODE id="1111" />Heptagon<NODE id="1119" />’s <NODE id="1122" />distance-sensing modules<NODE id="1146" /> to deliver superior measurement accuracy and precision. 'We’re excited about the advancements OLIVIA brings to the market' 'We’re excited about the advancements OLIVIA brings to the market,' says <NODE id="1343" />René Kromhof<NODE id="1355" />, <NODE id="1357" />Senior Vice President of Sales and Marketing<NODE id="1401" /> at <NODE id="1405" />Heptagon<NODE id="1413" />. 'Our team is moving fast – In less than 3 months from the release of LAURA, our first product, we have introduced OLIVIA, our next generation sensor. With over 20 years’ experience in highly accurate distance mapping and 3D imaging technology, Heptagon is uniquely positioned to innovate and rapidly bring world-class products to market.' <NODE id="1754" />Heptagon<NODE id="1762" /> <NODE id="1763" />developed<NODE id="1772" /> the <NODE id="1777" />OLIVIA 3DRanger<NODE id="1792" /> for long distance ranging, low power, small size and ease of use. OLIVIA monitors the environmental ambient light, automatically adjusts exposure settings, and calculates the distance. The user simply reads the result through a standard I2C interface. OLIVIA is especially suitable as a camera AF assist system to enable fast auto focus lock for primary and front facing smartphone cameras, even in dim lighting conditions or video modes. It is complimentary and enhances the performance of traditional contrast autofocus as well as more recent phase detection auto focus systems embedded in image sensors (PDAF), which typically perform less ideal in low light conditions and video. For the front facing camera, OLIVIA can also be used as a proximity sensor. OLIVIA provides accurate and repeatable absolute distance measurements and is Class 1 laser eye safe. The sensor comes in an ultra-small, thermally efficient package, which provides maximum integration flexibility, while embedded filters allow for lower-cost cover glass design. The sensor is standard reflow compatible; RoHS and REACH compliant. About Heptagon
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/2c5a0683-93da-3a71-8f9b-85c24e9f41ff" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-11T20:38:17Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:52:00.912Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://lbszone.com/2016/01/11/heptagon-introduces-next-generation-olivia-3dranger-time-flight-smart-sensor/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="0" endPos="8" type="organization-company" surface="Heptagon" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="36" endPos="52" type="product" surface="OLIVIA 3DRanger™" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="282" endPos="290" type="organization-company" surface="Heptagon" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="302" endPos="308" type="product" surface="OLIVIA" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1111" endPos="1119" type="organization-company" surface="Heptagon" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1122" endPos="1146" type="product-class" surface="distance-sensing modules" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1343" endPos="1355" type="person" surface="René Kromhof" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1357" endPos="1401" type="org-position" surface="Senior Vice President of Sales and Marketing" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1405" endPos="1413" type="organization-company" surface="Heptagon" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="1754" endPos="1762" type="organization-company" surface="Heptagon" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="1763" endPos="1772" type="provide-type" surface="developed" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1777" endPos="1792" type="product" surface="OLIVIA 3DRanger" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="12" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="13" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="14" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="5" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="15" NAME="OrganizationLeadership">
<Entity id="6" label="person" />
<Entity id="8" label="organization" />
<Entity id="7" label="position" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="16" NAME="">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="9" label="company" />
<Entity id="10" label="type" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
