<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>John King wrote: rovingtim wrote: 4) Without understanding equivalence , one cannot directly compare lenses from systems with different sized sensors. You also will not understand how two systems compare at the edge of the performance envelope. Here endeth the lesson If ONLY this last were true ... Tim, almost everyone I know understands the basic tenets of equivalence (note that this is NOT capitalised, like Relativity, or Evolution ... ), and have done so since well before your hero was even born ... Many, many people get sick of having something rammed down their throats as religious dogma, more particularly because they already understand the ramifications of using different lenses on different formats, or possibly even because they already use the identical lenses on different formats ... and have used different formats since before your hero was born. Being endlessly lectured to about this item of religious belief gets right up most rational peoples' left nostrils - I wonder why? Rhetorical question ... Many people here who strongly object to being shouted down about this topic all over this forum already own multiple format cameras - e.g. mFTs and 135 format cameras and lenses ... Speaking for myself, I have been using formats from my Minox (8mm film) at one end through to medium format Arca-Swiss (5x4) at the other. Does your hero understand this? I suspect not. Was your hero even born when I was using multiple formats? No ... When I pick up a different sensor camera, do I try to even contemplate this stuff? No, I don't. I put the camera to my eye, get the composition and exposure correct for my purposes and take a photograph. End of lesson! ZERO 'equivalence' involved at any single part of the process, and never has been. One gets to know one's tools, and mine currently span heaps of miscellaneous digital cameras and film cameras spanning from 8 mm to 6x6 cm, including three 135 format cameras (currently) ... When one adds to this that equivalence as a theory is around a first order approximation (I'm being kind, a zeroeth order approximation is probably closer to the truth ... ), it becomes harder to swallow 20,000 - 30,000 posts (at the very least) on this forum (1041) and the Olympus dSLR forum (1022) spanning many many years. It is not us objectors who need examining, but the bona fides of your hero. It is not our motives that need examining. It is those of your hero. It is not our understanding of the photographic tools with which we are pretty darn familiar that needs to be questioned, but why a whole lot of people feel the need to come here and continuously lecture us about the shortcomings of our gear of choice. Being lectured to by someone who does not even own said gear of choice is blatant trolling, flaming, baiting and plain old bad manners. Sorry, but I'm going to go watch some drivel on TV. Anything's better than reading more of this equivalence drivel. Bravo, spot on. -- hide signature -- Regards, john from Melbourne, Australia. . Please do not embed images from my web site without prior permission I consider this to be a breach of my copyright. -- -- -- . The Camera doth not make the Man (nor Woman) ... Perhaps being kind to cats, dogs &amp; children does ... . Galleries: http://canopuscomputing.com.au/gallery2/v/main-page/ Bird Control Officers on active service. -- hide signature -- http://nigelvoak.blogspot.it/
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/81ef1075-b70a-3ca7-8161-ff62ef63435c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-09T10:18:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:24:21.555Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.dpreview.com/forums/thread/3949075" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
