<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Global NFC Chips Market 2015-2019 By PR Newswire Article Rating: January 7, 2016 05:35 PM EST LONDON , Jan. 7, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- About NFC Chips NFC chips refer to the ICs in mobile devices, POS terminals, and retail products that store information and control transactions. NFC chips enable communication between NFC-enabled devices within a radius of 4 inches. These chips provide ease of transaction and data exchange between devices without the need to pair them. This has resulted in increased adoption of NFC chips across various segments. Technavio's analysts forecast the global NFC chips market to grow at a CAGR of 50.6% by volume over the period 2014-2019. Covered in this report The report includes the present scenario and growth prospects of the global NFC chips market for the period 2015-2019. The report segments the market based on end-users. Technavio's report, Global NFC Chips Market 2015-2019, has been prepared based on an in-depth market analysis with inputs from industry experts. The report covers its growth prospects in the coming years. The report includes a discussion on the key vendors operating in this market. Key Vendors Broadcom Inside Secure NXP Semiconductors Sony Other Prominent Vendors Media Tek Qualcomm Renesas Key Market Driver Increased Adoption of NFC Technology For a full, detailed list, view our report Key Market Challenge High Cost of NFC Chips For a full, detailed list, view our report Key Market Trend Rise in NFC-based Transactions For a full, detailed list, view our report Key Questions Answered in this Report What will the market size be in 2019 and what will the growth rate be What are the key market trends What is driving this market What are the challenges to market growth Who are the key vendors in this market space What are the market opportunities and threats faced by the key vendors What are the strengths and weaknesses of the key vendors Download the full report: https://www.reportbuyer.com/product/2060272/ About Reportbuyer Reportbuyer is a leading industry intelligence solution that provides all market research reports from top publishers http://www.reportbuyer.com For more information: Sarah Smith Research Advisor at Reportbuyer.com Email: [email protected] Tel: +44 208 816 85 48 Website: www.reportbuyer.com To view the original version on PR Newswire, visit: http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/global-nfc-chips-market-2015-2019-300201328.html SOURCE ReportBuyer Published January 7, 2016 Copyright 2016 SYS-CON Media, Inc. - All Rights Reserved. Syndicated stories and blog feeds, all rights reserved by the author. Cloud Expo &amp; DevOps Summit 2015 East KEYNOTES VIEW KEYNOTE WEBCASTS VIEW KEYNOTE WEBCASTS Most Influential Technology Blogs The Application Performance Gap By Steve Brar If a slow or unresponsive application on your mobile device or PC has ever left you feeling angry, frustrated and unproductive, you're not alone. Business success in today's digital age relies on application performance. Yet according to the Riverbed Global Application Performance Survey 2015, nine out of 10 organizations suffer from poor performance on a regular basis. Executives say the poor per... Jan. 7, 2016 05:30 PM EST IoT: Wi-Fi as Leading Technology Segment By Ram Sonagara Internet-of-Things (IoT) is touted as the next big thing slated to revolutionize how we communicate online or how we work. The majority of the chatter rising from industries nowadays is focused on how to deploy machine-to-machine (M2M) communication and optimally capitalize on the technology. Simply put, IoT is built on the paradigm of cloud computing and data gathering sensors networks. Hence, ... Jan. 7, 2016 05:00 PM EST Reads: 107 Is ITIL Still Relevant in the Digital World? By Rafi Katanasho Is ITIL (Information Technology Infrastructure Library) still relevant in the digital world? The short answer is…yes. The longer answer is: it depends on your organization’s understanding and application of ITIL. In order to best answer the question it’s important to take a step back and examine the goals and intent of ITIL. Jan. 7, 2016 04:45 PM EST Make Test Automation Less Challenging By Sanjay Zalavadia Test automation is arguably the most important innovation to the process of QA testing in software development. The ability to automate regression testing and other repetitive test cases can significantly reduce the overall production time for even the most complex solutions. As software continues to be developed for new platforms – including mobile devices and the diverse array of endpoints that ... Jan. 7, 2016 04:19 PM EST Time, Space and Speed - Mobile vs. Static Apps
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0eed2714-21e1-30eb-bc97-af5d57630d62" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-07T23:51:58Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:40:56.147Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.sys-con.com/node/3625389" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
