<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Janus Capital Management Has $517,961,000 Stake in Sensata Technologies Holding (ST) Filed Under: Market News • SEC Filing Articles Janus Capital Management decreased its stake in shares of Sensata Technologies Holding (NYSE:ST) by 1.1% during the third quarter, according to its most recent 13F filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission. The firm owned 11,681,398 shares of the company's stock after selling 130,484 shares during the period. Janus Capital Management owned 6.86% of Sensata Technologies Holding worth $517,961,000 as of its most recent filing with the SEC. Separately, KBC Group increased its stake in shares of Sensata Technologies Holding by 248.8% in the third quarter. KBC Group now owns 33,821 shares of the company's stock valued at $1,499,000 after buying an additional 24,124 shares during the last quarter. Shares of Sensata Technologies Holding ( NYSE:ST ) traded down 0.70% during trading on Friday, hitting $39.98. 1,330,407 shares of the company's stock were exchanged. Sensata Technologies Holding has a 12-month low of $39.57 and a 12-month high of $55.53. The company has a market cap of $6.80 billion and a P/E ratio of 34.47. The company has a 50-day moving average of $44.74 and a 200-day moving average of $46.45. Sensata Technologies Holding (NYSE:ST) last announced its quarterly earnings results on Tuesday, October 27th. The company reported $0.72 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, topping the Zacks' consensus estimate of $0.71 by $0.01. During the same period last year, the company posted $0.63 earnings per share. The firm had revenue of $727.40 million for the quarter, compared to analysts' expectations of $736.41 million. The business's quarterly revenue was up 26.0% on a year-over-year basis. On average, equities analysts expect that Sensata Technologies Holding will post $2.74 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. A number of brokerages have issued reports on ST. Zacks Investment Research upgraded shares of Sensata Technologies Holding from a sell rating to a hold rating in a report on Wednesday, October 28th. RBC Capital reiterated a hold rating on shares of Sensata Technologies Holding in a report on Friday, September 25th. SunTrust downgraded shares of Sensata Technologies Holding from a buy rating to a neutral rating and reduced their price target for the company from $55.00 to $50.00 in a report on Friday, November 13th. Citigroup Inc. downgraded shares of Sensata Technologies Holding from a buy rating to a neutral rating in a report on Wednesday, October 7th. Finally, Oppenheimer reduced their price target on shares of Sensata Technologies Holding from $60.00 to $56.00 and set an outperform rating on the stock in a report on Wednesday, October 28th. Six equities research analysts have rated the stock with a hold rating and six have given a buy rating to the company's stock. Sensata Technologies Holding has a consensus rating of Buy and an average price target of $58.38. In related news, SVP Martin J. Carter sold 66,000 shares of the company's stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, November 17th. The shares were sold at an average price of $43.87, for a total value of $2,895,420.00. Following the completion of the sale, the senior vice president now owns 38,080 shares of the company's stock, valued at $1,670,569.60. The sale was disclosed in a legal filing with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available at the SEC website . Also, VP Geert Braaksma sold 54,874 shares of the company's stock in a transaction dated Tuesday, November 3rd. The shares were sold at an average price of $49.29, for a total transaction of $2,704,739.46. Following the completion of the sale, the vice president now directly owns 5,505 shares of the company's stock, valued at approximately $271,341.45. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . <NODE id="3858" />Sensata Technologies Holding N.V.<NODE id="3891" /> is a global industrial technology company. The <NODE id="3939" />Company<NODE id="3946" /> is engaged in the <NODE id="3965" />development<NODE id="3976" />, <NODE id="3978" />manufacture<NODE id="3989" /> and <NODE id="3994" />sale<NODE id="3998" /> of <NODE id="4002" />sensors<NODE id="4009" /> and <NODE id="4014" />controls<NODE id="4022" />. The <NODE id="4028" />Company's<NODE id="4037" /> operating segments include <NODE id="4065" />Sensors<NODE id="4072" /> segment and <NODE id="4085" />Controls<NODE id="4093" /> segment. The <NODE id="4107" />Company<NODE id="4114" /> <NODE id="4115" />produce<NODE id="4122" /> <NODE id="4123" />sensors<NODE id="4130" /> and <NODE id="4135" />controls<NODE id="4143" /> for applications such as thermal <NODE id="4177" />circuit breakers<NODE id="4193" /> in aircraft, <NODE id="4207" />pressure sensors<NODE id="4223" /> in automotive systems, and <NODE id="4251" />bimetal current<NODE id="4266" /> and <NODE id="4271" />temperature control devices<NODE id="4298" /> in electric motors. The Company's sensors are customized devices that translate a physical phenomenon, such as force or position, into electronic signals that microprocessors or computer-based control systems can act upon. Its controls are customized devices embedded within systems to protect them from heat or current. The <NODE id="4624" />Company's<NODE id="4633" /> products include <NODE id="4651" />low-<NODE id="4655" />, <NODE id="4657" />medium-<NODE id="4664" /> and <NODE id="4669" />high-pressure sensors<NODE id="4690" />, <NODE id="4692" />temperature sensors<NODE id="4711" />, <NODE id="4713" />speed sensors<NODE id="4726" />, <NODE id="4728" />position sensors<NODE id="4744" />, <NODE id="4746" />force sensors<NODE id="4759" />, <NODE id="4761" />motor protectors<NODE id="4777" />, and thermal and magnetic-hydraulic circuit breakers and switches. This story was originally published by American Banking News (http://www.americanbankingnews.com) and is the sole property of American Banking News. If you are reading this article on another website, that means this article was illegally copied and re-published to this website in violation of U.S. and International copyright law. You can view the original version of this story at http://www.americanbankingnews.com/2016/01/10/janus-capital-management-has-517961000-stake-in-sensata-technologies-holding-st/ Receive News &amp; Ratings for Sensata Technologies Holding Daily - Enter your email address below to receive a concise daily summary of the latest news and analysts' ratings for Sensata Technologies Holding and related companies with MarketBeat.com's FREE daily email newsletter . Leave a Reply Click here to cancel reply.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/37c714f0-3b9b-3223-9c13-7ae0a83c8abb" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-11T00:49:18Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:56:20.677Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.americanbankingnews.com/2016/01/10/janus-capital-management-has-517961000-stake-in-sensata-technologies-holding-st/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="3858" endPos="3891" type="organization-company" surface="Sensata Technologies Holding N.V." />
<Entity id="1" startPos="3939" endPos="3946" type="organization-company" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="3965" endPos="3976" type="provide-type" surface="development" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="3978" endPos="3989" type="provide-type" surface="manufacture" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="3994" endPos="3998" type="provide-type" surface="sale" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="4002" endPos="4009" type="product-class" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="4014" endPos="4022" type="product-class" surface="controls" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="4028" endPos="4037" type="organization-company" surface="Company's" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="4065" endPos="4072" type="product-class" surface="Sensors" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="4085" endPos="4093" type="product-class" surface="Controls" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="4107" endPos="4114" type="organization-company" surface="Company" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="4115" endPos="4122" type="provide-type" surface="produce" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="4123" endPos="4130" type="product-class" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="4135" endPos="4143" type="product-class" surface="controls" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="4177" endPos="4193" type="product-class" surface="circuit breakers" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="4207" endPos="4223" type="product-class" surface="pressure sensors" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="4251" endPos="4266" type="product-class" surface="bimetal current" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="4271" endPos="4298" type="product-class" surface="temperature control devices" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="4624" endPos="4633" type="organization-company" surface="Company's" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="4651" endPos="4655" type="product-class" surface="low-" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="4657" endPos="4664" type="product-class" surface="medium-" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="4669" endPos="4690" type="product-class" surface="high-pressure sensors" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="4692" endPos="4711" type="product-class" surface="temperature sensors" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="4713" endPos="4726" type="product-class" surface="speed sensors" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="4728" endPos="4744" type="product-class" surface="position sensors" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="4746" endPos="4759" type="product-class" surface="force sensors" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="4761" endPos="4777" type="product-class" surface="motor protectors" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="27" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="5" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="product" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
<Entity id="2" label="type" />
<Entity id="4" label="type" />
<Entity id="3" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="28" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="8" label="product" />
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="29" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="13" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="product" />
<Entity id="17" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="product" />
<Entity id="16" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
<Entity id="11" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="19" label="product" />
<Entity id="23" label="product" />
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="25" label="product" />
<Entity id="22" label="product" />
<Entity id="26" label="product" />
<Entity id="21" label="product" />
<Entity id="24" label="product" />
<Entity id="18" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
