<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2012 (12) - Jaguar XF Diesel 3.0d V6 Premium Luxury 4dr Auto £20,991 Loading Images... Date Registered: May 2012 Mileage: 28,917 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £20,991 Colour: Red Body Style: Saloon Vehicle Trim / Variant: Premium Luxury EC Combined (mpg) 42 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 51.3 EC Urban (mpg) 30  &gt; 42 MPG 43 Insurance Group 240 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 0 CO2 (g/km) History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Premium Luxury Insurance Group 43, 1 Registered Keeper, Franchise Approved, Jaguar XF Diesel Saloon Finished in Claret Specification Includes Leather, Barley, 18'' Vela alloy wheels, 60/40 split folding rear seat, Anti-lock braking system ( ABS), Automatic climate control, Bright mesh grille, Cornering Brake Control ( CBC), Cruise control, Driver's airbag, Dynamic Stability Control, Electric heated door mirrors, Electric seats, Electric windows, Electronic Parking Brake, Emergency Brake Assist, Foldback electric mirrors, Front park aid, Heated front screen, Heated front seats, Jaguar SmartKey system, JaguarDrive Control, JaguarDrive Selector, JaguarSense, JaguarVoice system, Parking aid with rear sensor, Passenger airbag, Security system, Side airbags, Touring suspension, Traction control, 8-speed automatic transmission, Electric steering column Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0121 514 7357 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Years of criticism for being too 'traditional' and flagging sales prompted Jaguar to take a radical step when replacing the S-Type. Modern and elegant styling Unique interior Supremely comfortable Classier image than a BMW or a Mercedes Rear seat space a little cramped Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Climate control Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Leather seat trim Navigation system PAS Passenger airbag Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0121 514 7357 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 3 rear seat head restraints 3 spoke leather steering wheel 60/40 asymmetric split folding rear seats 7 colour screen ABS+EBA Auto air recirculation Auto climate control Auto dimming rear view mirror Auxiliary power socket Bluetooth telephone connectivity Brake pad warning light Bright window surrounds Door mirror integrated indicators DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Electric folding door mirrors Electric front/rear windows with one touch/anti pinch Electrically adjustable and heated door mirrors Electronic parking brake Front centre console storage box Front head restraints Heated front windscreen and timer Individual driver/passenger temperature controls Isofix child seat preparation Jaguar sense JaguarDrive selector Laminated windscreen Navigation system Rain sensor windscreen wipers Reach/rake electric adjustable steering column + entry/exit tilt away Rear parking sensor Servotronic PAS Softgrain leather instrument panel and door top rolls Softgrain leather upholstery Steering wheel gearshift paddles Traction control Trip computer with dual function Twin front cupholders Twin rear cupholders Entertainment Auxiliary input socket Steering wheel mounted audio/cruise controls
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1886e7ce-d71c-343f-a376-19cfcd849d93" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-08T19:01:21Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:44:35.22Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39901470/av" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
