<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (X) - Audi Q3 2.0 TDI (177) Quattro S Line 5dr S Tronic Auto £20,841 Reduced by £2,149 was £22,990 Loading Images... Date Registered: Nov 2015 Mileage: 40,488 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £20,841 Colour: Black Body Style: Estate Vehicle Trim / Variant: S Line Plus EC Combined (mpg) 51.4 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 57.6 EC Urban (mpg) 42.8  &gt; 51 MPG 25 Insurance Group 184 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 144 CO2 (g/km) £145 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: S Line Plus Insurance Group 25, Great looking car with the legendary Quattro all wheel drive system perfect for the winter great specification with automatic gearbox bluetooth xenon headlights with auto light activation and rear park sensor not only does it look good with the s line body styling it performs great with the punchy but efficient 2.0tdi with 177PS of power call to book a test driveABS Air Conditioning Alloy Wheels Automatic Gearbox Automatic Headlights Automatic Wipers Bluetooth Prepared CD Player Climate Control Electric Mirrors Electric Windows Engine Immobiliser Four Wheel Drive Front Fog Lights Full Service History Heated Mirrors Onboard Computer Parking Camera Parking Distance Control Power Steering Xenon Headlights. Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0191 448 9752 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Climate control Cruise control DAB digital radio Electrically adjustable drivers seat Electrically adjustable passenger seat Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Headlight washers Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Rear electric windows Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0191 448 9752 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V socket in rear centre console 3 spoke multi-function Q design steering wheel with paddle shift 6.5 colour display screen ABS+Electronic Brake force Distribution Acoustic windscreen Aluminium door sill trims Audi drive select Auto dimming rear view mirror Black cloth headlining Body colour door mirrors Cruise control Door mirror integrated indicators Dual zone climate control EDL + ASR Electric front lumbar adjustment Electromechanical parking brake ESP Front and rear electric windows Front and rear headrests Front centre armrest with storage compartment and angle adjustment Heated windscreen washer jets Height adjustable front seats Height/reach adjust steering wheel ISOFIX on front passenger and rear outer seats Jack and tool kit Light and rain sensor for auto activation of lights and windscreen wipers Low washer fluid indicator Matt brushed aluminium fascia and door trim inlays MMI - Multi Media Interface control system On board computer PAS Perforated leather gearknob Privacy glass Rear wiper Remote electric tailgate opening/closing Retractable luggage cover Service interval indicator Split fold rear seat Sunband for windscreen Under floor storage in luggage area Voice control system Entertainment Audi music interface DAB digital radio module
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/8b9cbbbc-b350-33b4-9161-65e7e9e214c4" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-13T12:56:09Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:28:05.703Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39453063/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
