<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 12, 2016 C O N T E N T S: Image Courtesy: link: http://www.robotshop.com/en/4wd-mecanum-wheel-beginner-mobile-robot-kit.html author: robotshop.com description: Beginner Mobile Robot Kit KEY TOPICS POWER COMPONENTS FOR MOBILE MOTION PRODUCTS <NODE id="385" />Rise Robotics<NODE id="398" /> <NODE id="399" />invents<NODE id="406" />, <NODE id="408" />develops<NODE id="416" />, and <NODE id="422" />manufactures<NODE id="434" /> novel <NODE id="441" />power components<NODE id="457" /> that are affordable, lightweight, and efficient. [1] <NODE id="511" />Kinova<NODE id="517" /> <NODE id="518" />designs<NODE id="525" /> and <NODE id="530" />manufactures<NODE id="542" /> <NODE id="543" />robotics platforms<NODE id="561" /> and <NODE id="566" />components<NODE id="576" /> that are simple, sexy and safe under two divisions: Assistive Robotics empowers disabled people to push beyond their current boundaries and limitations while Service Robotics empowers industry to interact with its environment more efficiently and safely. [1] The following items are included in each WorldSkills Mobile Robotics Component Collection. [2] A member of the FAULHABER Group, <NODE id="964" />MICROMO<NODE id="971" /> brings together the widest range of high quality, high performance <NODE id="1039" />linear and rotary micro motion solutions<NODE id="1079" />, decades of micro motion expertise based on DC motor technology and full service design, sourcing and manufacturing capability on a global basis to deliver benchmark motion solutions to markets such as medical, robotics and aerospace and defense. [1] Typical areas are robotics and applications in the medical industry or in specialized machine manufacturing. [3] <NODE id="1444" />Jabez Technologies<NODE id="1462" /> provides <NODE id="1472" />robot programming technologies<NODE id="1502" /> that enable versatile and profitable robotic solutions for industrial manufacturing applications. [3] <NODE id="1605" />Robotmaster<NODE id="1616" /> is the flagship product of <NODE id="1644" />Jabez Technologies<NODE id="1662" />, specializing in robot <NODE id="1686" />programming technologies for industrial automation, manufacturing and robotics<NODE id="1764" /> since <NODE id="1771" />1996<NODE id="1775" />. [3] Perfect application fits include humanoid robots, electric grippers used in process automation and high?performance traction drives used in inspection robotics. [3] OCTOPUZ allows us to show the industry how we can provide the best in automation solutions using simulation-based software, said Greg Culp, Robotics Sales Manager at In-House Solutions. [3] Today, OCTOPUZ provides a mainstream, versatile, powerful and effective solution for any robotic challenge. [3] <NODE id="2248" />IPR Robotics<NODE id="2260" /> offers a wide range of <NODE id="2284" />servo-driven 7th axis linear rails<NODE id="2318" /> for industrial robots. [3] The P1 Compensator is for use in automated assembly, bin picking, loading and unloading machines, robotic finishing, and more. [3] Mobile carts consolidate fulfillment of orders in distant break-pack picking areas, saving time and making the most of valuable labor resources, said Earl Wohlrab, palletizing and robotics systems product manager, Intelligrated. [3] Putting robotics at your service is a trademark of RobotShop inc. [4] As you may already know, <NODE id="2805" />RobotShop<NODE id="2814" /> offers all <NODE id="2826" />Lynxmotion robotic arms &amp; grippers<NODE id="2860" /> on our online catalog, which are based on the modular servo erector set. [5] While you may already have decided that you would like to use a Lynxmotion robotic arm, you may not be sure which kit would best fit your project. [5] This article intends to help you choose the right Lynxmotion robotic arm for your needs. [5] <NODE id="3182" />MICROMO<NODE id="3189" /> is pleased to announce the latest addition to the <NODE id="3240" />FAULHABER CR DC Motor<NODE id="3261" /> series. [3] I used 6 faulhaber dc motors you can find It's pdf here M2233_EN. [6] Its graphite commutation, powerful neodymium magnet and particularly high copper content in the FAULHABER rotor winding provide the compact 3890 CR with an enormous amount of power. [3] Additional power with the new FAULHABER 2668 ? CR motor The new 2668 ? CR DC motor from FAULHABER offers considerably more power than comparable drives, and is the most powerful copper-graphite commutated DC-micromotor in its size class. [7] Clearwater, Florida Motion Control <NODE id="3807" />MICROMO<NODE id="3814" /> is pleased to announce the latest addition to the <NODE id="3865" />FAULHABER CR DC Motor<NODE id="3886" /> series. [8] According to engineers at MICROMO (FAULHABER Group), in robot-guided surgery even a millimeter of error can drastically impact patient outcome. [9] It may be possible to arrange a group purchase of Faulhaber motors. [10] With no-load speeds of just over 5,000 rpm, the motors are optimally tailored for combination with FAULHABER gearheads. [8] Speed control or positioning tasks are managed either by the FAULHABER Speed Controller SC 1801 or the Motion Controller MCDC 3002. [8] Our Actin control for complex robots drives an autonomous oil rig, ensures safe medical robotics, and enables low-cost hardware to perform precise, reliable manipulation. [1] It is driven by conventional electric motors, and is intended to power wearable robotics used in the Construction, Industrial, and Medical markets. [1] Applications include medical &amp; laboratory equipment, aerospace &amp; defense, robotics &amp; automation, semiconductor, test and measurement, assembly and manufacturing. [1] RoboticsTomorrow.com is a technical resource featuring Products, Companies, News, Articles and Events for the Robotics, Advanced Manufacturing and Factory Automation industries. [1] With the resources of over 100 engineers in five locations and technical specialties ranging from machine vision optics and lighting, mechatronics, electronics, CAD, system builds, program management, software, new product design and development, tooling, custom robotics and automation, special machines, industrial automation installation service and support. [1] NewBotic Corporation is a robotic systems integrator headquartered in Thompson, Connecticut, best known for its specialized engineering services that designs advanced transformative manufacturing and warehousing processes for a wide variety of industries. [1] In business for over 20 years with over 40 ME?s along with a strong ecosystem of suppliers and contract manufacturers, Acorn has deep expertise in robotics and associated support infrastructure design. [1] These innovations allow us to lead the social robotics revolution with intelligent, interactive robots that have real-world instructional applications as teachers and therapists in schools, autism treatment centers, eldercare facilities, and private homes. [1] <NODE id="6148" />Vecna<NODE id="6153" />?s robotic logistics solutions are a family of <NODE id="6200" />autonomous mobile robots<NODE id="6224" />, built to work alongside humans. [1] <NODE id="6262" />Universal Robots<NODE id="6278" /> has reinvented industrial robotics with lightweight, flexible <NODE id="6341" />robot arms<NODE id="6351" />. [1] Robots for Roboticists is your source for professional robotic technologies. [1] <NODE id="6438" />Rocketfarm<NODE id="6448" /> is currently participating in the <NODE id="6483" />development<NODE id="6494" /> of new <NODE id="6502" />robotic services<NODE id="6518" /> such as a <NODE id="6529" />camera robot<NODE id="6541" /> and the worlds first robot to assist construction workers in drilling holes in concrete ceilings. [1] Robots for Roboticists presents technical subjects for building, testing and deploying real robotic systems. [1] Our distributorship division collaborates with Yujin Robot, Future Robot, Doog-Inc, Robai Cyton, Yudo Robotics, and the TOPY Crawler. [1] The Robot Report is a web-based resource for news and links about the business of robotics. [1] <NODE id="6991" />Rethink Robotics<NODE id="7007" /> is a pioneer in the category of collaborative robotics, and an innovator in developing affordable, user-friendly <NODE id="7121" />robots<NODE id="7127" /> that were designed and built from the ground up to operate safely next to people in production environments. [1] <NODE id="7241" />Jetta<NODE id="7246" /> is a leading <NODE id="7260" />ODM<NODE id="7263" />/<NODE id="7264" />OEM<NODE id="7267" /> in the consumer products industry including <NODE id="7312" />electronics<NODE id="7323" />, <NODE id="7325" />robotics<NODE id="7333" />, <NODE id="7335" />toys<NODE id="7339" />, <NODE id="7341" />infant/juvenile products<NODE id="7365" />, <NODE id="7367" />home appliances<NODE id="7382" />, <NODE id="7384" />tools<NODE id="7389" />, <NODE id="7391" />vacuums<NODE id="7398" />, <NODE id="7400" />wearable tech<NODE id="7413" /> and more. [1] RoboUniverse News Stay up to date on the incredible field of robotics! Enter your email address below to receive daily news about the robotics industry and updates on the RoboUniverse conference series, including show dates, announcements, exclusive discounts, and more. [1] Soft Robotics Inc. is a company focused on addressing the unmet needs of robotic manipulation through our proprietary and novel technology. [1] The New York Robotics Meetup will explore new technology and advancements in a fun Meetup setting. [1] <NODE id="7950" />RoboKind<NODE id="7958" /> is the world leader in creating affordable, <NODE id="8003" />expressive facial robotics technology<NODE id="8040" />. [1] <NODE id="8046" />CoroWare<NODE id="8054" /> is committed to improve robotics and technology education at all levels with the advent of its<NODE id="8149" />CoroBot Spark robotics kit<NODE id="8175" />. [1] <NODE id="8181" />CoroWare<NODE id="8189" /> is a solutions integrator with expertise in affordable and open <NODE id="8254" />mobile robotics<NODE id="8269" /> and data analytics. [1] Leveraging its state-of-the-art <NODE id="8326" />Ava? mobile robotics platform<NODE id="8355" />, <NODE id="8357" />iRobot<NODE id="8363" /> is bringing its solutions to new markets. [1] We provide a structured overview of robotics development and the people involved. [1] We provide the most comprehensive educational robotics ecosystem in the market. [1] The company has an extensive background in the industrial fiber optic communications, industrial controls/automation, satellite/missile guidance systems and autonomous robotics. [1] Redundant and hot-swap robotics, power and electronic components maximize availability. [11] Thanks to experience in the mechanical telecommunications sector with similar requirements for precision stepper motors, the FAULHABER GROUP was able to meet this challenge without any problems by deploying standard products. [12] The key to solving this problem was provided by the stepper motor specialists of the FAULHABER Group. [12] MICROMO is a member of the <NODE id="9220" />FAULHABER Group<NODE id="9235" /> which offers the world's largest consolidated portfolio of <NODE id="9295" />miniature and micro drive system technologies<NODE id="9340" /> available from one partner in the world today. [8] When <NODE id="9397" />aesthetic laser<NODE id="9412" /> <NODE id="9413" />manufacturer<NODE id="9425" />, <NODE id="9427" />Cutera Inc.<NODE id="9438" /> out of <NODE id="9446" />Brisbane<NODE id="9454" />, <NODE id="9456" />CA<NODE id="9458" /> began to <NODE id="9468" />develop<NODE id="9475" /> an innovative new <NODE id="9494" />skin-resurfacing laser<NODE id="9516" /> called the <NODE id="9528" />Pearl<NODE id="9533" />, their engineers turned to <NODE id="9561" />MICROMO<NODE id="9568" /> to provide a precision motion solution using <NODE id="9614" />FAULHABER<NODE id="9623" /> stepper motors<NODE id="9638" /> with PRECIstep technology in a compact, lightweight assembly. [13] <NODE id="9706" />MICROMO<NODE id="9713" /> is pleased to announce the <NODE id="9741" />FAULHABER cutting-edge 15/10 planetary gearhead<NODE id="9788" /> series–the only standard high torque precision gearhead in a 15 mm diameter on the market today. [14] Robust, High Speed Motors for Medical and Dental Handpieces Clearwater, Florida Motion Control The new FAULHABER MICROMO 2057?BHS Brushless DC Servo Motors are designed to address the specific requirements of the medical and dental handpiece markets. [15] <NODE id="10147" />MICROMO<NODE id="10154" /> is pleased to present the <NODE id="10181" />3272 CR DC Micro Motor<NODE id="10203" /> from FAULHABER. [14] <NODE id="10225" />MICROMO<NODE id="10232" /> is pleased to announce the arrival of the new, high performance <NODE id="10297" />FAULHABER Series 1218?B Brushless DC Motor<NODE id="10339" />. [14] With the new <NODE id="10359" />FDM0620<NODE id="10366" /> series, <NODE id="10375" />MICROMO<NODE id="10382" /> presents a high performance FAULHABER stepper motor with minimal size. [16] Stepper motors are popular for these applications due a combination of high performance and small size; for example, Faulhaber offers products with diameters down to 6 mm and lengths of 9.5 mm. [17] Thanks to the sturdy construction, the FAULHABER metal Planetary Gearheads are ideal for applications which demand the highest torque. [14] The Namiki motor can be compared with the specifications of three alternative motors: a Ø 6.0 mm × 3.75 mm long motor manufactured by Maxon Motor (EC 6), a Ø 1.9 mm × 10.82 mm long micromotor manufactured by Faulhaber (02/1), and the Squiggle motor. [18] Clearwater, Florida Micro Motion Control Encoders The new <NODE id="11111" />IEH3?4096 series<NODE id="11127" /> from <NODE id="11133" />FAULHABER<NODE id="11142" /> is the most compact <NODE id="11163" />3 channel encoder<NODE id="11180" /> of its class. [15] Integrated encoder <NODE id="11219" />IEH3?4096<NODE id="11228" /> from <NODE id="11234" />FAULHABER<NODE id="11243" /> offers more functionality in a very small format. [19] A single <NODE id="11308" />micromotor<NODE id="11318" /> <NODE id="11319" />manufactured<NODE id="11331" /> by <NODE id="11335" />Faulhaber<NODE id="11344" /> (02/1) ( Table 2 ) has been selected to drive the holding mechanism ( Figure 5(a) ). [18] <NODE id="11435" />MICROMO<NODE id="11442" /> introduces the new <NODE id="11462" />32ALN (32A Low Noise) gearhead<NODE id="11492" /> from FAULHABER. [14] MICROMO, a member of the FAULHABER Group, has been a full service, value added partner to the medical and laboratory industry in North America for custom micro motion solutions for over 50 years. [20] MICROMO ?s benchmark contributions with custom motion solutions are a part of many leading applications such as a variety of medical device offerings, robotics technologies and aerospace and defense systems (including unmanned systems technologies). [20] Motion Control Application Hand-held, robotic surgical instrument that helps patients hurt less and heal faster, uses high torque Maxon motors. [15] Frameless motor technology helps make possible advanced mobility, manipulation and grasping, with significantly positive implications for robotics applications. [14] National Instruments announced that it is donating design tools to the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) to help expand the use of NI software and hardware in the MIT Department of Mechanical Engineering via 10 mechatronics, robotics, manufacturing, control and design courses over the next five years. [14] For over 20 years <NODE id="12621" />Elmo<NODE id="12625" /> has provided the robotics industry with comprehensive, powerful, precise, safe, and durable <NODE id="12718" />motion control solutions<NODE id="12742" /> – a selection of which will be shown at the RoboBusiness Leadership Summit 2012 (Pittsburgh, PA, U.S., Oct. 22-24). [14] Engineered for precision robotics and packaging automation applications, the 3200 C Controller with EtherCAT integrates motion control, robotics and PLC within one central control system. [14] Compact &amp; Lightweight yet Powerful Unit provides benefits for Mobility Equipment, Robotics &amp; Automation Applications; IP-54 Sealed, High Power, 12 Vdc Gearmotor Develops 136 Lb. [14] The QC-001 Micro Robotic Tool Changer, recently developed by ATI Industrial Automation, Apex, NC, is ideal for high-speed spider or parallel-link robots enhancing their ability to switch end-effectors automatically. [14] EASY Packaging Machine Automation presentation explores strategies to simplify motion control and robotics. [14] Projects or production cells are individual, customized solutions, which cover a variety of requirements in terms of the combination of ARBURG ALLROUNDER injection molding machine, robotic system and peripherals. [16] A solution that overcomes this problem is the robotic legged locomotion device developed by Valdastri et al. (2009). [18] Custom Endoscopy, Generator Interface, Single/Limited Use, Monitoring Device, Robotic and RF Generator Cables in all materials including Silicone Rubber. [16] The versatility of this unit allows for use in fully integrated robotic cells, as a standalone unit, or most any production line. [16] The DVC Series is the latest addition to the M/V? Family of Electric Mobility and Mobile Robotics motor controllers. [14] Both of these series allow the user to perform a variety of demanding applications including: automated assembly, bin picking, loading and unloading, robotic finishing, and more. [16] Introducing Design Machine &amp; Mfg.?s latest development, the R-1 Robotic Case Packer. [16] Bourbakis N., Giakos G., Karargyris A. Design of new-generation robotic capsules for therapeutic and diagnostic endoscopy. [18] Furthermore the design of the Rapid Load Magazine is perfect for pairing with automatic or robotic case loaders, giving the flexibility to our customers to further automate production lines. [16] Tribolube-VG-0 was created as a replacement gear box grease used in industrial robotics. [16] Robotic Industries Association (RIA) is hosting the International Collaborative Robots Workshop (#ICRW2014) on Tuesday, September 30 at the San Jose Convention Center in San Jose, California. [14] The Association for Advancing Automation (A3) announced today the keynote speakers for the Automate 2015 Conference / 46th International Symposium on Robotics, which will be held March 23-26, 2015 at McCormick Place in Chicago. [14] Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation; April 2005; pp. 1309-1314. [18] Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics (ROBIO '05); July 2005; IEEE; pp. 161-167. [18] Proceedings of the 1st IEEE/RAS-EMBS International Conference on Biomedical Robotics and Biomechatronics (BioRob '06); February 2006; Pisa, Italy. [18] The Robotic Industries Association (RIA), the trade association for the North American robotics industry, has launched a completely redesigned website. [14] North America?s robotics trade group, Robotic Industries Association (RIA), will host two major events in Pittsburgh this coming October. [14] The initial summer offerings run through August 14 and will provide opportunities for children to try their hands at scientific disciplines such as robotics, engineering, electronics, digital fabrication, programming, create problem solving, and more, in an atmosphere of fun and discovery. [21] For 2015, iRex is expanding to showcase some of the latest in robotic technology. [22] Joseph F. Engelberger, an engineer and entrepreneur who pioneered the robotics field, will turn 90 years old on July 26th. [14] <NODE id="16649" />National Instruments<NODE id="16669" /> and <NODE id="16674" />DENSO Robotics<NODE id="16688" /> announced their collaboration to integrate NI measurement and vision technology with <NODE id="16774" />DENSO<NODE id="16779" /> robotic arms. [14] This type of mobile robotic device should be used on a level surface. [23] The latency (about 18 ms) of the embedded visual processing algorithms used by the latter authors still limits the reactivity of the supporting aerial robotic platform. [24] The power of the controller allows for multiple robotic transformations to run simultaneously. [25] Honegger et al also developed an optical flow sensor for stabilizing a robotic platform hovering over a flat terrain, but the performances of this sensor over a rugged terrain or a slope were not documented. [24] ELMO HAR-A5/50CG WITH FAULHABER 3546K024BK312 DC MINIMOTOR GEAR HEAD ENCODER. Unit is used and is dismantled from decommissioned machine. [26] Manufacture: Faulhaber Model: 1516E012S Description: Faulhaber 1516E012S Minimotor SA Motor Gear 15/5 900:1 Ratio Condition: used good Details: vac29/test/1 Extra Info: 1lbs Please Fully Read. more our Policy If it's NOT in the picture. [26] You get two each of a Faulhaber Gear motor and shaft assembly. [26] The drive motor is a Faulhaber with these ID numbers: 21B12 K1405/ 1624E024S84/031218 474. [26] The item is 3 off miniature gearboxes for fitting to Faulhaber Electric motors. [26] MINIMOTOR SA 16/3 485:1 Precision Gearhead(Swiss made) with Faulhaber DC micromotor 1616E006S(Germany made) Micromotor with gearhead. 485 to 1 Gear Reduction. [26] Faulhaber Precision Minimotor 2MCH-K1292 + SCANCON Encoder 2MC-H2000-558125 Warranty! Your offers are Welcome 14 days warranty Payment in 7 days. [26] Rotating collectors must be mechanically connected to the drive (Minimotor SA, Faulhaber). [27] Faulhaber MCDC3003C and MCDC3006C drives use DB9M with no power. [28] MICROMO Introduces New FAULHABER 3890 DC Motor and 17/1 Series Planetary Gearhead MICROMO?s latest addition to the FAULHABER CR DC Motor series has a. [29] Manufacturer: Faulhaber Model: 2444(2444H0074) Condition: Used Price: The photos show. more the exact item(s) the buyer will receive. [26] Manufacturer: Faulhaber, Part Number: N/A, Model: 2444V0040, Notes: Sold as-is. [26] As shown in figure 3, the retinal micro-scanning movements are performed by a miniature eccentric mechanism based on a small stepper motor (Faulhaber ADM 0620-2R-V6-01, 1.7 grams in weight, 6 mm in diameter) connected to an off-centered shaft. [24] FAULHABER 3557K024CS MINIMOTOR SERVO MOTOR This auction is for one Faulhaber 3557K024CS. This unit is in excellent physical condition and will arrive in the condition shown. [26] The distance of the collector from the lower emitter electrode is adjusted by vertically repositioning the whole collector (using Minimotor SA, Faulhaber). [27] FAULHABER MINIMOTOR SA SWISS MADE 22/2 97.3:1 209 HIGH PRECISION MOTOR. High performance In a working condition. [26] FAULHABER MINIMOTOR 1516E012S RL 2211 + GEARHEAD 16AC 76:1 428 PRICE FOR: 5pcs of motors and 5pcs of gearhead More info on photo. [26] Nikon Rotary Assembly Sendai Nikon Rotary Encoder RMN1000&amp; FAULHABER MINIMOTOR SA_ Item used. [26] This auction is for Faulhaber Minimotor SA. 2224U012S Item is used and in fair cosmetic condition. [26] POSSIBLY USEFUL The FlexFeeder, in combination with ABB's Integrated Vision, allows the sorting of an array of components, ranging from 3 -30 mm, without having to change the feeder each time a different component is fed into the system. [3] The problem is that the displacement introduced by the piezo effect is only a fraction of a percent of component size, while the MRI robot required up to about 100 mm of linear travel or a continuous 360 degree rotation. [30] Headquartered in <NODE id="20386" />Clearwater<NODE id="20396" />, <NODE id="20398" />Florida<NODE id="20405" />, <NODE id="20407" />MICROMO Inc.<NODE id="20419" /> is the <NODE id="20427" />North American <NODE id="20442" />source for the world?s smallest high precision <NODE id="20489" />DC drive systems<NODE id="20505" />, <NODE id="20507" />components<NODE id="20517" />, and <NODE id="20523" />controls<NODE id="20531" />. [8] The mass of the spinning components will determine the torque (power) required to get the device in motion. [31] <NODE id="20650" />JVL's<NODE id="20655" /> wide selection of quality products for motion control components include: <NODE id="20730" />Integrated VAC<NODE id="20744" /> and <NODE id="20749" />VDC Servo motors<NODE id="20765" />, <NODE id="20767" />Integrated Stepper motors<NODE id="20792" />, <NODE id="20794" />VAC Servo motor controllers<NODE id="20821" />, <NODE id="20823" />Motor drivers<NODE id="20836" /> (Stepper, VAC and VDC), <NODE id="20861" />Brakes<NODE id="20867" />, <NODE id="20869" />Gears<NODE id="20874" />, and <NODE id="20880" />HMI Modules<NODE id="20891" />. [12] Flexible solutions are increasingly being used, specifically the mirrors are becoming thin and adjustable and the objective lens itself is designed through individual components to be movable. [12] Axis, Inc. is an authorized distributor for some of the leading manufacturers of components used in automating factories. [1] <NODE id="21222" />Visual Components<NODE id="21239" /> is the premier <NODE id="21255" />3D software<NODE id="21266" /> <NODE id="21267" />provider<NODE id="21275" /> to simulate and visualize all disciplines encountered within a manufacturing environment. [1] This bearing is extremely tough, is of one piece construction (no mechanical components, no catastrophic failure mode or shaft grooving) and has the longest life test we know of on record. [12] <NODE id="21564" />Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc.<NODE id="21594" /> has entered into an agreement with <NODE id="21630" />RotoPrecision Inc.<NODE id="21648" />, a <NODE id="21652" />Canadian<NODE id="21660" />-based provider of precision <NODE id="21689" />mechanical<NODE id="21699" /> and <NODE id="21704" />power transmission components<NODE id="21733" />, to become <NODE id="21745" />Ruland?s<NODE id="21753" /> master distributor in <NODE id="21776" />Canada<NODE id="21782" /> for <NODE id="21787" />Ruland?s<NODE id="21795" /> complete product range of <NODE id="21822" />shaft collars<NODE id="21835" /> and <NODE id="21840" />couplings<NODE id="21849" />. [14] As an ISO 9001, AS9100 and ISO 13485 certified specialists in deep drawn enclosures, <NODE id="21941" />National Manufacturing Company<NODE id="21971" /> has been producing <NODE id="21991" />precision deep drawn metal components<NODE id="22028" /> for its global customer base in aerospace, medical, military, satellite, battery and electronic industries for over 70 years. [16] The PDS-100 Programmable Dispenser is the solution for precision production fluid dispensing in the manufacture of medical components and diagnostic test kits. [16] <NODE id="22325" />Nordson MEDICAL<NODE id="22340" /> is adding these compliant components to its <NODE id="22385" />Value Plastics<NODE id="22399" /> product line portfolio, and connectors are ready to ship to device manufacturers for testing and qualification. [16] <NODE id="22517" />PRECISION EXTRUSION, INC.<NODE id="22542" /> a <NODE id="22545" />manufacturer<NODE id="22557" /> of <NODE id="22561" />specialized thermoplastic tubing components<NODE id="22604" /> for medical devices is pleased to announce that it also offers semi-finished products. [16] <NODE id="22697" />Matrix Tooling/Matrix Plastic Products<NODE id="22735" /> is an ISO 13485/9001 certified custom manufacturer of<NODE id="22789" /> critical plastic injection molded components<NODE id="22834" /> and assemblies, and the precision tooling required to produce them. [16] FTT Medical Inc. is a precision components manufacturer for the medical device industry. [16] Ltd. is a leading manufacturer of precision, complex-shaped component parts using metal injection molding (MIM), also known as powder injection molding (PIM); investment casting; and ceramic injection molding (CIM). [16] <NODE id="23223" />Johnson Matthey<NODE id="23238" /> is a leading <NODE id="23252" />manufacturer<NODE id="23264" /> of <NODE id="23268" />Precious Metal<NODE id="23282" /> and <NODE id="23287" />Nitinol components<NODE id="23305" /> supplying tube, sheet, wire, and micro-machined parts. [16] AUSTIN, Texas - <NODE id="23382" />National Instruments<NODE id="23402" /> (Nasdaq: NATI) today announced it is expanding its motion control offering through a collaboration with <NODE id="23507" />Kollmorgen<NODE id="23517" />, a leading global provider of <NODE id="23548" />motion systems<NODE id="23562" /> and components for OEMs. These products include drives, motors, linear positioners, gearheads, cables and accessories. [14] Download CAD components of maxon motor products and shorten your design times. [14] We also offer artwork design and component assembly services for all of these products. [16] From component and product design and development to the final assembly and sterilization – we are here to manage your next medical device program. [16] Miniature components lead to miniature products, which in turn spawn innovative new applications; trying to understand and prevent bee colony death, scientist and engineers at CSIRO, Australia's national science agency, have developed a monitoring system that uses RFID tags small enough to be attached to individual honey bees. [17] IMI Precision Engineering, experienced in both manifold and component technology, can help the OEMs maximize the advantages of manifolds by selecting the best system based on their application requirements. [16] Applications include Nitinol components for medical stent grafts, heart valve frames, implant delivery components, vascular stents, vascular closures/connectors, and catheter based deployment components. [16] Our materials are applied in various medical fields as well as in the industrial field as a component for other devices. [16] The VHX-5000 Digital Microscope is the most advanced optical tool for visualization and analysis available for the inspection of medical components and devices. [16] Specializing in <NODE id="25080" />complex injection molded thermoplastic<NODE id="25118" /> and <NODE id="25123" />silicone solutions<NODE id="25141" />, <NODE id="25143" />GW Plastics<NODE id="25154" /> provides concept-to-market contract manufacturing services with a focus on medical/surgical components, fully-assembled devices, and single-use consumables. [16] By manufacturing the <NODE id="25338" />motors<NODE id="25344" /> and the majority of the <NODE id="25369" />pump?s<NODE id="25375" /> components in-house, <NODE id="25397" />GRI<NODE id="25400" /> has the flexibility to precisely configure an Integrity Series pump to meet an OEM?s specific flow and pressure requirements. [16] <NODE id="25532" />Parker?s Electromechanical Automaton Division<NODE id="25577" /> is proud to announce that its <NODE id="25608" />MPP series traction motor<NODE id="25633" /> and inverter are integral components of a series-electric hybrid truck deployed by <NODE id="25717" />U.S. 1 Industries<NODE id="25734" /> to serve at the Port of Long Beach. [14] <NODE id="25776" />Mitsubishi Electric Automation, Inc.<NODE id="25812" /> introduces the <NODE id="25828" />GOT2000 Series<NODE id="25842" />, a <NODE id="25846" />human machine interface<NODE id="25869" /> (HMI) that monitors and controls machine components with a graphical touchscreen. [14] The majority of our business is medically oriented, so we understand your needs (medical packaging to medical machine components). [16] It was designed and developed specifically to suit the shaft to hub connection needs of small shafts and drive components in the motion control and power transmission markets. [16] Quick-clamping shaft collars – Easy adjustment for rapid setup or frequent change-over One of the simplest and consequently most overlooked components in the power transmission industry is the shaft collar. [14] Our manufacturing facility is equipped with state-of-the-art CNC machinery capable of producing the highest quality components offering the best possible prices and quickest delivery in the industry. [16] Our long standing reputation as a supplier of superb quality makes us a natural choice for manufacturing your critical sealing components. [16] For 35 years, Elytone has been a full service contract manufacturer of quality electronic components, assemblies and systems. [16] <NODE id="26966" />Kollmorgen<NODE id="26976" /> is exhibiting its family of high-performance <NODE id="27022" />motion systems<NODE id="27036" />, components and services in booth 7566 at PACK EXPO 2012, from October 28 – 31, 2012, at McCormick Place in <NODE id="27145" />Chicago<NODE id="27152" />, <NODE id="27154" />Illinois<NODE id="27162" />. [14] The optimized U-rail not only guides the movement of the slider being driven by the ballscrew, but also can be used as a structural component when assembled into a multi-axis motion system. [16] The pump head internals are made from chemically resistant, sapphire-hard ceramics, ideal for dispensing a broad range of fluids including solvents, acids, saline, peroxide, lubricants, and adhesives used to bond, sterilize and assemble disposable medical components. [16] <NODE id="27637" />Argotec LLC<NODE id="27648" /> <NODE id="27649" />engineers<NODE id="27658" /> &amp; <NODE id="27661" />manufactures<NODE id="27673" /> <NODE id="27674" />ArgoMed films<NODE id="27687" />, top-of-the-line medical-grade <NODE id="27719" />thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU) films<NODE id="27757" /> used for liquid &amp; viral barriers, wound care &amp; transdermal components, and waterproof-breathable medical textiles. [16] Specializations include multi-axis force and blade pressure sensors for medical pumps, custom strain gages for turning customer supplied parts into active sensing components, and scale assemblies for patient weighing and center of gravity calculations. [16] Pentagon Company is a manufacturer's representative bringing unique electromechanical components and processes to medical OEMs. The company's technologies include electroformed components and bellows manufactured by Servometer, and edge-welded metal bellows manufactured by BellowsTech. [16] Nitinol (nickel-titanium) is often the material of choice in medical components because of its biocompatibility and unique properties, such as shape memory, and super-elasticity achieved through heat processing and shape setting. [16] MICROMO ?s experienced engineers look beyond just components to offer solutions optimized for your device?s mechanics and electronics. [20] For faster, easier and more economical development of handling systems, Bosch Rexroth has published a new brochure describing the EasyHandling solution, a comprehensive platform of components, drives and engineering software. [14] <NODE id="29034" />Newport Corporation<NODE id="29053" /> reported that it has entered into a definitive agreement to <NODE id="29114" />acquire<NODE id="29121" /> <NODE id="29122" />ILX Lightwave Corporation (ILX)<NODE id="29153" />, a market and technology leader in high-performance <NODE id="29206" />test and Measurement solutions for laser diodes<NODE id="29253" /> and other photonics components. [14] <NODE id="29291" />Nexen Group Inc.<NODE id="29307" /> announces they have entered into a national distribution with <NODE id="29370" />Minarik Corporation<NODE id="29389" /> (Minarik) for <NODE id="29404" />Nexen?s<NODE id="29411" /> line of <NODE id="29420" />Precision Motion Control components<NODE id="29455" />. [14] Since 1963, SECS, Inc. has been manufacturing a wide variety of precision mechanical components and electro-mechanical assemblies. [16] DPMS provides precision machined and assembled components to the Medical Device, Aerospace/Defense, Commercial and Electronics Markets. [16] Laserage?s target market is components for medical devices made from precision laser-cut tube or flat materials. [16] Manufacturing prototype and production components for Class II &amp; Class III medical devices for development, testing, proof of concept &amp; clinical trials, let us quote your next project. [16] A consideration of the difficulty in manufacturing and assembling such small and complex components would need to be taken into account when designing such a mechanism. [18] Being the best supplier of servo motion control components and systems means providing customers with what they need, when and where they need it. [14] The alternating head operation results in smooth, level flow, reducing the need for additional dampening components for systems sensitive to pulsation. [16] E. Wire sets for computer and electronic products, various communication, automatic control system, digital appliances and its peripheral component. [16] Since 1955, ROMAC has been a world-class source for products whose components require high-temperature alloy metals, the sealing of these metals to ceramic or glass, and/or machine-enhanced stamping. [16] East Carolina University is using a Galil DMC 4143 multi-axis motion controller to power components of the Sonic Plaza, a multimedia art piece on campus. [14] Shaft collars are one of the most versatile machine components with a variety of uses including positioning, guiding, stopping, clamping, and spacing. [14] These pin-and-receptacle fasteners are used to attach fixtures, plates, machine covers and more, joining the components with moderate clamping force. [16] Each machine incorporates flame-hardened and ground cast iron box ways with hand-scraped and fitted mating components (versus linear guide ways and milled surfaces). [16] Each machine incorporates a cast iron drill head base with hardened and ground steel box ways, plus hand-scraped and fitted mating components (versus linear guide ways and milled surfaces). [16] Seamlessly acquire full internal and external measurements of your components with the CXMM 50, a true X-ray based coordinate measuring machine. [16] For hygienic reasons, electric components must meet protection IP68 or IP69K. <NODE id="31953" />HBM<NODE id="31956" /> offers a <NODE id="31966" />hermetically encapsulated load cell<NODE id="32001" /> <NODE id="32002" />PW25<NODE id="32006" /> specifically for such applications. [16] In this article we will discuss a few of the components that have arisen in response to this challenge, as well as some applications that smaller sizes have made possible. [17] These miniature components are impressive enough, but the expansion of the IoT over the next few years will accelerate the shrinkage, with connectivity finding its way into successively smaller and smaller devices. [17] <NODE id="32445" />Parker Hannifin Corporation's<NODE id="32474" /> <NODE id="32475" />Parker Aerospace<NODE id="32491" /> today announced that it has <NODE id="32520" />acquired<NODE id="32528" /> <NODE id="32529" />Shaw Aero Devices, Inc.<NODE id="32552" /> a producer of aerospace components and equipment. [14] These components are color-coded which provides instant identification of sizes; light pink (40 mm), blue (50 mm), black (60 mm), white (70 mm), green (80 mm), yellow (90 mm), dark pink (100 mm), and orange (110 mm). [16] We provide the most advanced form-fill-seal packaging equipment with state of the art components that are easily purchased as off the shelf spare parts around the world. [16] However there were a number of issues with individual component parts and with the assembly of the parts which required addressing before a working prototype could be realised. [18] Molded components range in size from 7cm with micro features down to parts less than 1mm in size. [16] Figure 4 shows a section view through the component parts of the needle positioning mechanism. [18] The actuator comprises three main component parts: a microspike for taking the biopsy, a torsion spring actuator, and an SMA heating wire triggering mechanism. [18] The smaller laser spot with excellent detail resolution is ideal for manufacturing highly complex, sophisticated DMLS components. [16] However increasing the size of the components would make manufacturing generally easier. [18] This patented keyless shaft to hub connection system enables customers to easily phase, install, adjust and remove drive components, all while offering precise component positioning. [16] This process allows us to produce precision, complex components with features like undercuts etc. Some advantages of this process are low tooling costs, fast cycle times and quick die changes. [16] The beam quality and stable performance of the 200 watt fibre laser guarantee optimum, constant processing conditions for the production of high-quality components. [16] Complete line of quality compressors, dryers, filters and drain traps; rotary lobe blowers, vacuum pumps and other compressed air system components. [16] In terms of process and component quality, it corresponds to the EOS M 290, the leading system on the market for Direct Metal Laser Sintering (DMLS). [16] Carlisle Medical Technologies is the new global leader in medical device components. [16] PMC has been a FDA inspected and ISO 13485 certified contract OEM and component supplier of medical devices since 1993. [16] The industry?s leading companies rely on us to successfully bring their complex medical devices and components to market. [16] The new EXC-Series 2.3-inch AC Servo Motors, are high voltage, high performance brushless servo motors incorporating the latest electro-magnetic components creating high continuous torques with low inertia for rapid acceleration. [14] Setting new standards for compact drive systems, all components (including connections) are in a housing that measures just 9.7 mm in length and 6 mm in diameter. [16] Designers can design components with features you cant achieve with conventional die cast methods. [16] A completely modular design allows for easy expansion from a 2-component system up to a 4 component system. [16] We also provide key components for inclusion into the kits you manufacture, such as surgical drapes &amp; gowns, instruments, and many more critical items. [16] <NODE id="35768" />Qosina<NODE id="35774" /> offers a variety of <NODE id="35795" />luers<NODE id="35800" /> and <NODE id="35805" />tubing<NODE id="35811" /> along with thousands of single-use components. [19] <NODE id="35864" />Qosina<NODE id="35870" /> offers a variety of respiratory components in addition to thousands of single-use components. [16] <NODE id="35970" />Parylene<NODE id="35978" /> offers exceptional surface protection of delicate components. [16] Purpose-built protocols and ruggedized components yield robust industrial wireless networks. [14] All-encompassing expertise from kit assembly, component selection, sterilization, and logistics means zero compromise. [16] Injection molding components are economical and fast turnaround prototyping 3-D modeling offered at low costs. [16] A universally portable multiple component injection molding system to create a closure / cap with a molded-in gasket and septum. [16] Technology advances such as laser manufacturing allow <NODE id="36572" />JM<NODE id="36574" /> to <NODE id="36578" />produce<NODE id="36585" /> high quality <NODE id="36599" />electrodes<NODE id="36609" />, <NODE id="36611" />markers<NODE id="36618" />, and other complex metal and plastic components. [16] Accumold is a high-tech manufacturer of precision micro, small and lead frame injection molded plastic components. [16] PTI Engineered Plastics is a custom injection molder and manufacturer of plastic components and assemblies. [16] Phasa has enhanced the performance of its specialist plastic component joining machines with high performance new versions employing a key servo-based motion control system in place of a pneumatic actuator. [14] ADVANCED Motion Controls servo drives are compatible with ANY Motor, ANY Controller, ANY Feedback and ANY I/O which means you don't have to get locked into any particular component manufacturer when designing your system. [25] For your convenience we have compiled this list of 3 rd party component manufacturers that are known to work with our servo drives. [25] The main reason for this is that the process of nanomaterials manufacturing is influenced by numerous processing parameters which need to be properly regulated, and furthermore all device components must be resistant to interference from high voltage. [27] The examples also show an automatic increase in airflow speed after the conclusion of the spinning process that speeds up cooling of the internal components of the device. [27] The rotational component introduced by the rotating arm supporting the robot can be neglected in this study. [24] At each time step, we projected the position vector into the robot frame and took only the tangential components of the displacement. [24] Armed with even with the most-sophisticated motion controller, engineers can still find it difficult to attain precise linear motion unless the mechanical components. [32] If you interested in the components: the shaft is.187″ dia on the pulley end. 156″ on the encoder end X 1.73″ long, with 2 each.375″ od X.156″ id X.154″ wide ball bearings(I bought 2 similar bearings for $12 awhile back and they were so sloppy I couldn't use them for my app-these are way better) and a.315″od overrunning/backstop/one way sprag type clutch, a.465″ pulley for round belt with some type of occilator grove behind the pulley grove. [26] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (32 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) Related Related Articles
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/8f250600-1d4f-3bc1-b0b3-a5328a92cad1" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T21:18:37Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:29:26.891Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/faulhaber-robotics-components/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="385" endPos="398" type="organization-company" surface="Rise Robotics" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="399" endPos="406" type="provide-type" surface="invents" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="408" endPos="416" type="provide-type" surface="develops" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="422" endPos="434" type="provide-type" surface="manufactures" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="441" endPos="457" type="product-class" surface="power components" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="511" endPos="517" type="organization-company" surface="Kinova" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="518" endPos="525" type="provide-type" surface="designs" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="530" endPos="542" type="provide-type" surface="manufactures" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="543" endPos="561" type="product-class" surface="robotics platforms" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="566" endPos="576" type="product-class" surface="components" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="964" endPos="971" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1039" endPos="1079" type="product-class" surface="linear and rotary micro motion solutions" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1444" endPos="1462" type="organization-company" surface="Jabez Technologies" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="1472" endPos="1502" type="product-class" surface="robot programming technologies" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="1605" endPos="1616" type="product" surface="Robotmaster" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="1644" endPos="1662" type="organization-company" surface="Jabez Technologies" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="1686" endPos="1764" type="organization-company" surface="programming technologies for industrial automation, manufacturing and robotics" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="1771" endPos="1775" type="date" surface="1996" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="2248" endPos="2260" type="organization-company" surface="IPR Robotics" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2284" endPos="2318" type="product" surface="servo-driven 7th axis linear rails" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="2805" endPos="2814" type="organization-company" surface="RobotShop" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="2826" endPos="2860" type="product" surface="Lynxmotion robotic arms &amp; grippers" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="3182" endPos="3189" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="3240" endPos="3261" type="product" surface="FAULHABER CR DC Motor" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="3807" endPos="3814" type="product" surface="MICROMO" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="3865" endPos="3886" type="product" surface="FAULHABER CR DC Motor" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="6148" endPos="6153" type="organization-company" surface="Vecna" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="6200" endPos="6224" type="product-class" surface="autonomous mobile robots" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="6262" endPos="6278" type="organization-company" surface="Universal Robots" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="6341" endPos="6351" type="product-class" surface="robot arms" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="6438" endPos="6448" type="organization-company" surface="Rocketfarm" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="6483" endPos="6494" type="provide-type" surface="development" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="6502" endPos="6518" type="product-class" surface="robotic services" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="6529" endPos="6541" type="product-class" surface="camera robot" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="6991" endPos="7007" type="organization-company" surface="Rethink Robotics" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="7121" endPos="7127" type="product-class" surface="robots" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="7241" endPos="7246" type="organization-company" surface="Jetta" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="7260" endPos="7263" type="provide-type" surface="ODM" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="7264" endPos="7267" type="provide-type" surface="OEM" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="7312" endPos="7323" type="product-class" surface="electronics" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="7325" endPos="7333" type="product-class" surface="robotics" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="7335" endPos="7339" type="product-class" surface="toys" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="7341" endPos="7365" type="product-class" surface="infant/juvenile products" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="7367" endPos="7382" type="product-class" surface="home appliances" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="7384" endPos="7389" type="product-class" surface="tools" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="7391" endPos="7398" type="product-class" surface="vacuums" />
<Entity id="46" startPos="7400" endPos="7413" type="product-class" surface="wearable tech" />
<Entity id="47" startPos="7950" endPos="7958" type="organization-company" surface="RoboKind" />
<Entity id="48" startPos="8003" endPos="8040" type="product-class" surface="expressive facial robotics technology" />
<Entity id="49" startPos="8046" endPos="8054" type="organization-company" surface="CoroWare" />
<Entity id="50" startPos="8149" endPos="8175" type="product" surface="CoroBot Spark robotics kit" />
<Entity id="51" startPos="8181" endPos="8189" type="organization-company" surface="CoroWare" />
<Entity id="52" startPos="8254" endPos="8269" type="product-class" surface="mobile robotics" />
<Entity id="53" startPos="8326" endPos="8355" type="product" surface="Ava? mobile robotics platform" />
<Entity id="54" startPos="8357" endPos="8363" type="organization-company" surface="iRobot" />
<Entity id="55" startPos="9220" endPos="9235" type="organization-company" surface="FAULHABER Group" />
<Entity id="56" startPos="9295" endPos="9340" type="person_group" surface="miniature and micro drive system technologies" />
<Entity id="57" startPos="9397" endPos="9412" type="product-class" surface="aesthetic laser" />
<Entity id="58" startPos="9413" endPos="9425" type="provide-type" surface="manufacturer" />
<Entity id="59" startPos="9427" endPos="9438" type="organization-company" surface="Cutera Inc." />
<Entity id="60" startPos="9446" endPos="9454" type="location" surface="Brisbane" />
<Entity id="61" startPos="9456" endPos="9458" type="location" surface="CA" />
<Entity id="62" startPos="9468" endPos="9475" type="provide-type" surface="develop" />
<Entity id="63" startPos="9494" endPos="9516" type="product-class" surface="skin-resurfacing laser" />
<Entity id="64" startPos="9528" endPos="9533" type="product" surface="Pearl" />
<Entity id="65" startPos="9561" endPos="9568" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO" />
<Entity id="66" startPos="9614" endPos="9623" type="organization-company" surface="FAULHABER" />
<Entity id="67" startPos="9614" endPos="9638" type="product-class" surface="FAULHABER stepper motors" />
<Entity id="68" startPos="9706" endPos="9713" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO" />
<Entity id="69" startPos="9741" endPos="9788" type="product" surface="FAULHABER cutting-edge 15/10 planetary gearhead" />
<Entity id="70" startPos="10147" endPos="10154" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO" />
<Entity id="71" startPos="10181" endPos="10203" type="product" surface="3272 CR DC Micro Motor" />
<Entity id="72" startPos="10225" endPos="10232" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO" />
<Entity id="73" startPos="10297" endPos="10339" type="product" surface="FAULHABER Series 1218?B Brushless DC Motor" />
<Entity id="74" startPos="10359" endPos="10366" type="product" surface="FDM0620" />
<Entity id="75" startPos="10375" endPos="10382" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO" />
<Entity id="76" startPos="11111" endPos="11127" type="product" surface="IEH3?4096 series" />
<Entity id="77" startPos="11133" endPos="11142" type="organization-company" surface="FAULHABER" />
<Entity id="78" startPos="11163" endPos="11180" type="product-class" surface="3 channel encoder" />
<Entity id="79" startPos="11219" endPos="11228" type="product" surface="IEH3?4096" />
<Entity id="80" startPos="11234" endPos="11243" type="organization-company" surface="FAULHABER" />
<Entity id="81" startPos="11308" endPos="11318" type="product-class" surface="micromotor" />
<Entity id="82" startPos="11319" endPos="11331" type="type" surface="manufactured" />
<Entity id="83" startPos="11335" endPos="11344" type="organization-company" surface="Faulhaber" />
<Entity id="84" startPos="11435" endPos="11442" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO" />
<Entity id="85" startPos="11462" endPos="11492" type="product" surface="32ALN (32A Low Noise) gearhead" />
<Entity id="86" startPos="12621" endPos="12625" type="organization-company" surface="Elmo" />
<Entity id="87" startPos="12718" endPos="12742" type="provide-type" surface="motion control solutions" />
<Entity id="88" startPos="16649" endPos="16669" type="organization-company" surface="National Instruments" />
<Entity id="89" startPos="16674" endPos="16688" type="organization-company" surface="DENSO Robotics" />
<Entity id="90" startPos="16774" endPos="16779" type="organization-company" surface="DENSO" />
<Entity id="91" startPos="20386" endPos="20396" type="location" surface="Clearwater" />
<Entity id="92" startPos="20398" endPos="20405" type="location" surface="Florida" />
<Entity id="93" startPos="20407" endPos="20419" type="organization-company" surface="MICROMO Inc." />
<Entity id="94" startPos="20427" endPos="20442" type="location" surface="North American " />
<Entity id="95" startPos="20489" endPos="20505" type="product-class" surface="DC drive systems" />
<Entity id="96" startPos="20507" endPos="20517" type="product-class" surface="components" />
<Entity id="97" startPos="20523" endPos="20531" type="product-class" surface="controls" />
<Entity id="98" startPos="20650" endPos="20655" type="organization_group" surface="JVL's" />
<Entity id="99" startPos="20730" endPos="20744" type="product-class" surface="Integrated VAC" />
<Entity id="100" startPos="20749" endPos="20765" type="product-class" surface="VDC Servo motors" />
<Entity id="101" startPos="20767" endPos="20792" type="product-class" surface="Integrated Stepper motors" />
<Entity id="102" startPos="20794" endPos="20821" type="product-class" surface="VAC Servo motor controllers" />
<Entity id="103" startPos="20823" endPos="20836" type="product-class" surface="Motor drivers" />
<Entity id="104" startPos="20861" endPos="20867" type="product-class" surface="Brakes" />
<Entity id="105" startPos="20869" endPos="20874" type="product-class" surface="Gears" />
<Entity id="106" startPos="20880" endPos="20891" type="product-class" surface="HMI Modules" />
<Entity id="107" startPos="21222" endPos="21239" type="organization-company" surface="Visual Components" />
<Entity id="108" startPos="21255" endPos="21266" type="product-class" surface="3D software" />
<Entity id="109" startPos="21267" endPos="21275" type="provide-type" surface="provider" />
<Entity id="110" startPos="21564" endPos="21594" type="organization-company" surface="Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc." />
<Entity id="111" startPos="21630" endPos="21648" type="organization-company" surface="RotoPrecision Inc." />
<Entity id="112" startPos="21652" endPos="21660" type="location" surface="Canadian" />
<Entity id="113" startPos="21689" endPos="21699" type="product-class" surface="mechanical" />
<Entity id="114" startPos="21704" endPos="21733" type="product-class" surface="power transmission components" />
<Entity id="115" startPos="21745" endPos="21753" type="organization-company" surface="Ruland?s" />
<Entity id="116" startPos="21776" endPos="21782" type="location" surface="Canada" />
<Entity id="117" startPos="21787" endPos="21795" type="organization-company" surface="Ruland?s" />
<Entity id="118" startPos="21822" endPos="21835" type="product-class" surface="shaft collars" />
<Entity id="119" startPos="21840" endPos="21849" type="product-class" surface="couplings" />
<Entity id="120" startPos="21941" endPos="21971" type="organization-company" surface="National Manufacturing Company" />
<Entity id="121" startPos="21991" endPos="22028" type="organization-company" surface="precision deep drawn metal components" />
<Entity id="122" startPos="22325" endPos="22340" type="organization-company" surface="Nordson MEDICAL" />
<Entity id="123" startPos="22385" endPos="22399" type="product" surface="Value Plastics" />
<Entity id="124" startPos="22517" endPos="22542" type="organization-company" surface="PRECISION EXTRUSION, INC." />
<Entity id="125" startPos="22545" endPos="22557" type="provide-type" surface="manufacturer" />
<Entity id="126" startPos="22561" endPos="22604" type="product-class" surface="specialized thermoplastic tubing components" />
<Entity id="127" startPos="22697" endPos="22735" type="organization-company" surface="Matrix Tooling/Matrix Plastic Products" />
<Entity id="128" startPos="22789" endPos="22834" type="product-class" surface=" critical plastic injection molded components" />
<Entity id="129" startPos="23223" endPos="23238" type="organization-company" surface="Johnson Matthey" />
<Entity id="130" startPos="23252" endPos="23264" type="provide-type" surface="manufacturer" />
<Entity id="131" startPos="23268" endPos="23282" type="product-class" surface="Precious Metal" />
<Entity id="132" startPos="23287" endPos="23305" type="product-class" surface="Nitinol components" />
<Entity id="133" startPos="23382" endPos="23402" type="organization-company" surface="National Instruments" />
<Entity id="134" startPos="23507" endPos="23517" type="organization-company" surface="Kollmorgen" />
<Entity id="135" startPos="23548" endPos="23562" type="product-class" surface="motion systems" />
<Entity id="136" startPos="25080" endPos="25118" type="product-class" surface="complex injection molded thermoplastic" />
<Entity id="137" startPos="25123" endPos="25141" type="product-class" surface="silicone solutions" />
<Entity id="138" startPos="25143" endPos="25154" type="organization-company" surface="GW Plastics" />
<Entity id="139" startPos="25338" endPos="25344" type="product-class" surface="motors" />
<Entity id="140" startPos="25369" endPos="25375" type="product-class" surface="pump?s" />
<Entity id="141" startPos="25397" endPos="25400" type="organization-company" surface="GRI" />
<Entity id="142" startPos="25532" endPos="25577" type="organization-company" surface="Parker?s Electromechanical Automaton Division" />
<Entity id="143" startPos="25608" endPos="25633" type="product" surface="MPP series traction motor" />
<Entity id="144" startPos="25717" endPos="25734" type="organization-company" surface="U.S. 1 Industries" />
<Entity id="145" startPos="25776" endPos="25812" type="organization-company" surface="Mitsubishi Electric Automation, Inc." />
<Entity id="146" startPos="25828" endPos="25842" type="product" surface="GOT2000 Series" />
<Entity id="147" startPos="25846" endPos="25869" type="product-class" surface="human machine interface" />
<Entity id="148" startPos="26966" endPos="26976" type="organization-company" surface="Kollmorgen" />
<Entity id="149" startPos="27022" endPos="27036" type="product-class" surface="motion systems" />
<Entity id="150" startPos="27145" endPos="27152" type="location" surface="Chicago" />
<Entity id="151" startPos="27154" endPos="27162" type="location" surface="Illinois" />
<Entity id="152" startPos="27637" endPos="27648" type="organization-company" surface="Argotec LLC" />
<Entity id="153" startPos="27649" endPos="27658" type="provide-type" surface="engineers" />
<Entity id="154" startPos="27661" endPos="27673" type="provide-type" surface="manufactures" />
<Entity id="155" startPos="27674" endPos="27687" type="product" surface="ArgoMed films" />
<Entity id="156" startPos="27719" endPos="27757" type="product-class" surface="thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU) films" />
<Entity id="157" startPos="29034" endPos="29053" type="organization-company" surface="Newport Corporation" />
<Entity id="158" startPos="29114" endPos="29121" type="trigger" surface="acquire" />
<Entity id="159" startPos="29122" endPos="29153" type="organization-company" surface="ILX Lightwave Corporation (ILX)" />
<Entity id="160" startPos="29206" endPos="29253" type="product-class" surface="test and Measurement solutions for laser diodes" />
<Entity id="161" startPos="29291" endPos="29307" type="organization-company" surface="Nexen Group Inc." />
<Entity id="162" startPos="29370" endPos="29389" type="organization-company" surface="Minarik Corporation" />
<Entity id="163" startPos="29404" endPos="29411" type="organization-company" surface="Nexen?s" />
<Entity id="164" startPos="29420" endPos="29455" type="product-class" surface="Precision Motion Control components" />
<Entity id="165" startPos="31953" endPos="31956" type="organization-company" surface="HBM" />
<Entity id="166" startPos="31966" endPos="32001" type="product-class" surface="hermetically encapsulated load cell" />
<Entity id="167" startPos="32002" endPos="32006" type="product" surface="PW25" />
<Entity id="168" startPos="32445" endPos="32474" type="organization-company" surface="Parker Hannifin Corporation's" />
<Entity id="169" startPos="32475" endPos="32491" type="organization-company" surface="Parker Aerospace" />
<Entity id="170" startPos="32520" endPos="32528" type="trigger" surface="acquired" />
<Entity id="171" startPos="32529" endPos="32552" type="organization-company" surface="Shaw Aero Devices, Inc." />
<Entity id="172" startPos="35768" endPos="35774" type="organization-company" surface="Qosina" />
<Entity id="173" startPos="35795" endPos="35800" type="product-class" surface="luers" />
<Entity id="174" startPos="35805" endPos="35811" type="product-class" surface="tubing" />
<Entity id="175" startPos="35864" endPos="35870" type="organization-company" surface="Qosina" />
<Entity id="176" startPos="35970" endPos="35978" type="organization-company" surface="Parylene" />
<Entity id="177" startPos="36572" endPos="36574" type="organization-company" surface="JM" />
<Entity id="178" startPos="36578" endPos="36585" type="provide-type" surface="produce" />
<Entity id="179" startPos="36599" endPos="36609" type="product-class" surface="electrodes" />
<Entity id="180" startPos="36611" endPos="36618" type="product-class" surface="markers" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="181" NAME="Acquisition">
<Entity id="158" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="159" label="acquired" />
<Entity id="157" label="buyer" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="182" NAME="Acquisition">
<Entity id="170" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="171" label="acquired" />
<Entity id="169" label="buyer" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="183" NAME="CompanyBusinessRelationship">
<Entity id="67" label="product" />
<Entity id="65" label="vendor" />
<Entity id="59" label="customer" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="184" NAME="CompanyBusinessRelationship">
<Entity id="143" label="product" />
<Entity id="142" label="vendor" />
<Entity id="144" label="customer" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="185" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="1" label="type" />
<Entity id="2" label="type" />
<Entity id="3" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="186" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="8" label="product" />
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
<Entity id="6" label="type" />
<Entity id="7" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="187" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="188" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="13" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="189" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="14" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="190" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="16" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="191" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="19" label="product" />
<Entity id="18" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="192" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="21" label="product" />
<Entity id="20" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="193" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="23" label="product" />
<Entity id="22" label="location" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="194" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="27" label="product" />
<Entity id="26" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="195" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="29" label="product" />
<Entity id="28" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="196" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="33" label="product" />
<Entity id="32" label="product" />
<Entity id="30" label="company" />
<Entity id="31" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="197" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="35" label="product" />
<Entity id="34" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="198" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="40" label="product" />
<Entity id="44" label="product" />
<Entity id="46" label="product" />
<Entity id="43" label="product" />
<Entity id="45" label="product" />
<Entity id="42" label="product" />
<Entity id="39" label="product" />
<Entity id="41" label="product" />
<Entity id="36" label="company" />
<Entity id="38" label="type" />
<Entity id="37" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="199" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="48" label="product" />
<Entity id="47" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="200" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="50" label="product" />
<Entity id="49" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="201" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="52" label="product" />
<Entity id="51" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="202" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="53" label="product" />
<Entity id="54" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="203" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="56" label="product" />
<Entity id="55" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="204" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="57" label="product" />
<Entity id="59" label="company" />
<Entity id="58" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="205" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="64" label="product" />
<Entity id="63" label="product" />
<Entity id="59" label="company" />
<Entity id="62" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="206" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="69" label="product" />
<Entity id="68" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="207" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="71" label="product" />
<Entity id="70" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="208" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="73" label="product" />
<Entity id="72" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="209" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="74" label="product" />
<Entity id="75" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="210" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="76" label="product" />
<Entity id="78" label="product" />
<Entity id="77" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="211" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="79" label="product" />
<Entity id="80" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="212" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="81" label="product" />
<Entity id="83" label="company" />
<Entity id="82" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="213" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="85" label="product" />
<Entity id="84" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="214" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="87" label="product" />
<Entity id="86" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="215" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="96" label="product" />
<Entity id="97" label="product" />
<Entity id="95" label="product" />
<Entity id="93" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="216" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="101" label="product" />
<Entity id="99" label="product" />
<Entity id="100" label="product" />
<Entity id="98" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="217" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="108" label="product" />
<Entity id="107" label="company" />
<Entity id="109" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="218" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="113" label="product" />
<Entity id="114" label="product" />
<Entity id="111" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="219" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="118" label="product" />
<Entity id="119" label="product" />
<Entity id="117" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="220" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="121" label="product" />
<Entity id="120" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="221" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="123" label="product" />
<Entity id="122" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="222" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="126" label="product" />
<Entity id="124" label="company" />
<Entity id="125" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="223" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="128" label="product" />
<Entity id="127" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="224" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="131" label="product" />
<Entity id="132" label="product" />
<Entity id="129" label="company" />
<Entity id="130" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="225" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="135" label="product" />
<Entity id="134" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="226" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="136" label="product" />
<Entity id="137" label="product" />
<Entity id="138" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="227" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="140" label="product" />
<Entity id="139" label="product" />
<Entity id="141" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="228" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="143" label="product" />
<Entity id="142" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="229" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="147" label="product" />
<Entity id="146" label="product" />
<Entity id="145" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="230" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="149" label="product" />
<Entity id="148" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="231" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="155" label="product" />
<Entity id="156" label="product" />
<Entity id="152" label="company" />
<Entity id="154" label="type" />
<Entity id="153" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="232" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="160" label="product" />
<Entity id="159" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="233" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="164" label="product" />
<Entity id="163" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="234" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="167" label="product" />
<Entity id="166" label="product" />
<Entity id="165" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="235" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="174" label="product" />
<Entity id="173" label="product" />
<Entity id="172" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="236" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="180" label="product" />
<Entity id="179" label="product" />
<Entity id="178" label="type" />
<Entity id="177" label="customer" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="237" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="168" label="parent" />
<Entity id="169" label="child" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
