<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Digimarc to Showcase GS1 US Collaboration, Growing Partner Ecosystem at NRF 2016 Industry leading suppliers embrace Digimarc Barcode Digimarc The Barcode of Everything(TM) Facebook Twitter Pinterest Digimarc The Barcode of Everything(TM) BEAVERTON, Ore. and NEW YORK Jan. 12, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- NRF Booth #1201 --<NODE id="315" /> Digimarc Corp.<NODE id="330" /> (NASDAQ: DMRC ), <NODE id="348" />inventor<NODE id="356" /> of the <NODE id="364" />Digimarc Barcode<NODE id="380" />, announced that the company's presentation at the National Retail Federation's 2016 Big Show, being held at the Javits Center in <NODE id="510" />New York City<NODE id="523" /> <NODE id="524" />January 17-19<NODE id="537" /> , will introduce major new market development partners, including <NODE id="604" />GS1 US<NODE id="610" /> and leading retail scanner vendors. <NODE id="647" />Digimarc's<NODE id="657" /> progress will be on display in numerous locations around the show, evidencing growing support for its ground-breaking <NODE id="776" />Digimarc Discover® software<NODE id="803" /> and <NODE id="808" />Digimarc Barcode<NODE id="824" />. <NODE id="826" />Digimarc® Discover<NODE id="844" /> is the world's best scanning software for smartphones. The Discover mobile software development kit lets developers integrate scanning of UPC/EAN codes, other 1D and 2D consumer barcode formats commonly used at retail, and Digimarc Barcodes, into retailer and other consumer engagement applications. The software offers unprecedented performance and seamless scanning of multiple barcode formats, making identification of products by mobile consumers easier and more reliable than ever. Inclusion of detection of Digimarc Barcodes for print, packaging and audio means application developers get the best performance with today's dominant formats while 'future-proofing' their apps for increasing adoption of the Digimarc Barcode. Digimarc Barcodes are invisible; thus, can be replicated across all sides of a package, facilitating significant improvements in speed and accuracy at checkout for retailers and new engagement experiences for brands with consumers. Attendees are encouraged to visit Booth 1201, and the exhibits of numerous business partners, to experience Digimarc Barcode – The Barcode of Everything™ – for themselves. Digimarc Barcode enhances objects by giving them a pervasive network identity. Digimarc Discover software enables reliable and efficient discovery of enabled items. The combination of Digimarc Discover and Digimarc Barcode constitutes a platform that does everything traditional barcodes do better. The blossoming of this new generation barcode will be on display in Digimarc's booth.  Demonstrations will include leading scanning vendors, major product packaging print partners, and customers. Representatives from industry association GS1 US will be available to share their vision of how the Digimarc platform will address many concerns and opportunities of retailers. Visitors can also participate in a friendly competition, with a real-time leaderboard and daily prizes for the fastest scanning. Demonstrations and testimonials at the show will include: Industry Association Collaboration (Digimarc Booth 1201): Digimarc and GS1 US, the U.S. operation of the organization that maintains the global standards for barcodes, have announced a broad collaboration to help the industries served by GS1 to make effective use of Digimarc Barcode. GS1 US will educate, train and provide access to services to their 300,000 member businesses. Among other things, Digimarc and GS1 US intend to improve product identification for retailers and consumers with brand-certified, accurate product information via Digimarc Barcodes. Retail Scanner Suppliers: The Digimarc booth will have demonstrations of in-counter and handheld scanners from leading original equipment manufacturers (OEMs) of retail POS systems. Attendees can do hands-on evaluation of Digimarc Barcode performance improvements using scanners from Datalogic, Honeywell, NCR and others. Digimarc Barcode will also be featured in exhibits: Datalogic (Booth 3619): <NODE id="3798" />Datalogic<NODE id="3807" /> is the global leader in <NODE id="3832" />stationary POS scanners<NODE id="3855" /> with over fifty percent market share worldwide.  It was the first manufacturer to implement and deploy Digimarc Barcode decoding on retail scanners, industrial mobile computers, and handheld scanners. Honeywell (Booth 1543): <NODE id="4081" />Honeywell's<NODE id="4092" /> <NODE id="4093" />Xenon 1900 handheld barcode scanner<NODE id="4128" />, an entry-level <NODE id="4145" />Digimarc reader<NODE id="4160" />, features a custom image sensor that improves scanning aggressiveness and reliability. This area imager features image process software that offers advanced editing functionality, which produces high-quality digital images. Together with the Digimarc Barcode, the Xenon 1900 scanner removes the need for customers or store associates to locate and scan a traditional UPC or QR code, which enables a faster checkout experience. NCR (Booth 3105): RealScan™ 78 Bi-Optic Scanners can be upgraded to support Digimarc's new barcode technology, continuing to protect your investment. Microsoft (Booth 2803): Microsoft will demonstrate its vision for modern POS scanning, using Digimarc Barcodes. A Datalogic Magellan 9800, Microsoft Surface 4, and real product packaging will allow attendees to experience the combination of Digimarc technology with Microsoft's retail software solutions. Brand Deployment: Digimarc has partnered with leading brand deployment and pre-media service providers SGS and Schawk to offer Digimarc Barcode services to national and store brand owners and consumer products suppliers. Examples of Digimarc-enhanced packaging will be available at the Digimarc booth. Generic Pharmaceuticals: <NODE id="5370" />Perrigo<NODE id="5377" />, the world's largest <NODE id="5399" />manufacturer<NODE id="5411" /> of over-the-counter <NODE id="5432" />pharmaceutical products<NODE id="5455" /> for the store brand market, has <NODE id="5488" />adopted<NODE id="5495" /> <NODE id="5496" />Digimarc Barcode<NODE id="5512" /> to improve point-of-sale efficiency for retailers and provide consumers easier access to product information from enabled 'smart' labels. Variable-Weight Products: A considerable amount of grocery purchases involve variable-weight items, such as in deli. <NODE id="5768" />Bizerba<NODE id="5775" /> (Booth 2983), a leading <NODE id="5800" />manufacturer<NODE id="5812" /> of <NODE id="5816" />retail scales<NODE id="5829" />, <NODE id="5831" />slicers<NODE id="5838" /> and <NODE id="5843" />weigh price labeling equipment<NODE id="5873" /> for grocery, will demonstrate variable weight product labels enhanced with Digimarc Barcode. SPARC Mobile App for Walmart: Digimarc Barcode can improve inventory management for suppliers. The SP*, Supplier Portal Allowing Retail Coverage (SPARC) smartphone app delivers real-time product inventory data directly to Walmart suppliers, providing an overview of what products are on store shelves and in the backroom. Learn more about how Digimarc can help the supply chain be more efficient. Shazam: The Digimarc platform provides unprecedented consumer engagement via smartphones.  One of the world's foremost discovery applications for smartphones, <NODE id="6523" />Shazam<NODE id="6529" /> has <NODE id="6534" />integrated<NODE id="6544" /> <NODE id="6545" />Digimarc Discover<NODE id="6562" /> to create visual Shazaming, turning what customers see into opportunities to explore, engage and purchase products with their smartphones. Examples of visual Shazaming by leading brands will be showcased in the Digimarc booth. Display Marketing: Digimarc enables consumer engagement throughout the modern mobile-centric shopper's journey. See real world examples from world leaders in POP signage, cardboard end-of-aisle displays and dynamic poster advertising that have enabled their products with Digimarc Barcode. Customer Showcase: Attendees can examine Digimarc Barcode-enhanced packaging from Kraft Heinz Co. at the Digimarc booth. Private-label products will be available from innovative retailers including Wegmans, and New Seasons Market, a premium Northwest regional grocer. These packages will be used in Digimarc's retail scanning contest to demonstrate improvement in scanning at front-of-store. About Digimarc Digimarc Corp. (NASDAQ: DMRC
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/56f2a0d1-6562-3753-8d6f-8c82e19afd02" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T14:39:18Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:08:06.922Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/digimarc-to-showcase-gs1-us-collaboration-growing-partner-ecosystem-at-nrf-2016-300202788.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="315" endPos="330" type="organization-company" surface=" Digimarc Corp." />
<Entity id="1" startPos="348" endPos="356" type="provide-type" surface="inventor" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="364" endPos="380" type="product" surface="Digimarc Barcode" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="510" endPos="523" type="location" surface="New York City" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="524" endPos="537" type="date" surface="January 17-19" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="604" endPos="610" type="organization-company" surface="GS1 US" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="647" endPos="657" type="organization-company" surface="Digimarc's" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="776" endPos="803" type="product" surface="Digimarc Discover® software" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="808" endPos="824" type="product" surface="Digimarc Barcode" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="826" endPos="844" type="product" surface="Digimarc® Discover" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3798" endPos="3807" type="organization-company" surface="Datalogic" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="3832" endPos="3855" type="product-class" surface="stationary POS scanners" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="4081" endPos="4092" type="organization-company" surface="Honeywell's" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="4093" endPos="4128" type="product" surface="Xenon 1900 handheld barcode scanner" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="4145" endPos="4160" type="product-class" surface="Digimarc reader" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="5370" endPos="5377" type="organization-company" surface="Perrigo" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="5399" endPos="5411" type="provide-type" surface="manufacturer" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="5432" endPos="5455" type="product-class" surface="pharmaceutical products" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="5488" endPos="5495" type="trigger" surface="adopted" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="5496" endPos="5512" type="product" surface="Digimarc Barcode" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="5768" endPos="5775" type="organization-company" surface="Bizerba" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="5800" endPos="5812" type="provide-type" surface="manufacturer" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="5816" endPos="5829" type="product-class" surface="retail scales" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="5831" endPos="5838" type="product-class" surface="slicers" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="5843" endPos="5873" type="product-class" surface="weigh price labeling equipment" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="6523" endPos="6529" type="organization-company" surface="Shazam" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="6534" endPos="6544" type="trigger" surface="integrated" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="6545" endPos="6562" type="product" surface="Digimarc Discover" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="28" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="2" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="1" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="29" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="8" label="product" />
<Entity id="7" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="14" label="product" />
<Entity id="13" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="32" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="17" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
<Entity id="16" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="33" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="22" label="product" />
<Entity id="23" label="product" />
<Entity id="24" label="product" />
<Entity id="20" label="company" />
<Entity id="21" label="type" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="34" NAME="CompanyUsesProduct">
<Entity id="19" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
<Entity id="18" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="35" NAME="CompanyUsesProduct">
<Entity id="27" label="product" />
<Entity id="25" label="company" />
<Entity id="26" label="trigger" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
