<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT> 
It looks like your browser does not have JavaScript enabled. Please turn on JavaScript and try again.
 
Method for Assessment of indemnity/insurance
Method for Assessment of indemnity/insurance of Petroleum Authorisation Holders
25/06/2017 23:00:00
Mineral Exploration Prospecting Licence Competition
Mineral Exploration Quarterly Licence Competition for Licences newly available.
28/04/2017 17:30:00
 
It looks like your browser does not have JavaScript enabled. Please turn on JavaScript and try again.
 
http://www.dccae.gov.ie/en-ie/climate-action/consultations/Pages/National-Mitigation-Plan-.aspx
National Mitigation Plan to tackle greenhouse gas emissions
The development of Ireland's first statutory National Mitigation Plan represents a hugely important first step in enabling transition to a low carbon, climate-resilient and environmentally sustainable economy by 2050.
30/03/2017 23:00:00
http://www.dccae.gov.ie/en-ie/environment/consultations/Pages/National-Clean-Air-Strategy-Consultation.aspx
National Clean Air Strategy Consultation promoting clean air policies
We are developing a national Clean Air Strategy with the aim of promoting clean air.  The Strategy will provide strategic policies necessary to identify and promote integrated measures across government that are required to reduce air pollution
30/03/2017 11:00:00
 
It looks like your browser does not have JavaScript enabled. Please turn on JavaScript and try again.
 
Naughten announces Household Waste Collection Charging Arrangements
Minister Denis Naughten announces Household Waste Collection Charging Arrangements
27/06/2017 15:40:00
Naughten announces appointments to the Boards of An Post and EirGrid
Minister Naughten announces recent appointments to the Boards of An Post and EirGrid
23/06/2017 14:10:00

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/iter03/85" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.dccae.gov.ie/en-ie/Pages/default.aspx" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
