<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>River Forest to regulate residential beekeeping.

River Forest to regulate residential beekeeping
Dominican University
Dominican University staff and students care for one of the campus’ four beehives. River Forest trustees approved a resolution Nov. 27 to regulate residential beekeeping in the village.
Dominican University staff and students care for one of the campus’ four beehives. River Forest trustees approved a resolution Nov. 27 to regulate residential beekeeping in the village. (Dominican University)
Steve Schering Contact Reporter <NODE id="546" />Pioneer Press<NODE id="559" />
After months of discussion, River Forest trustees approved an ordinance to regulate residential beekeeping within the village beginning in 2018.
Trustees unanimously approved the residential beekeeping ordinance by a 5-0 vote on Nov. 27. Trustee Michael Gibbs was absent.
According to the ordinance, which was crafted by the village's new sustainability commission, the village will issue up to 22 residential beekeeping permits per year, which includes a $25 non-refundable permit application fee.
Residents registering for a permit would be required to notify neighbors adjacent to that resident's property line. Within seven days of receiving notice from the applicant, an adjacent resident may file a written objection to the village. Should an objector suffer from a life-threatening condition and submit documentation from a licensed physician or medical professional that confirms a condition related to bee stings, the application shall be denied.
Dominican University, which has four beehives on its campus, will be grandfathered into the new ordinance. Due to the proximity of the hives on campus, trustees said the university will not be required to notify adjacent property owners.
"There are properties adjacent to Dominican, but they are the equivalent of 10 houses away," Dominican professor Tama Weisman said. "They're far from [being] adjacent houses."
Resident Bruce Faland, who said he has kept bees on his property for nearly 30 years, said he was not in favor of having the village regulate beekeeping.
"There are a lot of communities that don't have legislation other than to register your bees with the state," Faland said. "One of the issues I have with the legislation is the 22 permits. That's too many hives. My bees will starve."
Village President Cathy Adduci cited safety as a key issue for the village's regulation. In addition to notifying neighbors, permit holders will be required to post signage on their property indicating the presence of a beehive and subject their hives to inspections.
"I think the purpose of the trustees and myself in even considering this ordinance, with the sustainability commission, is because we want you all to have beehives and we want you to be an enthusiast," Adduci said. "It's not being overly regulated. It's trying to say we represent everyone in River Forest. At the same token, I think we have to hear from people who are afraid of bees or afraid to get stung."
New permits will expire on Nov. 30 of each year, and holders will have to reapply annually at a $25 cost. Those found to be in violation of the new ordinance will face fines of up to $500 per day, officials said.

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="http://www.chicagotribune.com/ct-rfl-beekeeping-ordinance-tl-1207-20171130-story.html@2017-11-30T22:55:00.000+01:00" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.chicagotribune.com/ct-rfl-beekeeping-ordinance-tl-1207-20171130-story.html" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="546" endPos="559" type="organization" surface="Pioneer Press" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
