<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Breaking: Nikki Haley On Fire At UN, Makes Her Move Against NK.

Global Insecurity
(<NODE id="84" />Conservative Tribune<NODE id="104" />) – In the wake of North Korea’s latest missile test, U.N. Ambassador Nikki Haley made a move against North Korean regime and its enablers, promising that the Kim regime would be “completely destroyed” if it continued down its current path and calling on the Chinese government to cut off the North’s oil supply.
“If war does come, it will be because of continued acts of aggression like we witnessed yesterday,” Haley said during an emergency Wednesday meeting of the U.N. Security Council, according to Reuters.
“And if war comes, make no mistake, the North Korean regime will be utterly destroyed.”
The meeting came one day after the North Korean regime test-fired another <NODE id="780" />ICBM<NODE id="784" />, <NODE id="786" />one<NODE id="789" /> that analysts say would have been capable of reaching any location in the mainland United States.
The <NODE id="892" />missile<NODE id="899" /> flew both higher and farther than any <NODE id="938" />ICBM<NODE id="942" /> North Korea has tested thus far, <NODE id="976" />Reuters<NODE id="983" /> reported. However, U.S. intelligence analysts say that there isn’t any evidence the North Koreans have either a re-entry vehicle that can deliver a nuclear warhead without being burned up in the Earth’s atmosphere or a guidance system accurate enough to deliver the <NODE id="1250" />ICBM<NODE id="1254" /> where <NODE id="1261" />it<NODE id="1263" />’s intended to go.
In addition to warning the regime of North Korean dictator Kim Jong Un against aggression, Haley also turned up the the pressure on North Korea’s chief diplomatic enabler: China.
“We are once again at a time of reckoning,” Haley told the Security Council, according to the <NODE id="1555" />Washington Examiner<NODE id="1574" />.
While the Chinese government has taken some steps to distance itself from North Korea, China has generally shied away from taking a tougher line on the Kim regime, urging both the U.S. and its allies as well as North Korea to back off, in spite of North Korea’s recent missile and nuclear tests.
Even after sanctions, China still remains North Korea’s largest trading partner.
As for President Donald Trump, he also had words for Kim during a Wednesday speech in Missouri, where the president was stumping for tax reform.
“Little Rocket Man,” Trump said, referring to the North Korean leader. “He is a sick puppy.”
The president has repeatedly insisted that China is critical to solving the North Korean crisis, with Trump intimating that if China isn’t willing to fix the problem, his administration is more than willing to do so.
North Korea is looking for trouble. If China decides to help, that would be great. If not, we will solve the problem without them! U.S.A.
— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) April 11, 2017
Whether there’s a shift in the international community after this latest North Korean provocation remains to be seen. While the Trump administration and its emissaries — like Haley — have consistently taken a hard line on the North Koreans, other nations have waxed and waned in their willingness to take care of the problem.
Now that North Korea has an <NODE id="2952" />ICBM<NODE id="2956" /> <NODE id="2957" />that<NODE id="2961" /> can reach distant parts of the globe and is getting closer to guidance systems and heat shielding that could make a nuclear strike a distinct possibility, perhaps the rest of the world will realize the urgency of the moment.
We cannot afford the smoking gun to be a mushroom cloud — as Condoleeza Rice once said in different circumstances. North Korea’s nuclear ambitions must be arrested at all costs — and those that have enabled the Kim regime must pay a steep price if they continue to do so.
Please like and share on <NODE id="3484" />Facebook<NODE id="3492" /> and <NODE id="3497" />Twitter<NODE id="3504" /> if you agree.
conservativetribune.com/nikki-haley-move-nk/

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="https://www.teaparty.org/breaking-nikki-haley-fire-un-makes-move-nk-279468/@2017-11-30T20:00:11.000+01:00" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.teaparty.org/breaking-nikki-haley-fire-un-makes-move-nk-279468/" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="84" endPos="104" type="organization" surface="Conservative Tribune" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="780" endPos="784" type="product" surface="ICBM" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="786" endPos="789" type="product" surface="one" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="892" endPos="899" type="product" surface="missile" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="938" endPos="942" type="product" surface="ICBM" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="976" endPos="983" type="organization" surface="Reuters" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1250" endPos="1254" type="product" surface="ICBM" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1261" endPos="1263" type="product" surface="it" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1555" endPos="1574" type="organization" surface="Washington Examiner" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2952" endPos="2956" type="product" surface="ICBM" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2957" endPos="2961" type="product" surface="that" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="3484" endPos="3492" type="organization" surface="Facebook" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="3497" endPos="3504" type="organization" surface="Twitter" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="13" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
