<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT><NODE id="0" />Zumiez<NODE id="6" />’s Q3 Earnings Climb 11 Percent.

Posted by <NODE id="50" />SGB Media<NODE id="59" /> | Nov 30, 2017 | Apparel , Footwear , <NODE id="98" />SGB<NODE id="101" /> Updates , Update | 0 |
<NODE id="125" />Zumiez Inc.<NODE id="136" /> reported earnings for the third quarter ended October 28 rose 11.2 percent, reaching the high-end of guidance. Same-store sales rose 7.9 percent to top guidance.
Total net sales for the third quarter ended October 28, 2017 (13 weeks) increased 11.0 percent to $245.8 million from $221.4 million in the quarter ended October 29, 2016 (13 weeks). Comparable sales for the thirteen weeks ended October 28, 2017 increased 7.9 percent compared to a comparable sales increase of 4.0 percent for the thirteen weeks ended October 29, 2016. Net income for the third quarter of fiscal 2017 was $11.9 million, or 48 cents per diluted share, compared to net income of $10.7 million, or 43 cents per diluted share in the third quarter of the prior fiscal year.
When <NODE id="890" />it<NODE id="892" /> reported second-quarter results, the <NODE id="930" />company<NODE id="937" /> said <NODE id="943" />it<NODE id="945" /> expected sales to be in the range of $236 to $241 million resulting in net income per diluted share of approximately 43 cents to 48 cents a share. This guidance was based upon anticipated comparable sales growth between 4 percent and 6 percent.
Total net sales for the nine months (39 weeks) ended October 28, 2017 increased 8.1 percent to $619.2 million from $572.6 million reported for the nine months (39 weeks) ended October 29, 2016.  Comparable sales increased 5.1 percent for the thirty-nine weeks ended October 28, 2017 compared to a comparable sales decrease of 2.5 percent for the thirty-nine weeks ended October 29, 2016. Net income for the first nine months of fiscal 2017 was $6.9 million, or $0.28 per diluted share, compared to net income for the first nine months of the prior fiscal year of $7.7 million, or $0.31 per diluted share.
At October 28, 2017, the <NODE id="1821" />company<NODE id="1828" /> had cash and current marketable securities of $85.8 million compared to cash and current marketable securities of $49.2 million at October 29, 2016. The increase in cash and current marketable securities was driven by cash generated through operations, partially offset by capital expenditures.
Rick Brooks, chief executive officer of <NODE id="2164" />Zumiez Inc.<NODE id="2175" />, stated, “<NODE id="2186" />Our<NODE id="2189" /> top-line performance continues to improve even in the face of more challenging comparisons.  Third quarter comparable sales increased 7.9 percent on top of a 4.0 percent gain in the year ago period and <NODE id="2392" />our<NODE id="2395" /> momentum has carried over into November.  <NODE id="2438" />We<NODE id="2440" /> are confident that <NODE id="2460" />our<NODE id="2463" /> merchandise strategies, integrated sales channels and best in class sales team have <NODE id="2548" />Zumiez<NODE id="2554" /> well positioned to deliver strong holiday results and achieve meaningful earnings growth in the fourth quarter. Looking ahead, <NODE id="2682" />our<NODE id="2685" /> focus remains centered on serving the customer while profitably expanding <NODE id="2760" />our<NODE id="2763" /> global market share and returning increased value to <NODE id="2817" />our<NODE id="2820" /> shareholders over the long-term.”
November 2017 Sales Total net sales for the four-week period ended November 25, 2017 increased 11.3 percent to $77.1 million, compared to $69.3 million for the four-week period ended November 26, 2016. The <NODE id="3061" />company<NODE id="3068" />’s comparable sales increased 7.8 percent for the four-week period ended November 25, 2017 compared to a comparable sales increase of 5.7 percent for the four-week period ended November 26, 2016.
Fiscal 2017 Fourth Quarter Outlook
The <NODE id="3303" />company<NODE id="3310" /> is introducing guidance for the three months ending February 3, 2018. Net sales are projected to be in the range of $291 to $297 million resulting in net income per diluted share of approximately $0.78 to $0.84. This guidance is based upon anticipated comparable sales growth between 3 percent and 5 percent for the fourth quarter of fiscal 2017. The <NODE id="3662" />company<NODE id="3669" /> remains on track to open approximately 19 new stores in fiscal 2017, including up to 3 stores in Canada and 5 stores in Europe and 2 stores in Australia.
Photo courtesy <NODE id="3839" />Zumiez<NODE id="3845" />

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="https://sgbonline.com/zumiezs-q3-earnings-climb-11-percent/@2017-11-30T23:24:52.000+01:00" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://sgbonline.com/zumiezs-q3-earnings-climb-11-percent/" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="0" endPos="6" type="organization" surface="Zumiez" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="50" endPos="59" type="organization" surface="SGB Media" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="98" endPos="101" type="organization" surface="SGB" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="125" endPos="136" type="organization" surface="Zumiez Inc." />
<Entity id="4" startPos="890" endPos="892" type="organization" surface="it" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="930" endPos="937" type="organization" surface="company" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="943" endPos="945" type="organization" surface="it" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1821" endPos="1828" type="organization" surface="company" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="2164" endPos="2175" type="organization" surface="Zumiez Inc." />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2186" endPos="2189" type="organization" surface="Our" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2392" endPos="2395" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="2438" endPos="2440" type="organization" surface="We" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="2460" endPos="2463" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="2548" endPos="2554" type="organization" surface="Zumiez" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="2682" endPos="2685" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="2760" endPos="2763" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="2817" endPos="2820" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="3061" endPos="3068" type="organization" surface="company" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="3303" endPos="3310" type="organization" surface="company" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="3662" endPos="3669" type="organization" surface="company" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="3839" endPos="3845" type="organization" surface="Zumiez" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="21" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="3" label="source" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="19" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="20" label="target" />
<Entity id="18" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="13" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="0" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="22" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
