<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>New <NODE id="4" />2018 <NODE id="9" />Mercedes-Benz<NODE id="22" /> S-Class<NODE id="30" /> Silver Spring MD Washington-DC, MD #J80557.

Stock #: J80557
VIN: WDDUG8GB0JA374869
4MATIC(R), Black Leather, 13 Speakers, 19" Multi-Spoke Wheels, 4-Wheel Disc Brakes, ABS brakes, Adaptive suspension, Air Conditioning, AM/FM radio: SiriusXM, Android Auto, Anti-whiplash front head restraints, Apple CarPlay, Auto High-beam Headlights, Auto tilt-away steering wheel, Auto-dimming Rear-View mirror, Auto-leveling suspension, Automatic temperature control, Blind Spot Sensor, Brake assist, Bumpers: body-color, Burmester Surround Sound System, Child-Seat-Sensing Airbag, Compass, Delay-off headlights, Door auto-latch, Driver door bin, Driver vanity mirror, Dual front impact airbags, Dual front side impact airbags, Electronic Stability Control, Exterior Parking Camera Rear, Four wheel independent suspension, Front anti-roll bar, Front Bucket Seats, Front Center Armrest, Front dual zone A/C, Front reading lights, Garage door transmitter: Homelink, Genuine wood console insert, Genuine wood door panel insert, Head restraints memory, Heated door mirrors, Heated Front Seats, Heated front seats, HVAC memory, Illuminated entry, Knee airbag, Low tire pressure warning, Memory seat, Nappa Leather Upholstery, Navigation system: COMAND, Occupant sensing airbag, Outside temperature display, Overhead airbag, Overhead console, Panic alarm, Passenger door bin, Passenger vanity mirror, Power adjustable front head restraints, Power adjustable rear head restraints, Power door mirrors, Power driver seat, Power moonroof, Power passenger seat, Power steering, Power windows, Premium audio system: COMAND, Pre-Wiring for CD Player, Radio data system, Radio: COMAND w/Navigation, Rain sensing wipers, Rear anti-roll bar, Rear fog lights, Rear reading lights, Rear seat center armrest, Rear side impact airbag, Rear Window Blind, Rear window defroster, Remote keyless entry, Security system, SiriusXM Satellite Radio, Smartphone Integration, Speed control, Speed-sensing steering, Steering wheel memory, Steering wheel mounted audio controls, Tachometer, Telescoping steering wheel, Tilt steering wheel, Traction control, Trip computer, Turn signal indicator mirrors, Variably intermittent wipers, and Weather band radio. 17/27mpg Iridium Silver 4D Sedan 4.0L V8 9-Speed Automatic 27/17 Highway/City MPG 4MATIC(R) 4MATIC(R), Black Leather. *Your additional costs are sales tax, tag and title fees for the state in which the vehicle will be registered, $925 freight (all new <NODE id="2495" />Mercedes-Benz<NODE id="2508" /> models); $995 freight (all new <NODE id="2540" />Sprinter<NODE id="2548" /> models), any dealer-installed options (if applicable) and a $299 dealer processing fee. Pricing and incentives may vary if vehicle is leased. Prices are subject to change, and prior sales are excluded from these offers. While every reasonable effort is made to ensure the accuracy of this information, we are not responsible for any errors or omissions contained on these pages. Please verify any information in question with the dealer. *Your additional costs are sales tax, tag and title fees for the state in which the vehicle will be registered, $925 freight (all new <NODE id="3121" />Mercedes-Benz<NODE id="3134" /> models), any dealer-installed options (if applicable) and a $299 dealer processing fee. Pricing and incentives may vary if vehicle is leased. Prices are subject to change, and prior sales are excluded from these offers. While every reasonable effort is made to ensure the accuracy of this information, we are not responsible for any errors or omissions contained on these pages. Please verify any information in question with the dealer.
Visit our website for more information on this vehicle or to browse our large inventory of used vehicles.
Interested in this vehicle? Visit our website or give us a call toll free at:
888-569-7345
About <NODE id="3776" />Mercedes-Benz<NODE id="3789" /> of Silver Spring:
<NODE id="3808" />We<NODE id="3810" /> are a <NODE id="3817" />new<NODE id="3820" /> and <NODE id="3825" />certified used Mercedes-Benz<NODE id="3853" /> dealership<NODE id="3864" /> serving the Washington, D.C. area.
If you live in Silver Spring, Arlington or Rockville, you are just a short trip away from a <NODE id="3992" />new<NODE id="3995" /> or <NODE id="3999" />used <NODE id="4004" />Mercedes-Benz<NODE id="4017" /> car<NODE id="4021" />, <NODE id="4023" />truck<NODE id="4028" />, or <NODE id="4033" />SUV<NODE id="4036" />. Call or visit <NODE id="4052" />us<NODE id="4054" /> today for great offers!
To find another <NODE id="4095" />MileOne Automotive<NODE id="4113" /> dealership in your area, visit http://www.mileone.com
Address:
Silver Spring MD Washington-DC, MD 20904
Kategorie

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B8BVajfvnMg@2017-11-30T23:53:26.000+01:00" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B8BVajfvnMg" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="4" endPos="30" type="product" surface="2018 Mercedes-Benz S-Class" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="9" endPos="22" type="organization" surface="Mercedes-Benz" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="2495" endPos="2508" type="product" surface="Mercedes-Benz" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="2540" endPos="2548" type="product" surface="Sprinter" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="3121" endPos="3134" type="product" surface="Mercedes-Benz" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="3776" endPos="3789" type="product" surface="Mercedes-Benz" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="3808" endPos="3810" type="organization" surface="We" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="3817" endPos="3820" type="product" surface="new" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="3817" endPos="3864" type="organization" surface="new and certified used Mercedes-Benz dealership" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="3825" endPos="3853" type="product" surface="certified used Mercedes-Benz" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3992" endPos="3995" type="product" surface="new" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="3999" endPos="4021" type="product" surface="used Mercedes-Benz car" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="4004" endPos="4017" type="organization" surface="Mercedes-Benz" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="4023" endPos="4028" type="product" surface="truck" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="4033" endPos="4036" type="product" surface="SUV" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="4052" endPos="4054" type="organization" surface="us" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="4095" endPos="4113" type="organization" surface="MileOne Automotive" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="17" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="0" label="product" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="18" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="13" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="19" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="13" label="target" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="20" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="16" label="source" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
