<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Published on Friday, 30 June 2017
 
(Pasay City). <NODE id="50" />Electric vehicles<NODE id="67" /> (<NODE id="69" />EV<NODE id="71" />) are the future of motoring and the Department of Energy (DOE) under Secretary Alfonso Cusi has assured industry stakeholders of its full support for the continued development of <NODE id="251" />EVs<NODE id="254" /> or <NODE id="258" />e-vehicles<NODE id="268" /> in the country.
PHOTO RELEASE: Towards A Reliable Power System In Mindanao
Published on Friday, 30 June 2017
(Davao City). Last  Wednesday, 28 June, the Department of Energy together with the <NODE id="461" />Philippine Electricity Market Corp.<NODE id="496" /> (<NODE id="498" />PEMC<NODE id="502" />) held a ceremonial, symbolic and historical switched on during  the official launch of the Mindanao Wholesale Electricity Spot Market (WESM) which provides  a competitive and tr... Read more
Cusi Vows Long-Term Energy Security in Mindanao
Published on Wednesday, 28 June 2017
 
(Davao City). With the launch of the Mindanao Wholesale Electricity Spot Market (WESM) today (28 June), Energy Secretary Alfonso G. Cusi pledged his full commitment to President Duterte’s people-centered policies and government’s long term economic vision for the country.
Finally, WESM Mindanao Launched Wednesday
Published on Tuesday, 27 June 2017
(Taguig City). Some 11 years since being established in Luzon and over six years since taking a foothold in the Visayas, the Wholesale Electricity Spot (WESM) will come to Mindanao on Wednesday, 28 June 2017.

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/iter03/91" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.doe.gov.ph/" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="50" endPos="67" type="product" surface="Electric vehicles" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="69" endPos="71" type="product" surface="EV" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="251" endPos="254" type="product" surface="EVs" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="258" endPos="268" type="product" surface="e-vehicles" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="461" endPos="496" type="organization" surface="Philippine Electricity Market Corp." />
<Entity id="5" startPos="498" endPos="502" type="organization" surface="PEMC" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="6" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="7" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="4" label="source" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
