<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>User login Syndicate Home Impressively Spacious, Versatile and Authoritative. Leave your mark wherever you go with the New Urban All-Rounder: The all-new <NODE id="154" />BMW<NODE id="157" /> X1<NODE id="160" /> launched in India. The all-new <NODE id="192" />BMW<NODE id="195" /> X1<NODE id="198" /> debuted at the Auto Expo 2016. The second generation of the sportiest premium compact <NODE id="285" />sports activity vehicle<NODE id="308" /> (<NODE id="310" />SAV<NODE id="313" />) was unveiled by Mr. Sachin Tendulkar, the legendary sportsman. The all-new <NODE id="390" />BMW<NODE id="393" /> X1<NODE id="396" /> is locally produced at <NODE id="420" />BMW Plant Chennai<NODE id="437" /> and can be ordered at <NODE id="460" />BMW India<NODE id="469" /> dealerships<NODE id="481" /> from today onwards. Deliveries of the all-new <NODE id="528" />BMW<NODE id="531" /> X1<NODE id="534" /> will start from April 2016. Mr. Philipp von Sahr, President, <NODE id="596" />BMW Group India<NODE id="611" /> said, 'The <NODE id="623" />BMW<NODE id="626" /> X1<NODE id="629" /> established the premium compact <NODE id="662" />sports activity vehicle<NODE id="685" /> segment in India and became the trailblazer with its young and modern character. The all-new <NODE id="779" />BMW<NODE id="782" /> X1<NODE id="785" /> with its unmistakable <NODE id="808" />BMW<NODE id="811" /> X<NODE id="813" /> genes has more space for variable use and excellent driving dynamics with the new intelligent <NODE id="908" />all-wheel xDrive<NODE id="924" />. The latest generation of <NODE id="951" />BMW<NODE id="954" /> engines<NODE id="962" /> guarantees a thrilling power delivery and excellent responsiveness which generates a dynamic proposition on the road and gives assured driving pleasure. The all-new <NODE id="1128" />BMW<NODE id="1131" /> X1<NODE id="1134" /> combines the best of city driving with off-road performance and is the perfect vehicle for individuals with an active lifestyle.’’ The all-new <NODE id="1278" />BMW<NODE id="1281" /> X1<NODE id="1284" /> is available in three exclusive design schemes – <NODE id="1334" />Expedition<NODE id="1344" />; <NODE id="1346" />xLine<NODE id="1351" /> and <NODE id="1356" />M Sport<NODE id="1363" />. <NODE id="1365" />xLine<NODE id="1370" /> places the car’s robust and versatile character at centre stage whereas the <NODE id="1447" />M Sport model<NODE id="1460" /> bestows masculine character distinguishing itself as an elite <NODE id="1523" />sports model<NODE id="1535" />. The all-new <NODE id="1549" />BMW<NODE id="1552" /> X1<NODE id="1555" /> will be available in a diesel variant. The ex-showroom prices are as follows – The all-new <NODE id="1647" />BMW<NODE id="1650" /> X1 sDrive20d Expedition<NODE id="1674" /> : INR 29,90,000 The all-new <NODE id="1703" />BMW<NODE id="1706" /> X1 sDrive20d xLine<NODE id="1725" /> : INR 33,90,000 The all-new <NODE id="1754" />BMW<NODE id="1757" /> X1 <NODE id="1761" />xDrive<NODE id="1767" />20d xLine<NODE id="1776" /> : INR 35,90,000 The all-new <NODE id="1805" />BMW<NODE id="1808" /> X1 <NODE id="1812" />xDrive<NODE id="1818" />20d M Sport<NODE id="1829" /> : INR 39,90,000 The petrol variant will be launched later in 2016. *Price prevailing at the time of invoicing will be applicable. Delivery will be made ex-showroom. Ex-showroom price (inclusive of VAT @ 12.5% @) as applicable in New Delhi and Maharashtra but excludes Road Tax, RTO statutory taxes/fees, Insurance and Octroi (if applicable).VAT over and above 12.5%, if applicable, will be charged extra. Prices and options are subject to change without prior notice. For further information, please contact your local Authorised <NODE id="2360" />BMW<NODE id="2363" /> Dealer<NODE id="2370" />. The all-new <NODE id="2384" />BMW<NODE id="2387" /> X1<NODE id="2390" /> is available in Alpine White (non-metallic) and in the following metallic paintworks: Black Sapphire, Glacier Silver, Mineral White, Mineral Grey, Sparkling Brown, Sparkling Storm Brilliant Effect, Platinum Silver, Atlantic Grey, Mediterranean Blue and Chestnut Bronze. The exclusive metallic paintwork for the <NODE id="2702" />M Sport range<NODE id="2715" /> includes Estoril Blue. The range of fine upholstery combinations in all-new <NODE id="2792" />BMW<NODE id="2795" /> X1<NODE id="2798" /> include Sensatec Black and Black, Sensatec Canberra Beige and Black. In <NODE id="2871" />M Sport<NODE id="2878" />, the range of fine upholstery combinations in Dakota leather include Canberra Beige, Mocha with Black/Mocha, Oyster with Grey highlight and Black, Black with Black, Black with Blue Highlight. The all-new <NODE id="3083" />BMW<NODE id="3086" /> X1<NODE id="3089" /> Rugged proportions, powerfully sculpted surfaces and all the hallmark visuals of a sports activity vehicle (SAV) – the design of the second generation of <NODE id="3244" />BMW<NODE id="3247" /> X1<NODE id="3250" /> exudes poise and independence but remains unmistakably a <NODE id="3308" />BMW<NODE id="3311" />, even at first sight. The ‘three-eyed’ face formed by the twin circular <NODE id="3384" />LED headlights<NODE id="3398" /> and the fog lamps is likewise a hallmark feature <NODE id="3448" />X model<NODE id="3455" />. The interior design majors on authoritative driving pleasure. The interior of the all-new <NODE id="3547" />BMW<NODE id="3550" /> X1<NODE id="3553" /> boasts exemplary ergonomics and typical <NODE id="3594" />BMW<NODE id="3597" /> driver orientation. The elevated seating position typical of a <NODE id="3661" />BMW<NODE id="3664" /> X model<NODE id="3672" />, a new interpretation of the hallmark driver-focused cockpit treats its passengers to the best possible view, enjoyed with a premium ambience that exudes high quality and workmanship. Seats are electrically adjustable on both the driver and front seat passenger sides. There is another thing the all-new <NODE id="3977" />BMW<NODE id="3980" /> X1<NODE id="3983" /> has in abundance – space. The vehicle has grown in height and space compared to its predecessor. The luggage compartment now accommodates up to 505 litres. The rear seat can also be completely folded down to increase the compartment capacity to an impressive 1550 litres. The all-new <NODE id="4268" />BMW<NODE id="4271" /> X1<NODE id="4274" /> adapts perfectly not only to an active lifestyle but also to personal taste. The three exclusive design schemes – <NODE id="4389" />Expedition<NODE id="4399" />, <NODE id="4401" />xLine<NODE id="4406" /> and <NODE id="4411" />M Sport<NODE id="4418" /> offer options that meet individual requirements. <NODE id="4468" />xLine<NODE id="4473" /> is the perfect choice to further emphasise off-roading character of the all-new <NODE id="4554" />BMW<NODE id="4557" /> X1<NODE id="4560" />. It reinforces the impression through its satinised aluminium add-ons and specific <NODE id="4644" />18 light alloy wheels<NODE id="4665" />. Special colours and materials in the interior stylishly round off the <NODE id="4737" />xLine<NODE id="4742" />. <NODE id="4744" />M Sport<NODE id="4751" /> unleashes the sporting potential of the all-new <NODE id="4800" />BMW<NODE id="4803" /> X1<NODE id="4806" />. It is fitted with M aerodynamic package and <NODE id="4852" />18-inch M light-alloy wheels<NODE id="4880" /> along with <NODE id="4892" />M<NODE id="4893" /> badging on the sides that further emphasise its dynamic character. The interior features an extremely sporty cockpit design with <NODE id="5023" />M<NODE id="5024" /> sports seats and <NODE id="5042" />M<NODE id="5043" /> leather steering wheel. <NODE id="5068" />xLine<NODE id="5073" /> and <NODE id="5078" />M Sport<NODE id="5085" /> both feature panorama sunroof and ambient lighting scheme. The <NODE id="5149" />TwinPower Turbo 1,995 cc four- cylinder diesel engine<NODE id="5202" /> delivers excellent power output and responsiveness even at low RPMs. The turbocharger technology with variable turbine geometry and common rail direct fuel injection system ensures both fuel efficiency and low emissions that yields an exceptional power output of 140 kW / 190 hp. High torque of 400 Nm is available at just 1,750 – 2,500 rpm. The all-new <NODE id="5557" />BMW<NODE id="5560" /> X1sDrive 20d<NODE id="5573" /> (<NODE id="5575" />Expedition<NODE id="5585" /> and <NODE id="5590" />xLine<NODE id="5595" />) accelerates from 0 to 100 km / hr in 7.8 seconds with a top speed of 222 km / hr. The all-new <NODE id="5691" />BMW<NODE id="5694" /> X1<NODE id="5697" />xDrive<NODE id="5703" /> 20d<NODE id="5707" /> (<NODE id="5709" />xLine<NODE id="5714" /> and <NODE id="5719" />M Sport<NODE id="5726" />) accelerates from 0 to 100 km / hr in 7.6 seconds with a top speed of 219 km / hr. The new eight-speed steptronic automatic transmission performs smooth, almost imperceptible gear shifts. At any time, in any gear, the transmission collaborates perfectly with the <NODE id="5990" />engine<NODE id="5996" />, enabling it to develop its full power and efficiency. The all-new <NODE id="6064" />BMW<NODE id="6067" /> X1<NODE id="6070" /> is equipped as standard with Servotronic speed-sensitive steering assistance which allows parking and turning-off manoeuvres to be completed safely and comfortably with little steering effort. At higher speeds drivers can especially look forward to the steering precision. <NODE id="6344" />BMW<NODE id="6347" /> xDrive<NODE id="6354" />, an intelligent all-wheel-drive system, in the all-new <NODE id="6410" />BMW<NODE id="6413" /> X1<NODE id="6416" /> monitors the driving situation constantly, is quick to respond and is more efficient than ever. The compact, low-weight and efficient all-wheel-drive system distributes the <NODE id="6590" />engine<NODE id="6596" />’s power between the front and rear axle exactly to suit the driving situation and the surface. With <NODE id="6697" />xDrive<NODE id="6703" /> and <NODE id="6708" />Dynamic Stability Control<NODE id="6733" /> (<NODE id="6735" />DSC<NODE id="6738" />), the vehicle remains directionally stable and distributes drive power flexibly between the two axles for optimum grip and safety. The all-new <NODE id="6882" />BMW<NODE id="6885" /> X1<NODE id="6888" /> provides unparalleled performance coupled with cutting-edge safety technologies. <NODE id="6970" />BMW<NODE id="6973" />’s exemplary safety provides optimal support in any situation with six air bags, <NODE id="7054" />Anti-Lock Braking System<NODE id="7078" /> (<NODE id="7080" />ABS<NODE id="7083" />) with brake assist, <NODE id="7104" />Dynamic Stability Control<NODE id="7129" /> (<NODE id="7131" />DSC<NODE id="7134" />) including <NODE id="7146" />Dynamic Traction Control<NODE id="7170" /> (<NODE id="7172" />DTC<NODE id="7175" />), <NODE id="7178" />Cornering Brake Control<NODE id="7201" /> (<NODE id="7203" />CBC<NODE id="7206" />), <NODE id="7209" />Hill Descent Control<NODE id="7229" /> (<NODE id="7231" />HDC<NODE id="7234" />), <NODE id="7237" />Side-impact Protection<NODE id="7259" />, Runflat tyres with reinforced sidewalls, integrated emergency spare wheel, electronic vehicle immobiliser and crash sensor. <NODE id="7385" />BMW<NODE id="7388" /> EfficientDynamics<NODE id="7406" /> measures make a key contribution to the excellent fuel efficiency of the all- new <NODE id="7489" />BMW<NODE id="7492" /> X1<NODE id="7495" />. Aerodynamic excellence and the accompanying reduction in fuel consumption are guaranteed by details such as the side air blades on the tailgate and the air curtain integrated into the air inlets at the front. These measures are aided by additional features such as the 50:50 weight distribution, low centre of gravity, intelligent lightweight construction, automatic start/stop function, ECO PRO mode, brake energy regeneration, electric power steering and more. <NODE id="7960" />BMW<NODE id="7963" /> has been setting the standard for connectivity between human, car and the outside world for many years now. The <NODE id="8076" />BMW<NODE id="8079" /> ConnectedDrive<NODE id="8094" /> features <NODE id="8104" />BMW <NODE id="8108" />iDrive<NODE id="8114" /> (the on-board <NODE id="8129" />Driver Information system<NODE id="8154" />) with 16.5 cms display, <NODE id="8179" />BMW<NODE id="8182" /> Apps<NODE id="8187" />, <NODE id="8189" />Park Distance Control<NODE id="8210" /> (<NODE id="8212" />PDC<NODE id="8215" />), Connectivity through Bluetooth and USB/AUX IN connectivity. <NODE id="8278" />M Sport<NODE id="8285" /> comes with a 22.3 cms display along with a Head-Up Display and <NODE id="8349" />BMW<NODE id="8352" /> Navigation Plus<NODE id="8368" />. Privacy Policy - License Proudly hosted at <NODE id="8413" />Burst.net<NODE id="8422" />
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/67dbbb2a-b80f-383f-9159-b37df8d73f57" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-04T18:46:12Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:14:28.807Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.webnewswire.com/content/impressively-spacious-versatile-and-authoritative-leave-your-mark-wherever-you-go-new-urba-0" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="154" endPos="157" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="154" endPos="160" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="192" endPos="195" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="192" endPos="198" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="285" endPos="308" type="product" surface="sports activity vehicle" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="310" endPos="313" type="product" surface="SAV" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="390" endPos="393" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="390" endPos="396" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="420" endPos="437" type="organization" surface="BMW Plant Chennai" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="460" endPos="469" type="organization" surface="BMW India" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="460" endPos="481" type="organization" surface="BMW India dealerships" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="528" endPos="531" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="528" endPos="534" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="596" endPos="611" type="organization" surface="BMW Group India" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="623" endPos="626" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="623" endPos="629" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="662" endPos="685" type="product" surface="sports activity vehicle" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="779" endPos="782" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="779" endPos="785" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="808" endPos="811" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="808" endPos="813" type="product" surface="BMW X" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="908" endPos="924" type="product" surface="all-wheel xDrive" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="951" endPos="954" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="951" endPos="962" type="product" surface="BMW engines" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="1128" endPos="1131" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="1128" endPos="1134" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="1278" endPos="1281" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="1278" endPos="1284" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="1334" endPos="1344" type="product" surface="Expedition" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="1346" endPos="1351" type="product" surface="xLine" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="1356" endPos="1363" type="product" surface="M Sport" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="1365" endPos="1370" type="product" surface="xLine" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="1447" endPos="1460" type="product" surface="M Sport model" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="1523" endPos="1535" type="product" surface="sports model" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="1549" endPos="1552" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="1549" endPos="1555" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="1647" endPos="1650" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="1647" endPos="1674" type="product" surface="BMW X1 sDrive20d Expedition" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="1703" endPos="1706" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="1703" endPos="1725" type="product" surface="BMW X1 sDrive20d xLine" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="1754" endPos="1757" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="1754" endPos="1776" type="product" surface="BMW X1 xDrive20d xLine" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="1761" endPos="1767" type="product" surface="xDrive" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="1805" endPos="1808" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="1805" endPos="1829" type="product" surface="BMW X1 xDrive20d M Sport" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="1812" endPos="1818" type="product" surface="xDrive" />
<Entity id="46" startPos="2360" endPos="2363" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="47" startPos="2360" endPos="2370" type="organization" surface="BMW Dealer" />
<Entity id="48" startPos="2384" endPos="2387" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="49" startPos="2384" endPos="2390" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="50" startPos="2702" endPos="2715" type="product" surface="M Sport range" />
<Entity id="51" startPos="2792" endPos="2795" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="52" startPos="2792" endPos="2798" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="53" startPos="2871" endPos="2878" type="product" surface="M Sport" />
<Entity id="54" startPos="3083" endPos="3086" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="55" startPos="3083" endPos="3089" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="56" startPos="3244" endPos="3247" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="57" startPos="3244" endPos="3250" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="58" startPos="3308" endPos="3311" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="59" startPos="3308" endPos="3311" type="product" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="60" startPos="3384" endPos="3398" type="product" surface="LED headlights" />
<Entity id="61" startPos="3448" endPos="3455" type="product" surface="X model" />
<Entity id="62" startPos="3547" endPos="3550" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="63" startPos="3547" endPos="3553" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="64" startPos="3594" endPos="3597" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="65" startPos="3661" endPos="3664" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="66" startPos="3661" endPos="3672" type="product" surface="BMW X model" />
<Entity id="67" startPos="3977" endPos="3980" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="68" startPos="3977" endPos="3983" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="69" startPos="4268" endPos="4271" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="70" startPos="4268" endPos="4274" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="71" startPos="4389" endPos="4399" type="product" surface="Expedition" />
<Entity id="72" startPos="4401" endPos="4406" type="product" surface="xLine" />
<Entity id="73" startPos="4411" endPos="4418" type="product" surface="M Sport" />
<Entity id="74" startPos="4468" endPos="4473" type="product" surface="xLine" />
<Entity id="75" startPos="4554" endPos="4557" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="76" startPos="4554" endPos="4560" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="77" startPos="4644" endPos="4665" type="product" surface="18 light alloy wheels" />
<Entity id="78" startPos="4737" endPos="4742" type="product" surface="xLine" />
<Entity id="79" startPos="4744" endPos="4751" type="product" surface="M Sport" />
<Entity id="80" startPos="4800" endPos="4803" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="81" startPos="4800" endPos="4806" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="82" startPos="4852" endPos="4880" type="product" surface="18-inch M light-alloy wheels" />
<Entity id="83" startPos="4892" endPos="4893" type="product" surface="M" />
<Entity id="84" startPos="5023" endPos="5024" type="product" surface="M" />
<Entity id="85" startPos="5042" endPos="5043" type="product" surface="M" />
<Entity id="86" startPos="5068" endPos="5073" type="product" surface="xLine" />
<Entity id="87" startPos="5078" endPos="5085" type="product" surface="M Sport" />
<Entity id="88" startPos="5149" endPos="5202" type="product" surface="TwinPower Turbo 1,995 cc four- cylinder diesel engine" />
<Entity id="89" startPos="5557" endPos="5560" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="90" startPos="5557" endPos="5573" type="product" surface="BMW X1sDrive 20d" />
<Entity id="91" startPos="5575" endPos="5585" type="product" surface="Expedition" />
<Entity id="92" startPos="5590" endPos="5595" type="product" surface="xLine" />
<Entity id="93" startPos="5691" endPos="5694" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="94" startPos="5691" endPos="5694" type="product" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="95" startPos="5691" endPos="5707" type="product" surface="BMW X1xDrive 20d" />
<Entity id="96" startPos="5697" endPos="5703" type="product" surface="xDrive" />
<Entity id="97" startPos="5709" endPos="5714" type="product" surface="xLine" />
<Entity id="98" startPos="5719" endPos="5726" type="product" surface="M Sport" />
<Entity id="99" startPos="5990" endPos="5996" type="product" surface="engine" />
<Entity id="100" startPos="6064" endPos="6067" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="101" startPos="6064" endPos="6070" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="102" startPos="6344" endPos="6347" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="103" startPos="6344" endPos="6354" type="product" surface="BMW xDrive" />
<Entity id="104" startPos="6410" endPos="6413" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="105" startPos="6410" endPos="6416" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="106" startPos="6590" endPos="6596" type="product" surface="engine" />
<Entity id="107" startPos="6697" endPos="6703" type="product" surface="xDrive" />
<Entity id="108" startPos="6708" endPos="6733" type="product" surface="Dynamic Stability Control" />
<Entity id="109" startPos="6735" endPos="6738" type="product" surface="DSC" />
<Entity id="110" startPos="6882" endPos="6885" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="111" startPos="6882" endPos="6888" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="112" startPos="6970" endPos="6973" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="113" startPos="7054" endPos="7078" type="product" surface="Anti-Lock Braking System" />
<Entity id="114" startPos="7080" endPos="7083" type="product" surface="ABS" />
<Entity id="115" startPos="7104" endPos="7129" type="product" surface="Dynamic Stability Control" />
<Entity id="116" startPos="7131" endPos="7134" type="product" surface="DSC" />
<Entity id="117" startPos="7146" endPos="7170" type="product" surface="Dynamic Traction Control" />
<Entity id="118" startPos="7172" endPos="7175" type="product" surface="DTC" />
<Entity id="119" startPos="7178" endPos="7201" type="product" surface="Cornering Brake Control" />
<Entity id="120" startPos="7203" endPos="7206" type="product" surface="CBC" />
<Entity id="121" startPos="7209" endPos="7229" type="product" surface="Hill Descent Control" />
<Entity id="122" startPos="7231" endPos="7234" type="product" surface="HDC" />
<Entity id="123" startPos="7237" endPos="7259" type="product" surface="Side-impact Protection" />
<Entity id="124" startPos="7385" endPos="7388" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="125" startPos="7385" endPos="7406" type="product" surface="BMW EfficientDynamics" />
<Entity id="126" startPos="7489" endPos="7492" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="127" startPos="7489" endPos="7495" type="product" surface="BMW X1" />
<Entity id="128" startPos="7960" endPos="7963" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="129" startPos="8076" endPos="8079" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="130" startPos="8076" endPos="8094" type="product" surface="BMW ConnectedDrive" />
<Entity id="131" startPos="8104" endPos="8108" type="organization" surface="BMW " />
<Entity id="132" startPos="8104" endPos="8114" type="product" surface="BMW iDrive" />
<Entity id="133" startPos="8129" endPos="8154" type="product" surface="Driver Information system" />
<Entity id="134" startPos="8179" endPos="8182" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="135" startPos="8179" endPos="8187" type="product" surface="BMW Apps" />
<Entity id="136" startPos="8189" endPos="8210" type="product" surface="Park Distance Control" />
<Entity id="137" startPos="8212" endPos="8215" type="product" surface="PDC" />
<Entity id="138" startPos="8278" endPos="8285" type="product" surface="M Sport" />
<Entity id="139" startPos="8349" endPos="8352" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="140" startPos="8349" endPos="8368" type="product" surface="BMW Navigation Plus" />
<Entity id="141" startPos="8413" endPos="8422" type="organization" surface="Burst.net" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="142" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="143" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="144" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="7" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="145" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="12" label="product" />
<Entity id="11" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="146" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="15" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="147" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="18" label="product" />
<Entity id="17" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="148" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="19" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="149" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="23" label="product" />
<Entity id="22" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="150" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="25" label="product" />
<Entity id="24" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="151" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="27" label="product" />
<Entity id="26" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="152" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="35" label="product" />
<Entity id="34" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="153" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="37" label="product" />
<Entity id="36" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="154" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="39" label="product" />
<Entity id="38" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="155" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="41" label="product" />
<Entity id="40" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="156" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="44" label="product" />
<Entity id="43" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="157" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="49" label="product" />
<Entity id="48" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="158" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="52" label="product" />
<Entity id="51" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="159" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="55" label="product" />
<Entity id="54" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="160" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="57" label="product" />
<Entity id="56" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="161" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="63" label="product" />
<Entity id="62" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="162" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="66" label="product" />
<Entity id="65" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="163" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="68" label="product" />
<Entity id="67" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="164" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="70" label="product" />
<Entity id="69" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="165" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="76" label="product" />
<Entity id="75" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="166" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="81" label="product" />
<Entity id="80" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="167" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="101" label="product" />
<Entity id="100" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="168" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="103" label="product" />
<Entity id="102" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="169" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="105" label="product" />
<Entity id="104" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="170" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="111" label="product" />
<Entity id="110" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="171" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="125" label="product" />
<Entity id="124" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="172" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="127" label="product" />
<Entity id="126" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="173" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="130" label="product" />
<Entity id="129" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="174" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="132" label="product" />
<Entity id="131" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="175" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="135" label="product" />
<Entity id="134" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="176" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="140" label="product" />
<Entity id="139" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="177" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="74" label="target" />
<Entity id="91" label="target" />
<Entity id="31" label="target" />
<Entity id="61" label="target" />
<Entity id="35" label="target" />
<Entity id="92" label="target" />
<Entity id="79" label="target" />
<Entity id="138" label="target" />
<Entity id="78" label="target" />
<Entity id="30" label="target" />
<Entity id="71" label="target" />
<Entity id="42" label="target" />
<Entity id="81" label="target" />
<Entity id="50" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="52" label="target" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="97" label="target" />
<Entity id="49" label="target" />
<Entity id="18" label="target" />
<Entity id="59" label="target" />
<Entity id="66" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="84" label="target" />
<Entity id="27" label="target" />
<Entity id="28" label="target" />
<Entity id="70" label="target" />
<Entity id="55" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="87" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="68" label="target" />
<Entity id="32" label="target" />
<Entity id="63" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="111" label="target" />
<Entity id="72" label="target" />
<Entity id="73" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="105" label="target" />
<Entity id="101" label="target" />
<Entity id="39" label="target" />
<Entity id="57" label="target" />
<Entity id="33" label="target" />
<Entity id="90" label="target" />
<Entity id="98" label="target" />
<Entity id="76" label="target" />
<Entity id="37" label="target" />
<Entity id="29" label="target" />
<Entity id="96" label="target" />
<Entity id="53" label="target" />
<Entity id="85" label="target" />
<Entity id="127" label="target" />
<Entity id="25" label="target" />
<Entity id="44" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="178" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="56" label="target" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="110" label="target" />
<Entity id="34" label="target" />
<Entity id="139" label="target" />
<Entity id="102" label="target" />
<Entity id="100" label="target" />
<Entity id="112" label="target" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="58" label="target" />
<Entity id="67" label="target" />
<Entity id="64" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="124" label="target" />
<Entity id="134" label="target" />
<Entity id="54" label="target" />
<Entity id="38" label="target" />
<Entity id="26" label="target" />
<Entity id="40" label="target" />
<Entity id="89" label="target" />
<Entity id="24" label="target" />
<Entity id="69" label="target" />
<Entity id="75" label="target" />
<Entity id="65" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
<Entity id="129" label="target" />
<Entity id="43" label="target" />
<Entity id="131" label="target" />
<Entity id="62" label="target" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
<Entity id="46" label="target" />
<Entity id="36" label="target" />
<Entity id="51" label="target" />
<Entity id="104" label="target" />
<Entity id="48" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="13" label="target" />
<Entity id="22" label="target" />
<Entity id="19" label="target" />
<Entity id="126" label="target" />
<Entity id="80" label="target" />
<Entity id="128" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="179" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="4" label="source" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="180" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="21" label="source" />
<Entity id="96" label="target" />
<Entity id="45" label="target" />
<Entity id="107" label="target" />
<Entity id="42" label="target" />
<Entity id="103" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="181" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="23" label="source" />
<Entity id="99" label="target" />
<Entity id="88" label="target" />
<Entity id="106" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="182" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="77" label="source" />
<Entity id="82" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="183" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="108" label="source" />
<Entity id="116" label="target" />
<Entity id="115" label="target" />
<Entity id="109" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="184" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="113" label="source" />
<Entity id="114" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="185" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="117" label="source" />
<Entity id="118" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="186" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="119" label="source" />
<Entity id="120" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="187" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="121" label="source" />
<Entity id="122" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="188" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="132" label="source" />
<Entity id="133" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="189" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="136" label="source" />
<Entity id="137" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
