<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Satellite Technology News Satellite Spotlight: <NODE id="47" />Technavio<NODE id="56" /> Announces Top Nine Vendors in the Global <NODE id="98" />ZigBee Enabled Devices<NODE id="120" /> Market for 2016-2020 <NODE id="142" />Technavio<NODE id="151" /> has announced the top nine leading vendors in their recent global <NODE id="218" />ZigBee enabled devices<NODE id="240" /> market 2016-2020 report. This research report also lists 18 other prominent vendors who are expected to gain market share over the forecast period. To identify the top vendors, <NODE id="418" />Technavio<NODE id="427" />'s market research analysts have considered the top revenue contributors for the ZigBee ( News - Alert ) enabled devices market. The report includes market forecast of the global ZigBee market based on product segments that implement ZigBee wireless technology (<NODE id="689" />connected light bulbs<NODE id="710" />, <NODE id="712" />remote controls<NODE id="727" />, <NODE id="729" />smart meters<NODE id="741" />, <NODE id="743" />smart thermostats<NODE id="760" />, and <NODE id="766" />set-top-box<NODE id="777" />). The analysis in this report is based on vendor briefings, interviews with industry experts, and telephone and online surveys. <NODE id="906" />Technavio<NODE id="915" /> analysts have also presented a breakdown of market shares by the leading regions, including APAC, Americas, and EMEA. What spurs the demand for ZigBee? Need for low-energy wireless technology <NODE id="1108" />Technavio<NODE id="1117" />'s senior market research analyst for consumer electronics , Sunil Singh says, Though bluetooth and wi-fi technology is immensely popular and are extensively used in many <NODE id="1288" />IoT (internet of things) devices<NODE id="1320" />, these require high energy levels through <NODE id="1363" />battery-powered devices<NODE id="1386" />. Consumers and service providers are thus opting for alternate wireless technologies such as ZigBee to improve energy efficiency. ZigBee has a lower energy consumption rate than bluetooth and wi-fi and a longer communication range. ZigBee and ZigBee Pro require only 1/10,000th of the energy that is typically needed to run a wi-fi network. The use of a ZigBee wireless network thus counters low battery life and reduces the harmful effects of battery disposal, making it a more viable alternative to other connecting technologies. Top nine vendors in the global <NODE id="1950" />ZigBee enabled devices<NODE id="1972" /> market <NODE id="1980" />Amtel<NODE id="1985" /> <NODE id="1986" />Atmel<NODE id="1991" /> ( News - Alert ) <NODE id="2009" />designs<NODE id="2016" />, <NODE id="2018" />develops<NODE id="2026" />, and <NODE id="2032" />supplies<NODE id="2040" /> <NODE id="2041" />microcontrollers<NODE id="2057" /> and related products used in <NODE id="2087" />industrial<NODE id="2097" /> and <NODE id="2102" />automotive electronics<NODE id="2124" />, <NODE id="2126" />mobile computing<NODE id="2142" />, and <NODE id="2148" />communications devices<NODE id="2170" />. <NODE id="2172" />Atmel<NODE id="2177" /> <NODE id="2178" />offers<NODE id="2184" /> <NODE id="2185" />IEEE<NODE id="2189" /> ( News - Alert ) 802.15.4 ZigBee-certified wireless solutions. The company's ZigBee solutions provide <NODE id="2292" />single-chip<NODE id="2303" /> solutions, <NODE id="2315" />transceivers<NODE id="2327" />, and <NODE id="2333" />modules<NODE id="2340" />. Its BitCloud <NODE id="2355" />ZigBee PRO<NODE id="2365" /> is used in applications of lighting that includes <NODE id="2416" />fluorescent ballasts<NODE id="2436" />, <NODE id="2438" />high-intensity discharge (HID) ballasts<NODE id="2477" />, <NODE id="2479" />LED ballasts<NODE id="2491" />, and lighting control. It is also used in smart energy applications that include <NODE id="2573" />data concentrators<NODE id="2591" />, <NODE id="2593" />electricity meters<NODE id="2611" />, <NODE id="2613" />gas<NODE id="2616" /> and <NODE id="2621" />water meters<NODE id="2633" />, and <NODE id="2639" />in-home display units<NODE id="2660" />. <NODE id="2662" />Digi International<NODE id="2680" /> <NODE id="2681" />Digi International<NODE id="2699" /> <NODE id="2700" />provides<NODE id="2708" /> <NODE id="2709" />wireless products<NODE id="2726" />, <NODE id="2728" />cloud computing devices<NODE id="2751" />, and development services, which include <NODE id="2793" />microprocessors<NODE id="2808" />, <NODE id="2810" />modules<NODE id="2817" />, <NODE id="2819" />satellite communications products<NODE id="2852" />, <NODE id="2854" />development kits<NODE id="2870" />, <NODE id="2872" />software<NODE id="2880" />, and <NODE id="2886" />single-board computers<NODE id="2908" />. The company's ZigBee offerings are <NODE id="2945" />XBee<NODE id="2949" /> and <NODE id="2954" />XBee-PRO ZigBee RF modules<NODE id="2980" />, <NODE id="2982" />XBee ZigBee gateway<NODE id="3001" />, <NODE id="3003" />ConnectPort LTS 8/16/32<NODE id="3026" />, <NODE id="3028" />ConnectCore 6 Single Board Computer<NODE id="3063" />, <NODE id="3065" />ConnectPort X2<NODE id="3079" />, <NODE id="3081" />XBee-Pro ZigBee Wall Router<NODE id="3108" />, <NODE id="3110" />XBee sensors<NODE id="3122" />, <NODE id="3124" />XBee-Pro ZigBee adapters<NODE id="3148" />, and <NODE id="3154" />XStick USB adapters<NODE id="3173" />. The compny serves the energy, government, medical, industrial, retail, and transportation sectors. <NODE id="3274" />Freescale Semiconductor<NODE id="3297" /> ( News - Alert ) <NODE id="3315" />Freescale Semiconductor<NODE id="3338" /> <NODE id="3339" />designs<NODE id="3346" />, <NODE id="3348" />manufactures<NODE id="3360" />, and <NODE id="3366" />sells a wide range of products like<NODE id="3401" /> <NODE id="3402" />embedded microcontrollers<NODE id="3427" />, <NODE id="3429" />microprocessors<NODE id="3444" />, <NODE id="3446" />processors<NODE id="3456" />, <NODE id="3458" />ICs<NODE id="3461" />, <NODE id="3463" />sensors<NODE id="3470" />, <NODE id="3472" />digital signal<NODE id="3486" />, <NODE id="3488" />automotive<NODE id="3498" />, <NODE id="3500" />networking<NODE id="3510" />, <NODE id="3512" />computer<NODE id="3520" />, <NODE id="3522" />communications<NODE id="3536" />, <NODE id="3538" />multimedia<NODE id="3548" />, <NODE id="3550" />medical<NODE id="3557" />, <NODE id="3559" />industrial<NODE id="3569" />, <NODE id="3571" />analog<NODE id="3577" />, <NODE id="3579" />wireless<NODE id="3587" />, <NODE id="3589" />mixed signal<NODE id="3601" />, and <NODE id="3607" />RF products<NODE id="3618" />. The company provides <NODE id="3641" />ZigBee-compliant hardware<NODE id="3666" /> and <NODE id="3671" />software platforms<NODE id="3689" />, which have been certified by approved test labs of the <NODE id="3746" />ZigBee Alliance<NODE id="3761" />. Some <NODE id="3768" />ZigBee products<NODE id="3783" /> offered by the company are <NODE id="3811" />KW2xD<NODE id="3816" />, <NODE id="3818" />MCR20A<NODE id="3824" />, <NODE id="3826" />KW20Z<NODE id="3831" />, <NODE id="3833" />KW21Z<NODE id="3838" />, and <NODE id="3844" />KW41Z<NODE id="3849" />. The company's <NODE id="3865" />ZigBee products<NODE id="3880" /> are used in applications like lighting, security and alarm, <NODE id="3941" />door locks<NODE id="3951" />, <NODE id="3953" />home gateways<NODE id="3966" />, <NODE id="3968" />access controls<NODE id="3983" />, retail, and smart metering. <NODE id="4013" />GreenPeak Technologies<NODE id="4035" /> <NODE id="4036" />GreenPeak Technologies<NODE id="4058" /> provides products for wirelessly connected home applications. It offers advanced <NODE id="4140" />ultra-low-power wireless data communication controller chips<NODE id="4200" /> that are used in smart home applications for <NODE id="4246" />remote controls<NODE id="4261" />, lighting, and HVAC, energy efficiency, <NODE id="4302" />access control<NODE id="4316" />, and security. It offers <NODE id="4342" />ZigBee transceivers<NODE id="4361" />, <NODE id="4363" />ZigBee RF4CE<NODE id="4375" />, and communications solutions for smart home applications. In 2015, the company launched <NODE id="4465" />GP691<NODE id="4470" />, its next-generation <NODE id="4492" />ZigBee radio chip<NODE id="4509" /> and <NODE id="4514" />GPM6000 modules<NODE id="4529" />, for IoT and smart home networks. <NODE id="4564" />NXP Semiconductors<NODE id="4582" /> <NODE id="4583" />NXP Semiconductors<NODE id="4601" /> <NODE id="4602" />offer<NODE id="4607" /> <NODE id="4608" />32-bit microcontroller units<NODE id="4636" /> (<NODE id="4638" />MCUs<NODE id="4642" />) and <NODE id="4648" />IEEE802.15.4 products<NODE id="4669" /> that include <NODE id="4683" />JN51xx wireless microcontrollers<NODE id="4715" />, <NODE id="4717" />ZigBee smart energy<NODE id="4736" />, <NODE id="4738" />light link<NODE id="4748" />, home automation, and <NODE id="4771" />remote control<NODE id="4785" />. The company's <NODE id="4801" />ZigBee products<NODE id="4816" /> are used in home and building automation, wireless sensors networks, asset management, healthcare, <NODE id="4916" />remote control<NODE id="4930" />, security, and <NODE id="4946" />energy-harvesting sensors<NODE id="4971" /> and <NODE id="4976" />switches<NODE id="4984" />. <NODE id="4986" />Renesas Electronics<NODE id="5005" /> <NODE id="5006" />Renesas Electronics<NODE id="5025" /> <NODE id="5026" />offers<NODE id="5032" /> <NODE id="5033" />semiconductor products<NODE id="5055" /> such as <NODE id="5064" />logic ICs<NODE id="5073" />, <NODE id="5075" />memories<NODE id="5083" />, <NODE id="5085" />large-scale ICs<NODE id="5100" />, <NODE id="5102" />microcomputers<NODE id="5116" />, <NODE id="5118" />analog ICs under microcontrollers<NODE id="5151" />, and <NODE id="5157" />analog and power devices<NODE id="5181" />. It offers <NODE id="5193" />ZigBee<NODE id="5199" /> and <NODE id="5204" />IEEE802.15.4 short-range wireless communication network products<NODE id="5268" /> that include <NODE id="5282" />microcontrollers<NODE id="5298" />, M16C/6B solutions, and 78K, V850 solutions. The company's products are used in applications for detecting smoke and intrusion, monitoring environment, <NODE id="5451" />measuring<NODE id="5460" /> or <NODE id="5464" />data collecting systems<NODE id="5487" />, and <NODE id="5493" />locating<NODE id="5501" /> and <NODE id="5506" />tracking systems<NODE id="5522" />. <NODE id="5524" />Silicon Labs<NODE id="5536" /> <NODE id="5537" />Silicon Labs<NODE id="5549" /> <NODE id="5550" />provides<NODE id="5558" /> <NODE id="5559" />mesh networking wireless system-on-chip (SoC) devices<NODE id="5612" />, <NODE id="5614" />ZigBee<NODE id="5620" /> and <NODE id="5625" />thread-protocol stacks<NODE id="5647" />, and <NODE id="5653" />hardware<NODE id="5661" /> and <NODE id="5666" />software development tools<NODE id="5692" /> to OEMs and ODMs, adding ZigBee and thread-technology to <NODE id="5750" />their<NODE id="5755" /> <NODE id="5756" />connected device products<NODE id="5781" />. <NODE id="5783" />Silicon Labs<NODE id="5795" />'<NODE id="5796" /> <NODE id="5797" />mesh networking product<NODE id="5820" /> <NODE id="5821" />offerings include<NODE id="5838" /> <NODE id="5839" />EM358x<NODE id="5845" /> and <NODE id="5850" />EM359x SoCs<NODE id="5861" /> and <NODE id="5866" />network co-processors<NODE id="5887" />, <NODE id="5889" />EM35x SoCs<NODE id="5899" /> and <NODE id="5904" />network co-processors<NODE id="5925" />, and <NODE id="5931" />EM34x ZigBee remote control ICs<NODE id="5962" />. The company's <NODE id="5978" />wireless mesh networking solutions<NODE id="6012" /> are used in <NODE id="6025" />connected home<NODE id="6039" /> and <NODE id="6044" />lighting systems<NODE id="6060" />, <NODE id="6062" />smart meters<NODE id="6074" /> and <NODE id="6079" />thermostats<NODE id="6090" />, <NODE id="6092" />security systems<NODE id="6108" />, and a wide range of <NODE id="6130" />wireless sensor node<NODE id="6150" /> applications. <NODE id="6165" />STMicroelectronics<NODE id="6183" /> <NODE id="6184" />STMicroelectronics<NODE id="6202" /> <NODE id="6203" />offers<NODE id="6209" /> <NODE id="6210" />SPZB250 ZigBee module<NODE id="6231" /> and <NODE id="6236" />ZigBee Pro modules<NODE id="6254" /> based on <NODE id="6264" />STM32W chipset<NODE id="6278" /> that is used in smart energy applications, M2M industrial control, <NODE id="6346" />wireless sensor<NODE id="6361" /> networks, home and building automation, smart appliances, <NODE id="6420" />wireless alarms<NODE id="6435" /> and <NODE id="6440" />security systems<NODE id="6456" />, lighting control, and remote monitoring. In 2015, the company launched <NODE id="6529" />Voice-Over-Bluetooth low energy<NODE id="6560" /> for <NODE id="6565" />wearable<NODE id="6573" /> and <NODE id="6578" />remote-control<NODE id="6592" /> applications. <NODE id="6607" />Texas Instruments<NODE id="6624" /> <NODE id="6625" />Texas Instruments<NODE id="6642" /> <NODE id="6643" />provides<NODE id="6651" /> <NODE id="6652" />ultra-low power microcontrollers<NODE id="6684" />, high-performance <NODE id="6703" />DSP<NODE id="6706" /> and <NODE id="6711" />ARM<NODE id="6714" /> ( News - Alert ) <NODE id="6732" />processors<NODE id="6742" />, and <NODE id="6748" />wireless connectivity products<NODE id="6778" /> for industrial, automotive, personal electronics applications, and more. Its wireless connectivity portfolio supports many wireless technologies and standards such as Bluetooth, Sub-1 GHz, Wi-Fi, GPS and low-power wireless network standards like ZigBee. <NODE id="7033" />ZigBee products<NODE id="7048" /> offered by the company include <NODE id="7080" />SimpleLink ultra-low power ZigBee CC2630 wireless MCU<NODE id="7133" />, <NODE id="7135" />CC2530 wireless MCU<NODE id="7154" />, <NODE id="7156" />CC2531 wireless MCU<NODE id="7175" /> with USB, and <NODE id="7190" />CC2538 ARM Cortex-M3 wireless MCU<NODE id="7223" />. The company's ZigBee solutions are used in connected lighting and home automation, wireless lighting, and generic mesh. Browse Related Reports: Purchase three reports for the price of one by becoming a <NODE id="7427" />Technavio<NODE id="7436" /> subscriber. Subscribing to <NODE id="7464" />Technavio<NODE id="7473" />'s reports allows you to download any three reports per month for the price of one. Contact enquiry@technavio.com with your requirements and a link to our subscription platform. About <NODE id="7657" />Technavio<NODE id="7666" /> <NODE id="7667" />Technavio<NODE id="7676" /> is a leading global technology research and advisory company. The company develops over 2000 pieces of research every year, covering more than 500 technologies across 80 countries. Technavio has about 300 analysts globally who specialize in customized consulting and business research assignments across the latest leading edge technologies. <NODE id="8019" />Technavio<NODE id="8028" /> analysts employ primary as well as secondary research techniques to ascertain the size and vendor landscape in a range of markets. Analysts obtain information using a combination of bottom-up and top-down approaches, besides using in-house market modeling tools and proprietary databases. They corroborate this data with the data obtained from various market participants and stakeholders across the value chain, including vendors, service providers, distributors, re-sellers, and end-users. If you are interested in more information, please contact our media team at media@technavio.com . blog comments powered by Disqus
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/cbe5add8-af13-318f-bfd6-60a5931ebab1" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-26T04:02:33Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:52:39.045Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://satellite.tmcnet.com/news/2016/01/25/8307174.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="47" endPos="56" type="organization" surface="Technavio" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="98" endPos="120" type="product" surface="ZigBee Enabled Devices" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="142" endPos="151" type="organization" surface="Technavio" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="218" endPos="240" type="product" surface="ZigBee enabled devices" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="418" endPos="427" type="organization" surface="Technavio" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="689" endPos="710" type="product" surface="connected light bulbs" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="712" endPos="727" type="product" surface="remote controls" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="729" endPos="741" type="product" surface="smart meters" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="743" endPos="760" type="product" surface="smart thermostats" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="766" endPos="777" type="product" surface="set-top-box" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="906" endPos="915" type="organization" surface="Technavio" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1108" endPos="1117" type="organization" surface="Technavio" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1288" endPos="1320" type="product" surface="IoT (internet of things) devices" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="1363" endPos="1386" type="product" surface="battery-powered devices" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="1950" endPos="1972" type="product" surface="ZigBee enabled devices" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="1980" endPos="1985" type="organization" surface="Amtel" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="1986" endPos="1991" type="organization" surface="Atmel" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="2009" endPos="2016" type="trigger" surface="designs" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="2018" endPos="2026" type="trigger" surface="develops" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2032" endPos="2040" type="trigger" surface="supplies" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="2041" endPos="2057" type="product" surface="microcontrollers" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="2087" endPos="2097" type="product" surface="industrial" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="2102" endPos="2124" type="product" surface="automotive electronics" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="2126" endPos="2142" type="product" surface="mobile computing" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="2148" endPos="2170" type="product" surface="communications devices" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="2172" endPos="2177" type="organization" surface="Atmel" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="2178" endPos="2184" type="trigger" surface="offers" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="2185" endPos="2189" type="organization" surface="IEEE" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="2292" endPos="2303" type="product" surface="single-chip" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="2315" endPos="2327" type="product" surface="transceivers" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="2333" endPos="2340" type="product" surface="modules" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="2355" endPos="2365" type="product" surface="ZigBee PRO" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="2416" endPos="2436" type="product" surface="fluorescent ballasts" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="2438" endPos="2477" type="product" surface="high-intensity discharge (HID) ballasts" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="2479" endPos="2491" type="product" surface="LED ballasts" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="2573" endPos="2591" type="product" surface="data concentrators" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="2593" endPos="2611" type="product" surface="electricity meters" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="2613" endPos="2616" type="product" surface="gas" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="2621" endPos="2633" type="product" surface="water meters" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="2639" endPos="2660" type="product" surface="in-home display units" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="2662" endPos="2680" type="organization" surface="Digi International" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="2681" endPos="2699" type="organization" surface="Digi International" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="2700" endPos="2708" type="trigger" surface="provides" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="2709" endPos="2726" type="product" surface="wireless products" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="2728" endPos="2751" type="product" surface="cloud computing devices" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="2793" endPos="2808" type="product" surface="microprocessors" />
<Entity id="46" startPos="2810" endPos="2817" type="product" surface="modules" />
<Entity id="47" startPos="2819" endPos="2852" type="product" surface="satellite communications products" />
<Entity id="48" startPos="2854" endPos="2870" type="product" surface="development kits" />
<Entity id="49" startPos="2872" endPos="2880" type="product" surface="software" />
<Entity id="50" startPos="2886" endPos="2908" type="product" surface="single-board computers" />
<Entity id="51" startPos="2945" endPos="2949" type="product" surface="XBee" />
<Entity id="52" startPos="2954" endPos="2980" type="product" surface="XBee-PRO ZigBee RF modules" />
<Entity id="53" startPos="2982" endPos="3001" type="product" surface="XBee ZigBee gateway" />
<Entity id="54" startPos="3003" endPos="3026" type="product" surface="ConnectPort LTS 8/16/32" />
<Entity id="55" startPos="3028" endPos="3063" type="product" surface="ConnectCore 6 Single Board Computer" />
<Entity id="56" startPos="3065" endPos="3079" type="product" surface="ConnectPort X2" />
<Entity id="57" startPos="3081" endPos="3108" type="product" surface="XBee-Pro ZigBee Wall Router" />
<Entity id="58" startPos="3110" endPos="3122" type="product" surface="XBee sensors" />
<Entity id="59" startPos="3124" endPos="3148" type="product" surface="XBee-Pro ZigBee adapters" />
<Entity id="60" startPos="3154" endPos="3173" type="product" surface="XStick USB adapters" />
<Entity id="61" startPos="3274" endPos="3297" type="organization" surface="Freescale Semiconductor" />
<Entity id="62" startPos="3315" endPos="3338" type="organization" surface="Freescale Semiconductor" />
<Entity id="63" startPos="3339" endPos="3346" type="trigger" surface="designs" />
<Entity id="64" startPos="3348" endPos="3360" type="trigger" surface="manufactures" />
<Entity id="65" startPos="3366" endPos="3401" type="trigger" surface="sells a wide range of products like" />
<Entity id="66" startPos="3402" endPos="3427" type="product" surface="embedded microcontrollers" />
<Entity id="67" startPos="3429" endPos="3444" type="product" surface="microprocessors" />
<Entity id="68" startPos="3446" endPos="3456" type="product" surface="processors" />
<Entity id="69" startPos="3458" endPos="3461" type="product" surface="ICs" />
<Entity id="70" startPos="3463" endPos="3470" type="product" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="71" startPos="3472" endPos="3486" type="product" surface="digital signal" />
<Entity id="72" startPos="3488" endPos="3498" type="product" surface="automotive" />
<Entity id="73" startPos="3500" endPos="3510" type="product" surface="networking" />
<Entity id="74" startPos="3512" endPos="3520" type="product" surface="computer" />
<Entity id="75" startPos="3522" endPos="3536" type="product" surface="communications" />
<Entity id="76" startPos="3538" endPos="3548" type="product" surface="multimedia" />
<Entity id="77" startPos="3550" endPos="3557" type="product" surface="medical" />
<Entity id="78" startPos="3559" endPos="3569" type="product" surface="industrial" />
<Entity id="79" startPos="3571" endPos="3577" type="product" surface="analog" />
<Entity id="80" startPos="3579" endPos="3587" type="product" surface="wireless" />
<Entity id="81" startPos="3589" endPos="3601" type="product" surface="mixed signal" />
<Entity id="82" startPos="3607" endPos="3618" type="product" surface="RF products" />
<Entity id="83" startPos="3641" endPos="3666" type="product" surface="ZigBee-compliant hardware" />
<Entity id="84" startPos="3671" endPos="3689" type="product" surface="software platforms" />
<Entity id="85" startPos="3746" endPos="3761" type="organization" surface="ZigBee Alliance" />
<Entity id="86" startPos="3768" endPos="3783" type="product" surface="ZigBee products" />
<Entity id="87" startPos="3811" endPos="3816" type="product" surface="KW2xD" />
<Entity id="88" startPos="3818" endPos="3824" type="product" surface="MCR20A" />
<Entity id="89" startPos="3826" endPos="3831" type="product" surface="KW20Z" />
<Entity id="90" startPos="3833" endPos="3838" type="product" surface="KW21Z" />
<Entity id="91" startPos="3844" endPos="3849" type="product" surface="KW41Z" />
<Entity id="92" startPos="3865" endPos="3880" type="product" surface="ZigBee products" />
<Entity id="93" startPos="3941" endPos="3951" type="product" surface="door locks" />
<Entity id="94" startPos="3953" endPos="3966" type="product" surface="home gateways" />
<Entity id="95" startPos="3968" endPos="3983" type="product" surface="access controls" />
<Entity id="96" startPos="4013" endPos="4035" type="organization" surface="GreenPeak Technologies" />
<Entity id="97" startPos="4036" endPos="4058" type="organization" surface="GreenPeak Technologies" />
<Entity id="98" startPos="4140" endPos="4200" type="product" surface="ultra-low-power wireless data communication controller chips" />
<Entity id="99" startPos="4246" endPos="4261" type="product" surface="remote controls" />
<Entity id="100" startPos="4302" endPos="4316" type="product" surface="access control" />
<Entity id="101" startPos="4342" endPos="4361" type="product" surface="ZigBee transceivers" />
<Entity id="102" startPos="4363" endPos="4375" type="product" surface="ZigBee RF4CE" />
<Entity id="103" startPos="4465" endPos="4470" type="product" surface="GP691" />
<Entity id="104" startPos="4492" endPos="4509" type="product" surface="ZigBee radio chip" />
<Entity id="105" startPos="4514" endPos="4529" type="product" surface="GPM6000 modules" />
<Entity id="106" startPos="4564" endPos="4582" type="organization" surface="NXP Semiconductors" />
<Entity id="107" startPos="4583" endPos="4601" type="organization" surface="NXP Semiconductors" />
<Entity id="108" startPos="4602" endPos="4607" type="trigger" surface="offer" />
<Entity id="109" startPos="4608" endPos="4636" type="product" surface="32-bit microcontroller units" />
<Entity id="110" startPos="4638" endPos="4642" type="product" surface="MCUs" />
<Entity id="111" startPos="4648" endPos="4669" type="product" surface="IEEE802.15.4 products" />
<Entity id="112" startPos="4683" endPos="4715" type="product" surface="JN51xx wireless microcontrollers" />
<Entity id="113" startPos="4717" endPos="4736" type="product" surface="ZigBee smart energy" />
<Entity id="114" startPos="4738" endPos="4748" type="product" surface="light link" />
<Entity id="115" startPos="4771" endPos="4785" type="product" surface="remote control" />
<Entity id="116" startPos="4801" endPos="4816" type="product" surface="ZigBee products" />
<Entity id="117" startPos="4916" endPos="4930" type="product" surface="remote control" />
<Entity id="118" startPos="4946" endPos="4971" type="product" surface="energy-harvesting sensors" />
<Entity id="119" startPos="4976" endPos="4984" type="product" surface="switches" />
<Entity id="120" startPos="4986" endPos="5005" type="organization" surface="Renesas Electronics" />
<Entity id="121" startPos="5006" endPos="5025" type="organization" surface="Renesas Electronics" />
<Entity id="122" startPos="5026" endPos="5032" type="trigger" surface="offers" />
<Entity id="123" startPos="5033" endPos="5055" type="product" surface="semiconductor products" />
<Entity id="124" startPos="5064" endPos="5073" type="product" surface="logic ICs" />
<Entity id="125" startPos="5075" endPos="5083" type="product" surface="memories" />
<Entity id="126" startPos="5085" endPos="5100" type="product" surface="large-scale ICs" />
<Entity id="127" startPos="5102" endPos="5116" type="product" surface="microcomputers" />
<Entity id="128" startPos="5118" endPos="5151" type="product" surface="analog ICs under microcontrollers" />
<Entity id="129" startPos="5157" endPos="5181" type="product" surface="analog and power devices" />
<Entity id="130" startPos="5193" endPos="5199" type="product" surface="ZigBee" />
<Entity id="131" startPos="5204" endPos="5268" type="product" surface="IEEE802.15.4 short-range wireless communication network products" />
<Entity id="132" startPos="5282" endPos="5298" type="product" surface="microcontrollers" />
<Entity id="133" startPos="5451" endPos="5460" type="product" surface="measuring" />
<Entity id="134" startPos="5464" endPos="5487" type="product" surface="data collecting systems" />
<Entity id="135" startPos="5493" endPos="5501" type="product" surface="locating" />
<Entity id="136" startPos="5506" endPos="5522" type="product" surface="tracking systems" />
<Entity id="137" startPos="5524" endPos="5536" type="organization" surface="Silicon Labs" />
<Entity id="138" startPos="5537" endPos="5549" type="organization" surface="Silicon Labs" />
<Entity id="139" startPos="5550" endPos="5558" type="trigger" surface="provides" />
<Entity id="140" startPos="5559" endPos="5612" type="product" surface="mesh networking wireless system-on-chip (SoC) devices" />
<Entity id="141" startPos="5614" endPos="5620" type="product" surface="ZigBee" />
<Entity id="142" startPos="5625" endPos="5647" type="product" surface="thread-protocol stacks" />
<Entity id="143" startPos="5653" endPos="5661" type="product" surface="hardware" />
<Entity id="144" startPos="5666" endPos="5692" type="product" surface="software development tools" />
<Entity id="145" startPos="5750" endPos="5755" type="trigger" surface="their" />
<Entity id="146" startPos="5756" endPos="5781" type="product" surface="connected device products" />
<Entity id="147" startPos="5783" endPos="5795" type="organization" surface="Silicon Labs" />
<Entity id="148" startPos="5795" endPos="5796" type="trigger" surface="'" />
<Entity id="149" startPos="5797" endPos="5820" type="product" surface="mesh networking product" />
<Entity id="150" startPos="5821" endPos="5838" type="trigger" surface="offerings include" />
<Entity id="151" startPos="5839" endPos="5845" type="product" surface="EM358x" />
<Entity id="152" startPos="5850" endPos="5861" type="product" surface="EM359x SoCs" />
<Entity id="153" startPos="5866" endPos="5887" type="product" surface="network co-processors" />
<Entity id="154" startPos="5889" endPos="5899" type="product" surface="EM35x SoCs" />
<Entity id="155" startPos="5904" endPos="5925" type="product" surface="network co-processors" />
<Entity id="156" startPos="5931" endPos="5962" type="product" surface="EM34x ZigBee remote control ICs" />
<Entity id="157" startPos="5978" endPos="6012" type="product" surface="wireless mesh networking solutions" />
<Entity id="158" startPos="6025" endPos="6039" type="product" surface="connected home" />
<Entity id="159" startPos="6044" endPos="6060" type="product" surface="lighting systems" />
<Entity id="160" startPos="6062" endPos="6074" type="product" surface="smart meters" />
<Entity id="161" startPos="6079" endPos="6090" type="product" surface="thermostats" />
<Entity id="162" startPos="6092" endPos="6108" type="product" surface="security systems" />
<Entity id="163" startPos="6130" endPos="6150" type="product" surface="wireless sensor node" />
<Entity id="164" startPos="6165" endPos="6183" type="organization" surface="STMicroelectronics" />
<Entity id="165" startPos="6184" endPos="6202" type="organization" surface="STMicroelectronics" />
<Entity id="166" startPos="6203" endPos="6209" type="trigger" surface="offers" />
<Entity id="167" startPos="6210" endPos="6231" type="product" surface="SPZB250 ZigBee module" />
<Entity id="168" startPos="6236" endPos="6254" type="product" surface="ZigBee Pro modules" />
<Entity id="169" startPos="6264" endPos="6278" type="product" surface="STM32W chipset" />
<Entity id="170" startPos="6346" endPos="6361" type="product" surface="wireless sensor" />
<Entity id="171" startPos="6420" endPos="6435" type="product" surface="wireless alarms" />
<Entity id="172" startPos="6440" endPos="6456" type="product" surface="security systems" />
<Entity id="173" startPos="6529" endPos="6560" type="product" surface="Voice-Over-Bluetooth low energy" />
<Entity id="174" startPos="6565" endPos="6573" type="product" surface="wearable" />
<Entity id="175" startPos="6578" endPos="6592" type="product" surface="remote-control" />
<Entity id="176" startPos="6607" endPos="6624" type="organization" surface="Texas Instruments" />
<Entity id="177" startPos="6625" endPos="6642" type="organization" surface="Texas Instruments" />
<Entity id="178" startPos="6643" endPos="6651" type="trigger" surface="provides" />
<Entity id="179" startPos="6652" endPos="6684" type="product" surface="ultra-low power microcontrollers" />
<Entity id="180" startPos="6703" endPos="6706" type="product" surface="DSP" />
<Entity id="181" startPos="6711" endPos="6714" type="product" surface="ARM" />
<Entity id="182" startPos="6732" endPos="6742" type="product" surface="processors" />
<Entity id="183" startPos="6748" endPos="6778" type="product" surface="wireless connectivity products" />
<Entity id="184" startPos="7033" endPos="7048" type="product" surface="ZigBee products" />
<Entity id="185" startPos="7080" endPos="7133" type="product" surface="SimpleLink ultra-low power ZigBee CC2630 wireless MCU" />
<Entity id="186" startPos="7135" endPos="7154" type="product" surface="CC2530 wireless MCU" />
<Entity id="187" startPos="7156" endPos="7175" type="product" surface="CC2531 wireless MCU" />
<Entity id="188" startPos="7190" endPos="7223" type="product" surface="CC2538 ARM Cortex-M3 wireless MCU" />
<Entity id="189" startPos="7427" endPos="7436" type="organization" surface="Technavio" />
<Entity id="190" startPos="7464" endPos="7473" type="organization" surface="Technavio" />
<Entity id="191" startPos="7657" endPos="7666" type="organization" surface="Technavio" />
<Entity id="192" startPos="7667" endPos="7676" type="organization" surface="Technavio" />
<Entity id="193" startPos="8019" endPos="8028" type="organization" surface="Technavio" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="194" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="50" label="product" />
<Entity id="46" label="product" />
<Entity id="49" label="product" />
<Entity id="45" label="product" />
<Entity id="47" label="product" />
<Entity id="48" label="product" />
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="17" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="19" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="18" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="16" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="195" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="26" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="25" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="196" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="44" label="product" />
<Entity id="43" label="product" />
<Entity id="42" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="41" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="197" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="74" label="product" />
<Entity id="71" label="product" />
<Entity id="72" label="product" />
<Entity id="69" label="product" />
<Entity id="78" label="product" />
<Entity id="73" label="product" />
<Entity id="79" label="product" />
<Entity id="67" label="product" />
<Entity id="70" label="product" />
<Entity id="75" label="product" />
<Entity id="77" label="product" />
<Entity id="81" label="product" />
<Entity id="80" label="product" />
<Entity id="82" label="product" />
<Entity id="68" label="product" />
<Entity id="66" label="product" />
<Entity id="76" label="product" />
<Entity id="63" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="64" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="65" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="62" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="198" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="113" label="product" />
<Entity id="112" label="product" />
<Entity id="114" label="product" />
<Entity id="111" label="product" />
<Entity id="109" label="product" />
<Entity id="115" label="product" />
<Entity id="108" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="107" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="199" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="127" label="product" />
<Entity id="129" label="product" />
<Entity id="126" label="product" />
<Entity id="125" label="product" />
<Entity id="128" label="product" />
<Entity id="124" label="product" />
<Entity id="123" label="product" />
<Entity id="122" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="121" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="200" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="142" label="product" />
<Entity id="143" label="product" />
<Entity id="141" label="product" />
<Entity id="144" label="product" />
<Entity id="140" label="product" />
<Entity id="139" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="138" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="201" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="146" label="product" />
<Entity id="145" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="138" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="202" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="151" label="product" />
<Entity id="153" label="product" />
<Entity id="155" label="product" />
<Entity id="154" label="product" />
<Entity id="156" label="product" />
<Entity id="152" label="product" />
<Entity id="149" label="product" />
<Entity id="148" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="150" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="147" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="203" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="168" label="product" />
<Entity id="167" label="product" />
<Entity id="166" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="165" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="204" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="181" label="product" />
<Entity id="179" label="product" />
<Entity id="180" label="product" />
<Entity id="183" label="product" />
<Entity id="182" label="product" />
<Entity id="178" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="177" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
