<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT><NODE id="0" />Microsemi<NODE id="9" /> opens Aviation Center of Excellence for intelligent power PDF Date: 02/03/2016 Categories: Design Tools, Education, Training &amp; Careers, Government &amp; Industry, Manufacturing &amp; Assembly, Power Modules, Power Supplies <NODE id="225" />Microsemi<NODE id="234" /> , a leading provider of <NODE id="259" />semiconductor solutions<NODE id="282" /> differentiated by power, security, reliability and performance, today announced the opening of its <NODE id="382" />Aviation Centre of Excellence<NODE id="411" /> in Ennis, Ireland. The 1,900 square-foot research and development facility will support the design, development and manufacturing of <NODE id="545" />Microsemi’s<NODE id="556" /> new product line of <NODE id="577" />high reliability aviation intelligent power solutions ( IPS )<NODE id="638" />. During a grand opening ceremony this morning, Jim Aralis , chief technology officer and vice president of advanced development at <NODE id="770" />Microsemi<NODE id="779" /> , joined fellow executives, employees and community members for The Aviation Centre of Excellence’s unveiling. Following the event, Aralis is hosting an engineering forum open to the technical community. '<NODE id="985" />Our<NODE id="988" /> new Aviation Centre of Excellence is the latest example of <NODE id="1048" />Microsemi’s<NODE id="1059" /> investment in research and development in Ireland, and reflects our Ennis facility’s important contributions to the wider <NODE id="1182" />Microsemi<NODE id="1191" /> global product/technology development network. <NODE id="1239" />We<NODE id="1241" /> now offer a complete solution for <NODE id="1276" />high reliability aviation intelligent power solutions<NODE id="1329" /> from design to manufacturing,' said Aralis . 'The facility will not only provide access to a portfolio of highly integrated, flexible and scalable solutions for aviation electric actuation and power conversion applications, but customers will also have access to a full technical service provider as an extension of their design teams.' Development capabilities The facility’s new research and development laboratory is fully resourced with modeling, simulation, analysis and algorithm development capabilities providing accelerated product innovation. The state-of-the-art measuring equipment enables extensive product testing while a dedicated reliability laboratory facilitates product qualification and long-term application specific life testing. As the aviation sector continues to demand higher levels of reliability and integration in the area of power electronics in order to realize the goal of more electric aircraft (MEA), <NODE id="2265" />Microsemi’s<NODE id="2276" /> <NODE id="2277" />Aviation Centre of Excellence<NODE id="2306" /> will play a critical role in supporting this objective. According to professor Pat Wheeler, head of department, Electrical and Electronic Engineering and deputy head of the Power Electronics, Machines and Controls ( PEMC ) Research Group at the University of Nottingham (UK), power electronics is the enabling technology for the more electric aircraft. However MEA advantages are marginal with current technology and advancements in the areas of reliability, power density, wide band gap semiconductor materials and thermal management are essential to achieve its full potential. <NODE id="2887" />Microsemi<NODE id="2896" /> is developing <NODE id="2911" />IPS<NODE id="2914" /> products for a variety of growing applications within the commercial aviation industry. According to <NODE id="3016" />global market research and consulting<NODE id="3053" /> company <NODE id="3062" />MarketsandMarkets<NODE id="3079" /> , the actuator, electrical and electronics systems market was valued at $8 billion in 2013 and is expected to grow at a compound annual growth rate ( CAGR ) of 14 percent to reach $21 billion by 2020. The electrical systems are expected to grow at a CAGR of 16 percent and the electronics components market is expected to grow at a CAGR of 13 percent. Flagship products Among the flagship products of <NODE id="3481" />Microsemi’s<NODE id="3492" /> new <NODE id="3497" />Aviation Centre of Excellence<NODE id="3526" /> is the <NODE id="3534" />aviation power core module ( PCM )<NODE id="3568" /> with an integrated FPGA and hybrid power drive ( HPD ) stage. The PCM controls the electrical motors used in applications such as primary flight control actuation and landing gear systems. It interfaces seamlessly with aircraft power supplies and flight computers, providing vital sensor feedback for monitoring. Customization options are also available to ensure an optimized product offering for customers. The hybrid power drive ( HPD ) with integrated solenoid drive is also available as a stand-alone product. The manufacturing of these power systems leverages the <NODE id="4139" />company’s<NODE id="4148" /> existing operations infrastructure as well as the high quality and reliability processes in the current Ennis facility, which is a manufacturing center for <NODE id="4305" />Microsemi’s<NODE id="4316" /> high reliability discrete products. For more information, about the <NODE id="4385" />Aviation Centre of Excellence<NODE id="4414" />, visit <NODE id="4422" />http://www.microsemi.com/applications/commercial-aviation/aviation-center-of-excellence<NODE id="4509" />. 'This investment in aviation intelligent power solutions is a significant testament to our vision to be a full solutions provider, leveraging the extensive technologies and capabilities across the <NODE id="4708" />company<NODE id="4715" /> to expand our footprint in focus applications,' said Siobhan Dolan Clancy, vice president of business development, aerospace, at <NODE id="4845" />Microsemi<NODE id="4854" /> . 'By combining our team’s industry-leading technology from around the globe with our aerospace power module capabilities, we look forward to announcing truly game-changing developments in this market.' <NODE id="5058" />Microsemi<NODE id="5067" /> : Committed to Ireland <NODE id="5091" />Microsemi<NODE id="5100" /> established its presence in Ireland in 1992 through the acquisition of a facility in Ennis, Co. Clare and in 2012 the <NODE id="5219" />company<NODE id="5226" /> named the Ennis facility as its European headquarters. Over the past several years, <NODE id="5311" />Microsemi<NODE id="5320" /> has made a significant investment in <NODE id="5358" />its<NODE id="5361" /> Ennis operations and now employs 270 people, making <NODE id="5414" />it<NODE id="5416" /> one of the largest employers in the area. <NODE id="5459" />Microsemi’s<NODE id="5470" /> annual spend in Ireland is in excess of $20 million annually and <NODE id="5536" />it<NODE id="5538" /> continues to recruit engineers and other technical professionals. The Ennis facility’s key competencies are the development, manufacturing and high reliability testing of semiconductors to meet stringent aerospace, satellite, medical and security standards and it is now one of the largest such facilities globally. <NODE id="5855" />Microsemi<NODE id="5864" /> also has a design group in Dublin which is focused on <NODE id="5919" />advanced system-on-chip ( SoC ) software and solutions<NODE id="5973" /> with an emphasis on ARM processor-centric designs, and a group in Cork who are specialized in the <NODE id="6072" />development of highly efficient and scalable embedded hardware and software for real-time Ethernet operations<NODE id="6181" />. Commercial Aviation Electronics <NODE id="6215" />Microsemi<NODE id="6224" />
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/dfa51935-110b-3ea0-bb62-908504bae88c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-03T16:44:09Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:00:09.525Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.powersystemsdesign.com/microsemi-opens-aviation-center-of-excellence-for-intelligent-power" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="0" endPos="9" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="225" endPos="234" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="259" endPos="282" type="industry" surface="semiconductor solutions" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="382" endPos="411" type="organization" surface="Aviation Centre of Excellence" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="545" endPos="556" type="organization" surface="Microsemi’s" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="577" endPos="638" type="industry" surface="high reliability aviation intelligent power solutions ( IPS )" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="770" endPos="779" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="985" endPos="988" type="organization" surface="Our" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1048" endPos="1059" type="organization" surface="Microsemi’s" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="1182" endPos="1191" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="1239" endPos="1241" type="organization" surface="We" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1276" endPos="1329" type="industry" surface="high reliability aviation intelligent power solutions" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="2265" endPos="2276" type="organization" surface="Microsemi’s" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="2277" endPos="2306" type="organization" surface="Aviation Centre of Excellence" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="2887" endPos="2896" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="2911" endPos="2914" type="industry" surface="IPS" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="3016" endPos="3053" type="industry" surface="global market research and consulting" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="3062" endPos="3079" type="organization" surface="MarketsandMarkets" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="3481" endPos="3492" type="organization" surface="Microsemi’s" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="3497" endPos="3526" type="organization" surface="Aviation Centre of Excellence" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="3534" endPos="3568" type="product" surface="aviation power core module ( PCM )" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="4139" endPos="4148" type="organization" surface="company’s" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="4305" endPos="4316" type="organization" surface="Microsemi’s" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="4385" endPos="4414" type="organization" surface="Aviation Centre of Excellence" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="4422" endPos="4509" type="url" surface="http://www.microsemi.com/applications/commercial-aviation/aviation-center-of-excellence" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="4708" endPos="4715" type="organization" surface="company" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="4845" endPos="4854" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="5058" endPos="5067" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="5091" endPos="5100" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="5219" endPos="5226" type="organization" surface="company" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="5311" endPos="5320" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="5358" endPos="5361" type="organization" surface="its" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="5414" endPos="5416" type="organization" surface="it" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="5459" endPos="5470" type="organization" surface="Microsemi’s" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="5536" endPos="5538" type="organization" surface="it" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="5855" endPos="5864" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="5919" endPos="5973" type="industry" surface="advanced system-on-chip ( SoC ) software and solutions" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="6072" endPos="6181" type="industry" surface="development of highly efficient and scalable embedded hardware and software for real-time Ethernet operations" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="6215" endPos="6224" type="organization" surface="Microsemi" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="39" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
<Entity id="2" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="40" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="41" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="14" label="company" />
<Entity id="15" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="42" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="17" label="company" />
<Entity id="16" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="43" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="35" label="company" />
<Entity id="36" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="44" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="35" label="company" />
<Entity id="37" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="45" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="20" label="product" />
<Entity id="19" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="46" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="3" label="child" />
<Entity id="1" label="parent" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="47" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="13" label="child" />
<Entity id="12" label="parent" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="48" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="19" label="child" />
<Entity id="18" label="parent" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="49" NAME="CompanyWebsite">
<Entity id="24" label="website" />
<Entity id="23" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="50" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="18" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="26" label="target" />
<Entity id="31" label="target" />
<Entity id="0" label="target" />
<Entity id="22" label="target" />
<Entity id="38" label="target" />
<Entity id="34" label="target" />
<Entity id="21" label="target" />
<Entity id="25" label="target" />
<Entity id="28" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="33" label="target" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
<Entity id="30" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="32" label="target" />
<Entity id="35" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="27" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
