<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Polys push students to develop for the market Schools actively commercialise their work and students get to experience the industry A film that turns a smartphone into a 3D screen; a ready-to-drink Singapore Sling; and a smart sensor that tracks elderly patients' movements in the toilet - these are all homegrown products in the market that originated from the country's polytechnics. Just like universities here, polytechnics are actively commercialising their work, from assistive devices and games to tech applications and health products, and challenging students to solve real-world problems. In recent years, they have been clinching more licensing deals with companies, filing more patents and starting entrepreneurship programmes for students. Several, including <NODE id="772" />Nanyang Polytechnic (NYP)<NODE id="797" />, have piloted schemes to protect students' projects as they have noticed a growing interest from companies keen to adopt their work. POLYTECHNICS' CREATIVE EFFORTS <NODE id="962" />NANYANG POLYTECHNIC<NODE id="981" /> •About 160 patents in the last 10 years, compared to 57 from 1998 to 2004. •Clinched 60 licensing deals since 2009. <NODE id="1098" />TEMASEK POLYTECHNIC<NODE id="1117" /> •Filed 51 patents - six of which were awarded - in the last five years, from financial year (FY) 2010 to 2014. •From FY2005 to 2009, it filed 40 patents, 16 of which were awarded. •Its number of licensed projects also doubled from three in FY2005 to 2009 to six in FY2010 to 2014. <NODE id="1399" />NGEE ANN POLYTECHNIC<NODE id="1419" /> •Awarded six patents from 2010 to 2015, up from two from 2001 to 2009. •Had 12 licensed projects from 2010 to 2015, compared to none from 2001 to 2009. <NODE id="1572" />SINGAPORE POLYTECHNIC<NODE id="1593" /> •Filed 23 patents from 2010 to 2015, up from six in the preceding years from 1999, when it filed its first patent. <NODE id="1709" />REPUBLIC POLYTECHNIC<NODE id="1729" /> •Filed seven patents since 2003 when the polytechnic was first set up, with one patent awarded so far. •Had 10 projects licensed from 2009 to 2014, and none before that. These efforts are part of a push by polytechnics for students to go beyond classroom learning and exam results, and be able to think creatively. It is also a chance for students to have a taste of industry projects and the work that goes into filing patents and developing products. Such a push is even more relevant now as Singapore shifts to an innovation-driven economy, with the Government encouraging firms to adopt new technologies to stay ahead in the global economy. Dr Valdew Singh, director of <NODE id="2404" />NYP's<NODE id="2409" /> <NODE id="2410" />Centre for Technology Innovation and Commercialisation<NODE id="2464" />, said: Students learn to be resourceful, deal with limitations, liaise with companies and address issues on the spot when they are involved in projects. Some of these solutions can be adopted by firms. Dr Lee Mun Wai, senior manager of the <NODE id="2705" />Singapore Polytechnic's<NODE id="2728" /> <NODE id="2729" />Food Innovation Resource Centre<NODE id="2760" />, said students learn about global and local trends as they interact with researchers and industry experts. The polytechnics have entrepreneurship or commercialisation centres, which work with various industries to turn research into real-world technologies. <NODE id="3019" />NYP<NODE id="3022" />, which set up a centre for tech commercialisation and licensing in 2008, has had 60 licensing deals since 2009. Among the polytechnics, <NODE id="3159" />it<NODE id="3161" /> has also filed the most number of patents - about 160 in the last 10 years, compared with 57 from 1998 to 2004. <NODE id="3274" />Its<NODE id="3277" /> first patent was filed in 1998. A patent is a right granted to an invention's owner that prevents others from making, using, importing or selling the invention without permission. In the last decade, <NODE id="3478" />Temasek Polytechnic's<NODE id="3499" /> office of research and technology has worked on more than 150 research and development projects with industry partners, some of which led to patented inventions. <NODE id="3662" />It<NODE id="3664" /> filed 51 patents in the last five years, from the financial year (FY) 2010 to 2014, up from 40 patents from FY2005 to 2009. The polytechnics are also providing students with the space to take their ideas further. For instance, <NODE id="3892" />Ngee Ann Polytechnic<NODE id="3912" /> set up an innovation and entrepreneurship office called <NODE id="3969" />The Sandbox<NODE id="3980" /> last year for students to brainstorm and test their projects. Mr Gaines Goh, a third-year business studies student at <NODE id="4099" />Ngee Ann Polytechnic (NP)<NODE id="4124" />, worked on a project in sustainable cardbox packaging at The Sandbox last year. The school is very encouraging and lets us try out ideas. Whether we fail or succeed, it helps us reflect on the process of learning and trying, said the 20-year-old. Along with two friends from the <NODE id="4404" />National University of Singapore (NUS)<NODE id="4442" />, he developed an integrated smart terminal that indicates to bus drivers that there are elderly and people with disabilities who want to board their bus, so they can have an easier time boarding when the buses arrive. He is in talks with the <NODE id="4685" />Infocomm Development Authority of Singapore<NODE id="4728" /> to develop this idea further. Some of the polytechnics attach students with lecturers to guide them through their ideas. They also provide financial help to students who need funding for projects. Since 2010, <NODE id="4938" />NP<NODE id="4940" /> has supported about 250 student projects - each with a funding cap of $2,000 - to help students develop their ideas. In January last year, <NODE id="5080" />NYP<NODE id="5083" /> set aside $20,000 to protect students' works, as part of a pilot scheme to recognise and protect selected works of design students. <NODE id="5216" />It<NODE id="5218" /> is currently reviewing 10 projects. <NODE id="5255" />Its<NODE id="5258" /> spokesman said <NODE id="5274" />it<NODE id="5276" /> started the scheme as <NODE id="5299" />it<NODE id="5301" /> had in recent years received more requests to commercialise students' works that were displayed at public exhibitions. <NODE id="5421" />It<NODE id="5423" /> also wanted to educate students on intellectual property issues. Polytechnic students also learn about innovation in research projects. For instance, third-year biotechnology student Charmaine Lee was one of five <NODE id="5637" />Republic Polytechnic (RP)<NODE id="5662" /> students who were part of a project last year to develop a diagnostic kit that can differentiate between the dengue and chikungunya viruses in a single test. The kit was devised by researchers from <NODE id="5861" />NUS<NODE id="5864" /> and <NODE id="5869" />RP<NODE id="5871" />, who are in talks with biotechnology companies about its commercial potential. Ms Lee, 19, said the experience gave her a glimpse of what working as a researcher on a project with commercial potential feels like. I learnt new techniques, mainly technical, on how to run tests, how to operate machines and read results. Mr Goh said: Innovation and research is a stepping stone to developing yourself and the country. If people stick to the plain-old desk jobs and don't think out of the box, there will be no development, no latest technologies. He added: It also teaches you to never give up, even though you may fail many times. A version of this article appeared in the print edition of The Straits Times on January 25, 2016, with the headline 'Polys push students to develop for the market'. Print Edition | Subscribe We have been experiencing some problems with subscriber log-ins and apologise for the inconvenience caused. Until we resolve the issues, subscribers need not log in to access ST Digital articles. But a log-in is still required for our PDFs.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/8106c35a-4e9b-3292-a30a-12d1436338fd" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-24T22:57:11Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:24:00.525Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/education/polys-push-students-to-develop-for-the-market" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="772" endPos="797" type="organization" surface="Nanyang Polytechnic (NYP)" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="962" endPos="981" type="organization" surface="NANYANG POLYTECHNIC" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1098" endPos="1117" type="organization" surface="TEMASEK POLYTECHNIC" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1399" endPos="1419" type="organization" surface="NGEE ANN POLYTECHNIC" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1572" endPos="1593" type="organization" surface="SINGAPORE POLYTECHNIC" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1709" endPos="1729" type="organization" surface="REPUBLIC POLYTECHNIC" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="2404" endPos="2409" type="organization" surface="NYP's" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="2410" endPos="2464" type="organization" surface="Centre for Technology Innovation and Commercialisation" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="2705" endPos="2728" type="organization" surface="Singapore Polytechnic's" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2729" endPos="2760" type="organization" surface="Food Innovation Resource Centre" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3019" endPos="3022" type="organization" surface="NYP" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="3159" endPos="3161" type="organization" surface="it" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="3274" endPos="3277" type="organization" surface="Its" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="3478" endPos="3499" type="organization" surface="Temasek Polytechnic's" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="3662" endPos="3664" type="organization" surface="It" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="3892" endPos="3912" type="organization" surface="Ngee Ann Polytechnic" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="3969" endPos="3980" type="product" surface="The Sandbox" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="4099" endPos="4124" type="organization" surface="Ngee Ann Polytechnic (NP)" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="4404" endPos="4442" type="organization" surface="National University of Singapore (NUS)" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="4685" endPos="4728" type="organization" surface="Infocomm Development Authority of Singapore" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="4938" endPos="4940" type="organization" surface="NP" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="5080" endPos="5083" type="organization" surface="NYP" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="5216" endPos="5218" type="organization" surface="It" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="5255" endPos="5258" type="organization" surface="Its" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="5274" endPos="5276" type="organization" surface="it" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="5299" endPos="5301" type="organization" surface="it" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="5421" endPos="5423" type="organization" surface="It" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="5637" endPos="5662" type="organization" surface="Republic Polytechnic (RP)" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="5861" endPos="5864" type="organization" surface="NUS" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="5869" endPos="5871" type="organization" surface="RP" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="30" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="16" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="7" label="child" />
<Entity id="6" label="parent" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="32" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="9" label="child" />
<Entity id="8" label="parent" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="33" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
<Entity id="26" label="target" />
<Entity id="21" label="target" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="23" label="target" />
<Entity id="25" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="24" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="22" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="34" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="2" label="source" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="13" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="35" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="3" label="source" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="20" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="36" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="4" label="source" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="37" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="5" label="source" />
<Entity id="27" label="target" />
<Entity id="29" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="38" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="18" label="source" />
<Entity id="28" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
