<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>News Researchers Submit Patent Application, <NODE id="44" />Battery Thermal Management System<NODE id="77" /> Including <NODE id="88" />Thermal Interface Material<NODE id="114" /> with Integrated <NODE id="131" />Heater Element<NODE id="145" />, for... Politics &amp; Government Week | Thursday, 04 February 2016 18:30 (EST) Researchers Submit Patent Application, <NODE id="261" />Battery Thermal Management System<NODE id="294" /> Including <NODE id="305" />Thermal Interface Material<NODE id="331" /> with Integrated <NODE id="348" />Heater Element<NODE id="362" />, for Approval (USPTO 20160020496) By a News Reporter-Staff News Editor at Politics &amp; Government Week -- From Washington, D.C., VerticalNews journalists report that a patent application by the inventors Burrows, Neil Robert (White Lake Twp., MI); Chorian, Steve F. (Canton, MI); Garfinkel, George Albert (Westland, MI); Vejalla, Dhanunjay (Novi, MI); Kuo, Chung-hsing (Ann Arbor, MI), filed on July 21, 2014, was made available online on January 28, 2016. No assignee for this patent application has been made. News editors obtained the following quote from the background information supplied by the inventors: The need to reduce fuel consumption and emissions in <NODE id="1027" />automobiles<NODE id="1038" /> and other <NODE id="1049" />vehicles<NODE id="1057" /> is well known. Therefore, <NODE id="1084" />vehicles<NODE id="1092" /> are being developed that reduce or completely eliminate reliance on an <NODE id="1164" />internal combustion engine<NODE id="1190" />. <NODE id="1192" />Electrified vehicles<NODE id="1212" /> are one type of <NODE id="1229" />vehicle<NODE id="1236" /> currently being developed for this purpose. In general, <NODE id="1293" />electrified vehicles<NODE id="1313" /> differ from conventional <NODE id="1339" />motor vehicles<NODE id="1353" /> in that they are selectively driven by one or more <NODE id="1405" />battery powered electric machines<NODE id="1438" />. Conventional <NODE id="1453" />motor vehicles<NODE id="1467" />, by contrast, rely exclusively on the <NODE id="1506" />internal combustion engine<NODE id="1532" /> to drive the <NODE id="1546" />vehicle<NODE id="1553" />. <NODE id="1555" />Electrified vehicle batteries<NODE id="1584" /> are typically constructed of one or more <NODE id="1626" />battery arrays<NODE id="1640" /> that include a plurality of <NODE id="1669" />battery cells<NODE id="1682" />. It may be necessary to thermally manage the <NODE id="1728" />battery cells<NODE id="1741" />. For example, the <NODE id="1760" />battery cells<NODE id="1773" /> may need to be cooled during some conditions or heated during other conditions. As a supplement to the background information on this patent application, <NODE id="1928" />VerticalNews<NODE id="1940" /> correspondents also obtained the inventors' summary information for this patent application: A <NODE id="2036" />battery pack<NODE id="2048" /> according to an example of the present disclosure includes a <NODE id="2110" />battery cell<NODE id="2122" />, a <NODE id="2126" />thermal interface material<NODE id="2152" /> adjacent the <NODE id="2166" />battery cell<NODE id="2178" /> and a <NODE id="2185" />heater element<NODE id="2199" /> integrated with the <NODE id="2220" />thermal interface material<NODE id="2246" />. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the <NODE id="2313" />heater element<NODE id="2327" /> is a <NODE id="2333" />resistive heater wire<NODE id="2354" />. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the <NODE id="2421" />heater element<NODE id="2435" /> is embedded, bonded, overlaid or printed on the <NODE id="2484" />thermal interface material<NODE id="2510" />. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the <NODE id="2577" />heater element<NODE id="2591" /> is contiguous with a top surface or a bottom surface of the <NODE id="2652" />thermal interface material<NODE id="2678" />. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the <NODE id="2745" />thermal interface material<NODE id="2771" /> is sandwiched between the <NODE id="2798" />battery cell<NODE id="2810" /> and a second <NODE id="2824" />battery cell<NODE id="2836" />. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the <NODE id="2903" />heater element<NODE id="2917" /> is sandwiched between a first layer and a second layer of the <NODE id="2980" />thermal interface material<NODE id="3006" />. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the <NODE id="3073" />heater element<NODE id="3087" /> is arranged in a grid that includes a plurality of <NODE id="3139" />heating wires<NODE id="3152" /> arranged as a meandering loop. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the <NODE id="3249" />thermal interface material<NODE id="3275" /> is wrapped around the <NODE id="3298" />battery cell<NODE id="3310" />. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the <NODE id="3377" />thermal interface material<NODE id="3403" /> contacts a <NODE id="3415" />cold plate<NODE id="3425" />. A further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments includes a <NODE id="3495" />control system<NODE id="3509" /> that monitors at least one temperature condition associated with the <NODE id="3579" />battery cell<NODE id="3591" /> and actuates the <NODE id="3609" />heater element<NODE id="3623" /> if the at least one temperature condition drops below a predefined threshold value. A <NODE id="3710" />battery pack<NODE id="3722" /> according to an example of the present disclosure includes a <NODE id="3784" />battery array<NODE id="3797" /> that includes a plurality of <NODE id="3827" />battery cells<NODE id="3840" />, a <NODE id="3844" />tray<NODE id="3848" /> that supports the <NODE id="3867" />battery array<NODE id="3880" />, a <NODE id="3884" />thermal interface material<NODE id="3910" /> between the <NODE id="3923" />tray<NODE id="3927" /> and the <NODE id="3936" />battery array<NODE id="3949" />, and a <NODE id="3957" />heater element<NODE id="3971" /> that heats the plurality of <NODE id="4000" />battery cells<NODE id="4013" /> in response to at least one temperature condition dropping below a predefined threshold value. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the <NODE id="4174" />heater element<NODE id="4188" /> is integrated with the <NODE id="4212" />thermal interface material<NODE id="4238" />. A further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments includes a second <NODE id="4315" />battery array<NODE id="4328" /> adjacent to the <NODE id="4345" />battery array<NODE id="4358" />, the <NODE id="4364" />thermal interface material<NODE id="4390" /> positioned between the <NODE id="4414" />tray<NODE id="4418" /> and each of the <NODE id="4435" />battery array<NODE id="4448" /> and the second <NODE id="4464" />battery array<NODE id="4477" />. A further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments includes a <NODE id="4547" />control system<NODE id="4561" /> that includes a first <NODE id="4584" />sensor<NODE id="4590" /> that monitors a first temperature condition, a second <NODE id="4645" />sensor<NODE id="4651" /> that monitors a second temperature condition, and a <NODE id="4704" />control module<NODE id="4718" /> that selectively actuates the <NODE id="4749" />heater element<NODE id="4763" /> based on the first temperature condition and the second temperature condition. A further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments includes a <NODE id="4911" />cold plate<NODE id="4921" /> positioned between the <NODE id="4945" />thermal interface material<NODE id="4971" /> and the <NODE id="4980" />tray<NODE id="4984" />. A method according to an example of the present disclosure includes monitoring at least one temperature condition of a <NODE id="5105" />battery pack<NODE id="5117" /> that includes a <NODE id="5134" />battery cell<NODE id="5146" />, a <NODE id="5150" />thermal interface material<NODE id="5176" /> and a <NODE id="5183" />heater element<NODE id="5197" /> integrated with the <NODE id="5218" />thermal interface material<NODE id="5244" />, and conditioning the <NODE id="5267" />battery cell<NODE id="5279" /> with the <NODE id="5289" />heater element<NODE id="5303" /> if the at least one temperature condition drops below a predefined threshold value. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the monitoring step includes sensing a first temperature condition with a first <NODE id="5529" />sensor<NODE id="5535" />, sensing a second temperature condition with a second <NODE id="5590" />sensor<NODE id="5596" /> and comparing at least one of the first temperature condition and the second temperature condition to the predefined threshold value. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the first temperature condition is an ambient temperature condition and the second temperature condition is a temperature condition of the <NODE id="5931" />battery cell<NODE id="5943" />. A further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments includes ending the conditioning step once the at least one temperature condition exceeds the predefined threshold valve. In a further embodiment of any of the foregoing embodiments, the conditioning step is executed based on an estimated departure time selected by a vehicle operator. The embodiments, examples and alternatives of the preceding paragraphs, the claims, or the following description and drawings, including any of their various aspects or respective individual features, may be taken independently or in any combination. Features described in connection with one embodiment are applicable to all embodiments, unless such features are incompatible. The various features and advantages of this disclosure will become apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description. The drawings that accompany the detailed description can be briefly described as follows. BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS FIG. 1 schematically illustrates a <NODE id="6970" />powertrain<NODE id="6980" /> of an <NODE id="6987" />electrified vehicle<NODE id="7006" />. FIG. 2 illustrates a <NODE id="7029" />battery pack<NODE id="7041" /> according to a first embodiment of this disclosure. FIG. 3A illustrates a first configuration of a <NODE id="7141" />heater element<NODE id="7155" /> of a <NODE id="7161" />battery thermal management system<NODE id="7194" />. FIG. 3B illustrates a second configuration of a <NODE id="7244" />heater element<NODE id="7258" /> of a <NODE id="7264" />battery thermal management system<NODE id="7297" />. FIG. 3C illustrates a third configuration of a <NODE id="7346" />heater element<NODE id="7360" /> of a <NODE id="7366" />battery thermal management system<NODE id="7399" />. FIG. 3D illustrates a fourth configuration of a <NODE id="7449" />heater element<NODE id="7463" /> of a <NODE id="7469" />battery thermal management system<NODE id="7502" />. FIG. 4 illustrates a <NODE id="7525" />battery pack<NODE id="7537" /> according to a second embodiment of this disclosure. FIG. 5 illustrates another <NODE id="7618" />battery pack<NODE id="7630" />. FIG. 6 illustrates yet another <NODE id="7663" />battery pack<NODE id="7675" />. FIG. 7 schematically illustrates an exemplary control strategy for operating a <NODE id="7756" />battery thermal management system<NODE id="7789" />. For additional information on this patent application, see: Burrows, Neil Robert; Chorian, Steve F.; Garfinkel, George Albert; Vejalla, Dhanunjay; Kuo, Chung-hsing. <NODE id="7956" />Battery Thermal Management System<NODE id="7989" /> Including <NODE id="8000" />Thermal Interface Material<NODE id="8026" /> with Integrated <NODE id="8043" />Heater Element<NODE id="8057" />. Filed July 21, 2014 and posted January 28, 2016. Patent URL: http://appft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO2&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsearch-adv.html&amp;r=1313&amp;p=27&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;d=PG01&amp;S1=20160121.PD.&amp;OS=PD/20160121&amp;RS=PD/20160121 Keywords for this news article include: Patents. Our reports deliver fact-based news of research and discoveries from around the world. Copyright 2016, NewsRx LLC DISCLOSURE: The views and opinions expressed in this article are those of the authors, and do not represent the views of equities.com . Readers should not consider statements made by the author as formal recommendations and should consult their financial advisor before making any investment decisions. To read our full disclosure, please go to: http://www.equities.com/disclaimer You have to be logged in to leave a comment.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/556d8f46-fcbb-36b1-9f0d-66f6a47367da" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-05T20:52:05Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:07:32.739Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.equities.com/news/researchers-submit-patent-application-battery-thermal-management-system-including-thermal-interface-material-with-integrated-heater-element-for" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="44" endPos="77" type="product" surface="Battery Thermal Management System" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="88" endPos="114" type="product" surface="Thermal Interface Material" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="131" endPos="145" type="product" surface="Heater Element" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="261" endPos="294" type="product" surface="Battery Thermal Management System" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="305" endPos="331" type="product" surface="Thermal Interface Material" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="348" endPos="362" type="product" surface="Heater Element" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1027" endPos="1038" type="product" surface="automobiles" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1049" endPos="1057" type="product" surface="vehicles" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1084" endPos="1092" type="product" surface="vehicles" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="1164" endPos="1190" type="product" surface="internal combustion engine" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="1192" endPos="1212" type="product" surface="Electrified vehicles" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1229" endPos="1236" type="product" surface="vehicle" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1293" endPos="1313" type="product" surface="electrified vehicles" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="1339" endPos="1353" type="product" surface="motor vehicles" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="1405" endPos="1438" type="product" surface="battery powered electric machines" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="1453" endPos="1467" type="product" surface="motor vehicles" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="1506" endPos="1532" type="product" surface="internal combustion engine" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="1546" endPos="1553" type="product" surface="vehicle" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="1555" endPos="1584" type="product" surface="Electrified vehicle batteries" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="1626" endPos="1640" type="product" surface="battery arrays" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="1669" endPos="1682" type="product" surface="battery cells" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="1728" endPos="1741" type="product" surface="battery cells" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="1760" endPos="1773" type="product" surface="battery cells" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="1928" endPos="1940" type="organization" surface="VerticalNews" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="2036" endPos="2048" type="product" surface="battery pack" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="2110" endPos="2122" type="product" surface="battery cell" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="2126" endPos="2152" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="2166" endPos="2178" type="product" surface="battery cell" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="2185" endPos="2199" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="2220" endPos="2246" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="2313" endPos="2327" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="2333" endPos="2354" type="product" surface="resistive heater wire" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="2421" endPos="2435" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="2484" endPos="2510" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="2577" endPos="2591" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="2652" endPos="2678" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="2745" endPos="2771" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="2798" endPos="2810" type="product" surface="battery cell" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="2824" endPos="2836" type="product" surface="battery cell" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="2903" endPos="2917" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="2980" endPos="3006" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="3073" endPos="3087" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="3139" endPos="3152" type="product" surface="heating wires" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="3249" endPos="3275" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="3298" endPos="3310" type="product" surface="battery cell" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="3377" endPos="3403" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="46" startPos="3415" endPos="3425" type="product" surface="cold plate" />
<Entity id="47" startPos="3495" endPos="3509" type="product" surface="control system" />
<Entity id="48" startPos="3579" endPos="3591" type="product" surface="battery cell" />
<Entity id="49" startPos="3609" endPos="3623" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="50" startPos="3710" endPos="3722" type="product" surface="battery pack" />
<Entity id="51" startPos="3784" endPos="3797" type="product" surface="battery array" />
<Entity id="52" startPos="3827" endPos="3840" type="product" surface="battery cells" />
<Entity id="53" startPos="3844" endPos="3848" type="product" surface="tray" />
<Entity id="54" startPos="3867" endPos="3880" type="product" surface="battery array" />
<Entity id="55" startPos="3884" endPos="3910" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="56" startPos="3923" endPos="3927" type="product" surface="tray" />
<Entity id="57" startPos="3936" endPos="3949" type="product" surface="battery array" />
<Entity id="58" startPos="3957" endPos="3971" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="59" startPos="4000" endPos="4013" type="product" surface="battery cells" />
<Entity id="60" startPos="4174" endPos="4188" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="61" startPos="4212" endPos="4238" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="62" startPos="4315" endPos="4328" type="product" surface="battery array" />
<Entity id="63" startPos="4345" endPos="4358" type="product" surface="battery array" />
<Entity id="64" startPos="4364" endPos="4390" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="65" startPos="4414" endPos="4418" type="product" surface="tray" />
<Entity id="66" startPos="4435" endPos="4448" type="product" surface="battery array" />
<Entity id="67" startPos="4464" endPos="4477" type="product" surface="battery array" />
<Entity id="68" startPos="4547" endPos="4561" type="product" surface="control system" />
<Entity id="69" startPos="4584" endPos="4590" type="product" surface="sensor" />
<Entity id="70" startPos="4645" endPos="4651" type="product" surface="sensor" />
<Entity id="71" startPos="4704" endPos="4718" type="product" surface="control module" />
<Entity id="72" startPos="4749" endPos="4763" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="73" startPos="4911" endPos="4921" type="product" surface="cold plate" />
<Entity id="74" startPos="4945" endPos="4971" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="75" startPos="4980" endPos="4984" type="product" surface="tray" />
<Entity id="76" startPos="5105" endPos="5117" type="product" surface="battery pack" />
<Entity id="77" startPos="5134" endPos="5146" type="product" surface="battery cell" />
<Entity id="78" startPos="5150" endPos="5176" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="79" startPos="5183" endPos="5197" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="80" startPos="5218" endPos="5244" type="product" surface="thermal interface material" />
<Entity id="81" startPos="5267" endPos="5279" type="product" surface="battery cell" />
<Entity id="82" startPos="5289" endPos="5303" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="83" startPos="5529" endPos="5535" type="product" surface="sensor" />
<Entity id="84" startPos="5590" endPos="5596" type="product" surface="sensor" />
<Entity id="85" startPos="5931" endPos="5943" type="product" surface="battery cell" />
<Entity id="86" startPos="6970" endPos="6980" type="product" surface="powertrain" />
<Entity id="87" startPos="6987" endPos="7006" type="product" surface="electrified vehicle" />
<Entity id="88" startPos="7029" endPos="7041" type="product" surface="battery pack" />
<Entity id="89" startPos="7141" endPos="7155" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="90" startPos="7161" endPos="7194" type="product" surface="battery thermal management system" />
<Entity id="91" startPos="7244" endPos="7258" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="92" startPos="7264" endPos="7297" type="product" surface="battery thermal management system" />
<Entity id="93" startPos="7346" endPos="7360" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="94" startPos="7366" endPos="7399" type="product" surface="battery thermal management system" />
<Entity id="95" startPos="7449" endPos="7463" type="product" surface="heater element" />
<Entity id="96" startPos="7469" endPos="7502" type="product" surface="battery thermal management system" />
<Entity id="97" startPos="7525" endPos="7537" type="product" surface="battery pack" />
<Entity id="98" startPos="7618" endPos="7630" type="product" surface="battery pack" />
<Entity id="99" startPos="7663" endPos="7675" type="product" surface="battery pack" />
<Entity id="100" startPos="7756" endPos="7789" type="product" surface="battery thermal management system" />
<Entity id="101" startPos="7956" endPos="7989" type="product" surface="Battery Thermal Management System" />
<Entity id="102" startPos="8000" endPos="8026" type="product" surface="Thermal Interface Material" />
<Entity id="103" startPos="8043" endPos="8057" type="product" surface="Heater Element" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
