<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>SpatialNews Daily Newswire! Subscribe now! SpatialNews.com Press Release Bluesky Aerial Laser Survey Answers National Trust Landscape Questions Printer Friendly An aerial laser survey is helping the UK's <NODE id="204" />National Trust<NODE id="218" /> create a 3D map of historically important details of a Grade I listed park in Gloucestershire, England. <NODE id="323" />Bluesky<NODE id="330" /> conducted the LiDAR survey to help the <NODE id="370" />National Trust<NODE id="384" /> gain a better understanding of the significance of the extensive park and gardens at Lodge Park in Sherborne. Specifically, the <NODE id="513" />Trust<NODE id="518" /> was keen to understand and highlight the significance of the work of English landscape designer, Charles Bridgeman, and the park's heritage and ecological values. Charles Bridgeman was a renowned landscape designer and redesigned the parkland at Lodge Park in 1726. It is thought the Lodge Park plan is the only surviving copy of one of Bridgeman's working drawings, making it immensely important and significant. Bridgeman's proposals for Lodge Park included planting of the Great Avenue, a grand serpentine canal, as well as several 'theatres' of trees. However, despite explicit instructions in Sir John Dutton's will of 1742, it would appear that many elements of Bridgeman's plan were not implemented. Historic map evidence has been somewhat inconclusive in determining what of Bridgeman's landscape features were in fact implemented and still remain, commented Wendy Stott, Consultancy Manager - Historic Environment, for the <NODE id="1451" />National Trust<NODE id="1465" />. Post war aerial photographs similarly record tantalising glimpses of surviving 'lumps and bumps'. However, the LiDAR survey by <NODE id="1594" />Bluesky<NODE id="1601" /> has proved to be most telling of all. In support of a specially commissioned National Trust Conservation and Management Action Plan, the LiDAR survey of Lodge Park has revealed an unexpected level of detail. Remnants predating Bridgeman's work have been confirmed, including a Neolithic Long Barrow and early parish and other field boundaries, as well as lost features within the park. The LiDAR survey has also been able to confirm where Bridgeman's plans were modified, including a reduction in size of a central 'bastion' viewpoint to the west of the Lodge. These initial stages, including the LiDAR survey, have been principally about understanding and analysing the remains of the designed landscape, continued Wendy. The next stage will involve balancing these discoveries and agreeing priorities for future management and restoration of this rare and highly significant parkland landscape. Lodge Park is one of two parks at Sherborne, Gloucestershire, and is a significant element in the <NODE id="2597" />National Trust's<NODE id="2613" /> Sherborne Estate. It is listed as Grade I on the Register of Parks and Gardens of Special Interest in England and forms part of the National Heritage List. Lodge Park is famous for its mile-long Paddock Course, laid out by John 'Crump' Dutton in the 17th Century and the landscaping of soon to be Royal Gardener Charles Bridgeman. Credit is given to Christopher Gallagher and Sarah Rutherford authors of Lodge Park Conservation Management Plan. In order to capture highly accurate LiDAR (Light Detection and Ranging) data a survey aircraft equipped with a system of lasers is used. Lasers are transmitted to the ground and the time taken for the beam to be bounced back to the aircraft-mounted receivers is recorded. Using the known position of the aircraft (derived from on-board satellite positioning equipment), the time taken for the return of the laser beam and the known value of the speed of light, the distance between the aircraft and ground is calculated. Readings can also be taken to determine the height of buildings, vegetation and other surface structures such as above ground pipelines, highways, street furniture, power lines and railway tracks. <NODE id="3777" />Bluesky<NODE id="3784" /> is a UK-based specialist in <NODE id="3813" />aerial survey<NODE id="3826" /> including aerial photography, LiDAR and thermal data using the very latest survey technology, including two UltraCam Eagles and an Orion M300 LiDAR system. An internationally recognised leader with projects extending around the globe, <NODE id="4062" />Bluesky<NODE id="4069" /> is proud to work with prestigious organisations such as <NODE id="4126" />Google<NODE id="4132" />, the <NODE id="4138" />BBC<NODE id="4141" /> and Government Agencies. <NODE id="4167" />Bluesky<NODE id="4174" /> has unrivalled expertise in the <NODE id="4207" />creation of seamless, digital aerial photography<NODE id="4255" /> and maintains national off the shelf coverage of aerial photography, DTM and DSM through an on-going three-year update programme. By purchasing a world first sensor for the simultaneous capture of LiDAR, Thermal and Aerial Photography data, <NODE id="4497" />Bluesky<NODE id="4504" /> is in the enviable position of being able to provide customers with unique and cost effective solutions. <NODE id="4610" />Bluesky<NODE id="4617" /> is also leading the way in developing innovative solutions for <NODE id="4681" />environmental applications<NODE id="4707" />, including the UK's first <NODE id="4734" />National Tree Map (NTM)<NODE id="4757" />, solar mapping and citywide 'heat loss' maps, and is currently developing noise and air quality mapping products. www.bluesky-world.com Search <NODE id="4901" />GeoCommunity<NODE id="4913" /> for Related Items Search <NODE id="4939" />Google<NODE id="4945" /> for Related Stories Today's News Copyright 1995-2014 <NODE id="4999" />MindSites Group<NODE id="5014" /> / Privacy Policy <NODE id="5032" />GeoCommunity<NODE id="5044" />, <NODE id="5047" />Wireless Developer Network<NODE id="5073" />, <NODE id="5076" />GIS Data Depot®<NODE id="5091" />, and <NODE id="5097" />Spatial News<NODE id="5109" /> including all logos and other service marks are registered trademarks and trade communities of <NODE id="5206" />MindSites Group<NODE id="5221" />
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/9ce8fcb0-8852-37c1-af94-f883c3330426" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-11T04:04:13Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:34:39.462Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://spatialnews.geocomm.com/dailynews/2016/feb/10/news3.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="204" endPos="218" type="organization" surface="National Trust" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="323" endPos="330" type="organization" surface="Bluesky" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="370" endPos="384" type="organization" surface="National Trust" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="513" endPos="518" type="organization" surface="Trust" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1451" endPos="1465" type="organization" surface="National Trust" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1594" endPos="1601" type="organization" surface="Bluesky" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="2597" endPos="2613" type="organization" surface="National Trust's" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="3777" endPos="3784" type="organization" surface="Bluesky" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="3813" endPos="3826" type="industry" surface="aerial survey" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="4062" endPos="4069" type="organization" surface="Bluesky" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="4126" endPos="4132" type="organization" surface="Google" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="4138" endPos="4141" type="organization" surface="BBC" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="4167" endPos="4174" type="organization" surface="Bluesky" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="4207" endPos="4255" type="industry" surface="creation of seamless, digital aerial photography" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="4497" endPos="4504" type="organization" surface="Bluesky" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="4610" endPos="4617" type="organization" surface="Bluesky" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="4681" endPos="4707" type="industry" surface="environmental applications" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="4734" endPos="4757" type="product" surface="National Tree Map (NTM)" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="4901" endPos="4913" type="organization" surface="GeoCommunity" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="4939" endPos="4945" type="organization" surface="Google" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="4999" endPos="5014" type="organization" surface="MindSites Group" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="5032" endPos="5044" type="organization" surface="GeoCommunity" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="5047" endPos="5073" type="organization" surface="Wireless Developer Network" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="5076" endPos="5091" type="organization" surface="GIS Data Depot®" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="5097" endPos="5109" type="organization" surface="Spatial News" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="5206" endPos="5221" type="organization" surface="MindSites Group" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="26" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
<Entity id="8" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="27" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
<Entity id="13" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="28" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
<Entity id="16" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="29" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="17" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="23" label="child" />
<Entity id="24" label="child" />
<Entity id="21" label="child" />
<Entity id="22" label="child" />
<Entity id="25" label="parent" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
<Entity id="3" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="32" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="33" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="10" label="source" />
<Entity id="19" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="34" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="18" label="source" />
<Entity id="21" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="35" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="20" label="source" />
<Entity id="25" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
