<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Show Menu Smart Demand Response Market Will Grow Rapidly Owing To Enhanced R&amp;D Practices From 2014 To 2020: <NODE id="108" />Grand View Research, Inc.<NODE id="133" /> February 10 15:15 2016 <NODE id="157" />Grand View Research, Inc.<NODE id="182" /> – <NODE id="185" />Market Research And Consulting<NODE id="215" />. GrandViewResearch.com has announced the addition of Global Smart Demand Response Market Analysis And Segment Forecasts To 2020″ Market Research report to their Database. The worldwide smart demand response market was valued at USD 5 billion in 2014. Introduction of regulatory frameworks coupled with advancement in technology in utilities verticals are factors anticipated to boost smart grid deployment, which is projected to drive the market growth. Augmenting smart grid roll-outs enhances integration of renewable energy, automation in transmission and distribution and customer energy management systems. Furthermore, favorable DR programs and policies are anticipated to boost the growth. Full research report on smart demand response market analysis: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/smart-demand-response-market Advanced ICT DSM solutions coupled with intelligent metering for energy management in <NODE id="1142" />buildings<NODE id="1151" /> is the key opportunity to utilize renewable energy resources and obtain energy savings. This is also estimated to encourage customer's participation in the ecosystem. DR programs entail direct load control of the huge appliance at home6 for residential customers involving <NODE id="1425" />pool pumps<NODE id="1435" />, <NODE id="1437" />air condition<NODE id="1450" /> and <NODE id="1455" />hot water heaters<NODE id="1472" />. Rising use of distributed generation especially from the residential consumers assists in maximizing the DR potential. For protecting electrical grid during high peak energy demand, <NODE id="1656" />intelligent buildings<NODE id="1677" /> are anticipated to participate in DR programs. Electricity bills are projected to decrease on account of reduced loans during high cost period. This will be very beneficial for consumers. Request for sample of this research report: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/smart-demand-response-market/request Rising need for utilities for managing peak requirement will impact augmenting developments for commercial and industrial demand response. Also, it will affect improvements in <NODE id="2174" />hardware<NODE id="2182" /> technology involving <NODE id="2204" />control equipment<NODE id="2221" /> and metering. Asia pacific smart demand response market contributed over 15% of the total revenue in 2014. Rising adoption of <NODE id="2348" />smart meters<NODE id="2360" /> is the key factor attributing to the high growth in the region. Moreover, North America region accounted for over 60% of the total share. Also, <NODE id="2505" />buildings<NODE id="2514" /> are projected to contribute to the maximum peak load in California. Major market participant such as <NODE id="2616" />Schneider Electric<NODE id="2634" /> offers solutions electric utilities, <NODE id="2672" />Schneider Electric<NODE id="2690" /> <NODE id="2691" />introduced<NODE id="2701" /> <NODE id="2702" />WI-Fi thermostat<NODE id="2718" /> in December 2015. <NODE id="2737" />Wider Air thermostat<NODE id="2757" /> is equipped with ZigBee to interface with several <NODE id="2808" />intelligent home devices<NODE id="2832" /> and <NODE id="2837" />smart meters<NODE id="2849" />. The DR program assists in improving optimization, distribution, monitoring through development, optimization in addition to dispatching <NODE id="2987" />virtual power plants<NODE id="3007" />. <NODE id="3009" />ABB<NODE id="3012" /> announced the installation of 363 kilovolts in December 2015; it basically detaches the <NODE id="3101" />circuit breaker<NODE id="3116" /> in combination with <NODE id="3137" />fiber optic current sensor<NODE id="3163" />. Further, it also amalgamates substation functions involving disconnecting and circuit breaking into one single component. Hereafter, decreasing the space required for <NODE id="3332" />substation bay<NODE id="3346" />. View more reports of this category by <NODE id="3386" />Grand View Research<NODE id="3405" /> at: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry/electronic-devices About <NODE id="3477" />Grand View Research<NODE id="3496" /> <NODE id="3497" />Grand View Research, Inc.<NODE id="3522" /> is a U.S. based market research and consulting company, registered in the State of California and headquartered in San Francisco. The company provides syndicated <NODE id="3685" />research reports<NODE id="3701" />, customized <NODE id="3714" />research reports<NODE id="3730" />, and consulting services. To help clients make informed business decisions, we offer market intelligence studies ensuring relevant and fact-based research across a range of industries, from technology to <NODE id="3935" />chemicals<NODE id="3944" />, <NODE id="3946" />materials<NODE id="3955" /> and healthcare.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/b9738db2-eb4c-36f6-8713-c1a64951d3d3" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-11T00:37:20Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:45:39.972Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.nashvillenewsupdates.com/story/74099/smart-demand-response-market-will-grow-rapidly-owing-to-enhanced-rd-practices-from-2014-to-2020-grand-view-research-inc.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="108" endPos="133" type="organization" surface="Grand View Research, Inc." />
<Entity id="1" startPos="157" endPos="182" type="organization" surface="Grand View Research, Inc." />
<Entity id="2" startPos="185" endPos="215" type="product" surface="Market Research And Consulting" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1142" endPos="1151" type="product" surface="buildings" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1425" endPos="1435" type="product" surface="pool pumps" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1437" endPos="1450" type="product" surface="air condition" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1455" endPos="1472" type="product" surface="hot water heaters" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1656" endPos="1677" type="product" surface="intelligent buildings" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="2174" endPos="2182" type="product" surface="hardware" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2204" endPos="2221" type="product" surface="control equipment" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2348" endPos="2360" type="product" surface="smart meters" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="2505" endPos="2514" type="product" surface="buildings" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="2616" endPos="2634" type="organization" surface="Schneider Electric" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="2672" endPos="2690" type="organization" surface="Schneider Electric" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="2691" endPos="2701" type="trigger" surface="introduced" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="2702" endPos="2718" type="product" surface="WI-Fi thermostat" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="2737" endPos="2757" type="product" surface="Wider Air thermostat" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="2808" endPos="2832" type="product" surface="intelligent home devices" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="2837" endPos="2849" type="product" surface="smart meters" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2987" endPos="3007" type="product" surface="virtual power plants" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="3009" endPos="3012" type="organization" surface="ABB" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="3101" endPos="3116" type="product" surface="circuit breaker" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="3137" endPos="3163" type="product" surface="fiber optic current sensor" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="3332" endPos="3346" type="product" surface="substation bay" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="3386" endPos="3405" type="organization" surface="Grand View Research" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="3477" endPos="3496" type="organization" surface="Grand View Research" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="3497" endPos="3522" type="organization" surface="Grand View Research, Inc." />
<Entity id="27" startPos="3685" endPos="3701" type="product" surface="research reports" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="3714" endPos="3730" type="product" surface="research reports" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="3935" endPos="3944" type="product" surface="chemicals" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="3946" endPos="3955" type="product" surface="materials" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="31" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="2" label="product" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="32" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="15" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="13" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
