<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>1998 <NODE id="5" />BMW<NODE id="8" /> <NODE id="9" />M3<NODE id="11" /> Convertible Estoril Blue over Dove grey 5-spd manual 83,500 miles Clean title, no lien, no accidents. IMG_1665.jpg 0123161553.jpg IMG_1670.jpg IMG_1673.jpg 0123161615.jpg $12,600 no hurry Many more high-res pics available here: https://flic.kr/s/aHsktfAJqX This car has been a ton of fun, it starts and idles smoothly no matter the temperature, gets 25mpg and handles unbelievably well. It's been e nthusiast owned and maintained. This is my second <NODE id="461" />E36 M3<NODE id="467" /> and 4th <NODE id="476" />BMW<NODE id="479" /> (also had an <NODE id="493" />E30 318i<NODE id="501" /> and an <NODE id="509" />E39 M5<NODE id="515" />). I've had this car for almost 2 years and its been an absolute blast. I use it primarily as a weekend car, but have taken it to work plenty of times (80 mile round trip, mostly highway). I'm over 40 with a bunch of kids that love to ride in this car, never raced or tracked, but driven spiritedly. Ownership History: Originally purchased 11/1998 from Rick Hill BMW in TN. Owner #1 lived in FL. Owner #1 moved to Michigan and titled the car there in early 2001, with apprx 37k miles. Sold in April 2006 at 47,120 miles to Owner #2, an adult enthusiast. I was told car was always garaged by previous owners and stored during winter months while in MI/IL Purchased by another enthusiast, Owner #3, November 2008 at 49,144 miles and brought to NH. He only drove it on sunny days from May-October and properly stored it during the winter, always garaged at his house when not in use. I bought the car after a 4-month search. My son and I flew to New Hampshire and drove it 10 hours home to Hunt Valley, MD. The car had 63,500 miles when I picked it up in May of 2014. Production Details 1998 <NODE id="1604" />BMW<NODE id="1607" /> <NODE id="1608" />M3<NODE id="1610" /> Convertible VIN# WBSBK9338WEC42622 Built date: 5/98 in Regensburg, Germany 1 of 2252 US Spec E36 M3 convertibles w/manual transmission imported into the USA (only available 98-99) 1 of 317 US Spec E36 M3 convertibles w/manual trans with Estoril Blue/Dove Gray color combo imported into the USA Sticker Price - $49,870.00 Option List Cruise Control On-Board Computer Harman-Kardon Sound System Forged 17” 5-Spoke Wheels Operational Condition Runs perfectly. Clutch is direct with no slippage. Gear changes are smooth. Brakes are good. No check engine lights. No OBC errors. No Dead Pixels. No electrical issues. Exterior/Paint Original paint. All original body panels. No accidents. The paint is in great condition, shines and sparkles like Estoril should. There are normal rash marks/stone chips on the front, hood, etc. There is a scratch (4” long) on the front of the hood. It’s a surface scratch that I imagine can be removed by a good detailer. Small 1-inch long surface scratch near the left rear fender. Top of trunk has slight swirls and could use a buff. No dents. No rust. Interior Car has manual and non-heated seats. Passenger and rear seats are in great shape. Driver’s seat has some wear, but no rips/tears/etc – maybe a 8/10. Headliner is in excellent shape except for a small hole in the back. Steering wheel, arm rest, door cards, trim panels, etc are all in great condition. Maintenance The previous owner has a great PDF documenting all of the maintenance while under his care, available if you're interested. While I've owned it: changed the oil 4 times with OEM filter and Royal Purple full synthetic 5w30 Drain and fill diff fluid with Royal Purple 75w140 less than 2k miles ago New Speed Sensor Bled and replaced brake fluid with ATE Super Blue Replaced Battery less than a year ago Replaced Differential with OEM 3.15 LSD ​ Modifications The mods work really nicely together to give the car a very *analog* feel. Engine pulls really well at every rpm, very flat handling, exhaust sounds nice and deep. Conforti “SharK’ Tune Conforti Carbon Cold Air Induction UUC/Corsa RSC36 Cat-back exhaust http://www.uucmotorwerks.com/RSC36/ Ground Control Coilovers UUC EVO 3 Short Shift Kit with DSSR ZHP Shift knob Polyurethane Differential Bushings Wheels Car will come with two sets of wheels. First set is the original optional LTW forged wheels, “Style 24”. Relatively rare, these are fantastic looking wheels and in great shape. Some very minor curb rash. They are 17” and 7.5” up front and 8.5” out back. They have <NODE id="4144" />Sumitomo<NODE id="4152" /> <NODE id="4153" />HRTZ-III<NODE id="4161" /> tires on them. The fronts, as mentioned, have been grooved and should be replaced. The rears are great, I replaced them about 12k miles ago. Full 7.5” LTW spare w/tire in trunk. The second set are square 17-inch Speed Edition wheels that I bought so I could change my wheels for winter use. They have <NODE id="4463" />Dunlop<NODE id="4469" /> <NODE id="4470" />Sport M3<NODE id="4478" /> winters that did amazingly well the one day I drove them this year in the white stuff. I wouldn't expect too much more life out of them, tires are starting to cup on the inner edges. Suspension: Car will come with a Ground Control Coilover kit installed. It is comparable to their “Street/Hybrid Kit”. Koni single adjustable short struts with height adjustment. 500lb Eibach springs and stock M3 spring perch. Koni single adjustable shortened shock in rear with 550lb Eibach springs riding on height adjustable collars. Upgraded rear shock mount. The ride is firm but planted. It does not bounce. Ground Control is one of the better suspension options for this car and in it drives wonderfully. To eliminate any possibility of fender rubbing by the rear tires, the PO had a professional auto body shop that specialized in fender rolling roll the inside of the rear fenders very slightly. Worked out perfectly, you would never know. I'm including a full stock suspension as well: Front Struts, rear shocks (less than 12k miles on them), original F+R springs, HD rear shock mount. Extras Original Leather zippered attaché, including window sticker, radio codes, service manual, road-side assistance paperwork, owner’s manual, warranty info, etc. Receipt Binder Shark Injector and paperwork. Toolkit in trunk is intact. Light in glove compartment works. E36 Car Cover Stock headlights Smoked tails with stealth bulbs in turn signals (no fried egg look). I believe I got them from DDM. Smoked front corner lenses with stealth bulbs (again, no fried egg look). Also from DDM Smoked side indicator lenses Rear LED license plate lights Full interior LED conversion bulbs DJ Auto headlights retro-fitted with FX-R bi-xenon projectors, D2S 5k HID kit and <NODE id="6225" />Orion<NODE id="6230" /> <NODE id="6231" />V2 LED Angel Eyes<NODE id="6248" />. Chrome kidney grills Windscreen (these go for about $400 used) JVC aftermarket Head Unit with Bluetooth, MUCH better than stock, although stock HU is included Projects / Imperfections Shifter has typical E36 “5th-gear lean” during initial start up. Once it is warmed up and running – it goes away. Single chip in windshield - its been there for a year and isn't expanding. Leather is in decent shape, but darker lines are starting to form, see pictures. The top has a few point of wear and two of the inner plastic pieces are detaching, seals perfectly however. The driver's side nylon rope and plastic was broken, it could use some TLC. power steering hose has a very slow leak Occasional low beam failure message on OBC but headlights both stay on Inner sidewalls of the tires have been grooved by the coilovers prior to installing 10mm spacers - I've driven the car for 10k+ miles with no issues. Little $2 light behind the odometer burned out but you can still read the mileage easily. I have the light bulb and will include it with sale. Heater gets warm but does not blow hard as of a month ago - research has led me to conclude it needs a new Cabin microfilter, which comes with the car If I were keeping the car, I would do the following projects in the next year (I always ask this when buying a car so figured you might find it useful): replace water pump, new front tires, new front rotors, new foam for CAI. I'd also raise the suspension a bit and get an alignment. Text is best way to get in touch with me: 443-eight 5 eight, niner-1 six zero, my name is Chris
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/7bb29494-a32f-311b-9fb1-27594f7fc4ad" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-06T20:14:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:21:59.632Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.bimmerforums.com/forum/showthread.php?2282998-1998-Estoril-M3-Convertible-5-spd-manual-83k-miles-Excellent-condition&amp;p=29081291#post29081291" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="5" endPos="8" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="5" endPos="11" type="product" surface="BMW M3" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="9" endPos="11" type="head" surface="M3" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="461" endPos="467" type="product" surface="E36 M3" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="476" endPos="479" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="493" endPos="501" type="product" surface="E30 318i" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="509" endPos="515" type="product" surface="E39 M5" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1604" endPos="1607" type="organization" surface="BMW" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1604" endPos="1610" type="product" surface="BMW M3" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="1608" endPos="1610" type="head" surface="M3" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="4144" endPos="4152" type="organization" surface="Sumitomo" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="4144" endPos="4161" type="product" surface="Sumitomo HRTZ-III" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="4153" endPos="4161" type="head" surface="HRTZ-III" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="4463" endPos="4469" type="organization" surface="Dunlop" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="4463" endPos="4478" type="product" surface="Dunlop Sport M3" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="4470" endPos="4478" type="head" surface="Sport M3" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="6225" endPos="6230" type="organization" surface="Orion" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="6225" endPos="6248" type="product" surface="Orion V2 LED Angel Eyes" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="6231" endPos="6248" type="head" surface="V2 LED Angel Eyes" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="19" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="20" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="5" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="21" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="8" label="product" />
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="22" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="11" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="23" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="14" label="product" />
<Entity id="13" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="24" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="17" label="product" />
<Entity id="16" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="25" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="26" NAME="entity_head">
<Entity id="1" label="full_extent" />
<Entity id="2" label="head" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="27" NAME="entity_head">
<Entity id="8" label="full_extent" />
<Entity id="9" label="head" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="28" NAME="entity_head">
<Entity id="11" label="full_extent" />
<Entity id="12" label="head" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="29" NAME="entity_head">
<Entity id="14" label="full_extent" />
<Entity id="15" label="head" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="entity_head">
<Entity id="17" label="full_extent" />
<Entity id="18" label="head" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
