<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>IoT Chip Market Worth 10.78 Billion USD by 2022 February 09, 2016 -- PUNE, India , February 9, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- The report IoT Chip Market by Application Vertical (Wearable Device, Healthcare, Consumer Electronics, Building Automation, Industrial, Automotive &amp; Transportation) &amp; Geography ( North America , Europe , APAC, Row) - Global Forecast to 2022, published by <NODE id="371" />MarketsandMarkets<NODE id="388" />, the market is expected to grow from USD 4.58 Billion in 2015 to USD 10.78 Billion by 2022, at a CAGR of 11.5% between 2016 and 2022. Browse 41 market data Tables and 64 Figures spread through 175 Pages and in-depth TOC on IoT Chip Market. http://www.marketsandmarkets.com/Market-Reports/iot-chip-market-236473142.html Early buyers will receive 10% customization on this report. With the rapid technological advancements and the increasing dependence on technology in day-to-day lives, the Internet of Things concept has a promising future. Given the rate of proliferation of the network of wireless sensors, the increasing adoption of emerging technologies, and the mainstreaming of many smart consumer applications, Internet of Things has gained popularity across domains. The growing IoT market is the major driver for IoT chip manufacturers. The integration of connectivity capabilities in an increasing number of devices and applications acts as a major driver for the market Within the embedded device space, functions related to connectivity and network processing are increasingly being combined with embedded processors in applications beyond cell phones. For example, <NODE id="1567" />Qualcomm's<NODE id="1577" /> <NODE id="1578" />Snapdragon 602A<NODE id="1593" /> combines an application processor, GPU, DSP, GPS, 4G LTE, Wi-Fi, and Bluetooth, and is targeted for the automotive infotainment segment. Furthermore, Combo wireless connectivity chipsets with integrated NFC, Wi-Fi, and Bluetooth are expected to be used in smartphones and consumer electronic devices that would support multiple communication standards and protocols. Wearable device application to play a key role in the IoT chip market The wearable device application is expected to hold the largest market share and dominate the IoT chip market between 2016 and 2022 owing to the increasing adoption of wearable devices across the globe. The growing popularity of Internet of Things and the increasing adoption of smart watches and activity trackers in the consumer markets present huge opportunities for the IoT chip manufacturers. The demand for Connectivity ICs and MCUs is expected to gain momentum owing to the growing wearable device market. Automotive &amp; Transportation held the largest market share in 2015 Internet of Things (IoT) has given rise to new segments in the automotive and transportation sector such as connected cars and intelligent transportation systems (ITS). Connected cars, along with the implementations of ITS, are expected to boost the semiconductor industry's total addressable market with the growth in sensor content and integration of MEMS, connectivity devices, and MCUs. North America expected to hold the largest market share; APAC to grow at the highest rate North America is expected to hold the largest market share and dominate the IoT chip market between 2016 and 2022. The increasing R&amp;D at both academic and industry levels is broadening the application areas of Internet of Things in different industries such as consumer products, energy &amp; power, retail, automotive &amp; transportation, and healthcare, especially in North America . This is the main factor driving the growth of the IoT chip market in the region. In the APAC region, countries such as China , India , and Japan are aggressively taking initiatives such as heavy investments in R&amp;D to encourage the adoption of Internet of Things in the region, which is expected to boost the demand for IoT chip in the near future. Inquiry before Buying @ http://www.marketsandmarkets.com/Enquiry_Before_Buying.asp?id=236473142 The major players in the <NODE id="3939" />IoT chip<NODE id="3947" /> market include <NODE id="3963" />Intel Corporation<NODE id="3980" /> (U.S.), <NODE id="3989" />Qualcomm Inc.<NODE id="4002" /> (U.S.), <NODE id="4011" />Freescale Semiconductor<NODE id="4034" /> (U.S.), <NODE id="4043" />NXP Semiconductors<NODE id="4061" /> (U.S.), <NODE id="4070" />ARM Holding PLC<NODE id="4085" /> (U.K.), <NODE id="4094" />Atmel Corporation<NODE id="4111" /> (U.S.), <NODE id="4120" />Texas Instruments Incorporated<NODE id="4150" /> (U.S.), and others. The scope of the report covers detailed information regarding the major factors influencing the growth of the IoT chip market such as drivers, restraints, challenges, and opportunities. A detailed analysis of the key industry players has been done to provide insights into their business overview, products and services, key strategies, new product launches, mergers &amp; acquisitions, partnerships, agreements, collaborations, and recent developments associated with the IoT chip market. Browse Related Reports Industrial IoT Market by Industry Vertical (Manufacturing, Energy &amp; Power, Oil &amp; Gas, Metals &amp; Mining, Healthcare, &amp; Agriculture), Technology (Sensors, Networking Technology, DCS, &amp; Others), Software, &amp; Geography - Global Forecast to 2020 http://www.marketsandmarkets.com/Market-Reports/industrial-internet-of-things-market-129733727.html About <NODE id="5025" />MarketsandMarkets<NODE id="5042" /> <NODE id="5043" />MarketsandMarkets<NODE id="5060" /> is world's No. 2 firm in terms of annually published premium <NODE id="5122" />market research reports<NODE id="5145" />. Serving 1700 global fortune enterprises with more than 1200 premium studies in a year, <NODE id="5234" />M&amp;M<NODE id="5237" /> is catering to multitude of clients across 8 different industrial verticals. <NODE id="5315" />We<NODE id="5317" /> specialize in consulting assignments and business research across high growth markets, cutting edge technologies and newer applications. <NODE id="5455" />Our<NODE id="5458" /> 850 fulltime analyst and SMEs at <NODE id="5492" />MarketsandMarkets<NODE id="5509" /> are tracking global high growth markets following the Growth Engagement Model - GEM. The GEM aims at proactive collaboration with the clients to identify new opportunities, identify most important customers, write Attack, avoid and defend strategies, identify sources of incremental revenues for both the company and its competitors. <NODE id="5844" />M&amp;M's<NODE id="5849" /> flagship competitive intelligence and market research platform, <NODE id="5914" />RT<NODE id="5916" /> connects over 200,000 markets and entire value chains for deeper understanding of the unmet insights along with market sizing and forecasts of niche markets. The new included chapters on Methodology and Benchmarking presented with high quality analytical info graphics in our reports gives complete visibility of how the numbers have been arrived and defend the accuracy of the numbers. <NODE id="6304" />We<NODE id="6306" /> at <NODE id="6310" />MarketsandMarkets<NODE id="6327" /> are inspired to help <NODE id="6349" />our<NODE id="6352" /> clients grow by providing apt business insight with <NODE id="6405" />our<NODE id="6408" /> huge market intelligence repository. Contact: Mr. Rohan <NODE id="6465" />Markets and Markets<NODE id="6484" /> UNIT no 802, Tower no. 7, SEZ Magarpatta city, Hadapsar Pune , Maharashtra 411013, India Tel: +1-888-600-6441 Email: sales@marketsandmarkets.com Visit <NODE id="6636" />MarketsandMarkets<NODE id="6653" /> Blog @ <NODE id="6661" />http://www.marketsandmarketsblog.com/market-reports/electronics-and-semiconductors<NODE id="6743" /> Connect with us on LinkedIn @ http://www.linkedin.com/company/marketsandmarkets SOURCE <NODE id="6831" />MarketsandMarkets<NODE id="6848" />
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/dc33536a-f9c4-3647-8129-edc95af5d201" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-10T07:55:14Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:58:51.454Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.consumerelectronicsnet.com/article/IoT-Chip-Market-Worth-1078-Billion-USD-by-2022-4283747" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="371" endPos="388" type="organization" surface="MarketsandMarkets" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1567" endPos="1577" type="organization" surface="Qualcomm's" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1578" endPos="1593" type="product" surface="Snapdragon 602A" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="3939" endPos="3947" type="industry" surface="IoT chip" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="3963" endPos="3980" type="organization" surface="Intel Corporation" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="3989" endPos="4002" type="organization" surface="Qualcomm Inc." />
<Entity id="6" startPos="4011" endPos="4034" type="organization" surface="Freescale Semiconductor" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="4043" endPos="4061" type="organization" surface="NXP Semiconductors" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="4070" endPos="4085" type="organization" surface="ARM Holding PLC" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="4094" endPos="4111" type="organization" surface="Atmel Corporation" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="4120" endPos="4150" type="organization" surface="Texas Instruments Incorporated" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="5025" endPos="5042" type="organization" surface="MarketsandMarkets" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="5043" endPos="5060" type="organization" surface="MarketsandMarkets" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="5122" endPos="5145" type="industry" surface="market research reports" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="5234" endPos="5237" type="organization" surface="M&amp;M" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="5315" endPos="5317" type="organization" surface="We" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="5455" endPos="5458" type="organization" surface="Our" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="5492" endPos="5509" type="organization" surface="MarketsandMarkets" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="5844" endPos="5849" type="organization" surface="M&amp;M's" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="5914" endPos="5916" type="product" surface="RT" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="6304" endPos="6306" type="organization" surface="We" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="6310" endPos="6327" type="organization" surface="MarketsandMarkets" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="6349" endPos="6352" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="6405" endPos="6408" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="6465" endPos="6484" type="organization" surface="Markets and Markets" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="6636" endPos="6653" type="organization" surface="MarketsandMarkets" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="6661" endPos="6743" type="url" surface="http://www.marketsandmarketsblog.com/market-reports/electronics-and-semiconductors" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="6831" endPos="6848" type="organization" surface="MarketsandMarkets" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="28" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
<Entity id="3" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="29" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="9" label="company" />
<Entity id="3" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
<Entity id="3" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
<Entity id="3" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="32" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
<Entity id="3" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="33" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
<Entity id="3" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="34" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
<Entity id="3" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="35" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
<Entity id="13" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="36" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="2" label="product" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="37" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="19" label="product" />
<Entity id="18" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="38" NAME="CompanyWebsite">
<Entity id="26" label="website" />
<Entity id="25" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="39" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="24" label="target" />
<Entity id="14" label="target" />
<Entity id="23" label="target" />
<Entity id="20" label="target" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="18" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="21" label="target" />
<Entity id="22" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="25" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="40" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
