<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>System Integrator Reduces Commissioning with PC Control Platform A major automotive OEM expands the robotic footprint for its body-in-white assembly facility and reduces commissioning time for the control system by 50 percent. By Grant Gerke , <NODE id="244" />Automation World<NODE id="260" /> Contributing Writer, on January 22, 2016 Case Application System Integrator Reduces Commissioning with PC Control Platform A major automotive OEM expands the robotic footprint for its body-in-white assembly facility and reduces commissioning time for the control system by 50 percent. By Grant Gerke , <NODE id="563" />Automation World<NODE id="579" /> Contributing Writer, on January 22, 2016 With ever-increasing electronics and networking, multiple types of drivetrains, material lightweighting and more to meet regulatory and market demands, an automotive renaissance is underway. Many carmakers are relying on automation upgrades to meet new challenges. Portugal-based <NODE id="901" />Sodecia<NODE id="908" /> designs automated assembly systems and increasingly uses PC-based control platforms to tackle the complexity of manufacturing in the <NODE id="1042" />automotive industry<NODE id="1061" />. With 32 manufacturing facilities around the world, the <NODE id="1118" />company<NODE id="1125" /> makes <NODE id="1132" />manufacturing systems for chassis, powertrain and body-in-white (BIW) applications<NODE id="1214" />. <NODE id="1216" />Sodecia<NODE id="1223" /> relies on <NODE id="1234" />its<NODE id="1237" /> <NODE id="1238" />Global Tech &amp; Automation Centre (GTAC)<NODE id="1276" /> in London, Ontario, to specify automation hardware, software and engineering support for the <NODE id="1370" />company’s<NODE id="1379" /> manufacturing divisions. '<NODE id="1406" />Our<NODE id="1409" /> current bread-and-butter product is <NODE id="1446" />our<NODE id="1449" /> turnkey robotic weld cell solution,' says Brent Lekx-Toniolo, control system concept developer at <NODE id="1548" />Sodecia GTAC<NODE id="1560" />. 'Each project is slightly different—based on unique application requirements—but the core machine technology remains the same.' PC-based control in the driver’s seat Since 2008, the <NODE id="1744" />Sodecia GTAC<NODE id="1756" /> integration group has relied on <NODE id="1789" />PC-based control technology<NODE id="1816" /> from <NODE id="1822" />Beckhoff Automation<NODE id="1841" /> for <NODE id="1846" />its<NODE id="1849" /> automotive projects. 'To date, <NODE id="1881" />Sodecia GTAC<NODE id="1893" /> has built 49 manufacturing lines based on <NODE id="1936" />Beckhoff<NODE id="1944" /> PC-based control, ranging anywhere from machines with a single robot to lines with over 20 articulated robots,' says Jon Bysma, controls specialist at <NODE id="2096" />Sodecia GTAC<NODE id="2108" />. A recent automotive project—larger than any other undertaken by <NODE id="2174" />Sodecia GTAC<NODE id="2186" />—included 21 <NODE id="2199" />Kuka<NODE id="2203" /> <NODE id="2204" />robots<NODE id="2210" /> of various sizes, with payload capabilities of 6-210 kg (including the <NODE id="2282" />KR 210<NODE id="2288" />, <NODE id="2290" />KR 30<NODE id="2295" /> and <NODE id="2300" />KR 6 series<NODE id="2311" />). The BIW assembly line begins with an assortment of small stampings and subassemblies that are spot welded, arc welded (studs), stamped or sealed robotically. The finished subassemblies are automatically unloaded and transferred to subsequent stages. Multiple assemblies come together to form the bulk of the entire finished assembly. At this point, the process splits into two identical product pipelines—creating redundancy and improving throughput. This section has left- and right-hand assemblies running down the same line, so the entire concept essentially has four pipelines. The PC-based control system executes all sequencing for this assembly line, including fixture clamp/unclamp sequences, part detecting, error proofing, calling specific robots into fixtures, and necessary robot tasks. Sensors on set-down fixtures conduct comprehensive analysis and send data to the controller, ensuring that all fasteners are placed correctly on the assemblies. The controller also handles robot-to-robot interference detection, general production count and overall equipment effectiveness (OEE) tracking, while managing overall fault detection and annunciation by acting as the human-machine interface (HMI) for the machine. Quick commissioning This capital project began with <NODE id="3590" />Sodecia<NODE id="3597" /> completing a floor layout for the cell and robot training, while PLC programming started at about the same time. <NODE id="3711" />Kuka<NODE id="3715" /> controllers administer the motion control for each of the 21 robots in the assembly area, but the entire welding cell is coordinated by TwinCAT PLC software running on a 15-in. panel PC. <NODE id="3903" />Sodecia<NODE id="3910" /> used a range of software libraries to speed programming of the entire robot work cell that includes 228 devices. 'The software’s development environment and <NODE id="4068" />Sodecia’s<NODE id="4077" /> modular code framework based on structured text reduces engineering time by a wide margin,' says Rob Remillard, lead controls engineer for <NODE id="4217" />Sodecia GTAC<NODE id="4229" />. <NODE id="4231" />Sodecia<NODE id="4238" /> can develop sections of code in any of the IEC 61131-3 languages, prove them out, and then deploy instances of the code for evaluation. EtherCAT networking handles all robotic communications, I/O and programmable safety functions via the safety I/O terminals. 'With <NODE id="4505" />our<NODE id="4508" /> modular machine design model, <NODE id="4539" />our<NODE id="4542" /> safety configuration doesn’t change much,' Toniolo says. '<NODE id="4601" />We<NODE id="4603" /> simply remove sections <NODE id="4627" />we<NODE id="4629" /> don’t need from the pre-built framework, but the underlying functionality remains the same.' Each major automated component in the robotic assembly line is connected to a TwinSAFE logic terminal and a series of digital inputs and outputs to handle the processing of the safety I/O, as well as communication with other safety equipment. Safety functions include e-stops, machine monitoring, AND and OR functions, and decouplers. Automakers are leaning on integrators to make capital improvements seamless. '<NODE id="5136" />Sodecia<NODE id="5143" /> has cut control system commissioning time by at least 50 percent using PC-based control,' says Mark Mierkalns, plant manager for <NODE id="5273" />Sodecia GTAC<NODE id="5285" />. Production is also hitting its stride. The carmaker for this particular project reports that the BIW assembly line achieves an average cycle time of just under 50 seconds, with 72 complex parts per hour and up to 355,000 parts per year. IT Delivers on Automation’s Promise Sign up to receive timely updates from the editors at <NODE id="5614" />Automation World<NODE id="5630" /> and download this FREE Special Report on the transformative power of data in manufacturing. By integrating information and automation technologies, manufacturers are finally achieving major gains in productivity from their automated systems.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/eea2b5ba-b494-3ade-8334-9f3b7a17ef9a" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-23T02:07:13Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:05:53.068Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.automationworld.com/industrial-pcs/system-integrator-reduces-commissioning-pc-control-platform" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="244" endPos="260" type="organization" surface="Automation World" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="563" endPos="579" type="organization" surface="Automation World" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="901" endPos="908" type="organization" surface="Sodecia" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1042" endPos="1061" type="industry" surface="automotive industry" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1118" endPos="1125" type="organization" surface="company" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1132" endPos="1214" type="industry" surface="manufacturing systems for chassis, powertrain and body-in-white (BIW) applications" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1216" endPos="1223" type="organization" surface="Sodecia" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1234" endPos="1237" type="organization" surface="its" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1238" endPos="1276" type="organization" surface="Global Tech &amp; Automation Centre (GTAC)" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="1370" endPos="1379" type="organization" surface="company’s" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="1406" endPos="1409" type="organization" surface="Our" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1446" endPos="1449" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1548" endPos="1560" type="organization" surface="Sodecia GTAC" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="1744" endPos="1756" type="organization" surface="Sodecia GTAC" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="1789" endPos="1816" type="industry" surface="PC-based control technology" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="1822" endPos="1841" type="organization" surface="Beckhoff Automation" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="1846" endPos="1849" type="organization" surface="its" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="1881" endPos="1893" type="organization" surface="Sodecia GTAC" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="1936" endPos="1944" type="organization" surface="Beckhoff" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2096" endPos="2108" type="organization" surface="Sodecia GTAC" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="2174" endPos="2186" type="organization" surface="Sodecia GTAC" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="2199" endPos="2203" type="organization" surface="Kuka" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="2204" endPos="2210" type="industry" surface="robots" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="2282" endPos="2288" type="product" surface="KR 210" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="2290" endPos="2295" type="product" surface="KR 30" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="2300" endPos="2311" type="product" surface="KR 6 series" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="3590" endPos="3597" type="organization" surface="Sodecia" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="3711" endPos="3715" type="organization" surface="Kuka" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="3903" endPos="3910" type="organization" surface="Sodecia" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="4068" endPos="4077" type="organization" surface="Sodecia’s" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="4217" endPos="4229" type="organization" surface="Sodecia GTAC" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="4231" endPos="4238" type="organization" surface="Sodecia" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="4505" endPos="4508" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="4539" endPos="4542" type="organization" surface="our" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="4601" endPos="4603" type="organization" surface="We" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="4627" endPos="4629" type="organization" surface="we" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="5136" endPos="5143" type="organization" surface="Sodecia" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="5273" endPos="5285" type="organization" surface="Sodecia GTAC" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="5614" endPos="5630" type="organization" surface="Automation World" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="39" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
<Entity id="3" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="40" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="41" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
<Entity id="14" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="42" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="21" label="company" />
<Entity id="22" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="43" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="24" label="product" />
<Entity id="23" label="product" />
<Entity id="25" label="product" />
<Entity id="21" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="44" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="8" label="child" />
<Entity id="7" label="parent" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="45" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
<Entity id="38" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="46" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="2" label="source" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="31" label="target" />
<Entity id="29" label="target" />
<Entity id="36" label="target" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="28" label="target" />
<Entity id="26" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="47" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="8" label="source" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="32" label="target" />
<Entity id="30" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="20" label="target" />
<Entity id="12" label="target" />
<Entity id="13" label="target" />
<Entity id="35" label="target" />
<Entity id="37" label="target" />
<Entity id="19" label="target" />
<Entity id="34" label="target" />
<Entity id="33" label="target" />
<Entity id="16" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="48" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="15" label="source" />
<Entity id="18" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
