<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (15) - <NODE id="12" />Toyota<NODE id="18" /> <NODE id="19" />Verso 1.6 D-4D<NODE id="33" /> Icon Nav/Pan Rf 5dr [PP] £14,299 Loading Images... Date Registered: Mar 2015 Mileage: 12,662 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £14,299 Colour: Silver Body Style: People Carrier Vehicle Trim / Variant: Icon EC Combined (mpg) 62 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 72.4 EC Urban (mpg) 51.4  &gt; 62 MPG 14 Insurance Group 110 Performance (BHP) 7 Seats 119 CO2 (g/km) £30 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Icon Insurance Group 14, SAVE 9731 off new list price, Sat. Nav.,Cruise Control,Climate Control,Reversing Sensors Rear,16 inch Wheels,Electric Folding Mirrors,Privacy Glass,Bluetooth,DAB Radio,Alloy Wheels,Cloth Trim,Reverse Parking Camera,Protection pack - Verso,Metallic paint, 30 Annual Tax, 62 MPG,All vehicles come with the balance of the manufacturer's warranty, are inspected by trained technicians and are history checked. Test drives and part-exchange are available, and you can choose, buy and drive away the same day. For more details on this or one of over 4000 other cars at <NODE id="1035" />Motorpoint<NODE id="1045" />, the UKs leading <NODE id="1063" />Car Supermarket<NODE id="1078" />, search <NODE id="1087" />Motorpoint.co.uk<NODE id="1103" />. (If you wish to enquire about this vehicle please quote 668944) Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0141 413 0747 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Well built, practical and reliable - the <NODE id="1441" />Toyota<NODE id="1447" /> <NODE id="1448" />Verso<NODE id="1453" /> is an ideal people carrier for families. read more Plenty of interior space, comfortable and easy to drive, top build quality, seven seats Not a huge leap forward over the Corolla Verso, tight rear seats are tricky to get to, dull cabin Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Alloy wheels Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Cruise control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Ipod Connection Isofix child seat anchor points Navigation system PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0141 413 0747 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power point front/rear 2 individual folding 3rd row seats 2 speed intermittent front wiper with mist function 3 individual folding 2nd row seats 3 rear height adjustable headrests 3 spoke leather covered steering wheel ABS+Electronic Brake force Distribution Accessory socket front and rear Adjustable steering column Air recirculation control Ashtray and cigar lighter Bluetooth phone integration system Bottle holders Brake assist Central Storage Box Chrome air vent surrounds Clean air filter Cloth upholstery Coat hooks Cooled glovebox Cruise control Cupholders in front and rear Digital clock Door ajar warning Driver/passenger front seatback pockets Driver's footrest Dual zone automatic air conditioning Electric power steering Front and rear door pockets Front armrest Front/rear assist grips Front/rear electric windows with one-touch/anti-trap and key-off function Green tinted glass Heated glass rear screen Heated/electric door mirrors with integrated indicators Height adjustable driver's seat Height adjustable front headrests Height/reach adjust steering wheel Hidden under floor storage in boot Hill assist control Illuminated glovebox with lock Isofix child seat attachment Leather wrapped gear shift knob Lights on warning Luggage load hooks Outside temperature display Overhead console Privacy glass Rear armrest Rear headrests Rear removable tonneau cover Rear wiper Reclining 2nd row seats Reclining 3rd row seats Reclining/sliding front seat Remote boot release Remote fuel cap release Retractable door mirrors Sliding 2nd Row rear seats Storage under front passenger seat Titanium effect fascia Titanium effect interior door handles Titanium effect steering wheel and centre consol Touch 2 touchscreen with Go full map navigation, iPod connectivity and reversing camera Trip computer with fuel consumption/average speed Under floor storage in 2nd row Upper glovebox Vehicle stability control + traction control + brake assist Entertainment 6 speakers Audio integrated fit with LCD Auxiliary input socket DAB Digital radio Radio/single CD with MP3 and WMA compatability RDS with PTY + EON setting Steering wheel mounted audio controls USB port Exterior / Styling 16 alloy wheels + locking wheelnuts Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Chrome front fog light surround Chrome front grille Chrome rear garnish Electronic headlamp levelling Fixed panoramic glass sunroof Follow me home headlights Front fog lights Rear spoiler Retractable tonneau cover Roof mounted radio aerial Tyre repair kit Safety / Security Active front headrests Driver/front passenger side airbags Driver/passenger airbags with hybrid inflators Drivers knee airbag Five 3 point rear safety belts Front and rear curtain airbags Front seatbelt pretensioners with force limiters Height adjustable front seatbelts Key in reminder Passenger airbag deactivate switch Rear child proof door locks Remote alarm with perimeter Remote central double locking Steering column lock Transponder engine immobiliser Tyre pressure warning Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0141 413 0747 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 119
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/b40b176e-4ebf-39ea-bc4d-2e9355271782" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-22T15:27:38Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:43:37.155Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39874519/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="12" endPos="18" type="organization" surface="Toyota" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="12" endPos="33" type="product" surface="Toyota Verso 1.6 D-4D" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="19" endPos="33" type="head" surface="Verso 1.6 D-4D" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1035" endPos="1045" type="organization" surface="Motorpoint" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1063" endPos="1078" type="industry" surface="Car Supermarket" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1087" endPos="1103" type="url" surface="Motorpoint.co.uk" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1441" endPos="1447" type="organization" surface="Toyota" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1441" endPos="1453" type="product" surface="Toyota Verso" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="1448" endPos="1453" type="head" surface="Verso" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="9" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
<Entity id="4" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="10" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="11" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="7" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="12" NAME="CompanyWebsite">
<Entity id="5" label="website" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="13" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="14" NAME="entity_head">
<Entity id="1" label="full_extent" />
<Entity id="2" label="head" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="15" NAME="entity_head">
<Entity id="7" label="full_extent" />
<Entity id="8" label="head" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
