<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>World Smart Energy Week 2016 Opening Next Month in Japan World News: 01:35 GMT Wednesday 10th February 2016 . [ World Smart Energy Week Show Management via <NODE id="156" />Businesswire<NODE id="168" /> via SPi World News ] Reed Exhibitions Japan will be holding the 12th installment of Japan's largest show for smart and renewable energy - World Smart Energy Week 2016 next month from March 2-4 at Tokyo Big Sight . This Smart News Release features multimedia. View the full release here: http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20160209006897/en/ Scene from World Smart Energy Week 2015 (Photo: Business Wire) Best Platform for Smart &amp; Renewable Energy Business Composed of 9 exhibitions (PV EXPO, PV SYSTEM EXPO, FC EXPO, BATTERY JAPAN, WIND EXPO, INT'L SMART GRID EXPO,ENERGY MARKET LIBERALISATION EXPO, ECO HOUSE &amp; ECO BUILDING EXPO and INT'L BIOMASS EXPO) and 227 conference sessions, this comprehensive business event is expected to bring together 80,000 professionals and 21,000 conference attendees from across Japan and the world. The show will commence with a ribbon-cutting ceremony inviting over 45 renowned experts from Japan and overseas as dignitaries, followed by the World Smart Energy Week Keynote Session led by the <NODE id="1200" />Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry (METI)<NODE id="1246" /> to discussCurrent Situation and Issues in Renewable Energy &amp; Energy Conservation Policies and the <NODE id="1345" />U.S. Department of Energy<NODE id="1370" /> to hold a talk on Clean Energy Revolution Now: Innovating to Accelerate a Low Carbon Future. Details of all the Keynotes and Technical sessions can be found in the Conference Program . At the exhibitions a total of 1,430 exhibitors will be showcasing the latest products, technologies and solutions from various areas of smart and renewable energy business. Electricity Retail Business on the Rise There will be a big focus on the exhibits related to electricity retail business with the deregulation of the energy market starting April this year. ENERGY MARKET LIBERALISATION EXPO will gather various tools, applications and services to promote sales for both existing and new-comers to the electricity retail business. The latest business strategies of the major gas, electric companies, consultation firms, new-comers and players from overseas will be shared at the conference. At the ENERGY MARKET LIBERALISATION EXPO Keynote Session the key players of both Eastern and Western Japan - Tokyo Gas and The Kansai Electric Power will be sharing their thoughts. Growth of Biomass Power Generation A major highlight this year will be the launch of INT'L BIOMASS EXPO . The biomass power generation market in Japan is expected to grow and the latest pelletising technologies, logistic services, fuel products and other related services to support the business will be on show for local governments, plants and institutions to explore and compare. The leaders from the field will discuss visions for the development of the business at the INT'L BIOMASS EXPO Keynote Session. Solar Business Looking Bright After the expansion of PV cell and module installations influenced by the generous Feed-In-Tariff, the business for solar power in Japan is now shifting towards innovative technologies and solutions such as efficient manufacturing processes and cost reduction. Such products and technologies will be highlighted at PV EXPO as well as cells and modules of leading firms from both Japan and abroad. Japanese firms such as <NODE id="3393" />PANASONIC<NODE id="3402" />, <NODE id="3404" />SHARP<NODE id="3409" />, <NODE id="3411" />XSOL<NODE id="3415" />, will be showcasing their Total <NODE id="3448" />Energy<NODE id="3454" /> Solutions. Major firms from overseas will also continue to exhibit such as <NODE id="3530" />TRINA SOLAR<NODE id="3541" />, <NODE id="3543" />YINGLI GREEN ENERGY<NODE id="3562" />, <NODE id="3564" />CANADIAN SOLAR<NODE id="3578" />, <NODE id="3580" />HANWHA Q CELLS<NODE id="3594" />, <NODE id="3596" />JINKO SOLAR<NODE id="3607" />, <NODE id="3609" />JA SOLAR<NODE id="3617" />. Operation and Maintenance for PV systems will be a major theme at PV SYSTEM EXPO and the update of the latest trends and outlook of the business will be discussed at the PV EXPO Keynote Session by <NODE id="3816" />METI<NODE id="3820" />, <NODE id="3822" />PANASONIC<NODE id="3831" /> and the <NODE id="3840" />U.S. Department of Energy<NODE id="3865" />. Growth Returns to Japan's Wind Energy Increasing number of wind farm projects in Japan which have passed the 3-year environment assessment are now ready for business. As cabling and infrastructure between the capital and the northern region of Japan have also been installed, potential for wind energy is expected to grow. Various wind turbines, components, devices and O&amp;M related services will be exhibited at WIND EXPO to aid the expansion of the business. Being the largest wind energy show in Japan, it will be the perfect venue to negotiate and network with key players of the business. Future perspectives of the business will be shared by <NODE id="4514" />ENERCON<NODE id="4521" />, <NODE id="4523" />SENVION<NODE id="4530" />, <NODE id="4532" />GOLDWIND SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY<NODE id="4561" />, and <NODE id="4567" />GAMESA<NODE id="4573" /> at the WIND EXPO Special Session . Strategies and prospects will also be discussed by major players in Japan - <NODE id="4685" />METI<NODE id="4689" />, <NODE id="4691" />Municipal National Council for Wind Power Promotion<NODE id="4742" />, <NODE id="4744" />Marubeni Corp.<NODE id="4758" /> and <NODE id="4763" />MHI Vestas Offshore Wind<NODE id="4787" /> at the WIND EXPO Keynote Session . Advancing Battery Needs and Technologies With the advancements of applications for electric vehicles, drones and robots, the R&amp;D for next-generation batteries are accelerating. The latest systems for such batteries and capacitors will be highlighted at BATTERY JAPAN . A new featured exhibit zone for Battery Management Systems (BMS) will also be launched this year where BMS for the enhancement of safety, longer life and power efficiency of batteries will be showcased. As the world's largest renewable battery show, BATTERY JAPAN will be the best platform to seek the latest technologies and trends from experts across Japan and the world. Topics to be featured at the exhibition and the conference will be LIB, capacitors, electric vehicles, stationary battery and security measures. At the BATTERY JAPAN Keynote Session The latest trends of EV and battery storage technologies towards a low carbon society will be discussed by <NODE id="5755" />NISSAN MOTORS<NODE id="5768" />, <NODE id="5770" />LG CHEM<NODE id="5777" /> and <NODE id="5782" />TESLA MOTORS JAPAN<NODE id="5800" />. Hydrogen Society Infrastructure For the ongoing commercialisation of Fuel Cell Electric Vehicles (FCEVs) and development of its infrastructure, hydrogen stations, storage tanks, sensing devices, dispensers and component technologies will be highlighted at FC EXPO . The latest FCEV models from Japan such as <NODE id="6110" />Toyota's<NODE id="6118" /> <NODE id="6119" />MIRAI<NODE id="6124" /> will be available for test drive sessions arranged by <NODE id="6179" />THE RESEARCH ASSOCIATION OF HYDROGEN SUPPLY/UTILIZATION TECHNOLOGY (HySUT)<NODE id="6253" />. Being the largest show of its kind in the world, the show will also feature the latest and high quality materials, components, devices and technologies for hydrogen and fuel cells. To share the strategies and prospects towards a hydrogen society, <NODE id="6502" />METI<NODE id="6506" />, <NODE id="6508" />U.S. DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY<NODE id="6533" />, <NODE id="6535" />HONDA MOTORS<NODE id="6547" /> and <NODE id="6552" />KAWASAKI HEAVY INDUSTRIES<NODE id="6577" /> will be holding the FC EXPO Keynote Session. IoT technologies in Smart Communities As IoT technologies advance, the latest <NODE id="6701" />ICT services, sensor technologies for wireless networks for Home Energy Management Systems (HEMS) and Building Management Systems (BEMS)<NODE id="6837" /> will be major highlights at INT'L SMART GRID EXPO . Major players in the <NODE id="6911" />field<NODE id="6916" /> such as <NODE id="6925" />TOSHIBA<NODE id="6932" />, <NODE id="6934" />MITSUBISHI ELECTRIC<NODE id="6953" />, <NODE id="6955" />MITSUBISHI HEAVY INDUSTRIES<NODE id="6982" /> and <NODE id="6987" />FUJI ELECTRIC<NODE id="7000" /> will be exhibiting their latest technologies and solutions. At the conference , <NODE id="7081" />TOKYO ELECTRIC POWER<NODE id="7101" />, <NODE id="7103" />MITSUBISHI ELECTRIC<NODE id="7122" />, <NODE id="7124" />SUMITOMO ELECTRIC INDUSTRIES<NODE id="7152" />, <NODE id="7154" />TOSHIBA<NODE id="7161" /> and <NODE id="7166" />HITACHI<NODE id="7173" /> will be updating the visions of a smart grid society, latest technologies for a stable power system and developments of smart cities in Japan. The latest quality materials and technologies for smart homes and buildings will be showcased at the concurrently held ECO HOUSE &amp; ECO BUILDING EXPO . For further details of the exhibitors and exhibits, browse the Exhibitor Directory . Visit with a Free Exhibition Ticket World Smart Energy Week 2016 will be open to all smart and renewable energy related professionals. Exhibition Tickets can be obtained free by online registration . Visiting tips and show highlights can be found in the Visitor's Guide . For further details visit the official show websites or contact Show Management directly: visitor-eng.wsew@reedexpo.co.jp . View source version on businesswire.com: http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20160209006897/en/ More news and information about World Smart Energy Week Show Management Published By: <NODE id="8133" />Business Wire<NODE id="8146" />: 01:35 GMT Wednesday 10th February 2016
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/31efe6d3-4689-3903-af2f-a1ae24a5e09c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-10T06:32:30Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:54:08.463Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.sectorpublishingintelligence.co.uk/news/1358765/world+smart+energy+week+2016+opening+next+month+in+japan" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="156" endPos="168" type="organization" surface="Businesswire" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1200" endPos="1246" type="organization" surface="Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry (METI)" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1345" endPos="1370" type="organization" surface="U.S. Department of Energy" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="3393" endPos="3402" type="organization" surface="PANASONIC" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="3404" endPos="3409" type="organization" surface="SHARP" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="3411" endPos="3415" type="organization" surface="XSOL" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="3448" endPos="3454" type="industry" surface="Energy" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="3530" endPos="3541" type="organization" surface="TRINA SOLAR" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="3543" endPos="3562" type="organization" surface="YINGLI GREEN ENERGY" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="3564" endPos="3578" type="organization" surface="CANADIAN SOLAR" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3580" endPos="3594" type="organization" surface="HANWHA Q CELLS" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="3596" endPos="3607" type="organization" surface="JINKO SOLAR" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="3609" endPos="3617" type="organization" surface="JA SOLAR" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="3816" endPos="3820" type="organization" surface="METI" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="3822" endPos="3831" type="organization" surface="PANASONIC" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="3840" endPos="3865" type="organization" surface="U.S. Department of Energy" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="4514" endPos="4521" type="organization" surface="ENERCON" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="4523" endPos="4530" type="organization" surface="SENVION" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="4532" endPos="4561" type="organization" surface="GOLDWIND SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="4567" endPos="4573" type="organization" surface="GAMESA" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="4685" endPos="4689" type="organization" surface="METI" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="4691" endPos="4742" type="organization" surface="Municipal National Council for Wind Power Promotion" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="4744" endPos="4758" type="organization" surface="Marubeni Corp." />
<Entity id="23" startPos="4763" endPos="4787" type="organization" surface="MHI Vestas Offshore Wind" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="5755" endPos="5768" type="organization" surface="NISSAN MOTORS" />
<Entity id="25" startPos="5770" endPos="5777" type="organization" surface="LG CHEM" />
<Entity id="26" startPos="5782" endPos="5800" type="organization" surface="TESLA MOTORS JAPAN" />
<Entity id="27" startPos="6110" endPos="6118" type="organization" surface="Toyota's" />
<Entity id="28" startPos="6119" endPos="6124" type="product" surface="MIRAI" />
<Entity id="29" startPos="6179" endPos="6253" type="organization" surface="THE RESEARCH ASSOCIATION OF HYDROGEN SUPPLY/UTILIZATION TECHNOLOGY (HySUT)" />
<Entity id="30" startPos="6502" endPos="6506" type="organization" surface="METI" />
<Entity id="31" startPos="6508" endPos="6533" type="organization" surface="U.S. DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY" />
<Entity id="32" startPos="6535" endPos="6547" type="organization" surface="HONDA MOTORS" />
<Entity id="33" startPos="6552" endPos="6577" type="organization" surface="KAWASAKI HEAVY INDUSTRIES" />
<Entity id="34" startPos="6701" endPos="6837" type="industry" surface="ICT services, sensor technologies for wireless networks for Home Energy Management Systems (HEMS) and Building Management Systems (BEMS)" />
<Entity id="35" startPos="6911" endPos="6916" type="industry" surface="field" />
<Entity id="36" startPos="6925" endPos="6932" type="organization" surface="TOSHIBA" />
<Entity id="37" startPos="6934" endPos="6953" type="organization" surface="MITSUBISHI ELECTRIC" />
<Entity id="38" startPos="6955" endPos="6982" type="organization" surface="MITSUBISHI HEAVY INDUSTRIES" />
<Entity id="39" startPos="6987" endPos="7000" type="organization" surface="FUJI ELECTRIC" />
<Entity id="40" startPos="7081" endPos="7101" type="organization" surface="TOKYO ELECTRIC POWER" />
<Entity id="41" startPos="7103" endPos="7122" type="organization" surface="MITSUBISHI ELECTRIC" />
<Entity id="42" startPos="7124" endPos="7152" type="organization" surface="SUMITOMO ELECTRIC INDUSTRIES" />
<Entity id="43" startPos="7154" endPos="7161" type="organization" surface="TOSHIBA" />
<Entity id="44" startPos="7166" endPos="7173" type="organization" surface="HITACHI" />
<Entity id="45" startPos="8133" endPos="8146" type="organization" surface="Business Wire" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="46" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
<Entity id="6" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="47" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
<Entity id="6" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="48" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
<Entity id="6" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="49" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="39" label="company" />
<Entity id="35" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="50" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="36" label="company" />
<Entity id="35" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="51" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="38" label="company" />
<Entity id="35" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="52" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="37" label="company" />
<Entity id="35" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="53" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="28" label="product" />
<Entity id="27" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="54" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="45" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="55" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="30" label="target" />
<Entity id="20" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="56" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="2" label="source" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="31" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="57" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="34" label="source" />
<Entity id="35" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="58" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="36" label="source" />
<Entity id="43" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
