<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Classified in: PUNE, India , Feb. 5, 2016 /PRNewswire-iReach/ -- This market research report includes a detailed segmentation of the global liquid analytical instrument market by application (pH/ORP, conductivity/resistivity, turbidity, and oxygen analysis/dissolved oxygen analysis), product type (transmitter and sensor) and end-user (water, chemical, oil and gas, power, and pharmaceuticals). It outlines the market shares for key regions such as the Americas, APAC, and EMEA. The key vendors analyzed in this report are <NODE id="524" />ABB<NODE id="527" />, <NODE id="529" />Emerson Electric<NODE id="545" />, <NODE id="547" />Endress+Hauser<NODE id="561" />, and <NODE id="567" />Teledyne<NODE id="575" />. Photo - http://photos.prnewswire.com/prnh/20160204/329794LOGO Market outlook of the global liquid analytical instrument market The research analyst predicts the global liquid analytical instrument market to grow steadily at a CAGR of about 6% during the forecast period. There has been a growing need to measure parameters, such as the amount of dissolved oxygen, conductivity and resistivity, turbidity, and pH/ORP of a liquid that is applicable in almost all process industries such as water and wastewater, oil and gas, chemical, power, biotechnology, and pharmaceuticals. This need has created a high demand for these liquid analytical instruments leading to the growth of the market. Complete Report Details at https://www.wiseguyreports.com/reports/global-liquid-analytical-instrument-market-2016-2020 . There is a growing demand for real-time data monitoring in several end-user industries such as the water treatment industry to improve the overall process efficiency. Several oil companies are trying to convert their existing fields into smart fields, which require the use of instruments to analyze the process and monitor the content of substance. The increased conversion of oil and gas fields to the digital form will be a growth driver for various liquid analytical instruments. Application segmentation and analysis of the global liquid analytical instrument market pH/ORP Conductivity/resistivity Turbidity Oxygen analysis/dissolved oxygen The pH/ORP application segment dominated the global liquid analytical instrument market in 2015. This segment is expected to grow at a CAGR of about 7% during the forecast period. The pH/ORP measurement is mainly used in the water and wastewater treatment industry and helps in determining the hardness of water. Product segmentation and analysis of the global liquid analytical instrument market Transmitter Sensor The transmitter product segment dominated the global liquid analytical instrument market during 2015. A liquid analytical transmitter is used to measure the resistivity/conductivity, pH/ORP, and dissolved oxygen in a liquid. It is mainly used in conductivity measurement, which is utilized in a variety of industrial applications. Order a Purchase Copy @ https://www.wiseguyreports.com/checkout?currency=one_user-USD&amp;report_id=334945 . End-user segmentation and analysis of the global liquid analytical instrument market Water Chemical Oil and gas Power Pharmaceuticals The water industry was the most dominant end-user of the global liquid analytical instrument market in 2015. This segment is expected to grow at a CAGR of around 5% during the forecast period. The growth of the global water industry has generated high demand for liquid analytical instruments. Water such as seawater, groundwater, municipal drinking water, and wastewater are treated using water treatment equipment. Analytical instruments are used to measure the pH/ORP, turbidity, oxygen analysis/dissolved oxygen, conductivity/resistivity, chlorine, and total organic carbon in water. Geographical segmentation and analysis of the global liquid analytical instrument market Americas EMEA APAC The Americas accounted for around 39% of the market share during 2015. The presence of many pharmaceutical companies in the region has contributed to the growth of the liquid analytical instrument market. Increased adoption of liquid analytical instruments for water and wastewater treatment applications has also been propelling market growth in the region. Competitive landscape and key vendors Large and international vendors dominate the <NODE id="4158" />global liquid analytical instrument market<NODE id="4200" />. Regional and local vendors find it difficult to compete with established players as analytical instruments require the incorporation of precise electronics that comes at a high price. Hence, small vendors are discouraged from entering the capital-intensive market. The leading vendors in the <NODE id="4494" />market<NODE id="4500" /> are - <NODE id="4507" />ABB<NODE id="4510" /> <NODE id="4511" />Emerson Electric<NODE id="4527" /> <NODE id="4528" />Endress+Hauser<NODE id="4542" /> <NODE id="4543" />Teledyne<NODE id="4551" /> Other prominent vendors in the <NODE id="4583" />market<NODE id="4589" /> include <NODE id="4598" />AMETEK<NODE id="4604" />, <NODE id="4606" />Analytik Jena<NODE id="4619" />, <NODE id="4621" />Danaher<NODE id="4628" />, <NODE id="4630" />GE<NODE id="4632" />, <NODE id="4634" />Honeywell<NODE id="4643" />, and <NODE id="4649" />Yokogawa Electric<NODE id="4666" />. Inquire For Discount @ https://www.wiseguyreports.com/check_discount/global-liquid-analytical-instrument-market-2016-2020 . Contact for More Information at sales@wiseguyreports.com or +1 (646) 845 9349 (US) and +44 208 133 9349 (UK) About <NODE id="4907" />Us<NODE id="4909" /> <NODE id="4910" />Wise Guy Reports<NODE id="4926" /> is part of the <NODE id="4942" />Wise Guy Consultants Pvt. Ltd.<NODE id="4972" /> and offers premium <NODE id="4992" />progressive statistical surveying, market research reports, analysis &amp; forecast data for industries and governments<NODE id="5107" /> around the globe. <NODE id="5126" />We<NODE id="5128" /> also provide COTS (Commercial off the Shelf) business sector reports as custom exploration agreeing your particular needs. Media Contact: Norah Trent , WiseGuy Reports, +1 646 845 9349, sales@wiseguyreports.com News distributed by PR Newswire iReach: https://ireach.prnewswire.com SOURCE WiseGuy Reports
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/51d53be7-7e61-3208-9151-ae9a60c7521d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-06T10:30:07Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:06:10.535Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.lelezard.com/en/news-9308182.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="524" endPos="527" type="organization" surface="ABB" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="529" endPos="545" type="organization" surface="Emerson Electric" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="547" endPos="561" type="organization" surface="Endress+Hauser" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="567" endPos="575" type="organization" surface="Teledyne" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="4158" endPos="4200" type="industry" surface="global liquid analytical instrument market" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="4494" endPos="4500" type="industry" surface="market" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="4507" endPos="4510" type="organization" surface="ABB" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="4511" endPos="4527" type="organization" surface="Emerson Electric" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="4528" endPos="4542" type="organization" surface="Endress+Hauser" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="4543" endPos="4551" type="organization" surface="Teledyne" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="4583" endPos="4589" type="industry" surface="market" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="4598" endPos="4604" type="organization" surface="AMETEK" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="4606" endPos="4619" type="organization" surface="Analytik Jena" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="4621" endPos="4628" type="organization" surface="Danaher" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="4630" endPos="4632" type="organization" surface="GE" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="4634" endPos="4643" type="organization" surface="Honeywell" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="4649" endPos="4666" type="organization" surface="Yokogawa Electric" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="4907" endPos="4909" type="organization" surface="Us" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="4910" endPos="4926" type="organization" surface="Wise Guy Reports" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="4942" endPos="4972" type="organization" surface="Wise Guy Consultants Pvt. Ltd." />
<Entity id="20" startPos="4992" endPos="5107" type="industry" surface="progressive statistical surveying, market research reports, analysis &amp; forecast data for industries and governments" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="5126" endPos="5128" type="organization" surface="We" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="22" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="23" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="24" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="9" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="25" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="26" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="13" label="company" />
<Entity id="10" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="27" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
<Entity id="10" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="28" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="11" label="company" />
<Entity id="10" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="29" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="16" label="company" />
<Entity id="10" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
<Entity id="10" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="14" label="company" />
<Entity id="10" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="32" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="18" label="company" />
<Entity id="20" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="33" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="18" label="child" />
<Entity id="19" label="parent" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="34" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="35" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="1" label="source" />
<Entity id="7" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="36" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="2" label="source" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="37" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="3" label="source" />
<Entity id="9" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="38" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="4" label="source" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="10" label="target" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="39" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="18" label="source" />
<Entity id="17" label="target" />
<Entity id="21" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
