<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Friday, 29 January 2016 | MYT 10:00 AM Digitalisation: The next step for Malaysia’s automotive industry by adam yee Car tech: A <NODE id="128" />fully automated car door assembly line<NODE id="166" /> with virtualisation capabilities in the <NODE id="207" />Siemens<NODE id="214" /> <NODE id="215" />factory<NODE id="222" />. — <NODE id="226" />Siemens<NODE id="233" /> Although <NODE id="243" />cars<NODE id="247" /> were flying off the shelf in Malaysia during the last few weeks of 2015, this year is shaping up to be a new ballgame altogether. A research firm recently revealed that the outlook for Malaysia's <NODE id="444" />auto<NODE id="448" /> industry in the months ahead is on the cautious side, with living costs on the rise and the ringgit continuing to slide. The impact of these factors is being felt across the automotive manufacturing sector in the form of higher component costs and overall lowering margins. On the flipside, e-commerce has seen a growing global market for <NODE id="788" />auto parts<NODE id="798" />, with America comprising the majority of the consumer base. According to a survey published in the Borneo Post and conducted by a top <NODE id="933" />e-commerce platform<NODE id="952" /> provider, online demand for <NODE id="981" />auto parts<NODE id="991" /> and <NODE id="996" />accessories<NODE id="1007" /> among <NODE id="1014" />vehicle<NODE id="1021" /> owners is set to continue increasing over the next few years. It is inevitable that competition will grow stiffer, as we begin to see more automotive distributors and vendors in Malaysia as well as other countries turning to these online channels to access foreign markets. According to Aseanbriefing.com, Malaysia is one of the top <NODE id="1355" />automobile<NODE id="1365" /> producers in the Asia Pacific region, with an annual production of around 0.65 million <NODE id="1453" />cars<NODE id="1457" /> and a combined total of over 600 plants for finished <NODE id="1511" />cars<NODE id="1515" /> and part makers. To sustain this industry amid the current ringgit situation and the increase in cross-border trading, automotive manufacturers will have to be one step ahead in its technology and processes. Leveraging technology The progression of technology has always been integral to each industrial revolution wave since the 1700s. Today, digitalisation is revolutionising manufacturing processes across industries, enabling businesses to gain a competitive edge over other companies. In a nutshell, digital solutions work to link up <NODE id="2055" />automation components<NODE id="2076" /> such as <NODE id="2085" />controllers<NODE id="2096" /> and <NODE id="2101" />motor<NODE id="2106" /> management, including other <NODE id="2135" />hardware<NODE id="2143" /> and <NODE id="2148" />software interfaces<NODE id="2167" />, with a host of <NODE id="2184" />sensors<NODE id="2191" /> and <NODE id="2196" />actuators<NODE id="2205" />. This way, plant operators gain enhanced visibility of the factory's processes as manufacturing data is centrally consolidated and updated in real-time. This data trove also signifies the transformation of the entire product and production lifecycle, equipping manufacturers with greater control over their product quality, factory efficiency and time-to-market targets. Improving production processes Product design and product planning, for example, are two key processes in automotive production, with the potential to determine factory performance and overall product quality. Typically, it takes months for a particular <NODE id="2831" />car<NODE id="2834" /> model design to be fully developed. A significant amount of time goes into creating and recreating physical prototypes, which undergo time-consuming tests to determine its <NODE id="3007" />vehicle<NODE id="3014" /> performance and suitability for a range of applications. With digital technologies, engineers will be able to leverage on its simulation capabilities to create and test these virtualised prototypes. Overall, expenses and time spent are reduced, as fewer physical models have to be built and assessed during the design process. Production planning is also optimised with digital solutions that allow manufacturers to simulate the placement of new production lines to determine the best plant layout and equipment locations. Being able to perform feasibility analysis on digital models of assembly manufacturing processes also increases the likelihood of achieving time-to-market targets as potential issues are eliminated from the get-go. Furthermore, with proper alignment of manufacturing processes with product designs, there is greater quality control and wastage in the form of scraps and rework is reduced. Change is the new constant In this world of ever-changing market demands and stiffening global competition, businesses need to be nimble and adjust quickly – whether by adopting new technologies or reassessing their company strategy. Considering the challenges faced by Malaysian <NODE id="4207" />auto<NODE id="4211" /> manufacturers, it is important for them to leverage digital solutions as a way to elevate their production processes to the next level. With thorough planning and the enhancement of efficiencies, manufacturers can lower overall costs and ensure quality output. This way, Malaysia's automotive sector will be able to secure not just a local but global competitive advantage as well. Adam Yee is the senior vice president of division lead digital factory and process industry and drives, <NODE id="4698" />Siemens Malaysia<NODE id="4714" />. Copyright © 1995- Star Media Group Berhad (ROC 10894D) (Formerly known as Star Publications (Malaysia) Berhad)
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/acc552f8-94e1-3220-be8d-1a5981ffdd3c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-29T20:01:27Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:40:41.02Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.thestar.com.my/tech/tech-opinion/2016/01/29/digitalisation-the-next-step-for-malaysias-automotive-industry/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="128" endPos="166" type="product" surface="fully automated car door assembly line" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="207" endPos="214" type="organization" surface="Siemens" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="215" endPos="222" type="trigger" surface="factory" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="226" endPos="233" type="organization" surface="Siemens" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="243" endPos="247" type="product" surface="cars" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="444" endPos="448" type="product" surface="auto" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="788" endPos="798" type="product" surface="auto parts" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="933" endPos="952" type="product" surface="e-commerce platform" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="981" endPos="991" type="product" surface="auto parts" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="996" endPos="1007" type="product" surface="accessories" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="1014" endPos="1021" type="product" surface="vehicle" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="1355" endPos="1365" type="product" surface="automobile" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="1453" endPos="1457" type="product" surface="cars" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="1511" endPos="1515" type="product" surface="cars" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="2055" endPos="2076" type="product" surface="automation components" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="2085" endPos="2096" type="product" surface="controllers" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="2101" endPos="2106" type="product" surface="motor" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="2135" endPos="2143" type="product" surface="hardware" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="2148" endPos="2167" type="product" surface="software interfaces" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="2184" endPos="2191" type="product" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="2196" endPos="2205" type="product" surface="actuators" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="2831" endPos="2834" type="product" surface="car" />
<Entity id="22" startPos="3007" endPos="3014" type="product" surface="vehicle" />
<Entity id="23" startPos="4207" endPos="4211" type="product" surface="auto" />
<Entity id="24" startPos="4698" endPos="4714" type="organization" surface="Siemens Malaysia" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="25" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="0" label="product" />
<Entity id="2" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
