<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>UAV Payload Market Will Grow Rapidly Owing To Enhanced Demand In Military And Commercial UAV Industry Till 2022: <NODE id="113" />Grand View Research, Inc.<NODE id="138" /> (February 06, 2016) <NODE id="159" />Grand View Research, Inc.<NODE id="184" /> - Market Research And Consulting. GrandViewResearch.com has announced the addition of Global UAV Payload Market Analysis And Segment Forecasts To 2022 Market Research report to their Database The global UAV payload market size is expected to reach USD 6.34 billion by 2022 according to a new report by Grand View Research, Inc. Technological advancements and increasing investments in R&amp;D have driven the UAV market. Increasing demand in military and commercial UAV industry has propelled industry growth. Payloads are a part of larger drone system and depend on the application segment of the UAV system. UAV payload comprises sensors, cameras, gimbal controllers, communications systems, and weaponry. Applications of such UAVs in energy, agriculture, retail, and media and entertainment sectors along with fire fighting and surveying are expected to positively impact payload industry growth. Drones are gradually becoming popular in the commercial sector as well after making their presence felt in the military sector. However, stringent government policies regulating the use of such UAVs commercially are expected to pose a challenge to the payload industry. Full research report on UAV payload marketanalysis: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/uav-payload-market Further key findings from the report suggest: Camera, imagers, and sensing equipment segment led the global UAV payload industry accounting for nearly 40% of the industry revenue share in 2014. Increasing applications in law enforcement and surveillance activities are expected to drive the demand for such equipment over the next seven years. Moreover, use of drones with high resolution cameras in commercial film industry and aerial photography activities is expected to generate considerable demand for such equipment. Radar and communication equipment form an essential part of military and commercial UAS. These form a link between the drone operator at the ground control unit and the UAVs enabling efficient navigation and maneuvering. Weaponry payload equipment is projected to grow at a CAGR of over 5% owing to the increasing adoption and deployment of drones in military and defense activities across the globe. Other payload equipment such as agricultural equipment, delivery drone equipment, and panels for solar-powered drone are anticipated to witness steady growth over the next few years. North America dominated the global UAV equipment industry acquiring over 40% of the overall global revenue share in 2014. Extensive use of advanced military drones in combat operations and war zones is expected to drive growth in the region. Favorable initiatives by the government and <NODE id="2866" />aviation regulatory authorities<NODE id="2897" /> such as the <NODE id="2910" />FAA<NODE id="2913" /> in the U.S. and <NODE id="2930" />EASA<NODE id="2934" /> in the European region regarding the use of commercial drones have led to an overall surge in demand for drone payload in the region. Projected to grow at a CAGR of 5.6% from 2015 to 2022, Asia Pacific regional market is anticipated to be a region with vast growth avenues in the industry. Increased investments by countries such as China, India, and Japan in military and commercial drones are expected to derive huge demand for drones and its payloads over the forecast period. Key <NODE id="3419" />drone payload manufacturers<NODE id="3446" /> include <NODE id="3455" />Israel Aerospace Industries<NODE id="3482" />, <NODE id="3484" />L-3 Communications<NODE id="3502" />, <NODE id="3504" />Insitu<NODE id="3510" />, <NODE id="3512" />Orbit<NODE id="3517" />, and <NODE id="3523" />Textron Inc<NODE id="3534" />. Vendors are increasingly adopting mergers and acquisitions to establish dominance in the market. Drone manufacturers collaborate with technology suppliers to enhance their products as compared to their competitors products in the industry. Request for sample of this research report: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/uav-payload-market/request Grand View Research has segmented the global UAV payload market on the basis of equipment and region: UAV Payload Equipment Outlook (Revenue, USD Million, 2012 2022) Cameras &amp; Sensors Radar &amp; Communications Weaponry Others UAV Payload Regional Outlook (Revenue, USD Million, 2012 2022) North America Europe Asia Pacific Latin America MEA View more reports of this category by Grand View Research at: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry/emerging-and-next-generation-technologies About Grand View Research <NODE id="4408" />Grand View Research, Inc.<NODE id="4433" /> is a U.S. based <NODE id="4450" />market research and consulting<NODE id="4480" /> company, registered in the State of California and headquartered in San Francisco. Thecompany provides syndicated research reports, customized research reports, and consulting services. To help clients make informed business decisions, <NODE id="4717" />we<NODE id="4719" /> offer <NODE id="4726" />market intelligence studies<NODE id="4753" /> ensuring relevant and fact-based research across a range of industries, from technology to chemicals, materials and healthcare. Web: www.grandviewresearch.com Media Contact Company Name: <NODE id="4941" />Grand View Research, Inc.<NODE id="4966" /> Contact Person: Sherry James, Corporate Sales Specialist - U.S.A. Email: sales@grandviewresearch.com Phone: 1-415-349-0058, Toll Free: 1-888-202-9519 Address:28 2nd Street, Suite 3036 City: San Francisco State: California Country: United States Website: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/uav-payload-market Source: ABNewswire Page: 1 Related Keywords:Business, Manufacturing &amp; Industry, Technology, Source:Copyright (c) AB Digital, Inc. All Rights Reserved This advertisement will close in seconds...
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/e796f09b-39a4-3c7d-8db6-5fcf2b4c5a8d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-07T13:57:05Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:03:10.694Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.reviewseeker.com/articles/viewarticle.jsp?id=4280572" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="113" endPos="138" type="organization" surface="Grand View Research, Inc." />
<Entity id="1" startPos="159" endPos="184" type="organization" surface="Grand View Research, Inc." />
<Entity id="2" startPos="2866" endPos="2897" type="industry" surface="aviation regulatory authorities" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="2910" endPos="2913" type="organization" surface="FAA" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="2930" endPos="2934" type="organization" surface="EASA" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="3419" endPos="3446" type="industry" surface="drone payload manufacturers" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="3455" endPos="3482" type="organization" surface="Israel Aerospace Industries" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="3484" endPos="3502" type="organization" surface="L-3 Communications" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="3504" endPos="3510" type="organization" surface="Insitu" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="3512" endPos="3517" type="organization" surface="Orbit" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3523" endPos="3534" type="organization" surface="Textron Inc" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="4408" endPos="4433" type="organization" surface="Grand View Research, Inc." />
<Entity id="12" startPos="4450" endPos="4480" type="industry" surface="market research and consulting" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="4717" endPos="4719" type="organization" surface="we" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="4726" endPos="4753" type="industry" surface="market intelligence studies" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="4941" endPos="4966" type="organization" surface="Grand View Research, Inc." /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="16" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
<Entity id="2" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="17" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
<Entity id="2" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="18" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="19" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="20" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="9" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="21" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="22" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="23" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="11" label="company" />
<Entity id="12" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="24" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="13" label="company" />
<Entity id="14" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="25" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="13" label="target" />
<Entity id="15" label="target" />
<Entity id="11" label="target" />
<Entity id="1" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
