<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Edge 2016 041-060 Most Important Recent Scientific News http://edge.org/responses/what-do-you-consider-the-most-interesting-recent-scientific-news-what-makes-it 2016: What do you consider the most interesting recent [scientific] news? What makes it important? 041. John C. Mather Nobel Prize in Physics Laureate; Senior Astrophysicist, Observational Cosmology Laboratory, NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center Bayesian Program Learning --- You may not like it! But artificial intelligence jumped a bit closer this year with the development of Bayesian Program Learning, by Lake, Salakhutdinov, and Tenenbaum, published in Science. It's news because for decades I've been hearing about how hard it is to achieve artificial intelligence, and the most successful methods have used serious brute force. Methods based on understanding the symbols and logic of things and language have had a tough time. The challenge is to invent a computer representation of complex information, and then enable a machine to learn that information from examples and evidence. Lake et al. give a mathematical framework, an algorithm, and a computer code that implements it, and their software has learned to read 1623 handwritten characters in 50 languages as well as a human being. They say Concepts are represented as simple probabilistic programs--that is, probabilistic generative models expressed as structured procedures in an abstract description language. Also, a concept can be built up by re-using parts of other concepts or programs. The probabilistic approach handles the imprecision of both definitions and examples. (Bayes' theorem tells us how to compute the probability of something complicated, if we know the probabilities of various smaller things that go into the complicated thing.) Their system can learn very quickly, sometimes in one shot, or from a few examples, in a human-like way, and with human-like accuracy. This ability is in dramatic contrast to competing methods depending on immense data sets and simulated neural networks, which are always in the news. So now there are many new questions: How general is this approach? How much structure do humans have to give it, to get it started? Could it really be superior in the end? Is this how living intelligent systems work? How could we tell? Can this computer system grow enough to represent complex concepts that are important to humans in daily life? Where are the first practical applications? This is a long-term project, without any obvious limits to how far it can go. Could this method be so efficient that it doesn't take a super-duper supercomputer to achieve or at least represent artificial intelligence? Insects do very well with a tiny brain after all. More generally, when do we get really accurate transcriptions of multi-person conversations, instantaneous machine language translation, scene recognition, face recognition, self-driving cars, self-directed UAVs safely delivering packages, machine understanding of physics and engineering, machine representation of biological concepts, and machine ability to read the Library of Congress and discuss it in a philosophy or history class? When will my digital assistant really understand what I want to do, or tell me what I ought to do? Is this how the Intelligent Mars Rover will hunt for signs of life on Mars? How about military offense and defense? How could this system implement Asimov's three laws of robotics, to protect humans from robots? How would you know if you should trust your robot? When will people be obsolete? I'm sure many people are already working on all of these questions. I see many opportunities for mischief, but the defense against the dark arts will push very rapid progress too. I am both thrilled and frightened. 042. Bill Joy Co-Founder, Former Chief Scientist, Sun Microsystems; Partner Emeritus, Greentech Venture Group, KPCB 3 Decarbonizing Scientific Breakthroughs and Some Lessons Learned --- Climate change is an enormous challenge. Rapid decarbonization of manufacturing, electricity generation and transportation is critical and may become a crisis because of non-linear effects. 2015 brought not-widely-disseminated news of the commercial availability of three substantial scientific breakthroughs that can significantly accelerate decarbonization. 1) Decarbonizing Concrete; Commoditizing CO2 After water, concrete is the most widely used material in the world. The manufacture of Portland cement for use in concrete accounts for up to 5 percent of global anthropogenic emissions. A new Solidia cement, invented by Dr. Richard Riman of Rutgers University, can be made from the same ingredients as Portland cement and in the same kilns but at lower temperature while incorporating less limestone thus emitting substantially less CO2 in its manufacture. Unlike Portland cement, which consumes water to cure, this new cement cures by consuming CO2. Concrete products made from this new cement have their CO2 footprint reduced by up to 70 percent. Thousands of tons of the new cement have been manufactured and 2015 brings news that large manufacturers are now modifying their factories to use it--rather than Portland cement--to make concrete; its widespread adoption would multiply the demand for industrial CO2 substantially, creating a strong economic incentive for CO2 capture and reuse. Previous attempts at introducing radically low-carbon cements have all failed to scale--because they required raw materials that were not ubiquitous, necessitated new and expensive capital equipment, and/or because of the large range of material properties required by regulation or for specific applications. Despite overcoming these problems and having lower cost and better performance, rapid adoption in an existing infrastructure requires adoption to be incredibly simple--in this case by changing only a single step of the manufacturing process to cure with CO2 rather than water. Can we similarly expect to reduce the CO2 footprint of other high-embodied-energy materials such as steel and aluminum while reusing the existing infrastructure? A decade-long search found no suitable candidate breakthroughs, so these decarbonizations may unfortunately require a much slower process of redesigning products to use lower-embodied-energy materials like structural polymers and fibers. 2) Scalable Wind Turbines for Distributed Wind More than a billion people, mostly in rural areas in the developing world, lack access to a reliable grid and electricity--it matters greatly whether they will get electricity from renewables or fossil fuels. Wind turbines today are the cheapest renewable but only in very large multi-megawatt Utility-Scale units unsuitable for distributed generation (DG); at smaller sizes the performance of existing wind turbine designs degrades substantially. A new type of shrouded wind turbine, invented by Dr. Walt Presz and Dr. Michael Werle of Ogin Energy, saw its first multi-unit deployment at Mid-Scale (100kW-rated range) in 2015. This new turbine's shroud system pumps air around the turbine so that it is efficient at both Mid- and Small-Scale sizes and at lower wind speeds, thus supporting DG and microgrids. A recent analysis shows Utility-Scale Wind the cheapest renewable with unsubsidized cost at about $80/MWh, Solar PV at about $150/MWh; conventional Mid-Scale Wind is $240/MWh--too expensive to make a substantial contribution. The new shrouded turbines provide electricity at half the cost of the conventional Mid-Scale turbines today, and will be cost-competitive with Utility-Scale Wind when they are in volume production. We need to deploy enormous amounts of renewables to fully decarbonize electricity generation and enable the necessary decommissioning of most of the existing fossil-fuel consuming generating equipment. Wind can be deployed extensively much more quickly, safely, and cheaply than the often proposed scale-up of nuclear energy, and can be combined with grid storage such as batteries to make it fully dispatchable. If we get serious about decarbonization, Small- and Mid-Scale turbines can be quickly scaled to high-volume production using existing manufacturing infrastructure, much as was done for materiel during WW II. Having cost-effective wind at all scales complements Solar PV and, with grid storage, completes a portfolio that can further accelerate the already dramatic trend towards most new electric capacity being supplied by renewables. 3) Room Temperature Ionic Electrolyte for Solid State Batteries Current lithium-ion batteries use a flammable liquid electrolyte and typically incorporate materials that further increase the fire danger. Most contain expensive metals such as lithium, cobalt, and nickel. 2015 brings publication of the existence of a new polymer electrolyte, invented by Michael Zimmerman of Ionic Materials, that is the first solid to have commercially practical ionic conductivity at room temperature. The polymer is also inherently safe, self-extinguishing when set on fire. It creates a substantially different chemical environment than a liquid, supporting novel and abundant cathode materials such as sulfur, which is high capacity, light, and inexpensive, and novel and inexpensive metal anodes, thereby supporting multivalent species such as Zn2+. Many desirable battery chemistries, infeasible with liquid electrolytes, are newly possible. This scientific breakthrough, shown only in the 2030's on most battery-industry roadmaps, has long been desired because solid batteries can be substantially cheaper, safe, and store more energy. Solid polymer batteries can be manufactured using mature and inexpensive scale-manufacturing equipment from the plastics industry. 15 percent of global CO2 fossil fuel emissions result from wheeled transportation. India and China's fleets will grow substantially in the years ahead; whether energy for these additional vehicles is provided by renewables or fossil fuels will make a significant difference in global emissions. Low cost, safe and high-capacity batteries can greatly accelerate the electrification of transportation and these fleets beyond the current modest projections. In the 21^st century we need to stop combusting fossil fuels. Electrochemistry--both better batteries and fuel cells--has far greater potential than is generally realized and can displace most combustion. There are other gas- and liquid-based technologies that we can hope to convert to solid-state to reduce their CO2 impact, such as cooling which generally uses a liquid-gas phase transition today. I hope that the future brings news of a solid-state cooling breakthrough that, like the above technologies, can be quickly taken to scale. 043. Michael Vassar Co-founder and Chief Science Officer, MetaMed Research Broke People Ignoring $20 Bills On The Sidewalk --- It's not every year that Edge echoes South Park. I guess everyone's trying to figure out what's real right now. The 2015 South Park season revolved around people losing the ability to distinguish between news and advertising. One day, they wake up broke, at war, and unable to easily distinguish friend from foe. News, as a concept, is gone. Science, as a concept, is gone. In information warfare, the assumption that reliable, low-context communication is even possible recedes into fantasy, taking with it both news and science and replacing them with politics and marketing. I think that the real news, viewed from behind the new, extra-strength Veil of Maya, is what you think you see with your own eyes AND have checked out against the analytic parts of the scholarly literature. Here's what I've got. Last November, I was visiting Francisco Marroquin University in Guatemala (UFM), which is known primarily for being the most Libertarian University in the world. While there, on the floor of the economics department, my co-conspirator found local currency worth almost exactly twenty US dollars. Technically, the money wasn't visible from the sidewalk, but the signs announcing gasoline prices clearly are. In the last few years, I have observed those prices decoupling, both from the price of oil and from one another, whether across town or even across the street. Growing up, I always noticed whether the gas prices on opposite sides of the road differed by one, two, or sometimes even three cents. Today, such prices typically differ by more like twenty cents. I recently saw two stations across the street from one another with prices differing by $.36/gallon and two stations a mile apart charging respectively $2.49/gallon and $3.86/gallon. For a median American driver, $.20/gallon, invested at historically normal rates of return, would add up to about $1500 over the next decade. Median retirement savings for families aged 55-64 is only $15,000, and for families with retirement accounts, median savings are still only $150,000. I'm OK with people not behaving like Homo Economicus, but if broke people are becoming less economically rational with time, this suggests that people don't feel that they can predict the future in basic respects. That they aren't relying on savings to provide for their basic needs. Who can blame them for financial recklessness? Theory, as well as practice, tells us that their leaders have been setting an ever worse example for generations. Financial economics provides the analytic literature on economic caution and risk. In 1987, Larry Summers &amp; Brad DeLong showed that given a risk premium, a standard assumption in financial economics, irrational noise traders crowd out rational actors over time. When Peter Thiel talks about the shift from concrete optimism to abstract optimism; I think that he is characterizing the pattern that is selected for by this dynamic. This shift towards noise trading inflates equity prices, concentrates wealth, and causes more speculative assets to command higher prices each decade than similarly speculative assets would have commanded in the previous decade. With 84 percent of corporate valuations now taking the form of intangibles, up from 16 percent forty years ago--that sounds like the world I see around me. The overall divergence of map from territory in economic settings ultimately means the annihilation of strategy as we know it for most people, making apparent economic prudence a predictably loosing strategy, which means that in the long run, if we can't figure out a better way to aggregate local economic information, we won't have the patience to effectively use that information. 044. Gregory Benford Emeritus Professor of Physics and Astronomy, UC-Irvine; Novelist, Shipstar Pluto Now, Then On To 550 A.U. --- The most long-range portentous event of 2015 was NASA's New Horizons spacecraft arrowing by Pluto, snapping clean views of the planet and its waltzing moon system. It carries an ounce of Clyde Tombaugh's ashes, commemorating his discovery of Pluto in 1930. Tombaugh would have loved seeing the colorful contrasts of this remarkable globe, far out into the dark of near-interstellar space. Pluto is now a sharply-seen world, with much to teach us. As the spacecraft zooms near an iceteroid on New Year's Day, 2019, it will show us the first member of the chilly realm beyond, where primordial objects quite different from the wildly eccentric Pluto also dwell. These will show us what sort of matter made up the early disk that clumped into planets like ours--a sort of family tree of worlds. But that's just an appetizer. New Horizons is important not just for completing our first-look at every major world in the solar system. It points outward, to a great theatre in the sky, where the worlds of the galaxy itself are on display. Beyond Pluto looms a zone where the Sun's mass acts as a giant lens, its gravitation focusing the light of other stars to a small area. Think of it as gravity gathering starlight into an intense pencil, focused down as dots on a chilly sphere. Einstein calculated such gravitational bending of light in 1912, though Newton knew the effect should occur in his own theory of mechanics and optics. Images of whole galaxies made by this effect were not discovered until 1988. Such magnification of light from a star and the planets near it naturally creates a telescope of unparalleled power. It can amplify images by factors that can vary from a hundred million to a quadrillion, depending on frequency. This suggests using such power to study worlds far across the interstellar reaches. We have already detected over two thousand planets around other stars, thanks to the Kepler mission and other telescopes. We can sense the atmospheres of some, when they pass across our view of their stars, silhouetted against that glare. Many more will come. Our space telescopes envisioned for the next several decades can only tease out information about a planet at interstellar distances by studying how light reflects or absorbs changes. At best, such worlds will be dots of faint light. But at the lensing distance, under enormously better resolution, we can see the worlds themselves--their atmospheres and moons, their seas and lands, perhaps even their cities. Hearty New Horizons now zooms along at about 15 kilometers a second, or more usefully said, at about three Astronomical Units (AU, the distance between Earth and our sun) in a year, relative to the sun. The focus spot of the sun is 550 AU out, as Einstein predicted in 1936. New Horizons will take 180 years to get to that focus and be long dead as its nuclear power supply fades. So future missions to put a telescope out there demands speeds ten or more times faster. (Voyager, flying after thirty-eight plus years, is only 108 AU away from earth.) We know of ways to propel spacecraft to such speeds. Most involve flying near the sun and picking up velocity by firing rockets near it, or getting a boost from its intense light using unfurled solar sails, and other astro-tricks. Those feats we can fashion within decades, if we wish. Our goal could be to put an observing spacecraft that can maneuver out at the focus of God's zoom lens--a 70 billion mile long telescope that light takes over three days to traverse. An observing spacecraft could see whatever is behind the sun from it, many light years away. This would vastly improve our survey of other worlds, to pick off strings of stars and examine their planets. Using the sun as a lens works on all wavelengths, so we could look for signs of life--say, oxygen in an atmosphere--and perhaps even eavesdrop on aliens' radio stations, squawking into the galactic night. A first, such a telescope could scrutinize Alpha Centauri's planets, if it has some, the next big step before trying to travel there. The craft could trace out a spiral pattern perpendicular to its outward path, slightly shifting its position relative to scan the Alpha Centauri system. Then look further still--because the focus effect remains beyond 550 AU, as a spacecraft moves outward, still seeing the immense magnifications. New Horizons maybe the best-named spacecraft of all, for it does indeed portend fresh, bold perspectives. 045. Robert Provine Research Professor/Professor Emeritus, University of Maryland, Baltimore County; Author, Curious Behavior: Yawning, Laughing, Hiccupping, and Beyond Space Exploration, New and Old --- Surprising images of dwarf planet Pluto from a flyby of the New Horizons spacecraft put space exploration back in the headlines as one of the biggest science stories of 2015. Instead of a barren, frigid globe, Plato proved to be colorful, contrasty, and complex, with diverse geological structure including mountains, valleys, and plains of water and nitrogen ice, evidence of past and present glacial flows, possible volcanoes spewing water ice from a warmer core, and a thin atmosphere that extends hundreds of miles above the planetary surface. Similar insights are being gleaned from Chiron and the smaller of Pluto's five moons. 2015 also brought Pluto news of a more arcane sort. The historic 24-inch Clark refractor telescope of Lowell Observatory was refurbished and opened to the public for viewing. Why mention Lowell and Earth-based optical astronomy? As a young Lowell employee, Clyde Tombaugh discovered Pluto in 1930 on photographic plates taken with a Lowell instrument. For many, telescopes, whether optical leviathans or the modest backyard variety, are spaceships for the eye and mind that provide a compelling sensory immediacy lacking in the pricier technological tour de force of a spacecraft. Recall the aesthetic impact of the starry night viewed from a dark country path or seeing Saturn for the first time through a telescope. Although modern Earth-based telescopes continue to provide astronomical breakthroughs, old telescopes and the observatories that house them survive as domed, verdigris-covered cathedrals of science. The Pluto flyby of 2015 is an occasion to celebrate space exploration new and old, and the value of looking upward and outward. 046. Paul J. Steinhardt Albert Einstein Professor in Science, Departments of Physics and Astrophysical Sciences, Princeton University; coauthor: Endless Universe The Big Bang Cannot Be What We Thought It Was --- A year and half ago, the scientific community and the press trumpeted the claim by a team of scientists that they had found definitive proof that the universe began with a Big Bang followed by a period of accelerated expansion, known as inflation. Their proof was that the light produced in the infant universe and collected by their detectors exhibited a distinctive pattern of polarization that could only be explained if the large scale structure of the universe was set when the temperature and density of the universe were extraordinarily high, just as posited in the Big Bang inflationary picture. Over the ensuing year, though, it became clear that the claim was a blunder: in searching for a cosmic signal from the distant universe, the team had not taken proper account of the polarization of light that occurred nearby when it passed through the dust in our Milky Way on the way to their detectors. The new claim from the team, published in recent months, is that there is no sign of the cosmic polarization they had been seeking despite an extensive search with extraordinarily sensitive detectors. The retraction received considerable attention but the full import of the news has not been appreciated: we now know that the Big Bang cannot be what we thought it was. The prevailing view has been that the Big Bang was a violent high-energy event during which space, time, matter and energy were suddenly created from nothing in a distorted, non-uniform distribution. To account for the undistorted nearly uniform universe we actually observe, many cosmologists hypothesize a period of rapid stretching (inflation) just after the bang when the concentration of energy and matter was still very high. If there were inflationary stretching only, the universe would become perfectly smooth, but there is always quantum physics in addition to stretching and quantum physics resists perfect smoothness. At the high concentrations of energy required for inflation, random quantum fluctuations keep generating bumps and wiggles in the shape of space and the distribution of matter and energy that should remain when inflation ends. The quantum-generated irregularities should appear today as hot spots and cold spots in the pattern of light emanating from the early universe, the so-called cosmic background radiation. Indeed, the hot and cold spots have been observed and mapped in numerous experiments since the COBE satellite detected the first spatial variations in the cosmic background radiation temperature in 1992. The problem is that, when the concentration of energy is high, the quantum-generated distortions in space should modify the way light scatters from matter in the early universe and imprint a spiraling pattern of polarization across the cosmos. It was the detection of this spiraling pattern (referred to as B-mode) that was claimed as proof of the Big Bang inflationary picture, and then retracted. The failure to detect the B-mode pattern means that there is something very wrong with the picture of a violent Big Bang followed by a period of high energy-driven inflation. Whatever processes set the large-scale structure of the universe had a to be a gentler, lower-energy process than has been supposed. Simply lowering the energy concentration at which inflation starts, as some theorists have suggested, only leads to more trouble. This leaves more time after the Big Bang for the non-uniform distribution of matter and energy to drive the universe away from inflation. Starting inflation after the Big Bang and having enough inflation to smooth the universe becomes exponentially less likely as the energy concentration is lowered. The universe is more likely to emerge as too rough, too curved, too inhomogeneous compared to what we observe. Something more radical is called for. Perhaps an improved understanding of quantum gravity will enable us to understand how the Big Bang and inflation can be discarded in favor of gentler beginning. Or perhaps the Big Bang was actually a gentle bounce from a previous period of contraction to the current period of expansion. During a period of slow contraction, it is possible to smooth the distribution of space, matter and energy and to create hot spots and cold spots without creating any B-modes at all. As the news sinks in, scientists will need to rethink depending on whether forthcoming, more sensitive efforts to detect a B-mode pattern find anything at all. Whatever is found, our view of the Big Bang will be changed, and that is newsworthy. 047. Robert Kurzban Psychologist, UPenn; Director, Penn Laboratory for Experimental Evolutionary Psychology (PLEEP); Author, Why Everyone (Else) is a Hypocrite The Ongoing Battles With Pathogens --- The end of the year saw two stories about pathogens, one hopeful and the other less so. The hopeful one is the advancing ability to insert genes that are desirable (from humans' point of view) into organisms and facilitating that gene's spread through the population. Consider the case of malaria, a focus of current efforts. Inserting a gene that inhibits the spread of malaria into a mosquito genome is helpful, but to only a limited degree: if the gene doesn't spread in wild populations, then its effects will be fleeting. If, however, mosquitoes are released that have the gene in question as well as genes that facilitate the spread of the gene, then the effects can be long-lasting. The less hopeful case is so-called super-gonorrhea, strains of the pathogen that are resistant to the antibiotics currently in use. As is well known, the use of antibiotics gives an advantage to strains of pathogens that are resistant. The tools we use to treat disease become the means by which we make the diseases harder to treat. Cases of super-gonorrhea have appeared in England, leading to a certain amount of concern. Malaria still infects tens of millions of people and causes hundreds of thousands of deaths. Of course global climate change and political strife are important issues, but pathogens still account for millions of lives lost around the world. Historically, as illustrated by the super-gonorrhea case, fighting pathogens has been something of an arms race: humans build better weapons, pathogens evolve counter-strategies. The present age is seeing a confluence of a number of advances that hold the promise of turning the arms race into something that might be more like a winnable war. First is progress in genetics, including techniques for inserting genes into genomes. Second is a sophisticated understanding of evolution and a fluorescence of ideas about how to harness it: in the past, evolution worked against us, as in the case of resistant strains of pathogens. We are becoming better at harnessing it. And third is a growing sophistication in thinking about systems. It is unlikely that the same sorts of mistakes will be made in the past, in which simplistic ecological interventions led to somewhat disastrous outcomes, as in the case of cane toads in Australia. Our view of ecosystems is more humble and more sophisticated than ever before. It seems likely that pathogens, of one sort or another, are likely to be important for a substantial period of time: this is because they are moving targets with tremendous capacity for harm. On the other hand, recent advances hold the promise of taming them in a way that we have not previously seen. 048. Aubrey de Grey Gerontologist; Chief Science Officer. SENS Foundation; Author, Ending Aging Antibiotics Are Dead; Long Live Antibiotics! --- We've been hearing the tales of doom for quite a few years now: the breathtaking promiscuity of bacteria, which allows them to mix and match their DNA with others' to an extent that puts Genghis Khan to shame, has increasingly allowed them to accumulate genetic resistance to more and more of our antibiotics. It's been trumpeted for decades that the rate at which this occurs can be slowed by careful use, especially by not ceasing a course of antibiotics early--but inevitably there is a lack of compliance, and here we are with MRSA, rife in hospitals worldwide, and other major species becoming more broadly antibiotic-resistant with every passing year. The bulk of high-profile expert commentary on this topic is becoming direr with ever passing year. But this pessimism rests entirely on one assumption: that we have no realistic prospect of developing new classes of antibiotics any time soon, antibiotics that our major threats have not yet seen and thus not acquired resistance to. And it now seems that that assumption is unwarranted. It is based on history--on the fact that no new antibiotic class with broad efficacy has been identified for decades. But very recently, a novel method was identified for isolating exactly those--and it seems to work really, really well. It arose from a case of sheer chutzpah. Scientists from Boston and Germany got together and reasoned as follows: 1. Antibiotics are generally synthesised in nature by bacteria (or other microbes) as defences against each other. 2. We have identified antibiotics in the lab, and thus necessarily only those made by bacterial species that we can grow in the lab. 3. Almost all bacterial species cannot be grown in the lab using practical methods. 4. That hasn't changed for decades. 5. But those bacteria grow fine in the environment, typically the soil. 6. So... can we isolate antibiotics from the soil? And that's exactly what they did. They built a device that allowed them to isolate and grow bacteria in the soil itself, with molecules freely moving into and out of the device, thereby sidestepping our ignorance of which such molecules actually matter. And then they were able to isolate the compounds that those bacteria were secreting and test them for antibiotic potency. And it worked. They found a completely new antibiotic that has already been shown to have very broad efficacy against several bacterial strains that are resistant to most existing antibiotics. And as if that were not enough, here's the kicker. This was not some kind of massive high-throughput screen of the kind we so often hear about in biomedical research these days. The researchers tried this approach just once, in essentially their back yard, on a very small scale, and it STILL worked the first time. What that tells us is that it can work again--and again, and again. Don't get me wrong--there is certainly no case for complacency at this stage. This new compound and those discovered by similar means will still need to grind their way through the usual process of clinical evaluation--though, it must be said, there is reason for considerable optimism that that process is dramatically speeding up, with the recent case of an Ebola vaccine being a case in point. But still, even though any optimism must for now be cautious, it is justified. Pandemics may not be our future after all. 049. Antony Garrett Lisi Theoretical physicist The News That Wasn't There --- On July 4, 2012, the European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN) announced the discovery of the Higgs boson. While this was big news in fundamental physics, it was not surprising. The existence of the Higgs boson, or something like it, was necessary for the consistency of the Standard Model of particle physics, established in the 1970s and now supported by an extraordinary amount of experimental data. Finding the Higgs was central to confirming the Standard Model. However, despite the well-deserved attention accorded to the discovery of the Higgs, this was not the biggest news. The biggest recent news in fundamental physics is what has NOT been discovered: superparticles. The theory of supersymmetry--that all existing particles are matched by superpartners having opposite spins--was introduced in the 1970s, soon after the Standard Model was established, and quickly became a darling of theoretical physicists. The theory helped solve a fine tuning problem in the Standard Model, with superparticles balancing the quantum contributions to existing particle masses and making the observed masses more natural. (Although, why particles have precisely the masses they do remains the largest open question in fundamental physics.) Also, for proponents of Grand Unified Theories (GUTs), the three strengths of the known Standard Model forces more perfectly converge to one value at high energies if superparticles exist. (Although a similar convergence can be achieved more simply by adding a handful of non-super bosons.) And, finally, supersymmetry (SUSY) became a cornerstone of, and necessary to, superstring theory--the dominant speculative theory of particle physics. One of the strongest motivations for constructing the Large Hadron Collider (LHC), along with finding the Higgs, was to find superparticles. In order for SUSY to help the Standard Model's naturalness problem, superparticles should exist at energies reachable by the LHC. During the collider's first run, the anticipation of superparticles at CERN was palpable--it felt as if a ballroom had been set up, complete with a banner: Welcome home SUSY! But superparticles have not shown up to the party. The fact that the expected superparticles have not been seen puts many theorists, including string theorists, in a scientifically uncomfortable position. Imagine that you had a very vivid dream last night that you saw a unicorn, probably in your backyard. The dream was so vivid that the next day you go into your backyard and look around, expecting to find your unicorn. But it's not there. That is the position string theorists and other SUSY proponents now find themselves in. You may claim, correctly, that even though you now know there is no unicorn in the backyard, the Bayesian expectation that the unicorn is actually hiding in the closet has increased! You are narrowing in on finding your unicorn! This is precisely the argument SUSY proponents are presenting now that the LHC has failed to find superparticles near the electroweak energy scale. Yes, it is correct that the probability the unicorn is in the closet, and that superparticles might be found during the current LHC run, has gone up. But do you know what has gone up more? The probability that the unicorn and superparticles do not exist at all. A unicorn would be a wonderful and magical animal, but maybe it, and SUSY, and superstrings, really just don't exist, and it's time to think about other animals. 050. Paul Bloom Brooks and Suzanne Ragen Professor of Psychology, Yale University; Author, Just Babies: The Origins of Good and Evil Science Itself --- The most exciting recent scientific news is about science itself: how it is funded, how scientists communicate with another, how findings get distributed to the public--and how it can go wrong. My own field of psychology has been Patient Zero here, with well-publicized cases of fraud, failures to replicate important studies, and a host of concerns, some of them well-founded, about how we do our experiments and analyze our results. There's a lot to complain about with regard to how this story has played out in the popular press and over social media. Psychology--and particularly social psychology--has been unfairly singled out. The situation is at least as bad in other fields, such as cancer research. More importantly, legitimate concerns have been exaggerated and used by partisans on both the left and the right to dismiss any findings that don't fit their interests and ideologies. But it's a significant story, and a lot of good can come from it. It's important for non-scientists to have some degree of scientific literacy, and this means more than a familiarity with certain theories and discoveries. It requires an appreciation of how science works, and how it stands apart from other human activities, most notably religion. A serious public discussion of what scientists are doing wrong and how they can do better will not only lead to better science, it will help advance scientific understanding more generally. 051. David G. Myers Professor of Psychology, Hope College; Author Intuition: Its Powers and Perils and Psychology, 11th Edition We Fear the Wrong Things --- If we knew that AK-47-wielding terrorists were destined to kill 1,000 people in the U.S. in 2016--a thinkable possibility--then we should be afraid ... albeit 1/10^th as afraid of other homicidal gun violence (which kills more than 10,000), and 1/30^th as fearful of riding in a motor vehicle, where more than 30,000 Americans die each year. Yet several recent surveys indicate we are much less fearful of the greater, everyday threats than of the dreaded horror. The hijacking of our rationality by fears of terrorist guns highlights an important and enduring piece of scientific news: we often fear the wrong things. Shortly after 9/11, when America was besieged by fear, I offered a calculation: If we now flew 20 percent less and instead drove half those unflown miles, then--given the greater safety of scheduled airline flights--we could expect about 800 more people to die on our roads. A German colleague, Gerd Gigerenzer, later checked that prediction. He reported that, actually, in the year after 9/11 an estimated 1,500 Americans died on the road in the attempt to avoid the fate of the [246] passengers who were killed in the four fatal flights. Long after 9/11, the terrorists were still killing us. Why? Why do we fear flying, when, for most of us, the most dangerous part of our trip is the drive to the airport? Why do terrorist fears so effectively inflate our stereotypes of Muslims, inflame us/them thinking, and make many of us Christians forget the ethics of Jesus (I was a stranger and you welcomed me)? Underlying our exaggerated fears is the availability heuristic: We fear what's readily available in memory. Vivid, cognitively available images--a horrific air crash, a mass slaughter--distort our judgments of risk. Thus, we remember--and fear--disasters (tornadoes, air crashes, attacks) that kill people dramatically, in bunches, while fearing too little the threats that claim lives one by one. We hardly notice the half-million children quietly dying each year from rotavirus, Bill Gates once observed--the equivalent of four 747s full of children every day. And we discount the future (and its future weapon of mass destruction, climate change). If only such deaths were more dramatic and immediate. Imagine (to adapt one mathematician's suggestion) that cigarettes were harmless--except, once in every 25,000 packs, for a single cigarette filled with dynamite. Not such a bad risk of having your head blown off. But with 250 million packs a day consumed worldwide, we could expect more than 10,000 gruesome daily deaths (the approximate actual toll of cigarette smoking)--surely enough to have cigarettes banned. News-fed, cognitively available images can make us excessively fearful of infinitesimal risks. And so we spend an estimated $500 million per U.S. terrorist death but only $10,000 per cancer death. As one risk expert explained, If it's in the news, don't worry about it. The very definition of news is 'something that hardly ever happens.' It's entirely normal to fear violence from those who despise us. But it's also smart to be mindful of the realities of how most people die, lest the terrorists successfully manipulate our politics. With death on their minds, people exhibit terror management. They respond to death reminders by derogating those who challenge their worldviews. Before the 2004 election, reported one research team, reminders of 9/11 shifted people's sympathies toward conservative politicians and antiterrorism policies. Media researcher George Gerbner's cautionary words to a 1981 congressional subcommittee ring true today: Fearful people are more dependent, more easily manipulated and controlled, more susceptible to deceptively simple, strong, tough measures and hard-line postures. Ergo, we too often fear the wrong things. And it matters. 052. John Naughton Vice-President, Wolfson College; Author, From Gutenberg to Zuckerberg A New Algorithm Makes Us Rethink What Computers Can--and Cannot--Do --- The most interesting news came late in 2015--on November 10, to be precise, when László Babai of the University of Chicago announced that he had come up with a new algorithm for solving the graph-isomorphism problem. This algorithm appears to be much more efficient than the previous best algorithm, which has ruled for over thirty years. Since graph isomorphism is one of the great unsolved problems in computer science, if Babai's claim stands up to the kind of intensive peer-review to which it will now be subjected then the implications are fascinating, not least because we may need to rethink our assumptions about what computers can and cannot do. The graph isomorphism problem seems deceptively simple: how to tell when two different graphs (which is what mathematicians call networks) are really the same in the sense that there's an isomorphism--a one-to-one correspondence between their nodes that preserves each node's connections--between them. Easy to state, but difficult to solve, since even small graphs can be made to look very different just by moving their nodes around. The standard way to check for isomorphism is to consider all possible ways to match up the nodes in one network with those in the other. That's tedious but feasible for very small graphs, but it rapidly gets out of hand as the number of nodes increases. To compare two graphs with just ten nodes, for example, you'd have to check over 3.6 million (i.e. 10 factorial) possible matchings. For graphs with 100 nodes you're probably looking at a number bigger than all the molecules in the universe. And in a Facebook age, networks with millions of nodes are commonplace. &gt; From the point of view of practical computing, factorials are really bad news because the running time of a factorial algorithm can quickly escalate into billions of years. So the only practical algorithms are those for problems whose solutions can be expressed as polynomials (e.g. n-squared or n-cubed, where n is the number of nodes) because running times for them increase much more slowly than those for factorial or exponential functions. The intriguing--tantalizing--thing about Babai's algorithm is that it is neither pure factorial nor polynomial but what he calls quasi-polynomial. It's not clear yet what this means, but the fuss in the mathematics and computer science community suggests that while the new algorithm might not be the Holy Grail, it is nevertheless significantly more efficient than what's gone before. If that turns out to be the case, what are the implications? Well, firstly, there may be some small but discrete benefits. Babai's breakthrough could conceivably help with other kinds of computationally difficult problems. For example, in genomics researchers have been trying for years to find an efficient algorithm for comparing the long strings of chemical letters within DNA molecules. This is a problem analogous to that of graph isomorphism and any advance in that area may have benefits for genetic research. But the most important implication of Babai's work may be inspirational--in reawakening mathematicians' interests in other kinds of hard problems that currently lie beyond the reach of even the most formidable computational resources. The classic example is the public-key encryption system on which the security of all online transactions depends. This works on asymmetry: it is relatively easy to take two huge prime numbers and multiply them together to produce an even larger number. But--provided the original primes are large enough--it is computationally difficult (in the sense that it would take an impracticable length of time) to factorize the product, i.e. determine the two original numbers from which it was calculated. If, however, an efficient factorizing algorithm were to be found, then our collective security would evaporate and we would need to go back to the drawing board. 053. Peter Turchin Evolutionary Scientist, University of Connecticut; Author, Ultrasociety: How 10,000 Years of War Made Humans the Greatest Cooperators on Earth. Fatty Foods Are Good For Your Health --- Amid all the confusing fluctuations in dietary fashion to which Americans have been exposed since the 1960s, one recommendation has remained unchallenged. Beginning in the 1960s and until 2015 the Americans have been getting consistent dietary advice: fat, especially saturated fat, is bad for your health. By the 1980s, the belief equating a low-fat diet with better health had become enshrined in the national dietary advice from the US Department of Agriculture and was endorsed by the surgeon general. Meanwhile, as Americans ate less fat, they steadily became more obese. Of course, the obesity epidemic probably has many causes, not all well understood. But it is becoming clear that the misguided dietary advice with which we have been bombarded over the past five decades, is an important contributing factor. In fact, there has never been any scientific evidence that cutting down total fat consumption has any positive effect on health; specifically, reduced risks of heart disease and diabetes. For years those who pointed this out were marginalized, but recently evidence debunking the supposed benefits of low-fat diets has reached a critical mass, so that a mainstream magazine such as Time could write in 2014: Scientists labeled fat the enemy. Why they were wrong. And now the official Scientific Report of the 2015 Dietary Guidelines Advisory Committee admits that much. There are several reasons why eating a low-fat diet is actually bad for your health. One is that if you lower the proportion of fat in your diet, you must replace it with something else. Eating more carbohydrates (whether refined or complex) increases your chances of becoming diabetic. Eating more proteins increases your chances of getting gout. But perhaps a more important reason is that many Americans stopped eating food, and switched to highly-processed food substitutes: margarine, processed meats (such as the original Spam--not to be confused with email spam), low-fat cookies, and so on. In each case, we now have abundant evidence that these are anti-health foods, because they contain artificial trans fats, preservatives, or highly-processed carbohydrates. While controlled diet studies are important and necessary for making informed decisions about our diets, an exciting recent scientific breakthrough has resulted from the infusion of evolutionary science into nutrition science. After all, you need first to figure out what hypotheses you want to test with controlled trials, and evolution turned out to be a fertile generator of theoretical ideas for such tests. One of the sources of ideas to test clinically is the growing knowledge of the characteristic diets of early human beings. Consider this simple idea (although it clearly was too much for traditional nutritionists): we will be better adapted to something eaten by our ancestors over millions of years than to, say, margarine, which we first encountered only 100 years ago. Or take a food like wheat, to which some populations (those in the Fertile Crescent) have been exposed for 10,000 years, and others (Pacific Islanders) for only 200 years. Is it surprising that Pacific Islanders have the greatest prevalence of obesity in the world (higher even than in the United States)? And should we really tell them to switch to a Mediterranean diet, heavy on grains, pulses, and dairy, to which they've had no evolutionary exposure whatsoever? Our knowledge of ancestral diets, of course, is itself evolving very rapidly. But it seems clear that we are adapted to eating a variety of fatty foods, including grass-fed ruminants (beef and lamb) and seafood (oily fish), both good sources of Omega-3 fatty acids. Of particular importance could be bone marrow--it is quite likely that first members of the genus Homo (e.g., habilis) were not hunters, but scavengers who competed with hyenas for large marrow bones. It's very probable that nutrients from bone marrow (and brains!) of scavenged savannah ungulates were the key resource for the evolution of our own oversized brains. In light of the new knowledge it is clear why Americans are getting fatter by eating low-fat diets. When you eliminate fatty foods that your body and--especially--brain need, your body will start sending you persistent signals that you are malnourished. So you will overeat on foods other than fatty ones. The extra, unnecessary calories that you consume (probably from carbohydrates) will be stored as fat. As a result, you will be unhappy, unhealthy, and overweight. You can avoid those extra pounds, of course, if you have a steely will (which few people have)--then you will not be overweight, merely unhappy and unhealthy. So to lose fat you need to eat--not fat--but fatty foods. Paradoxically, eating enough fatty food of the right sorts will help to make you lean, as well as happy and--Edge readers, take note--smart! 054. Andrian Kreye Editor, The Feuilleton (Arts and Essays), of the German Daily Newspaper, Sueddeutsche Zeitung, Munich We Are Not Unique In The Universe, But We Are Very Much Alone --- It has been increasingly exciting to follow the recent surge in the discovery of exoplanets. Not only because what started as a needle in the haystack endeavor in the late 1980s has become a booming field of space exploration, when it gained its latest momentum with the success of Nasa's Kepler Telescope. As of this moment of writing, the exoplanet data explorer maintained by Jason Wright at Penn State lists 1,642 confirmed planets and 3,787 unconfirmed Kepler candidates. There are severe downsides to most of those planets. Only 63 light years away for example a blue marble planet named HD 189733b orbits its star. Daytime temperatures on this planet average 1,700 degrees Fahrenheit, wind speeds reach 7,000 miles per hour and the blue color in the atmosphere comes from rains of molten glass. Only four of the exoplanets found by now have the right distance to their stars to host life. Given the UC Berkeley estimate of 11 billion earth-like planets in the milky way alone, there is a definite conclusion though that our home planet is far from unique in the universe, even though we as humans are very much alone. Most conclusions drawn from the discovery of exoplanets aren't quite as philosophical. Great findings about the history of the universe and the origins of life are made. There's even a practical side to it. Given that the search for exoplanets has enabled science to peer farther into the universe as ever before, short-distance space missions have been reduced to outer space prancings of status seeking enterprises and emerging nations trying to prove they are the new superpowers. While the glamour of physical space exploration still lives on in the dreams of billionaires and potentates, even pop culture ideas of settling space are gaining traction again. With the apocalyptic specter of climate change rendering this planet inhabitable colonizing other planets seem like an attractive idea. Blockbusters like Interstellar and The Martian have used this longing for a life beyond our atmosphere for great entertainment. But even when Harvard astronomer Dimitar Sasselov toured the conference circuit a few years ago talking about the thrill of discovering far away planets (his team had actually once found the furthest planet of them all), you could sense the pangs of science fiction longings in the audience. What if there indeed is life out there? Other habitable planets? They still lingered, no matter the thoroughly scientific nature of the research of exoplanets. After all, Sasselov also serves as the director of Harvard's origins of life initiative. But it is exactly those lingering science fiction dreams, which make the news about the vast number of exoplanets of important. As symbols they can serve as an extension of the Blue Marble image of planet earth taken by the Apollo 17 crew in December of 1972. Back then the Blue Marble showed mankind the reality of what Buckminster Fuller had called spaceship earth just four years before--earth being a rather small vehicle with finite resources. The Blue Marble went on to the cover of Stewart Brand's Whole Earth Catalog, the principle manual of the emerging ecological movement. Even though the recent wave of anachronistic space age glamour overshadows the great news about exoplanets, they are great symbols of a shift in global consciousness. With all escape routes now officially closing (planet HD 189733b being just one sensational example of the forbidding nature of space), the realization that mankind has to make the best out of its home planet starts to become common knowledge not only in progressive circles. Climate talks in Paris have shown that the political will to take action finally transcends borders, ideologies and national interests. The symbolism of exoplanets goes beyond the Buckminster Fuller metaphor of spaceship earth. It shows that the drive of science knows no limits. When astronomers will confirm the first extragalactic planets, the reach for infinity will open even wider realms of understanding the universe. This understanding coupled with a new consciousness about the value and fragility of planet earth can lead to a will to push for solutions right here on earth. Science will continue to reach ever farther into infinity for ever great findings. Here on earth this will just strengthen the realization that the dream of habitable planets or even communicating life forms in our reach is as absurd as the ideas of afterlives and deities. 055. W. Tecumseh Fitch Department of Cognitive Biology, University of Vienna; Author, The Evolution of Language Paleo-DNA and De-Extinction --- When prehistoric humans arrived in America they found a continent populated by mammoths, wooly rhinos, giant sloths, sabertooths, horses, and camels. By the time Columbus arrived, all of these species were extinct, due mainly to human hunting. But today, paleobiologists are sequencing the genomes of these extinct species. Furthermore, genetic engineering is approaching the point where genetically engineered versions of these extinct species may walk the Earth again. This year's big news--cloning of a dead pet dog--is thus merely a small beginning. In the near future, the news will concern what paleo-DNA specialist Beth Shapiro dubs de-extinction: generating living organisms bearing genes recovered from extinct species. Paleo-DNA (the somewhat degraded DNA recovered from bones or hair of extinct species) can be extracted from recently extinct species like mammoths and those exterminated by humans during historical times including passenger pigeons, dodos or thylacines (Jurassic Park fans note: the truly ancient DNA from dinosaurs is too degraded to currently allow sequencing). Trace amounts of DNA can be recovered, amplified and sequenced. Key genes could then be engineered into cells of the closest living relatives (Asian elephants for mammoths) to produce shaggy, cold tolerant elephants. This is nearly within technological reach today. Although birds pose unique challenges (being unclonable with current technologies), the de-extinction of passenger pigeons or moas (3.5 m tall flightless birds exterminated by hunting when the Maori arrived in New Zealand) appears within our technical grasp, and major de-extinction projects for these species are already underway. So should we do it? Shapiro's recent book How to Clone a Mammoth provides an excellent introduction to the arguments. Given the polarized opinions generated by reintroducing wolves to Yellowstone, one can easily imagine diversity of public reactions to reintroducing sabertooth tigers or giant cave bears. I think that the best pro arguments are ecological--by reviving lost species we can restore habitats damaged or destroyed as our species spread over the planet. Mammoth-like elephants stomping through the tundra of Siberia's Paleozoic Park would benefit the environment by slowing the process of permafrost melting and the attendant carbon release. &gt; From a purely scientific, curiosity-driven viewpoint, de-extinction will offer biological and ecological insights available in no other way. Economically, tourists would pay top dollar to watch moas wandering the beech forests of New Zealand, or mammoths roaming Siberia. The con arguments are mostly practical (why spend money reviving extinct species rather than saving living endangered species?) or techno-fearful (humans shouldn't play god), but nonetheless passionately advocated. By far the most significant issues will concern extinct hominids like Neanderthals, and society needs to prepare for the challenging ethical questions raised by such research. In 1997 researchers at Svante Pääbo's paleo-DNA lab in Leipzig made the news by sequencing mitochondrial DNA from Neanderthals. Today, after breathtaking technological progress, a full Neanderthal genome is available online. Even more exciting, in 2010 Pääbo's group discovered Denisovans, a previously-unknown Asian hominid species, based on DNA extracted from a tiny finger bone. The discovery of Denisovans from paleo-DNA makes it crystal clear that when modern humans emerged from Africa, they encountered a world inhabited by multiple near-human species--all of them now extinct. Recovering the genome sequence of an extinct hominid species is exciting because it provides answers to a host of biological questions concerning which stones and bones (the previous mainstay of paleoanthropology) will remain forever mute. For example, it seems likely based on pigmentation genes that Neanderthals had light skin and some had red hair. Paleo-DNA has clarified that some interbreeding probably occurred when the first modern humans migrated out of Africa and encountered Neanderthals. As a result, all non-African human populations bear traces of Neanderthal DNA in their genomes (and many Asians bear additional Denisovan DNA). Similarly, the issue of whether Neanderthals had spoken language has divided scholars for decades. Although the case remains far from closed, we now know that Neanderthals shared the derived human version of the FOXP2 gene which enhances our speech motor control. This suggests that Neanderthals were able at least to produce complex vocalizations, even if they lacked modern, syntactic language. Such findings have fueled an ongoing sea-change in contemporary interpretations of Neanderthals--from oafish thugs to smart, resourceful near-humans. Paleo-DNA sequencing has changed not only our understanding of Neanderthals, but of ourselves. Neanderthals were not modern humans: they lacked the rapid cultural progress characterizing our species, and thus presumably some of our cognitive capacities. But what precisely were these differences? Do these differences make us, the survivors, human? Or were Neanderthals human, but differently abled? Certainly, with the bodies of Olympic wrestlers and brains slightly larger than modern humans, they'd be first picks for your rugby scrum; perhaps they had unique cognitive abilities as well. Progress will be rapid in addressing these issues, because each new insight into the genetic basis of the human brain yields parallel insights into our understanding of Neanderthal brains--and of the cognitive differences between the two. But the truly deep ethical issues concern the possible de-extinction of Neanderthals or other extinct hominids. From a scientific viewpoint this would promise insights into hominid evolution and human nature unimaginable a decade ago. But from a legal viewpoint it would involve creating humans expressing Neanderthal genes, and thus require human cloning already forbidden in many countries. But few doubt that, within this century, genetic engineering of our own species will be both technologically possible and ethically acceptable in at least some sub-cultures. Clearly, a human expressing Neanderthal genes (as many of us already do!) would retain all basic human rights, but the moral and ethical implications raised by Neanderthals in the workplace (or on college football teams) might easily eclipse those raised by racism or slavery. Clearly paleo-DNA will remain in the news for the foreseeable future, offering scientific insights and posing unprecedented ethical quandaries. It will thus behoove all thinking people (especially politicians drafting legislation) to become acquainted with the technology and the biological facts before forming an opinion. 056. John Tooby Founder of field of Evolutionary Psychology; Co-director, Center for Evolutionary Psychology, Professor of Anthropology, UC Santa Barbara The Race Between Genetic Meltdown and Germline Engineering --- The most remarkable breaking news in science is that I exist. Well, not just me. People like me who, without technology, would have died early. Of the roughly 5 ½ billion people who survived past puberty, perhaps only one billion would be here were it not for modern sanitation, medicine, technology, and market-driven abundance. Ancestrally, the overwhelming majority of humans died before they had a full complement of children, often not making it past childhood. For those who live in developed nations, our remodeled lifetables are among the greatest of the humane triumphs of the Enlightenment--delivering parents from the grief of holding most of their children dead in their arms, or of children losing their parents (and then themselves dying from want). But there is hidden and unwelcome news at the core of this triumph. This arises out of the brutal way natural selection links childbearing to the elimination of genetic disease. The first thing to recall is that even our barest functioning depends on amazingly advanced organic technology at all scales--technology engineered by selection. For example, our eyes--macroscopic objects--have two million moving parts, and yet individual rods are so finely crafted they can respond to single photons. Successful parents in every species live near spiring summits on adaptive landscapes. The second thing to remember is that physics is perpetually hurling us off these summits, assaulting the organization that is necessary to our existence. Entropy not only ages and kills us as individuals, but also successfully attacks each parent's germ line. Indeed, the real news is that a number of methods have converged on the estimate that every human child contains roughly 100 new mutations--genetic changes that were not present in their parents. To be sure, many of these occur in inert regions, or are otherwise silent and so do no harm. But a few are very harmful individually; and although the remainder are individually small in effect, collectively they plague each individual with debilitating infirmities. These recent estimates are striking when one considers how, in an entropy-filled world, we maintained our high levels of biological organization. Natural selection is the only physical process that pushes species' designs uphill against entropy toward greater order (positive selection), or maintains our favorable genes against the downward pull exerted by mutation pressure (purifying selection). If a species is not to melt down under the hard rain of accumulating mutations, the rate at which harmful mutations are introduced must equal the rate at which selection removes them (mutation-selection balance). This removal is self-executing: Harmful genes cause impairments to the healthy design of the individuals they are situated in. These impairments (by definition) are characteristics that reduce the probability that the carrier will reproduce, and thereby reduce the number of harmful genes passed on. For a balance to exist between mutation and selection, a critical number of offspring must die before reproduction--die because they carry an excess load of mutations. Over the long run, successful parents average a little more than two offspring that survive into parenthood. (The species would go extinct or fill the planet if the average were smaller or greater.) This is as true for humans with our handful of children as it is for an ocean sunfish with a nest full of 300 million. To understand how endlessly cruel the anti-entropic process of selection is, consider a sunfish mother with one nest. On average 299,999,997 of her progeny die, and 2 or 3 become comparable parents. Since the genotypes of offspring are generated randomly, the number of coin flips (in 300 million series) guarantees a lower end of the bionomial distribution of mutations that are many standard deviations out. That is, there are two or three who become parents because they received a set of genes that are improbably free of negative mutations. These parents therefore restart the lineage's next generation having shed enough of the mutational load to have rolled back mutational entropy to the parental level. Ancestral humans, with far smaller offspring sets, maintained our functional organization more precariously, having survived over evolutionary time on the edge of a far smaller selective gradient between those children with somewhat smaller sets of impairments and those with somewhat larger sets. Most ancestral humans were fated by physics to be childless vessels whose deaths served to carry harmful mutations out of the species. Now, along comes the demographic transition--the recent shift to lower death rates and then lower birth rates. Malthusian catastrophe was averted, but the price of relaxing selection has been moving the mutation-selection balance toward an unsustainable increase in genetic diseases. Various naturalistic experiments suggest this meltdown can proceed rapidly. (Salmon raised in captivity for only a few generations were strongly outcompeted by wild salmon subject to selection.) Indeed, it is possible that the drop in death rates over the demographic transition caused--by increasing the genetic load--the subsequent drop in birth rates below replacement: If humans are equipped with physiological assessment systems to detect when they are in good enough condition to conceive and raise a child, and if each successive generation bears a greater number of micro-impairments that aggregate into, say, stressed exhaustion, then the paradoxical outcome of improving public health for several generations would be ever lower birth rates. One or two children are far too few to shed incoming mutations. No one could regret the victory over infectious disease and starvation now spreading across the planet. But we as a species need an intensified research program into germline engineering, so that the Enlightenment science that allowed us to conquer infectious disease will allow us to conquer genetic disease (through genetic repair in the zygote, morula, or blastocyst). With genetic counseling, we have already focused on the small set of catastrophic genes, but we need to sharpen our focus on the extremely high number of subtle, minor impairments that statistically aggregate into major problems. I am not talking about the ethical complexities of engineering new human genes. Imagine instead that at every locus, the infant received healthy genes from her parents. These would not be genetic experiments with unknown outcomes: Healthy genes are healthy precisely because they interacted well with each other over evolutionary time. Parents could choose to have children created from their healthiest genes, rather than leaving children to be shotgunned with a random and increasing fraction of damaged genes. Genetic repair would replace the ancient cruelty of natural selection, which only fights entropy by tormenting organisms because of their genes. 057. Timothy Taylor Professor of the Prehistory of Humanity, University of Vienna; Author, The Artificial Ape Weapons Technology Powered Human Evolution --- Thomas Hobbes's uncomfortable view of human nature looks remarkably prescient in the light of new discoveries in Kenya. Back in the mid 17th century--before anyone had any inkling of deep time or the destabilization of essential identity that would be brought about by an understanding of the facts of human evolution (i.e. before the idea was possible that nature was mutable)--Hobbes argued that we were fundamentally beastly (selfish, greedy, cruel) and, in the absence of certain historically-developed and carefully nurtured institutional structures, would regress to live in a state of nature, in turn understood as a state of perpetual war. We can assume that John Frere would have agreed with Hobbes. Frere, we may read (and here Wikipedia is orthodox, typical and, in a critical sense, wrong), was an English antiquary and a pioneering discoverer of Old Stone Age or Lower Paleolithic tools in association with large extinct animals at Hoxne, Suffolk in 1797. In fact, while Frere did indeed make the first well-justified claim for a deep-time dimension to what he carefully recorded in situ, saying that the worked flints he found dated to a very remote period indeed, he did not think they were tools in any neutral sense, stating that the objects were evidently weapons of war, fabricated and used by a people who had not the use of metals. Frere's sharp-edged weapons can now be dated to Oxygen Isotope Stage 11--in other words, to a period lying between 427 and 364 thousand years ago--and even he might have been surprised to learn that the people responsible were not modern humans, but a species, Homo erectus, whose transitional anatomy would first come to light through fossil discoveries in Java a century later. Subsequent archaeological and palaeoanthropological work (significant aspects of it pioneered by Frere's direct descendant, Mary Leakey) has pushed the story of genus Homo back ever further, revealing as many as a dozen distinct species (the number varies with the criteria used). Alongside the biological changes runs a history, or prehistory, of technology. It has usually been supposed that this technology, surviving mainly as modified stone artifacts, was a product of the higher brain power that our human ancestors displayed. According to Darwin's sexual selection hypothesis, female hominins favored innovative male hunters, and the incremental growth in intelligence led, ultimately, to material innovation (hence the evocative but not taxonomic term, Homo faber--Man the Maker). So powerful was this idea that, although chipped stone artifacts dating to around 2.6 million years ago have been known for some time, there was a strong presumption that genus Homo had to be involved. This is despite the fact that the earliest fossils with brains big enough to be classified in this genus dated at least half a million years later. It was a fairly general hunch within palaeoanthropology that the genus Homo populations responsible for early chipped-stone technologies had simply not yet been discovered. Those few of us who, grounded in the related field of theoretical archaeology, thought differently, remained reliant on a very broad kind of consilience to counter this ex silencio assumption. So to me it was wonderful news when, in May 2015, Sonia Harmand and co-workers published an article in Nature entitled 3.3-million-year-old stone tools from Lomekwi 3, West Turkana, Kenya, because the strata at their site date to a period when no one seriously doubts that australopithecines, with their chimp-sized brains, were the smartest of the savannah-dwelling hominins. The discovery shows unambiguously that technology preceded, by more than one million years, the expansion of the cranium that is traditionally associated with the emergence of genus Homo. Harmand et al follow current convention in naming their artifacts tools, rather than offensive weapons. This apparently more neutral terminology is, I think, a reflex of our continual and pervasive denial of Hobbes's truth. Hobbes obviously did not have the information available to understand the time-depths or the bio-taxonomic and evolutionary issues involved, but had he known about Lomekwi 3 he would probably have called it differently, as Frere subsequently did at Hoxne. The pre-human emergence of weapons technology makes functional and evolutionary sense. We are not talking about choosing appropriate twigs for the efficient extraction of termites, or the leaves best suited to carrying water, but about the painstaking modification of fine-grained igneous rocks into sharp-edged or bladed forms whose principal job was to part flesh from flesh and bone from bone. If the word hunting helps gloss the reality of what such sharp stone artifacts were used for, then we can reflect on the type of hunting recently documented from the Aurora stratum at the site of Gran Dolina (Atapuerca), Spain. Here, Palmira Saladie Balleste and co-workers recently reported (Journal of Human Evolution, 2012) on a group of Homo antecessor (or, arguably, erectus) who fed on individuals from, presumably, a rival group. The age profile of the victims was similar to the age profiles seen in cannibalism associated with intergroup aggression in chimpanzees, that is, those eaten were infants and immature individuals. That much of the data on early, systematic, endemic violence in our deeper (and shallower) prehistory comes as a surprise is due to the pervasive myth about the small-scale band societies of the archaeological past having somehow been egalitarian. This idea has an odd genealogy that probably goes back to the utopian dreaming of Hobbes's would-be intellectual nemesis, Jean-Jacques Rousseau, with his ideas of harmony and purity in nature, and his belief that the savage state of humanity was noble rather than decadent. Rousseau, like Hobbes, lacked the possibility of an evolutionary perspective, and also dealt in more or less essentialist assertions. But once we have to bridge from wild primate groups to early human ancestors, the tricky question of the roots of egality arises. If the chimpanzees and gorillas that can be studied in the wild have clear status hierarchies that are established, maintained and altered by force, including orchestrated murder and cannibalism, then how could fair play magically become a base-line behavior? Somewhere along the way, it seems to have been forgotten that the 19^th century founders of modern socio-cultural anthropology, Lewis Henry Morgan, Edward Burnett Tylor, and Edvard Westermarck, recorded all kinds of unfairness in indigenous North American and Pacific societies: we may not want the Tlingit and Haida, Ojibwa and Shawnee to have had slaves, for instance, but avoiding mentioning it in modern textbooks does a great disservice to the original ethnographic accounts (and the slaves). Returning to the news from Lomekwi 3, we can now see that technology was not just a figural but a literal arms race. Reanalyzing the take-off in cranial capacity that began around 2 million years ago, we can see that blades and choppers needed to be already available to replace the missing biology--the massive ripping canines and heavy jaw muscles that previously hampered, in direct bio-mechanical terms, the expansion of the braincase. As Frere would immediately have understood, these artifacts included weapons, perhaps predominantly and pre-eminently. Only by postulating high-level competition between groups can we understand the dramatic adaptive radiation of hominin types and the fact that, ultimately, only one hominin species survived. The paradox is that, by sharpening the first knives to extend the range of possible forms of aggression, we opened up a much broader horizon, in which technology could be used for undreamed-of purposes. Yet Hobbes's instinct that our nature was borne of war, and Frere's conclusion that the world's primal technology was offensive, should not be ignored. In the artificial lulls when atavism is forced into abeyance we are happy to forget Hobbes's admonition that it is only through the careful cultivation of institutions that stable peace is at least possible. 058. A. C. Grayling Master of the New College of the Humanities, London, and Professor of Philosophy at Birkbeck College, University of London, and a Supernumerary Fellow of St Anne's College, Oxford; Author, The God The Decline Of Cancer --- In a great year for science it is hard to restrict applause to just one area, but a worthy one is cancer research, which has seen a number of advances. Genetic manipulation has rapidly reversed colorectal cancer in mice, a Dutch team has developed a highly accurate blood test for cancer, a general cure for cancer is promised by the discovery that attaching malaria proteins to cancerous cells destroys them, the Mayo Clinic has found a way of short-circuiting cancer cell growth by using a certain junction protein (PLEKHA7), early diagnosis of pancreatic cancer looks more possible following the identification of a protein on particles released by cancer cells in the pancreas, low-toxicity nano-pills for treatment of breast cancer look to be on the way, and the FDA has approved Palbociclid for breast cancer treatment. There may have been other announcements in the oncology field this year, but the cumulative effect of these developments would appear to support the claim made by a leading oncologist that within a generation no one under the age of eighty will die of cancer. 059. Helen Fisher Biological Anthropologist, Rutgers University; Author, Why Him? Why Her? How to Find and Keep Lasting Love The Mother Of All Addictions --- Falling in love activates the same basic brain system for wanting (the Reward System--specifically the mesolimbic dopamine pathway), as do all drugs of abuse, including addiction to heroin, cocaine, alcohol, and nicotine. Because this central neural network becomes active when addicted to any drug of abuse, I have long wondered whether feelings of romantic love can smother a drug craving; whether a drug craving can smother feelings of romantic love instead; or whether these two very different cravings might even work together--sensitizing this brain network to make the drug addict more receptive to romantic love and/or make the lover more prone to other forms of addiction. In short: how does this central brain system accommodate two different cravings at once? All of these questions are still largely unanswered. But in 2012 a new article has made some inroads into this conundrum. In this study, Xiaomeng Xu and her colleagues put eighteen Chinese nicotine-deprived smokers who had also just fallen madly in love into a brain scanner, using functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI). As these men and women looked at a photo of a hand holding a cigarette and also at a photo of their newly beloved, the researchers collected data on their brain activity. Results? Among those who were moderately addicted to nicotine, the craving for the beloved reduced activity in brain regions associated with the craving for a cigarette. But there is some added value here. The article also suggests that engaging in any kind of novel activity (unrelated to romance) may also alleviate nicotine craving--by hijacking this same dopaminergic reward system. This single correlation could be of tremendous value to those trying to quit smoking. And I shall go out on a limb to propose a wider meaning to these data. Although there is only this very limited evidence for my hypothesis, this study suggests to me that there may be a hierarchy to the addictions. In this case, one's addiction to a newly beloved may, in some cases, suppress one's addiction to nicotine. Romantic love may be the mother of all addictions--indeed a positive addiction that enables one to overcome other cravings to win life's greatest prize: a mating partner. 060. Alex (Sandy) Pentland Professor of Computer Science, MIT; Director, Human Dynamics Lab and the Media Lab Entrepreneurship Program; Author, Social Physics A World That Counts --- In 2014 a group of big data scientists (including myself), representatives of big data companies, and the heads of National Statistical Offices from nations in both the northern and southern hemispheres, met within the United Nations headquarters and plotted a revolution. We proposed that all of the nations of the world begin to measure poverty, inequality, injustice, and sustainability in a scientific, transparent, accountable, and comparable manner. Surprisingly, this proposal was approved by the UN General Assembly in 2015, as part of the 2030 Sustainable Development Goals. This apparently innocuous agreement is informally known as the Data Revolution within the UN, because for the first time there is an international commitment to discover and tell the truth about the state of the human family as a whole. Since the beginning of time, most people have been isolated, invisible to government and without information about or input to government health, justice, education, or development policies. But in the last decade this has changed. As our UN Data Revolution report, titled A World That Counts, states: Data are the lifeblood of decision-making and the raw material for accountability. Without high-quality data providing the right information on the right things at the right time, designing, monitoring and evaluating effective policies becomes almost impossible. New technologies are leading to an exponential increase in the volume and types of data available, creating unprecedented possibilities for informing and transforming society and protecting the environment. Governments, companies, researchers and citizen groups are in a ferment of experimentation, innovation and adaptation to the new world of data, a world in which data are bigger, faster and more detailed than ever before. This is the data revolution. More concretely, the vast majority of humanity now has a two-way digital connection that can send voice, text, and most recently, images and digital sensor data because cell phone networks have spread nearly everywhere. Information is suddenly something that is potentially available to everyone. The Data Revolution combines this enormous new stream of data about human life and behavior with traditional data sources, enabling a new science of social physics that can let us detect and monitor changes in the human condition, and to provide precise, non-traditional interventions to aid human development. Why would anyone believe that anything will actually come from a UN General Assembly promise that the National Statistical Offices of the member nations will measure human development openly, uniformly, and scientifically? It is not because anyone hopes that the UN will manage or fund the measurement process. Instead we believe that uniform, scientific measurement of human development will happen because international development donors are finally demanding scientifically sound data to guide aid dollars and trade relationships. Moreover, once reliable data about development start becoming familiar to business people, we can expect that supply chains and private investment will begin paying attention. A nation with poor measures of justice or inequality normally also has higher levels of corruption, and a nation with a poor record in poverty or sustainability normally also has a poor record of economic stability. As a consequence, nations with low measures of development are less attractive to business than nations with similar costs but better human development numbers. Historically we have always been blind to the living conditions of the rest of humanity; violence or disease could spread to pandemic proportions before the news would make it to the ears of central authorities. We are now beginning to be able to see the condition of all of humanity with unprecedented clarity. Never again should it be possible to say we didn't know. No one should be invisible. This is the world we want--a world that counts.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/8022d7d8-8b75-3f0b-a7e7-457267f4e35f" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-17T23:05:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:23:40.697Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://stirling-westrup-tt.blogspot.com/2016/01/tt-edge-2016-041-060-most-important.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
