<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Okay Oculus fans. At the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) this week, the VR headset is being showcased to the public. I use the term public loosely since CES tends to be gear more towards retailers, industry experts, and those lucky enough to get a pass into the show. I wish I were one of those people... But! The Oculus Rift is making a big showing on it's nifty features, and they are already taking pre-orders with an expected shipping date of June this year. Some outlets are stating that those who were in the crowdfunding phase will receive theirs as early as March 28th. If you want to pre-order, here's the link. The system costs $599 and will include the VR headset, sensor, remote, cables, and XBox One controller, and two games: Eve: Valkyrie and Lucky's Tale. If you are lucky enough to be at CES this week you can test out one of the systems and experience the cool insanity that is VR. Oculus has also announced a general pricing system for games released with the system. The Premium games like Eve will be in the $60 range. So really, it's not any more expensive then a current gen console (PS4, XBoxOne) game. Staff for Oculus on the floor at CES have noted that there will be different levels of games that won't be as flashy as Eve, therefore they will be available at lower price points. These can range from free to anything below $60. Needless to say, simply doing a port of Call of Duty to Oculus isn't going to net it another $60. It might be half that price (as the game was not developed for VR). We're getting our hands on Oculus Rift much sooner then expected! And the gameplay looks pretty clean for VR. Get ready to have that Dramamine on standby. I anticipate a lot of motion sickness for gamers.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/79780c01-3ac4-385d-af6c-4acb67478f12" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-07T17:49:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:21:09.353Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://the-geek-spot.blogspot.com/2016/01/oculus-rift-release-date-and-gaming.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
