<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Weekly Newsletter Extra for New Products / Design Developments Today's Circulation: 19,152 « Prev | By Date | Next » Issue 904 - 14 January 2016 Socomec - With its New Testing Laboratory, the 'Tesla Power Lab'... Featured Video Socomec has just opened its new, extended testing laboratory. Named 'Tesla Power Lab', this technological platform of nearly 2000m² has the resources to carry out the most comprehensive tests, certifying the quality of products designed and manufactured by the company, including electrical, mechanical, climatic and functional tests. The Tesla Power Lab is also certified by international bodies (DEKRA and UL) to perform the... Click to Watch Danfoss - Great Success for Danfoss Drives at SPS IPC Drives Fair Featured Video Europe’s leading exhibition for electric automation - the SPS IPC Drives fair - took place for the 26th time from 24-26 November in Nuremberg, Germany. 14 halls were packed full with 1,666 exhibitors from different countries around the world. The exhibition welcomed 64,386 visitors eager to hear about the latest products, trends and innovations in the industry. The exhibition was a very important milestone for Danfoss Drives... Click to Watch Wieland Electric - It’s a Classic - Wieland’s Gesis RST CLASSIC Socket Wieland has added the gesis® RST® CLASSIC socket to its gesis® RST CLASSIC Series, for use with 2- to 5-pole female RST® connectors. This means that the gesis® RST® concept can be used throughout an installation by means of the CLASSIC socket, from the power source up to the final device. The mechanical lock of the RST® CLASSIC ensures the safe connection of plug and socket, which can be unlocked with a screwdriver... Read More Schneider Electric Launches Com’X 510 – All Inclusive Energy Management... Schneider Electric, the global specialist in energy management, has announced the launch of its new energy management software, Energy Server Com’X 510. The simple energy management solution collects and stores energy data from electrical distribution devices, smart panels, environmental sensors such as temperature, humidity, CO2 levels in the building and wages metering devices. The easy to navigate software analyses real-time... Read More Mitsubishi Electric - Innovative New Heat Pump Matches New-Build Hot Water... Mitsubishi Electric has launched a new 4kW Ecodan air source heat pump designed specifically to tackle the needs of new-build homes, with a system that matches the hot water requirements, whilst still meeting the lower heating demand of today’s well insulated properties. New homes built today differ from previous ones because the requirement for hot water is likely to exceed the demand for heating for the first time. A reduction in... Read More Airedale International Launches Middle East Awards Programme for Business... In the course of ‘UAE Innovation Week’ (22-28 November 2015), British cooling systems manufacturer, Airedale International, launched a programme of annual awards for its business partners in the GCC (Gulf Cooperation Council) and Middle East territories. The purpose of the awards was to recognise and celebrate expertise and innovation in the application of energy-saving, resilient cooling technologies throughout the region. The 2015... Read More
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/27041755-fa14-3070-80e3-41362dc6087b" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-16T12:18:06Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:50:00.796Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.buildingdesign-news.co.uk/Online-Extra16/140116/Index.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
