<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2014 (64) - BMW 1 Series 5-Door £19,226 Reduced by £1,129 was £20,355 Loading Images... Date Registered: Sep 2014 Mileage: 10,429 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £19,226 Colour: Grey Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport EC Combined (mpg) 57.6 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 67.3 EC Urban (mpg) 47.1  &gt; 57 MPG 31 Insurance Group 218 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 128 CO2 (g/km) £110 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport Insurance Group 31, Satellite Navigation, 18 Alloys, Front Foglights, Rain Sensor Wipers with Auto Headlight Activation, Automatic Air Conditioning, Bluetooth Telephone Preparation, 12v Auxiliary Power Socket, DAB Digital Radio, Multi Function Steering Wheel, Auto Drive Away Locking System Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01246 642175 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Beauty may be in the eye of the beholder but you would have to be a bit of BMW fan to believe the original 1-Series was a good looking hatchback. read more Better looking than the previous model Fun to drive Superb fuel economy with diesel engines Cramped in the rear Deals will be few and far between Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Alloy wheels Audio remote control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642175 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power socket in centre console 12V power socket in passenger footwell 2 cupholders 4 grab handles 60/40 split rear seats ABS/EBD Automatic Stability Control (ASC) BMW emergency call BMW teleservices Body coloured door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Door armrests Door sill finishers with illuminated M designation Drive Performance Control DSC+ Dual zone automatic air conditioning Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric front windows + one touch + anti-pinch Electric rear windows Electrically adjustable door mirrors Engine start/stop button Folding rear seat head rests Front door storage bins Front folding/sliding centre armrest with storage Front head restraints Front isofix attachment + airbag deactivation Front sports seats with electric side bolster adjustment Glovebox Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated door mirrors Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist Individual anthracite headlining Isofix rear child seat preparation Leather gear knob and handbrake grip 'Lights On' warning buzzer Load restraint lashing eyes M sports leather steering wheel Multifunction steering wheel with audio controls Oil level indicator On board computer On board diagnostics Outside temperature display Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear wash/wipe Service interval indicator Speed limiter Storage compartments in front/rear door panels Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio with CD player Digital Audio Broadcast (DAB) Tuner Exterior / Styling 18 light alloy wheels - M Star spoke style 386M Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Brake force display Chrome exhaust tailpipe Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Follow me home headlights Front fog lights High gloss shadow line M aerodynamic bodystyling Run flat tyres Safety / Security Child locks on rear doors Crash sensor Driver/Passenger airbags (Impact dependent) Drivers knee airbag Electronic immobiliser Front side airbags ITS head airbags for front/rear Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Remote central locking Seat belt force limiter Thatcham Cat.1 alarm Three 3 point rear seatbelts Tyre pressure monitor Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642175 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 128
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/2a59b155-7743-31f9-b303-e82b74d338ce" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-04T11:18:25Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:51:15.612Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39239171/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
