<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Press Release Distribution <NODE id="27" />MEMSIC<NODE id="33" /> Launches <NODE id="43" />MDP200 Pressure Sensor<NODE id="65" /> for HVAC Applications at AHR Expo By providing a very high level of stability and accuracy, MEMSIC enables HVAC system engineers and developers to reduce costs while providing greater reliability and performance to their customers MEMSIC sensor for VAV damper control as well as many other HVC applications Jan. 19, 2016 - PRLog -- MEMSIC Launches MDP200 Pressure Sensor for HVAC Applications at AHR 2016 HVAC System Designers &amp; Manufacturers can improve performance and reliability without increasing cost January 19, 2016 – AHR Expo, Orlando, Florida – Booth 1094 MEMSIC Inc. (http://www.memsic.com/) will be demonstrating their latest MEMS based <NODE id="715" />pressure sensor<NODE id="730" /> at the upcoming AHR 2016 show in Orlando, Florida, which begins January 25, 2016. This new MEMSIC sensor was designed for VAV damper control as well as HVC applications such as room pressure monitoring, fume hood controls, furnace press switches, heat recovery systems, burner control, fan control, filter monitoring and many others. The new MEMSIC MDP200 thermal differential pressure sensor provides HVAC system developers with competitively priced sensors with high null stability, accuracy and reliability of a MEMS structure and CMOS platform backed up by over a decade of experience and technology knowhow with millions of similar devices in the market. 'By providing a very high level of stability and accuracy, MEMSIC enables HVAC system engineers and developers to reduce costs while providing greater reliability and performance to their customers,' says Ohlan Silpachi, MEMSIC Flow Sensor Product Manager. 'The MDP200 is an integrated MEMS thermal differential pressure sensor that utilizes thermopile structures similar to our highly successful MEMS accelerometers that been sold into millions into consumer and automotive applications in the past decade.' MEMSIC is one of a few companies to offer a high-tech integrated thermal MEMS flow chip in a differential pressure sensor platform. Integrating electronics into the sensor chip eliminates the presence of wire bonding (from the sensor chip to the electronics) in the flow channel. Such integration improves reliability as there are no wires to trap fuzz and dust or to be exposed to corrosion. Integration of sensors and electronics also reduces the sensor costs by reducing electronics components and packaging size. Please contact Ohlan Silpachi at osilpachai@memsic.com to set up a meeting at AMR Expo. More about <NODE id="2516" />MEMSIC MEMSIC Inc.<NODE id="2534" />, headquartered in Andover, Massachusetts, <NODE id="2577" />provides<NODE id="2585" /> advanced <NODE id="2595" />semiconductor sensors<NODE id="2616" /> and <NODE id="2621" />multi-sensor system<NODE id="2640" /> solutions based on micro-electromechanical systems (MEMS) technology and sophisticated integration technologies in both the IC level and module level. MEMSIC’s unique and proprietary approach combines leading-edge <NODE id="2855" />sensor technologies<NODE id="2874" />, such as <NODE id="2884" />magnetic sensors<NODE id="2900" />, accelerometers, <NODE id="2918" />flow sensors<NODE id="2930" /> and current sensors with mixed-signal processing circuitry to produce reliable, high quality, cost-effective solutions for the mobile phone, automotive, consumer, industrial, medical and general aviation markets. FOR MORE INFORMATION MEMSIC Inc., One Tech Drive, Suite 325, Andover, MA 0180 Tel: 978-738-0900 Fax: 978-738-0156 Email: info@memsic.com www.memsic.com/flow-sensors Contact Ohlan Silpachi osilpachai@memsic.com ***@srs-techpr.com --- End --- Verified Account Email Address Verified Account Phone Number Disclaimer: Issuers of the press releases are solely responsible for the content of their press releases. PRLog can't be held liable for the content posted by others. Report Abuse Latest News By SRS Tech Media Relations More News ...
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/16b0dcfd-1388-309e-9174-91f62fe79bef" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-19T20:02:30Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:43:52.411Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.prlog.org/12526083-memsic-launches-mdp200-pressure-sensor-for-hvac-applications-at-ahr-expo.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="27" endPos="33" type="organization-company" surface="MEMSIC" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="43" endPos="65" type="product" surface="MDP200 Pressure Sensor" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="715" endPos="730" type="product-class" surface="pressure sensor" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="2516" endPos="2534" type="organization-company" surface="MEMSIC MEMSIC Inc." />
<Entity id="4" startPos="2577" endPos="2585" type="provide-type" surface="provides" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="2577" endPos="2585" type="trigger" surface="provides" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="2595" endPos="2616" type="product-class" surface="semiconductor sensors" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="2621" endPos="2640" type="product-class" surface="multi-sensor system" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="2855" endPos="2874" type="product-class" surface="sensor technologies" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2884" endPos="2900" type="product-class" surface="magnetic sensors" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2918" endPos="2930" type="product-class" surface="flow sensors" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="11" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="12" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="provide_type" />
<Entity id="7" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="trigger" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="13" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="provide_type" />
<Entity id="6" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="trigger" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
