<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Suche Custom-made double-sided displays with latest eyevis high brightness panel make commercials at POS in JET gas stations reliably visible 28.01.2016 - 10:00 | 447015 PressRelease by eyevis Gesellschaft für Projektions- und Großbildtechnik mbH (PresseBox) - Since August 2015, 46-inch double-sided displays have presented the latest commercials of Reemtsma Cigarettenfabriken GmbH at 200 Jet gas stations all over Germany ? reliably during sunshine and at night. eyevis developed these custom-made displays on special request of PMS perfect media solutions GmbH, who put them to their first use for Reemtsma, one of the leading German providers of tobacco products. Optimized for the exterior and interior The completely novel double-sided display, whose two sides are optimized for different brightness conditions, enables the simultaneous display of digital signage content in the salesroom as well as in the sunlit shop window. eyevis, the renowned manufacturer of large-screen systems, constructed this product exclusively for PMS within the framework of eyevis? Custom LCD series. With a high brightness panel, a standard panel and an internal PC, which are combined in a special tailor-made housing, the double-sided display meets its challenges on both sides. To this end, a high brightness panel, which is also used in eyevis? EYE-LCD-4600-XHB, offers maximum luminance of up to 5000 cd/m² to the shop window side. Thus, best image quality, visibility and readability can still be guaranteed under direct sunlight. An ambient <NODE id="1537" />light sensor<NODE id="1549" /> automatically adjusts screen luminance and switches appropriately between high brightness mode with maximum brightness and the high gamut mode with an extended color space, ensuring optimum image quality for the viewer at all times. To the salesroom side, the double-sided displays are equipped with standard panels, with their luminance of 700 cd/m² perfectly adapted to the requirements of interior lighting situations. Both panels are Full HD capable and are operated within the double-sided display, which is hanging upright from the ceiling. This type of installation gave rise to a special feature in the design of the display housing: It can be opened while hanging, which simplifies the systems? maintenance. Integrated in the digital signage network PMS, as the system integrator and operator for the whole project, managed the integration of eyevis? double-sided displays within the existing national digital signage network for 23/7 operation at gas stations. The content is controlled centrally by the digital signage management system PerfectShow and sent to the individual sites via LTE and UMTS. A change in campaign can easily and cost-efficiently be implemented through the network. ?During sunshine, the screens of our digital signage network to date have lagged far behind the quality of poster advertising,? explains Stefan Pagenkemper, one of the managing directors at PMS. He is confident of the new eyevis panels: ?Thanks to eyevis? double-sided displays, Reemtsma?s content is now perfectly visible in all weather conditions. The integration of our PerfectShow hardware and software into the display allowed for an integration not only into the existing infrastructure, but also into the whole digital signage concept of the shops.? Convincing high brightness displays thanks to highest luminance During the conception phase of the custom-made displays, eyevis offered different panels with luminance levels from 2500 cd/m² up to 5000 cd/m². ?Digital signage in shop windows poses a great challenge, for which we have developed our latest High Brightness series,? states Reiner Lutz from eyevis. He adds: ?PMS has unequivocally decided on the brightest display version with 5000 cd/m² during the testing phase. Our premium LCD displays were thus put to their first use and since this summer have proven that they can truly handle any lighting situation. We are happy to have found a reliable and highly productive partner in PMS and that we were able to implement this innovative project in cooperation.? About eyevis eyevis, the German manufacturer of large scale video systems, is one of the leading providers and integrators of visualization systems for professional applications in control rooms, virtual reality and simulation as well as broadcast and AV. eyevis has a worldwide network of subsidiaries and certified retailers. As one of only a few providers, eyevis is capable of offering entire systems from one source. The complete solutions of eyevis include display solutions, graphic controllers, software applications as well as all necessary accessories. About PMS PMS perfect media solutions GmbH is one of the leading providers of digital signage systems. With its own software called PerfectShow, PMS operates a network of more than 1000 displays for Reemtsma among other clients. PMS offers project solutions in the area of digital signage, media technology, IPTV and medical technology ? from the individual solution to installation and operation to on-site service. Company information / Profile: About eyevis eyevis, the German manufacturer of large scale video systems, is one of the leading providers and integrators of visualization systems for professional applications in control rooms, virtual reality and simulation as well as broadcast and AV. eyevis has a worldwide network of subsidiaries and certified retailers. As one of only a few providers, eyevis is capable of offering entire systems from one source. The complete solutions of eyevis include display solutions, graphic controllers, software applications as well as all necessary accessories. About PMS PMS perfect media solutions GmbH is one of the leading providers of digital signage systems. With its own software called PerfectShow, PMS operates a network of more than 1000 displays for Reemtsma among other clients. PMS offers project solutions in the area of digital signage, media technology, IPTV and medical technology ? from the individual solution to installation and operation to on-site service. further Information: http:// Kontakt-Informationen: Firma: eyevis Gesellschaft für Projektions- und Großbildtechnik mbH Stadt: Reutlingen Number of hits: 40 Linking-Tips:
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/2d96e89e-da17-3a3c-9f30-3c3b1d328a5e" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-29T00:57:05Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:52:29.918Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.pressekat.de/pressrelease447015.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1537" endPos="1549" type="product-class" surface="light sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
