<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Featured Company Global Fiber <NODE id="30" />Optics Sensors<NODE id="44" /> Market<NODE id="51" /> 2016-2020 - Leading Vendors are <NODE id="84" />Banner Engineering<NODE id="102" />, <NODE id="104" />ifm Efector<NODE id="115" />, <NODE id="117" />OMRON<NODE id="122" /> &amp; <NODE id="125" />Sick<NODE id="129" /> PR Newswire Tuesday, January 19th 2016 DUBLIN , Jan. 19, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- Research and Markets ( http://www.researchandmarkets.com/research/4wpdlb/global_fiber ) has announced the addition of the Global Fiber Optics Sensors Market 2016-2020 report to their offering. The report predicts the global fiber optic sensors market to grow steadily at a CAGR of about 9% during the forecast period. The fiber optic sensors capability of a higher tolerance for high temperatures is expected to drive the demand for these sensors in applications that has extreme environmental conditions and where <NODE id="723" />electrical sensors<NODE id="741" /> fail to function properly, such as the oil and gas, and manufacturing sector. Increased exploration of unconventional resources is another major factor expected to increase the revenues of the fiber optic sensors market during the forecast period. Fiber optic sensors are integrated into equipment used during the drilling and exploration stages. The increase in consumption of oil and gas and the decline in the production of conventional oil reserves has forced vendors and governments to indulge in exploration and drilling activities, therefore, leading to greater demand for fiber optic sensors in this industry. The Americas accounted for almost 42% of the market share during 2015 and is expected to grow at a CAGR of close to 10% during the forecast period. Key questions answered in the report include: What will the market size and the growth rate be in 2020? What are the key factors driving the global fiber optic sensors market? What are the key Market trends impacting the growth of the global fiber optic sensors market? What are the challenges to market growth? Who are the key vendors in the global fiber optic sensors market? What are the market opportunities and threats faced by the vendors in the global fiber optic sensors market? Trending factors influencing the market shares of the Americas, APAC, and EMEA. What are the key outcomes of the five forces analysis of the global fiber optic sensors market? Leading Vendors are: Banner Engineering ifm Efector OMRON Sick
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/3fe65ec7-2ece-3e18-9d17-62a6ac75d21c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-19T16:16:30Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:59:23.273Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.virtual-strategy.com/2016/01/19/global-fiber-optics-sensors-market-2016-2020-leading-vendors-are-banner-engineering-ifm-e" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="30" endPos="44" type="product-class" surface="Optics Sensors" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="30" endPos="51" type="industry" surface="Optics Sensors Market" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="84" endPos="102" type="organization-company" surface="Banner Engineering" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="104" endPos="115" type="organization-company" surface="ifm Efector" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="117" endPos="122" type="organization-company" surface="OMRON" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="125" endPos="129" type="organization-company" surface="Sick" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="723" endPos="741" type="product-class" surface="electrical sensors" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="7" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="1" label="industry" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="8" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
<Entity id="1" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="9" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="1" label="industry" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="10" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
<Entity id="1" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="11" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="0" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="12" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="0" label="product" />
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="13" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="0" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="14" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="0" label="product" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
