<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2014 (14) - BMW 4 Series 2.0 420d M Sport 2dr Auto £26,990 Loading Images... Date Registered: Apr 2014 Mileage: 12,000 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £26,990 Colour: White Body Style: Convertible Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport EC Combined (mpg) 56.5 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 64.2 EC Urban (mpg) 47.9  &gt; 56 MPG 31 Insurance Group 184 Performance (BHP) 4 Seats 131 CO2 (g/km) £130 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport Insurance Group 31, 1 Registered Keeper, White, Air-Conditioning, Start/Stop System, Cruise Control, DAB Radio, Parking Aid, Seats Heated, Alloy Wheels, Alarm, In Car Entertainment, Telephone Equipment, Keyless Go, Electric Windows, Tinted Glass, Hill Holder, Computer, Rain Sensor, Tyre Pressure Control, Upholstery Leather. 4 seats, 26,990 Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01642 694519 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Climate control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Electrically adjustable drivers seat Electrically adjustable passenger seat Front electric windows Front fog lights Headlight washers Heated door mirrors Heated front seat Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01642 694519 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V sockets in front centre console and passenger footwell 2 speed adjustable intermittent wipers with wash/wipe function 3 spoke leather M multifunction sports steering wheel ABS/EBD Anthracite headlining Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic Stability Control (ASC) BMW emergency call BMW teleservices Body colour door mirrors Brake pad wear indicator warning light CBC - (Cornering brake control) Check control system Door/boot open warning Drive Performance Control DSC+ Dual zone climate control Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric adjustable heated door mirrors Electric front and rear windows with fingertip open/close + anti-trap all round Electrically adjustable front seats - driver seat with memory Front cupholders x 2 Front door storage with bottle holder Front head restraints Front sports seats with electric side bolster adjustment Front/rear armrests within door panels Front/rear Parking distance control Glovebox with lid Heat insulating tinted glass Heated front seats Heated windscreen washer jets Height adjustable front seats Hill start assist Integrated rear head restraints ISOFIX child seat preparation+airbag deactivation Lashing eyelets in boot Leather gearknob and handbrake lever Lights on warning Oil temperature gauge On board computer Outside temperature display Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear centre armrest Run flat indicator Service interval indicator Stop/start button Storage compartment behind rear seat Storage compartment in rear centre console Storage compartment in rear seat base Toolkit located in luggage compartment Windscreen with grey shadeband Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio/CD/MP3 DAB Digital radio Exterior / Styling Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Body colour roof mouldings Chrome exhaust tailpipe Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Daytime running lights Door sill finishers Extended lights package - 4 Series Follow me home headlights Front fog lights Headlight washers High gloss shadow line M aerodynamic bodystyling Run flat tyres Safety / Security Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Drive away door locking Driver seatbelt warning indicator Driver/Front Passenger airbags Electronic immobiliser Front passenger airbag deactivation Front seatbelt force limiters Front seatbelt pretensioner Front side airbags Remote central locking Remote control Thatcham category 1 alarm Roll over protection Tyre pressure monitor Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01642 694519 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 131
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0eaadc7c-94cd-385c-be14-239fbe9ff3bd" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-29T18:44:26Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:40:50.084Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-40018797/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
