<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Samsung Gear S2 smartwatch launched in India for Rs 24300 Author: Alice Johnson ; Last update: 21 January , 2016 11:15:45 As for the variants, Samsung says that the Gear S2 is ideal for those who are on-the-go and have an admiration for minimal and modern design. The company has also announced the launch of Gear VR virtual reality headset in India at Rs 8,200. The Gear S2 is available in two variants - Gear S2 is priced at Rs 24,300 and the Gear S2 Classic at Rs 25,800. Kris Jenner Is 'Excited and Anxious' for Upcoming Show I'll forever be obsessed with you! Kris Jenner continues to star in the reality show Keeping Up with the Kardashians. I'm more of a from a friend standpoint. Although the invite doesn't mention Gear S2 explicitly, the image it contains speaks for itself. The Tizen OS based smartwatch has been launched in phases in a number of global markets. Armed with cutting edge features such as a paradigm defining Circular UI, connectivity solutions and fitness solutions, the Samsung Gear S2 seamlessly blends mobility with convenience. While the Gear S2 supports touch inputs, what sets it apart from other smartwatches is an intuitive rotating bezel. Mayor: Teachers in sick-out should return to schools Factoring the investment of new school-level positions, DPS expects to save between $8 million and $10 million, Ferrandino said. It has left many teachers anxious that Detroit Public Schools will go out of existence, said Bailey, the teachers union leader. The Gear S2 smartwatch features a 1.2-inch full circle design, which is its most attractive feature. Putting aside the obvious feeling I have for my new gadget, the first thing I noticed off the bat was the navigation dial that makes life a whole lot easier. There are many other bands available for S2 (mendini, warm grey and red) and Gear S2 Classic (grey leather and brown leather). United States crude oil prices stabilize but market sentiment remains bearish USA crude oil prices have trended down for a year and a half, and have fallen nearly 40 percent in just the past three months. NYMEX front-month WTI futures fell to an intraday low of $27.92 a barrel, extending its slide from July 2014 to 75%. This smartwatch being IP68 certified is water and dust resistant and is fueled by a 250mAh battery, which lasts up to 2-3 days on average use. On the storage front, there is 4GB inbuilt memory available. It also comes with a heart rate sensor which monitors the heart rate of the user. The Gear S2 works with Android devices running Android 4.4 and above along with the devices which pack more than 1.5GB of RAM. The consumer version of Gear VR is compatible with select Samsung smartphones including the Galaxy Note 5, Galaxy S6 Edge+, Galaxy S6 and Galaxy S6 Edge. With the Gear S2, Samsung is setting courageous new standards in the wearables category in India. Bookmark this page and stay connected! Netflix down - Aussie geo-blocking has started Microsoft's 'last Lumia' reportedly launching on February 1st
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1f9435d9-ea74-38fe-a246-216da297083a" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-21T12:32:57Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:47:14.429Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bsccomment.com/2016/01/21/samsung-gear-s2-smartwatch-launched-in-india-for-rs-24300.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
