<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>January 2016 News Release AutomatedBuildings.com Your Complete Source for Building <NODE id="83" />Automation Sensors <NODE id="102" />Veris Industries<NODE id="118" /> (Click Message to Learn More) EnOcean Alliance at AHR Expo 2016: The Self-Powered Wireless Standard for Building Automation - Booth #1247 Seamless integration of <NODE id="281" />battery-less sensors<NODE id="301" /> and switches with local controllers, gateways, and building management systems build a network for integrated control, meeting individual requirements San Ramon, CA/Orlando, FL _ January 11, 2016 _ At AHR Expo 2016 (Orange County Convention Center, Orlando, January 25-27), the EnOcean Alliance will show the possibilities of the interoperable EnOcean ecosystem for integrated building control. The ecosystem wall _ shown at booth 1247 _ will represent a complete automation system based on the EnOcean energy harvesting wireless standard. It will include all necessary components for intelligent HVAC and lighting control as well as energy management. The solutions presented offer maximum flexibility based on maintenance-free wireless devices, which are powered by their surrounding environment. Due to EnOcean Alliance's open approach to interoperability, users can combine products from different vendors seamlessly. Intelligent building control calls for solutions that can be flexibly adapted to individual project requirements. Breaking down the barriers of isolated applications, the interoperable EnOcean Alliance ecosystem of more than 400 member companies and over 1,500 products offer integrated systems that connect several building applications and control them depending on the current situation. Due to strong partnerships with leading organizations of the wireless industry, such as the ZigBee Alliance, the AllSeen Alliance or the Open Interconnect Consortium, the EnOcean Alliance opens the world of energy harvesting wireless communication to an interoperable, worldwide Internet of Things (IoT). The key advantages of wireless control are the ease of upgrading existing buildings and expanding a system at any time. No new control wiring is required for existing systems; they simply are upgraded with wireless control units. Wireless control systems can even provide greater installation flexibility if units within the system do not require dedicated cabling or batteries for power, says Graham Martin, Chairman of the EnOcean Alliance. At AHR Expo, the EnOcean Alliance will show an integrated building system covering the following areas: Self-Powered Switches and Sensors Intelligent lighting control can be covered on the basis of three main wireless components: kinetic-powered light switches, including dimmers, solar-powered light sensors, and solar-powered <NODE id="2691" />occupancy sensors<NODE id="2708" />. This system can additionally support a wireless daylight harvesting application, which is a lighting controls system that automatically adapts the light level to the amount of available natural light in a room measured by light level sensors. In a typical commercial building with such an automated lighting control system, it is possible to reduce energy consumption by up to 30%. Wireless sensors can also lay the foundation for energy savings, increased comfort, and healthier living through automated HVAC control. Self-powered temperature, gas, and climate sensors combined with hydronic heating valves form a wireless network that supplies heat or cool air depending on individual needs and behavior or when room conditions need to be adapted to predefined set points. Gateways and Local Controllers The approach of seamlessly integrating the control of different building areas can be realized with gateways and local controllers. These directly communicate with the self-powered wireless devices and with each other to process the delivered data and information for a synchronized building management system. This results in better energy efficiency while increasing comfort and security at the same time. Building Management Systems These same gateways can also bridge the EnOcean standard to work with other established protocols such as BACnet, LonMark, WiFi, ZigBee, or the cloud. This provides maximum flexibility to installing professionals to expand and adapt building automation systems based on other protocols at any time with wireless components and to centrally control the whole system. More details on the self-powered wireless solutions shown at the EnOcean Alliance booth 1247 can be found at www.enocean-alliance.org/en/products . Visitors to AHR Expo 2016 can experience energy harvesting wireless solutions from over 15 EnOcean Alliance members, including the following exhibitors: Caleffi (1857), Delta Controls (1021), Distech Controls (1242), Dwyer Instruments (1617), KMC Controls (1219), LonMark International (1337), Neptronic (1613), Reliable Controls (1050), Schneider Electric (1404), Spartan Peripheral Devices (1426), Thermokon (1011), Viconics Technologies (1035), WAGO (1708), Titus (2013) and Siemens Building Technologies (1829). About EnOcean Alliance Leading companies worldwide from the building sector formed the EnOcean Alliance to establish innovative automation solutions for sustainable building projects _ making buildings more energy-efficient, more flexible and more cost effective. The core technology of the Alliance is energy harvesting wireless technology for flexibly positioned and service-free sensor solutions. The EnOcean Alliance aims to internationalize the energy harvesting wireless technology, and is dedicated to creating interoperability between the products of OEM partners. Basis for this is the international standard ISO/IEC 14543-3-1X, which is optimized for wireless solutions with ultra-low power consumption and energy harvesting. More than 400 companies currently belong to the EnOcean Alliance. The headquarters of the non-profit organization is located in San Ramon, California. www.enocean-alliance.org
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/080bd1c0-a0d5-37c6-9b95-7d78aa9f4018" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-16T21:45:19Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:38:22.014Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://automatedbuildings.com/releases/jan16/160115105606enocean.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="83" endPos="102" type="product-class" surface="Automation Sensors " />
<Entity id="1" startPos="102" endPos="118" type="organization-company" surface="Veris Industries" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="281" endPos="301" type="product-class" surface="battery-less sensors" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="2691" endPos="2708" type="product-class" surface="occupancy sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
