<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>With a diameter of 58 mm, the optical absolute singleturn and multiturn EtherNet/IP encoders have been designed for time-critical applications Optical absolute <NODE id="160" />Sendix F58 EtherNet/IP<NODE id="182" /> encoders Posted on February 8, 2016 - ( views) by Sara Ibrahim Kübler Group - Fritz Kübler GmbH Industrial Ethernet is increasingly imposing itself as the communication standard in automation technology. The goal is to achieve vertical integration - that is to say, one single calculator core from the supervisor level up to the industrial production plants - in order to be able to control any piece of equipment. Availability and performance are of great relevance especially for time-critical and cost-sensitive plants. Based on these requirements, Kübler is expanding its Industrial Ethernet encoder portfolio. Besides Profinet and EtherCAT, Ethernet/IP encoders will from now on enrich the products range. More Performance The optical absolute singleturn and multiturn Sendix F58 EtherNet/IP encoders with a diameter of 58 mm have been designed for time-critical applications. In addition to supporting plant performance and availability, their specific features also greatly contribute to save time and costs. Equipped with their robust Safety-Lock™ bearing design, these encoders withstand installation errors, shocks and vibrations. Position value transmission is 5 times faster than common market encoders, therefore ensuring more performance. RPI time is only 1 ms. This feature allows operating this encoder in time-critical applications up to a 1,000 Hz update frequency. The fast start-up is another strong point of the encoder. It takes place immediately after applying the supply voltage. Therefore, nothing stands in the way of an increase of plant performance, of plant availability and of the reduction of cost-sensitive standstills. Cyclic services allow fast and easy commissioning and configuration, saving costs and time. Thanks to the implementation of DLR (Device Level Ring) a single cable break does not lead to plant stoppage. Ring redundancy is ensured. These absolute singleturn and multiturn Sendix encoders are available in solid shaft or blind hollow shaft version. The blind hollow shaft has a diameter of 15 mm. Their IP65 protection level and their wide temperature range from -40°C...+80°C allow operating these encoders reliably also in harsh environmental conditions. Thanks to their <NODE id="2405" />optical sensors<NODE id="2420" />, these devices are 100% insensitive to magnetic fields. Total resolution is 32 bits. The devices are ODVA-certified. The Sendix F58 EtherNet/IP encoders are used for example in the following applications: Automotive production, logistics, metal processing, textile, printing and packaging machines. View other Videos
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1d319c00-a934-34d8-8d5a-f002a065a700" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-08T13:21:37Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:46:20.727Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.ien.eu/article/ethernetip-encoder-sendix-f58/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="160" endPos="182" type="product" surface="Sendix F58 EtherNet/IP" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="2405" endPos="2420" type="product-class" surface="optical sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
