<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>unpretty: unpretty: unpretty: findingnewnormal: slytherinlynx: hollydonlan: heartfilledminds: thegoldheart: joehabana: unpretty: do microwaves in other countries have different quick setting buttons? are american microwaves the standard? do people outside the u.s. have a potato button, is what i want to know. Mexican here, we have potato button I’m in Brazil and here we don’t have a potato button, we have a rice button. I’m from the Netherlands and we have a potato button:) In Scotland and we have a potato button but not on all microwaves just the nice ones. In France I had a microwave with a chicken button and a breadloaf button I’m from England and I didn’t know potato buttons were even a thing Potato Button: United States Mexico Canada Netherlands Posh Scotland Rice Button: Brazil Breadloaf Button???: France No Dedicated Carbs Button: England okay i got sick of waiting for answers so i hopped onto some international versions of amazon and here is what i found: australian amazon only sells books?? what the fuck same for chinese amazon but that’s not as surprising german microwaves have a potato button, but only when there are buttons. most of these things have dials. like… what. only weird fancy american microwaves have dials. also i saw a yogurt button. indian microwaves seem to generally feature a ‘stuffed veg’ button instead of a potato-specific button. there is also a rice button. but do you know what else is standard. A GODDAMNED CHICKEN TANDOORI BUTTON. FUCK ME. german and indian microwaves both had beverage buttons, which was not a surprise, but they also both had pizza buttons, which WAS a surprise. the indian microwaves called it a bread snack but it was clearly a picture of a pizza. why is the pizza button more universal than the potato button?? japanese microwaves have rice buttons and not potato buttons. no surprises there. the big surprise is that they also favor the dial. for that matter india had a lot of microwaves with dials, too. what gives. why the dials. where are your flat, easy to clean buttons. according to italian amazon, in italian you call a kitchenaid stand mixer a “robot da cucina”. that is the cutest fucking thing i have ever heard. but back to microwaves. once again i’m seeing a lot of dials. you know these aren’t real ovens, right? why are you adjusting the strength so much. keep it on high and hit the one minute button. stop complicating things with dials. a lot of these are just rebranded german microwaves, so there is a potato button, and also a yogurt button. see above for spain. y’all just have the same microwave. spain’s amazon is a lot less intuitive than every other country’s. i don’t know why. spanish amazon, please fix your menu system. it is wrong. This concludes my fact-finding mission. Australia, why are your microwaves so mysterious. I’m getting a lot of repeat questions as a result of this so I’m just going to answer them here, where none of the people who asked can see. Australians, I appreciate your enthusiasm, but you can stop sending me pictures of your microwaves. You have a potato button. Someone of you need to buy new microwaves because those things look like they belong on the bridge of the original USS Enterprise. I thought it was self-explanatory but the yogurt button is for heating milk in order to make yogurt. According to some of these microwaves you can also use it to proof yeast. I prefer a crockpot to make yogurt, personally, and using a microwave for that would weird me out. But if you read that and were immediately intrigued by the notion of a hot yogurt dish feel free to google çılbır. It is delicious. You are welcome. Baking a potato in the oven takes literally forever and some of us have lives to lead. Mitch Hedberg had a whole bit about this. Does not everyone know about this bit? There is literally no benefit to baking a potato in the oven. Microwave it. Yes, we have popcorn buttons. Everyone has popcorn buttons, basically. I did not cover that issue here because this is about the potato button. Same for the frozen veg button or the dinner plate/leftovers button. They need to stop trying to steal the potato’s thunder. Some of you are very defensive of your microwave dials, and I am here to tell you: sorry, but you are the weird ones. Doubling as a toaster oven is a weird feature for a microwave to have. There are probably microwaves like that in the U.S. but they are probably super expensive, or else old and weird. Some of you are way too proud of yourselves for not owning a microwave. Stop trying to get smug about the fact that it takes you twenty minutes to reheat soup. I’m not buying it. Valid things to cook in a microwave: potatoes; popcorn; mochi; hot dogs; steamed buns; actually basically anything you need to steam; white rice; anything that comes out of a can. Invalid things to cook in a microwave: fresh meats; fish of any kind; frozen pizzas, how fucking dare you, put your fucking pizza in the oven and learn to love yourselves; brown or wild rice; anything that you want to be crispy, like pizza, you animals. The food-specific buttons only exist on low-end to middle-of-the-road microwaves in the United States. Fancy microwaves have general, all-purpose sensor-settings.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/f8b36093-7bae-39d0-b4c0-7a94091ce32f" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T05:00:12Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:09:42.965Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://thenjw.tumblr.com/post/137132720365" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
