<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Great Bustard wrote: NCV wrote: Forgottenbutnotgone wrote: NCV wrote: Forgottenbutnotgone wrote: Tony8232 wrote: The problem isn't so much the threads its the equivalence posts on topics that really have noting to do with equivalence. Someone will respond to the post mentioning equuvalence and then the battle is joined. Would you mind linking a few examples. Most of the time I've seen equivalence being mentioned it's been in response to someone attempting to pass of fiction as fact. When such a statement is corrected with factual, proven physics, people's egos run ahead of their common sense. That's where the battles start. Equivalence is merely a group of facts that quantifies the tradeoffs of smaller versus larger <NODE id="726" />sensors<NODE id="733" /> and supporting systems. They are as real as the relationship between shutter speed and motion blur or aperture and depth of field. I can't increase shutter speed without either decreasing exposure or depth of field. (now some would even argue that point by saying the exposure would not be decreased if I were to increase the ISO, that argument would come from an improper understanding of exposure) Everyone generally accepts those facts so there is no contention when they are employed and mentioned. The factors equivalence describes are just as true and relevant but people who do not want to understand it get their feathers ruffled. that's where the battle is. The OP gets disgusted stops posting and the thread continues until it reaches its limit. Nothing gets settled but now we have a frustrated m43 user wondering if all photographers are crazy. A lot of people are sick and tired of it. Actually the OPs should use the complain button more often if they feel the thread is being hijacked. After a while this nonesense will stop. The reality is that this is a public forum If you make statements that are not true you should expect for them to be challenged. Doing so is not hijacking a thread. People should complain when other people argue against relevant facts with untrue statements. The biggest fallacy is that size doesn't matter. It most certainly does when it comes to image quality. Case in point, why is the Pro 40-150 so much bigger than the previous one? Is it just to impress the ladies? Personally I feel that posts dealing with equivalence as the main topic don't belong here because there just enough immature people here to screw things up. Much like the resistance to equivalence, your argument doesn't add up. You are actually saying that the truth shouldn't be told because people are immature and that the moderators should back that up. No offense to you but in my mind that borders on idiotic. The problem should be dealt with, not the truth. The the problem is the immature people. They should be moved to another forum. That's right! THEY should be moved to another forum. Robert May I say that a lot of the problems start when the case is stated for this or that and the poster is certain that he is 100% right as he has textbook physics and maths to back him up and prove it. If the poster is right, he's right. It shouldn't make anyone mad. It often gets forgotten that photography is APPLIED science and some of the theoretical rules start to be less cut and dried as a whole gamut of little factors and manufacturing tolerances get factored in. Manufacturing tolerances don't change the science any more than a misgraduated measuring device would change the actual measure of a gallon of water. So one should take a little care before calling out the other who has stated perhaps a more practical view born out of real life observation. Your practical observation seems to favorably coincide with what the poster has not only said in his banishable bantering but has also probably practically observed, just as you and many others have. Maybe the care should be taken by he who has had no problem taking the poster to task for his explanation of a phenomenon that you on one hand seem to disagree with yet at the same time have practically observed. I'm not saying any of this to be contentious. I'm saying it because there has been a long history of denial of facts in the Olympus forums that is downright embarrassing. Not so long ago, people who told the truth about the noisy character of Four Thirds sensors were ridiculed, right up until the point that we got a good sensor in a mft body. Then the same people demanded one in the new Four Thirds camera, again after flatly denying there was a need for it. Those who then recognized the handwriting on the wall concerning the demise of Four Thirds were likewise ridiculed and bullied. When it came true, many of said bullies scurried off to Nikon without so much as an apology. Now the E phenomenon that people have been prejudiced against for so long is published and explained by a well known and respected person, Richard Butler and yet there people's attitudes have not changed. There has also been a long history of placating the majority at the expense of the credibility of the forum at large. Some of those who would otherwise be some of the best reasons to frequent this forum are the very ones that end up trolling, yep, trolling their OWN forum by purposely and willfully denying obvious truth when it goes against their egos.Hopefully that will change. It will be a better look for all of us. Robert Thank you for a thoughtful reply. Let’s get one thing clear. I have no doubt that the theoretical side ties up closely with the observed results. I deal all day with maths and applied science so I am quite capable of understanding these technical issues. So, you've changed your mind in the past couple of days since previous denial of the objectivity of DOF with regards to Equivalence? I have replied to you and others several times on this subject starting off by saying more or less I am shure what you are saying is mathematicaly correct but. ............ But you know that “information” can be used to push agendas if presented in a certain ways. More to the point, the denial of that information is *constantly* used to push a particular agenda. For example using certain characteristics of the optical differences of seemingly similar lenses we can try to show that the format we have chosen is superior or belittle the format of the other guy if we please. Or we can instead note that, with regards to cross-format comparisons, the total amount of light falling on the sensor is a central consideration and that it is the resolution in the photo (lw/ph), as opposed to the resolution of the lens (lp/mm) that is the primary consideration (a relationship, by the way, that is well described by Equivalence). This is the real reason for the arguments that arise. I agree -- the real reasons for the arguments is the denial of facts to push a particular agenda. At least we agree on this point. -- hide signature -- http://nigelvoak.blogspot.it/
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/cf6d1236-ef3b-3dea-a642-3b4414d5d22f" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T22:44:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:53:59.17Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.dpreview.com/forums/thread/3950076?page=5" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="726" endPos="733" type="product-class" surface="sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
