<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 18, 2016 C O N T E N T S: Image Courtesy: link: https://media.ford.com/content/fordmedia/fna/us/en/news/2016/01/05/smart-cars-meet-smart-homes.html author: media.ford.com description: Hero Image KEY TOPICS While Samsung is betting on its 2016 range of smart TVs to become the center of your connected home, LG has announced a device for the job that looks more than a little like the Amazon Echo. [1] Our new app for Apple TV brings interactive video monitoring to the biggest, most convenient screen in your home, while our new Amazon Echo integration will enable voice commands for your smart lights and smart thermostat. [2] Amazon Echo with Alexa voice control offers an intuitive and useful way for Alarm.com users to make their smart home safer and more comfortable, said Jay Kenny, Senior Vice President of Marketing at Alarm.com. [3] The Amazon Echo and Alexa integration makes voice control the latest in a wide range of options for controlling an Alarm.com smart home. [3] VIENNA, Va. and LAS VEGAS, Jan. 04, 2016 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) - Alarm.com (Nasdaq:ALRM), the leading platform solution for the smart home, announced plans for smart home voice control for lighting and smart thermostats through Amazon Echo. [3] Alarm.com is one of the first smart home security platforms to integrate Amazon Echo. [3] Echo can control both the Belkin WeMo Switch and Philips's Hue light bulbs (among other smart home devices). [4] Suddenly, the possibilities of using an Echo for a smart home controller get much bigger. [4] Perhaps like me, you have various smart home devices such as lights or a thermostat connected to your Echo. [5] When asked about the plans for thermostats, Amazon's spokeswoman, Brittany Turner said, Amazon Echo customers can control many smart home devices today with their voice by just asking Alexa, including lights, and thermostats and more through IFTTT. We look forward to adding more devices soon. [6] Customers can connect Amazon Echo to their Vivint smart home in three easy steps using the Amazon Alexa app. From inside the home, users now have the option to control their smart home using their voice with Amazon Echo, or to use the Vivint SkyControl panel or Vivint mobile app. [7] SPECIAL TO CES - Today at CES 2016, Vivint Smart Home?, a leading provider of smart home technology, announced it is working with Amazon to connect its Vivint Sky smart home platform with Amazon Echo. [7] Many companies demonstrated voice control of their smart home devices via Amazon Echo during CES 2016, including Vivint, Belkin Wemo, Big Ass Fans, Qolsys with Alarm.com, Insteon and others. [8] With Amazon Echo and the Amazon cloud-based voice service Alexa, a simple spoken command, such as Alexa, turn on the living room lights, triggers a response in the home. [3] We thought, Okay, this is now a best-in-class product,? says Jeremy Warren, the chief technology officer for home security company Vivint, which announced at CES that it has integrated the Echo and Alexa into its entire smart appliance lineup. [9] That means you'll be able to control your Nexia-compatible smart home gear simply by talking to Alexa, Echo's cloud-connected, voice-activated AI. [10] Amazon has created perhaps one of the best voice-activated cloud platforms for the smart home yet. [5] The most important name in the smart home is the one you?re least likely to find plastered inside the cavernous halls of the Las Vegas Convention Center: Alexa. [9] As The Verge's Nick Statt notes, this is  Amazon's stealth takeover of the smart home at CES 2016 [5] Amazon has offered up the Echo, but it also lets third-parties use Alexa independently of the company's own smart home hub. [11] Amazon Echo and the Alexa speech engine have changed the way we want to interact with the smart home. [8] How to Make the Amazon Echo the Center of Your Smart Home Think a couple years into the future, as more devices get added to the Internet of Things and are able to connect to Alexa's voice-powered brain. [12] Much like an Amazon Echo, which can be connected to other smart things in your home, the SmartThinQ Hub is designed to connect to washers, dryers, as well as other smart appliances to deliver notifications to you. [13] The Amazon Echo, the connected speaker that uses voice recognition to answer questions, control lights, and plays games, is slated to add another home appliance to its repertoire: thermostats, according to sources who work with the Amazon Echo platform. [6] Vivint customers can talk to Alexa, the cloud-based voice service that powers Amazon Echo, using the Vivint skill and their home will respond with context-aware actions. [7] The $179 Amazon Echo is the hardware home for Alexa, the cloud-connected digital assistant that became one of CES 2016's major talking points. [11] Our forthcoming Amazon Echo integration will turn the idea into reality for millions of Alarm.com users early this year, with voice control enabled by Amazon's Alexa voice service. [2] It appears Alexa is a trendsetter: LG will debut its SmartThinQ Hub next month and it looks very much like an Amazon Echo. [14] What looks like an Amazon Echo, connects to smarthome products but doesn't have a microphone for voice commands? Say hello to the LG SmartThinQ Hub. [14] Amazon Echo is a product, but Alexa is really the platform that matters most. [5] A number of hardware makers took to CES by announcing Amazon Echo integration through Alexa, even though Amazon itself isn't at the show. [5] Ask an Amazon Echo, Alexa, where are you? And you're sure to get any number of witty responses. [5] Our Amazon Echo interface will launch early this year, with voice control for additional devices already in development. [2] Earlier this week, Ford announced it too would integrate with the Amazon Echo. [5] The smart home platform is one of a rapidly growing number of products and services to integrate with the popular connected speaker. [10] Samsung now owns SmartThings, which makes a hub for routing gadgets from multiple different manufacturers, including Samsung of course, through a single app. Walk around here at CES, and you?ll find countless companies hawking the next great smart home ecosystem, with no solution providing any more clarity of vision than the next. [9] At CES Unveiled today, we're unveiling two new, intuitive ways to interact with and control your Alarm.com smart home. [2] Of all the forecasts made here at CES, the smart home feels like one of the nearest to coming true. [9] Making the smart home easy to use is a key to helping consumers realize the full potential of the new technology. [3] This time, it's the Nexia connected home platform that's announcing compatibility with the popular smart home speaker. [10] Alarm.com is the leading cloud-based platform for the smart home. [3] Ford is working to integrate its in-car systems with smart home packages. [5] LG?s device will focus on the connected home–monitoring various sensors and monitoring and controlling smart home appliances–where the Echo is more of a personal digital assistant. [15] Today, there are two basic ways to incorporate Amazon Echo into a home automation system or smart-home device. [8] Homeowners speak to Alexa through the Amazon Echo or Fire TV to arrange appointments on-demand for home repairs such as plumbing emergencies. [16] LAS VEGAS, Jan. 6, 2016 /PRNewswire/ - (CES) HomeAdvisor, a leading nationwide home services digital marketplace, announced the development of the first home services apps for Apple TV, Amazon Echo and connected home platforms powered by Zonoff. [16] Vivint Smart Home announced it was working with Amazon to connect its Vivint Sky smart home platform with the Echo, enabling customers to use a voice-enabled device to control their smart home for the first time. [17] LG Smart Hub Wants to Push Amazon Echo Out of the Home LG is gunning for Amazons spot in the smart home market with its new smart hub in a speaker. [18] What?s Next for Smart Home: Simplicity Trumps Smarts The Nest thermostat and Amazon Echo have raised the smart home bar by focusing on simplicity, and more amazing appliances are on the way. [18] By releasing vast majority of new smart gadgets and technologies at CES, Amazon has set itself in the prime position to be the king of castle at CES. If you want smart home then go for Amazon?s Echo Alexa. [19] During the Smart Home panel I moderated at the show, Icontrol CMO Letha McLaren called Echo the most important phenomenon in IoT over the past year. [8] We will include it in our Smart Home Experience center and it will become the centerpiece of the natural user interface story will be discussing with our clients in 2016. [8] The Hub connects to a smartphone app, allowing you to control SmartThinQ appliances and sensors, as well as smart home devices that utilize WiFi, Bluetooth, ZigBee, and AllJoyn. [20] Marking the first time the voice-enabled device will work with a managed smart home system, this relationship allows Vivint customers to use their voice to control their smart home. [7] HomeAdvisor is currently the only company that has the on-demand technology platform to integrate into smart home devices, making them a leader and innovator in the connected home space. [16] These smart home apps are an extension of the convenience that smart home devices provide for homeowners and advance the smart home from a notification device to a full home-service solution. [16] Even people that have smart homes don't engage with their devices because it's easier to flip a wall switch or press a button than to fidget with a phone and app. And it's even easier to do nothing at all. [8] Smart home systems powered by Zonoff can access HomeAdvisor's Instant Connect when devices in the home detect a need such as fixing a leaky pipe. [16] Chris Terrill, HomeAdvisor's CEO. With over eight million project requests submitted last year and more than a decade of experience, no other player in our category has the scale or technology to offer homeowners a way to instantly and seamlessly connect with a local service provider through smart home platforms. [16] This partnership, announced today, integrates HomeAdvisor's on-demand service with Zonoff's enterprise-scale Consumer IoT Platform for mass-market Smart Home offerings. [16] Linking smart devices like Amazon Echo and (smart home platform) Wink to vehicles via SYNC would fulfill that desire, and allow consumers to connect with their vehicles even when they aren't behind the wheel. [21] The partnership, unveiled at the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas, aims to bring together connected vehicles with Amazon's Echo smart home hub. [21] Keeping with the voice-control trend, Alarm.com announced it will allow customers to control lighting and smart thermostats through Amazon Echo - Amazon's smart speaker equipped with the cloud-based voice service Alexa. [22] We?re excited to work with Vivint to bring Amazon Echo and the magic of far-field voice control to more customers, said Charlie Kindel, Director, Amazon Echo and Alexa. [7] One difference between Amazon Echo and SmartThinQ Hub is LG's placement of a 3.5 color LCD display on the device itself. [13] If you?re a fan of talking to your smart-home devices without pulling out your phone, you?ll be glad to know Amazon Echo had its own slew of compatibility announcements. [23] It's meant to compete with other hubs, like Wink or SmartThings, and it looks a lot like the Amazon Echo. [20] For power Amazon Echo users, adding native thermostat support means that they should be able to group thermostats in with lights to create Good Night or Good Morning settings that works with lights. [6] Along with the Fire TV and tablet, the Amazon Echo ranked in the top five through Amazon's Prime Now service on Christmas Eve. [11] The Amazon Echo lets companies access its platform in two different ways. [6] The innards of the 9-inch-tall Amazon Echo includes a 2.5-inch subwoofer, a 2-inch tweeter, a reflex port and a ring of seven microphones that can make out words through music and across rooms. [11] At CES 2016, LG is finally gearing up to challenge its homegrown rival with a smart home hub of its very own. [20] Set to be shown off at the upcoming CES in Las Vegas, LG has unveiled the SmartThinQ Hub, a core for your smart home. [13] The release indicates that Lowe's and LG will be integrating LG?s smart devices with Lowe?s Iris smart home services, though it's unclear exactly what that means. [20] In the new arena of the smart home, Samsung has SmartThings, and LG has SmartThinQ. [20] LG has also announced a partnership with Lowe's, which sells its own smart home system. [20] It's a strange move for Lowe's, considering it just launched a new version of its own smart home hub. [20] Vivint Smart Home is a leading provider of smart home technology. [7] We believe voice control is the future of the smart home, and Vivint is pleased to integrate with the best far-field voice solution on the market, said Matt Eyring, chief strategy and innovation officer at Vivint. [7] To learn more about a Vivint Smart Home, visit www.vivint.com. [7] Alarm.com is one of the first home security companies to integrate with Amazon Echo, and it plans to expand voice control across its suite of connected devices. [22] At CES 2016 held last week, many new smart gadgets relied upon Amazon Echo and its voice-command operating system Alexa as the central hub of it all. [19] Amazon's Alexa can now narrate Kindle books through the Echo The Verge (3 days ago) – Amazon has put out yet another useful update for its Alexa digital assistant and Echo smart speaker. [24] Echo smart speakers, designed, developed and marketed by the ecommerce giant Amazon have been updated recently. [17] Amazon continues to add new features to its Echo smart speaker with the new updates. [17] LAS VEGAS–Ford unveiled an alliance Tuesday with Amazon aimed at allowing people to connect their cars into smart home networks. [21] Amazon has created perhaps the best voice-activated cloud platform for the smart home yet. [19] Amazon Echo is a great way to control your smart home gadgets, including Philips Hue, WeMo, Samsung SmartThings, Wink, Insteon and more, using just one device. [25] Ford Motor is teaming with drone maker DJI to focus on drone-to-vehicle communications that can be used in emergency zones that are not accessible to ground vehicles, while also exploring technology that will link vehicles with Amazon Echo and smart home platform Wink. [26] LG has kicked off the event early, quietly releasing details on a new Smart Home Hub that is eerily similar to Amazon Echo. [27] Amazon Echo, a combination of a personal assistant and a Bluetooth speaker, has proved very popular for smart homes this year. [25] The car maker now expects to use Amazon Echo, paired with the Alexa cloud-based voice service, to let users access their vehicles from inside their homes. [26] I will tell you what they both are: Amazon Echo is a product, but Alexa is really the platform that matters most. [19] Voice control emerged as a prominent theme, with several major companies unveiling products with voice-control capability enabled by devices like the Amazon Echo (more on that below). [22] There are also solutions for local voice processing, said to Philip Lewer, director of marketing for IOT and smart home NXP Semiconductors, in an interview at CES. NXP already offers technology that allows for localized voice control on low-powered devices in the smart home like lighting, sensors, switches and outlets, he said. [22] Due out in late 2016, the Sengled Voice connected LED light will respond to your vocal commands, and relay them to other smart home devices. [18] Vivint also announced last week that it can integrate with the Nest Learning Thermostat, which allows Vivint customers to choose Nest over Element and allows existing Nest customers to adopt Vivint's full suite of smart home products. [22] Honeywell, a veteran of the smart home industry, announced the expansion of its Lyric line of connected home products last week. [22] The introduction of new products and services is good for the expansion of the smart home industry overall. [22] It's important to note that while LG would undoubtedly love you to go bonkers with its assortment of smart home appliances, as mentioned above SmartThinQ can work with any appliance that follows open source standards. [28] The LG SmartThinQ Hub is just another example of the open approach we believe is the future of the smart home. [29] The Best Smart Home Hub Is Just Less Bad Than Others We reviewed the top five smart home hubs, and all of them had issues. [18] Best Smart Home Gadgets of 2016 Raise your homes IQ with the best smart home gadgets, from security cameras and Wi-Fi locks to cutting edge light bulbs. [18] Established smart home companies are starting to collaborate with connected car startups, such as Vinli (more on that below also). [22] At CES, NXP announced a suite of new production-ready modules and reference designs for smart lighting, smoke detection, and a variety of other smart home applications. [22] Openness and strong partnerships with industry leaders is what will make smart home technology more accessible and more convenient to consumers. [29] Consumer education is still lacking in the smart home marketplace, and that's hindering the next phase of mass adoption, said Greg Roberts, vice president of marketing at Icontrol. [22] Vinli works with the smart home automation system to determine if there are still people in the house once the car has pulled out of the driveway. [22] Against this backdrop, here are some of the top smart home announcements from CES 2016. [22] Amazon's Echo was one of the stars of the retail giant's record-breaking holiday period, and it was only a matter of time before competitors started making their own smart speakers. [24] If you are confusing with what is Amazon Echo and what is Alexa, if you haven?t heard earlier then don?t worry. [19] Last week, Ford announced that it will too integrate with the Amazon Echo, which will turn out be an outstanding integration. [19] Not only that but also the recently added features allow Amazon Echo speaker to play Jeopardy. [17] According to Time, the North American car company is working to make Sync compatible with Amazon Echo. [30] Ford said Tuesday it is also looking at linking smart devices like Amazon Echo and Wink to its vehicles in a way that would allow consumers to control lights, thermostats and their security systems from their cars. [26] Ford is exploring linking smart devices like Amazon Echo and Wink to its vehicles to allow consumers to control lights, thermostats, security systems and other features of their homes from their car, and to stop, start, lock, unlock and check their vehicle?s fuel range from the comforts of their couch. [31] Simple Control announced today that its popular iOS apps for control of AV gear and smart home devices have been certified by Amazon for use with their Amazon Echo product. [32] Ford also said it is looking into linking smart devices like Amazon Echo and the Wink smart home platform to its SYNC-equipped vehicles. [33] One of the highlights of Ford's Tuesday CES event was its announcement of plans to connect its Sync smart car technology with smart home applications from Amazon and Wink. [34] Rated 5.0 out of 5.0 by SB Thank you Home Depot for carrying the Amazon Echo I've been looking at getting one of these for a long time. [35] Linking smart devices like Amazon Echo and Wink to vehicles via SYNC would fulfill that desire, and allow consumers to connect with their vehicles even when they aren?t behind the wheel. [36] Like Amazon Echo, LG's new hub has a built-in speaker that can be used with iHeartRadio or to stream any service from your device over Bluetooth. [27] In a press release, Ford has noted that they have added support for Alexa, the Amazon Echo virtual assistant, within the Ford SYNC infotainment system giving consumers a leg up on those who wish to automate tasks that they'd like to perform with their automobiles. [36] This could be done by using voice commands with the Amazon Echo and its built-in personal assistant Alexa. [37] The carmaker is exploring Sync integration with devices like Amazon Echo and Wink. [37] Drone integration, which Ford also discussed at CES, is driving the connection with Amazon Echo, Chandrasekar noted. [34] LG's tall, cylindrical hub could be described as a copy-cat design of Amazon Echo. [27] It is a brighter, more efficient version than previous generations, and the LIFX Color 1000 works with IFTTT, Nest Learning Thermostat, Apple Watch and Amazon Echo, among others. [25] All-in-all, we are very pleased with our purchase of Amazon Echo, and we can definitely recommend the product. [35] The SmartThinQ Hub plays a central role in LG?s smart home platform by collecting information from smart appliances as well as conventional devices connected to SmartThinQ sensors via Wi-Fi, Zigbee and Bluetooth. [27] The car and home are typically separate domains, but Ford wants to change that by giving drivers the ability to control smart home devices from their car – and their car from their smart home devices. [37] Ford says it is also working with smart home platform Wink, as a means of easily controlling smart home devices from the dashboard or using voice commands. [37] According to Ford, nearly 50% of consumers will buy a device for their smart home within the next year. [36] Ford intends to connect its Sync AppLink with Wink's smart home technology to remotely open a garage, unlock a front door or turn on the house lights, among other things. [34] The new platform communicates via the ZigBee protocol, which is a common standard amongst smart home devices. [27] It's no surprise that LG is attempting to slide into this space with an all-in-one smart home hub and speaker. [27] Data is displayed in the form of notifications on the LCD screen or announced through its embedded speaker, acting as the central hub of the smart home. [27] LG has packed the SmartThinQ Hub with all the typical sensors that smart home users have come to expect including Bluetooth and Wi-Fi connectivity. [27] The LG SmartThinQ Hub is just another example of the open approach we believe is the future of the smart home, said Jo Seong-jin, president and CEO of the LG Electronics Home Appliance &amp; Air Solution Company. [27] LG recently formed a partnership with Lowe?s, the world?s second-largest hardware retail chain, to integrate LG?s smart devices with Lowe?s Iris smart home services. [27] LG?s partnerships with other service providers are a key advantage of LG?s smart home system, which prioritizes compatibility across multiple brands. [27] With the smart home expected to grow, this is an interesting feature for OEMs to integrate in order to provide useful services for the driver, Chandrasekar told TechNewsWorld. [34] Ford also mentions that it is working with Wink, the smart home platform creator, in order further integrate the automobile with the smart home using the cloud. [36] A Shakeout For DIY Platforms With consumers still not entirely convinced they want to buy a DIY smart home kit and install it, DIY smart home platforms struggled to get beyond the early adopter crowd. [38] Openness and strong partnerships with industry leaders is what will make smart home technology more accessible and more convenient to consumers. [27] Wink is looking into ways to expand the use of the technology through advanced machine learning and predictive capabilities that could enable the smart home to automate itself. [34] Wink last fall teamed with Evolved Vehicle Environments on EVE Connect, which connects Tesla Model S and Model X vehicles to smart homes. [34] Dojo provides you with smart home security, will automatically block any attacks, and will alert you if you have to take any action. [25] Before we get to the exciting technology and innovation that the smart home will present for 2016, here is a snapshot of some of best smart home tech from 2015. [25] Each year more and more companies launch smart home gadgets to make our lives easier and more secure, and 2015 was no different. [25] With 2015 breathing its final breath, I thought I'd take a look back at the defining stories and trends for this past year in smart home with a few hints of what this portends for the coming year. [38] Rose demoed Echo with the Vivint Smart Home at CES and was surprised to learn that you can use the device to voice control locks. [39] SYNC Connect and Amazon Echo Ford is looking to use new SYNC Connect technology to link vehicles with the Amazon cloud-based voice service Alexa, which would allow customers to access their vehicle from inside their home. [31] Without lifting a finger, tell Alexa (the Amazon Echo voice interface) to control any of your Insteon devices, or even have Alexa set the mood with some music – and it happens – this is voice control that works! Whether your looking for convenience, or you just want to impress your family and friends – controlling your home with your voice is an experience, and sure to be a conversation piece for all. [40] Once Simple Control is paired with Amazon Echo, users can control the home environment simply by speaking commands to Alexa, such as Alexa, tell Simple Control to turn on the TV in the kitchen. [32] This partnerships works similarly to Amazon Echo, but instead of Alexa doing the chores, the driver can remotely operate the lights, garage door, and other home functions himself. [31] After learning about how Ford plans to use Amazon Echo, I believe that it took a big step in addressing the growing need of consumers to stay connected to their homes while they?re on the move. [31] The Amazon Echo is a speaker and personal assistant meant to be used in the home, but a newer version that's easier to use on the go might be in the works. [41] Simple Control, a leader in IP-based home automation, is one of the first home control companies to gain Amazon Echo certification. [32] With Amazon Echo and Insteon, home control is easy and fun. [40] In addition to its new partnership with Amazon, Ford is also set to begin its collaboration with smart home platform Wink to bring together a number of smart home devices from different companies and put them under one roof. [31] Amazon Echo and Wink connectivity innovations are part of Ford Smart Mobility, the plan to take Ford to the next level in connectivity, mobility, autonomous vehicles, the customer experience, and data and analytics. [31] Linking smart devices like Amazon Echo and Wink to vehicles via SYNC would fulfill that desire, and allow consumers to connect with their vehicles even when they aren't behind the wheel, he said. [33] Being able to link smart devices like Amazon Echo and Wink via the new SYNC system achieves that objective. [31] Families can also use voice control and voice recognition systems to communicate with the smart appliances in their home through the use of digital personal assistants like Siri with Apple Homekit, Cortana with Microsoft Windows, and Alexa with Amazon Echo to activate and monitor devices in their home. [42] Joining Fields on stage, Greg Hart, vice president of Amazon Echo and Alexa Voice Services, explained how smart home technology can be integrated with a vehicle. [43] Since Alexa also powers Amazon's Echo smart speaker and new Fire TV, both devices will likely evolve into smart home hubs in the near future. [44] Amazon's Echo - a voice-activated personal assistant like Siri, designed for the home - has been available to the public for a year now and according to a recent GeekWire article, half a million users have literally said, I love you to the device. [45] Packed inside is a personal digital assistant, an audio entertainment center and a smart home hub. [46] SYNC?s compatibility with the Wink system makes it easier for homeowners to remotely control their smart home devices from the confines of their own car. [31] Compatibility with SYNC AppLink enables Wink users to easily control and automate their smart home device on the dashboard of their car or through voice control. [31] SYNC AppLink and Wink Ford also is working with Wink, the smart home platform that brings together smart home devices from many different companies. [31] It can also control smart home devices such as those made by WeMo, Philips Hue, Wink, and Samsung SmartThings. [41] In 2014, they launched Vivint Sky, with a focus on smart home services complete with their own proprietary app. In the past they've fell as low as an F rating from the BBB, but recently, that rating has improved to a B-. [39] Further blurring the boundaries between Silicon Valley, Detroit, and science fiction, on Tuesday Ford reinforced its commitment to autonomous vehicles, announced smart home integration plans, and launched a developer challenge to turn its F-150 truck into an aircraft carrier for drones. [33] You can start with the basics and grow your system as needed or you can start with a full blown smart home by adding things like cameras, door locks, and connected smoke detectors. [39] This comes as half of consumers say they will buy at least one smart home product in the next year, according to Icontrol Networks. [31] Vivint has added two innovative products to their smart home lineup: the Ping Camera and Smart Doorbell. [39] As smart homes and smart cars continue to evolve, SYNC technology makes it easy to implement features that will make life better and more convenient for our customers. [31] If you aren't sure you want to start with home security or smart home security, we advise that you start small and work your way up. [39] Integration of Insteon devices with with Amazon Echo and Alexa requires the included Insteon Hub (Hub II). [40] Amazon Echo works with Insteon Hub to control a wide range of Insteon devices outside of this kit. [40] Plug in the Amazon Echo, sync it up with your Insteon Hub using the Amazon Echo App nd your voice is now your remote control. [40] Amazon Echo includes Alexa, a cloud-based voice service that can be used to give commands to Simple Control. [32] Possible commands might include, Alexa, ask my Ford to unlock doors, for example. (Alexa is the default name by which Amazon Echo can be addressed.) [33] The Insteon Hub acts as an interface between Amazon Echo and other Insteon devices. [40] When the integration is enabled - no delivery date has been announced - Ford owners with suitably equipped cars and Amazon Echo will be able to interact with certain vehicle systems using voice commands. [33] In addition to their own innovative product lineup, Vivint has also announced that they will work with Nest and Amazon Echo. [39] The Amazon Echo is completely controlled by voice, making it a valuable tool for people who are blind or visually impaired. [46] I've had insteon for almost two years, and was one of the lucky ones to get an Amazon Echo early on (for $99, but Amazon invite) The two have integrated seamlessly, and what Echo can do just keeps getting better! I'm in my late 50s, somewhat tech savvy (emphasis on'somewhat'!) and have had no problems setting it up by myself. [40] Three of 2015s most intriguing assistive technology breakthroughs – the Apple Watch, 6dot Braille Label Maker and Amazon Echo – could be used by everyone, including people with blindness and other disabilities. [46] Ford partners with Amazon to connect cars with homes The automaker is keen to use Amazon Echo and Wink to bring Internet of Things into its cars. [47] Ford is working to integrate SYNC Connect and Amazon Echo to provide voice-control access between the car and home, according to the release. [48] Echo has a new competitor in LG's smart home hub and one look will give you a good idea of where they got their idea for this product. [49] Amazon's Alexa can now narrate Kindle books through the Echo Amazon has put out yet another useful update for its Alexa digital assistant and Echo smart speaker. [12] Ford is joining forces with Amazon to deliver smart home integration: a feature that Fields believes will set Ford apart from the competition. [43] The growth of Amazon's Prime ecosystem beyond e-commerce and into smart homes, vehicles, and entertainment could disrupt the growth of Google's ecosystem. [44] Here is a small sample of the many exhibitors and smart home product lines that were on display during CES 2016 at the Smart Home Marketplace in the Sands Convention Center. [42] When choosing convenient solutions for smart home management, how secure and trustworthy is each piece of connected technology and how reliable are the companies behind them? In the same way that a mobile phone owner considers downloading a convenient app from an online store, evaluate the quality of a company's business practices, along with the quality of its product engineering, before you let that next shiny new device into your home. [42] Amazon Echo with Alexa voice control offers an intuitive and useful way for Alarm.com users to make their smart home safer and more comfortable, said Jay Kenny, Senior Vice President of Marketing at Alarm.com. [50] Ford is exploring linking smart devices like Amazon Echo and Wink to its vehicles to allow consumers to control lights, thermostats, security systems and other features of their homes from their auto, and to stop, start, lock, unlock and check their vehicle's fuel range from the comforts of their couch. [50] Introduced in November of 2014, Amazon Echo was positioned as a wireless, voice-activated smart speaker for the home. [51] Amazon Echo does two-way duty as both an audio player and an electronic hub that activates other connected devices through a voice recognition and control system called Alexa. [42] Alexa to gain a small family: A portable, less expensive Amazon Echo Instead, third-party device makers and service providers are taking advantage of Amazon's Alexa Voice Services and the cloud platform that Alexa taps into. [12] The automaker is keen to use Amazon Echo and Wink to bring Internet of Things into its cars. [47] The technology is not yet available to Amazon Echo users, but work is underway, he said. [48] Qualcomm also revealed a smart home reference platform powered by its Snapdragon 212 processor, a Bluetooth Smart SoC designed for low-power devices, and an expansion of its partnership with pharma giant Novartis to produce connected inhalers. [44] Ford SYNC AppLink drivers also may connect with the Wink smart home platform to create seamless home automation, which would include the ability to program garage doors to open and porch lights to turn on when the driver is a certain distance from home. [48] As homeowners become more comfortable assimilating sensor devices into their ecosystems with minimum installation efforts, smart home technologies could become more desirable for the general public. [42] As the Internet of Things becomes bundled with an Internet of Services, many companies are now jumping into the smart home industry to couple hardware electronics and sensor peripherals together with cellular phone apps that can run on Apple iOS, Android, Microsoft Windows, or Linux operating systems. [42] Iris by Lowes smart home system offers a mobile app that allows a homeowner to view the security cameras in the home remotely, scanning room by room. [42] Ford CEO and President Mark Fields unveiled the future of Ford Tuesday morning at CES 2016, outlining the company's direction toward smart home integration, a feature that Fields believes will set Ford apart from the competition. [43] A gallery of products from Iris by Lowes smart home system. [42] Our theme this year is 2016: Year of the Smart Home and we will be demonstrating the mind-blowing and life-changing features of modern Smart Homes. [52] Virginia-based smart security provider Alarm.com is bringing system controls to television sets equipped with Apple TV, and to the Amazon Echo smart speaker, too. [50] Ford says it's working to connect its SYNC in-car technology platform with Amazon's Echo smart speaker and Alexa virtual assistant – letting drivers turn off the living-room lights from their auto, for example, or start their vehicle using a voice command from the kitchen. [50] Amazon has detailed the latest update to hit its Echo smart speaker, which brings some new sources of news to Alexa's Flash Briefing feature. [53] It looks quite similar in design to Amazon's Echo, but LG is positioning the hub as a gateway to your connected home rather than a voice-activated personal assistant that lives on your countertop. The cylindrical device has a built-in speaker and a 3.5-inch color LCD display that's positioned on the slanted top of the hub. [54] If your connected home is powered by Alarm.com, and you own Amazon's Echo, you'll soon be able to tell Alexa to turn your lights on and off. [50] The SmartThinQ Hub plays a central role in LG's smart home platform by collecting information from smart appliances as well as conventional devices connected to SmartThinQ sensors via Wi-Fi, Zigbee and Bluetooth. [55] The company announced its SmartThinq Hub today, a smart home hub with an LCD display that can control intelligent appliances and sensors and stream music. [54] Compatibility with SYNC AppLink enables Wink users to easily control and automate their smart home device on the dashboard of their auto or through voice control. [50] At CES 2016, ASUS has announced a variety of products, and the latest round includes a new smart home gateway and a rugged Chromebook. [53] This week, LG showed off its take on connecting the smart home, the SmartThinQ Hub. [55] The smart home gateway is based on Google's Brillo platform and utilizes the Google Weave communications protocol. [53] Smart home technology was supposed to be a huge deal in 2015. [55] In addition to the touchscreen, the fridge comes embedded with Amazon?s Alexa voice capabilities and/or can pair with an existing Amazon Echo. [56] As Amazon is wont to do, it has updated the Amazon Echo with another nifty new feature: Alexa can now read Kindle books to you. [53] The device doesn't offer speech commands, which is one of the key selling points of the Amazon Echo. [55] From trivia to traffic to to-do lists, the Amazon Echo personal assistant and speaker has you covered. [57] The latest weekly update to the Amazon Echo brings a number of new features to the speaker, including Star Wars knowledge to answer your questions and you can now find out if you are on the naughty or nice list. [53] POSSIBLY USEFUL You can use the service to program your devices to run routines, react to triggers, or pass commands to other devices in your home. [4] Filling your home with smart devices that let you use your phone or issue voice commands is just the start. [4] Use this recipe to tell Alexa to turn up your Nest smart thermostat. [4] Raise the Roof! What if you threw a party and it was boring? Tell Alexa to put your Philips Hue smart LED lights on a color loop, that's what. [4] What makes the Echo so powerful is its ability to link to and control other devices. [4] Link either of them to your Echo, and you can turn your lights on and off with your voice. [4] The Echo has a seven-minute-workout skill that you can use to get in shape in your living room. [4] Its most unique feature is that it's primarily controlled by Amazon's Alexa voice command platform. [4] On the Echo's product page, however, it's marketed first and foremost as a music player. [4] Invoxia, one of the recipients of an Alexa Fund investment from Amazon last September, announced this week at CES that it?s the first third-party hardware maker to incorporate all the power of Alexa into a product other than the Echo. [9] Nexia calls Echo a more accessible and versatile virtual assistant than the alternatives, and claims that you'll be able to use Alexa to control individual devices or execute any of your programmed automations. [10] Over the course of a few months, however, Alexa has moved beyond Echo and into a host of third-party devices, in part thanks to Amazon?s $100 million Alexa Fund, which helps other companies incorporate the software into their products. [9] It will collect information from smart, connected products around the home. [14] Users can already interact with their homes via the web, smartphone and tablet apps (iOS, Android and Windows Phone) and apps for wearables and smart TVs. [3] Alarm.com integrates devices across the home into a single solution, which we are making easier to use every day through intuitive apps and new user experiences that go beyond the traditional app. [3] Without a booth or logo in sight, Alexa is weaving its way into third-party products here as varied as home security cameras, lighting systems, and Ford vehicles. [9] A few miles from home, you can tell Alexa to turn on lights and adjust the temperature, simply by speaking to the in-car Ford system. [5] Away from home, you can do the same – simply give the same instruction to your Alexa app, and your lights will turn off no matter where you are. [2] A broad ecosystem of IoT devices are easily controlled through a single, intuitive app and automated through intelligent analytics to help keep homes safer, smarter, and more efficient. [3] LG says that the SmartThinQ Hub will allow you to control and monitor washing machines, refrigerators, ovens, robotic vacuum cleaners, air conditioners, as well as sensors around the home. [1] LG says that will allow the SmartThinQ Hub to communicate with a number of sensors, robotic vacuum cleaners, air conditioners and home appliances, such as washing machines, ovens and refrigerators; items which LG just happens to manufacture. [14] With the ability to control customized light groups and names, Alarm.com users can easily create personalized controls for their home. [3] Our innovative smarter home security, video, and energy management solutions are available through our network of thousands of professional service providers. [3] It?s becoming the easiest and most accessible way to talk to everything in your home with a Wi-Fi or Bluetooth chip - and for aspiring smart appliance makers to get a voice interface. [9] Sitting at home you might want to know the fuel range of your Ford vehicle: Simply ask Alexa and she can tell you. [5] Then there's Invoxia's Triby : A small Bluetooth speaker with a magnet so you can attach it to various things around the home. [5] Every day, millions of people depend on Alarm.com's technology to help protect and manage the things that matter most – their homes, families, and small businesses. [3] The Bottom Line: As home automation systems go, the Nexia Bridge offers a great mix of simplicity and functionality, but the monthly fee is a tough sell, especially for casual users. [10] Relaxing in the living room but left the kitchen lights on? Alexa, turn off the kitchen lights, is all you need to say, and your kitchen's smart lights will dim without you having to lift a finger. [2] Owners of an Echo speaker can now ask Alexa to lock their doors, turn off their lights, or adjust their Nest thermostat. [9] It?s not just its looks that recall the Echo, like Amazon?s device it can keep you up to date with your personal calendars and stream music. [1] The name corresponds to Amazon?s cloud-based voice assistant, which began as the personal assistant inside the online shopping company?s Echo speaker that went on sale to the public in June. [9] In addition to joining up with Echo, Nexia unveiled a new Windows 10 app for use on PCs, tablets, and smartphones running Microsoft's latest operating system. [10] You don't need to have a smartphone handy or nearby to use the Echo: You simply speak to the product. [14] Invoxia is currently working on a software feature that, when combined with Alexa, will let the Triby identify every member of a household and prevent certain users, like an eight-year-old child, from ordering a truckload of candy on Amazon. [9] That creates what Warren calls coopetition - or frenemies if you prefer - among startups like Vivint and tech giants like Google, Samsung, and Amazon. [9] By creating a voice interface for asking about the weather, playing music, and the mundane resupplying of paper towels and snacks, Amazon has emerged as the go-to partner for industries in need of powerful natural language processing and fast access to information from the internet. [9] The benefit for Amazon is obvious: voice software tied directly to the Everything Store is a great way to keep people spending money on Amazon. [9] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (61 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) 1. (25) Are We Getting Any Closer to the Smart Home? A Look at Trends From CES | Greentech Media 2. (24) Ford Upgrades SYNC With Amazon Echo And Alexa, Wink | car News @ Top Speed Related Previous post
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/4897201c-4c6c-3a31-8fdd-2d7f099b79dd" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-18T19:19:06Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:02:40.75Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/amazon-echo-at-the-center-of-smart-homes/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
