<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT><NODE id="0" />Sensata Technologies<NODE id="20" /> Holding (ST) Price Target Lowered to $50.00 at Stifel Nicolaus Posted by Kristian Gore on Jan 12th, 2016 // No Comments Sensata Technologies Holding (NYSE:ST) had its target price reduced by Stifel Nicolaus from $54.00 to $50.00 in a report published on Monday morning, Market Beat Ratings reports. They currently have a buy rating on the stock. Shares of Sensata Technologies Holding ( NYSE:ST ) traded up 0.41% during mid-day trading on Monday, hitting $39.56. The stock had a trading volume of 529,847 shares. The stock has a 50 day moving average price of $44.55 and a 200-day moving average price of $46.39. Sensata Technologies Holding has a 52-week low of $38.49 and a 52-week high of $55.53. The company has a market cap of $6.73 billion and a PE ratio of 34.10. Sensata Technologies Holding (NYSE:ST) last issued its earnings results on Tuesday, October 27th. The company reported $0.72 earnings per share for the quarter, topping the consensus estimate of $0.71 by $0.01. The firm earned $727.40 million during the quarter, compared to analysts' expectations of $736.41 million. During the same period last year, the business posted $0.63 earnings per share. The company's quarterly revenue was up 26.0% compared to the same quarter last year. On average, equities analysts expect that Sensata Technologies Holding will post $2.74 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. In other news, VP Geert Braaksma sold 54,874 shares of the business's stock in a transaction on Tuesday, November 3rd. The shares were sold at an average price of $49.29, for a total transaction of $2,704,739.46. Following the transaction, the vice president now directly owns 5,505 shares in the company, valued at approximately $271,341.45. The transaction was disclosed in a filing with the SEC, which is available at this hyperlink . Also, SVP Martin J. Carter sold 66,000 shares of the business's stock in a transaction on Tuesday, November 17th. The shares were sold at an average price of $43.87, for a total transaction of $2,895,420.00. Following the transaction, the senior vice president now owns 38,080 shares in the company, valued at $1,670,569.60. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . A number of hedge funds and institutional investors have recently added to or reduced their stakes in the company. Stock Yards Bank &amp; Trust Company purchased a new position in Sensata Technologies Holding during the fourth quarter worth $350,000. KBC Group raised its position in Sensata Technologies Holding by 248.8% in the third quarter. KBC Group now owns 33,821 shares of the company's stock worth $1,499,000 after buying an additional 24,124 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Eagle Asset Management raised its position in Sensata Technologies Holding by 99.5% in the third quarter. Eagle Asset Management now owns 966,484 shares of the company's stock worth $42,852,000 after buying an additional 481,991 shares in the last quarter. Other research analysts have also issued reports about the company. Zacks Investment Research raised Sensata Technologies Holding from a sell rating to a hold rating in a research report on Wednesday, October 28th. Oppenheimer cut their price objective on Sensata Technologies Holding from $60.00 to $56.00 and set an outperform rating on the stock in a research report on Wednesday, October 28th. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. lowered their target price on Sensata Technologies Holding to $61.00 and set an <NODE id="3463" />overweight<NODE id="3473" /> rating for the company in a research note on Wednesday, October 28th. SunTrust downgraded Sensata Technologies Holding from a buy rating to a neutral rating and lowered their target price for the company from $55.00 to $50.00 in a research note on Friday, November 13th. Finally, RBC Capital raised their target price on Sensata Technologies Holding from $45.00 to $50.00 and gave the company a sector perform rating in a research note on Wednesday, October 28th. Six equities research analysts have rated the stock with a hold rating and six have issued a buy rating to the company's stock. The company presently has an average rating of Buy and a consensus target price of $57.38. <NODE id="4157" />Sensata Technologies Holding N.V.<NODE id="4190" /> is a global <NODE id="4203" />industrial technology<NODE id="4224" /> company. <NODE id="4234" />The Company<NODE id="4245" /> is engaged in the development, manufacture and <NODE id="4293" />sale of <NODE id="4301" />sensors<NODE id="4308" /> and controls. The Company's operating segments include Sensors segment and Controls segment. The Company produce sensors and controls for applications such as thermal circuit breakers in aircraft, pressure sensors in automotive systems, and bimetal current and temperature control devices in electric motors. The Company's sensors are customized devices that translate a physical phenomenon, such as force or position, into electronic signals that microprocessors or computer-based control systems can act upon. Its controls are customized devices embedded within systems to protect them from heat or current. The Company's products include low-, medium- and <NODE id="4968" />high-pressure sensors<NODE id="4989" />, <NODE id="4991" />temperature sensors<NODE id="5010" />, <NODE id="5012" />speed sensors<NODE id="5025" />, <NODE id="5027" />position sensors<NODE id="5043" />, <NODE id="5045" />force sensors<NODE id="5058" />, <NODE id="5060" />motor protectors<NODE id="5076" />, and thermal and magnetic-hydraulic circuit breakers and switches. This story was originally published by WKRB News (http://www.wkrb13.com) and is the sole property of WKRB News. If you are reading this article on another website, that means this article was illegally copied and re-published to this website in violation of U.S. and International copyright law. You can view the original version of this story at http://www.wkrb13.com/markets/1017075/sensata-technologies-holding-st-price-target-lowered-to-50-00-at-stifel-nicolaus/ Receive News &amp; Ratings for Sensata Technologies Holding Daily - Enter your email address below to receive a concise daily summary of the latest news and analysts' ratings for Sensata Technologies Holding and related companies with MarketBeat.com's FREE daily email newsletter . Advertisement
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/32932035-2cde-378c-aa56-eeb1eb11529d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T18:45:53Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:54:22.334Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.wkrb13.com/markets/1017075/sensata-technologies-holding-st-price-target-lowered-to-50-00-at-stifel-nicolaus/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="0" endPos="20" type="organization-company" surface="Sensata Technologies" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="3463" endPos="3473" type="industry" surface="overweight" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="4157" endPos="4190" type="organization-company" surface="Sensata Technologies Holding N.V." />
<Entity id="3" startPos="4203" endPos="4224" type="industry" surface="industrial technology" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="4234" endPos="4245" type="organization-company" surface="The Company" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="4293" endPos="4308" type="industry" surface="sale of sensors" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="4301" endPos="4308" type="product-class" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="4968" endPos="4989" type="product-class" surface="high-pressure sensors" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="4991" endPos="5010" type="product-class" surface="temperature sensors" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="5012" endPos="5025" type="product-class" surface="speed sensors" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="5027" endPos="5043" type="product-class" surface="position sensors" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="5045" endPos="5058" type="product-class" surface="force sensors" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="5060" endPos="5076" type="product-class" surface="motor protectors" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="13" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
<Entity id="3" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="14" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
<Entity id="5" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="15" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="6" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="16" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
<Entity id="2" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
