<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>PR Apex Garage Door Experts ABC Announces Relocation and 10 Percent off Services Dallas, TX -- ( SBWIRE ) -- 02/09/2016 -- Garage Door Experts ABC offers 24/7 services to perform repairs or install an entirely new door when needed. The company has more than seven years of experience providing quality products and reliable service. The garage door experts are familiar with multiple brands and configurations. Free quotes are available online and if customers can find a better price for the same services, the company will match it. High quality services and customer satisfaction is our number one priority, said Holmgren. A garage door can stop working for any number of reasons, resulting in inconvenience and creating a serious security problem. <NODE id="752" />Garage Door Experts ABC repairs<NODE id="783" />, <NODE id="785" />replaces<NODE id="793" /> and installs door opening hardware, dented and damaged doors, and <NODE id="860" />sensors<NODE id="867" />. The company can restore rollers, broken springs and weather seals, along with handles, hinges and door openers. Garage doors are a convenience, but like any machine they require regular maintenance and a monthly check is recommended to keep them working in optimal condition. Garage Door Experts ABC provides monthly check-ups to ensure that cables, pulleys, tracks and mounting hardware is working properly and isn't showing signs of wear. With proper maintenance, a garage door and opener can last for many years, but those with systems manufactured before Jan.1, 1993 may want to consider having them changed. New garage doors must be equipped with reversing mechanisms, a photo eye or <NODE id="1558" />edge sensor<NODE id="1569" /> for safety to prevent entrapment. Garage Door Experts ABC provides removal of old systems and installation of safe, modern doors. A garage door system provides safe and secure storage for vehicles, tools and possessions, enhances curb appeal, and allows individuals to begin their mornings without the need to brave inclement weather to close a heavy garage door. A malfunctioning system is inconvenient and creates unnecessary stress. Garage door repair in Dallas comes with a one-year warranty on products installed by the company's professionals and a 30-day warranty on all labor and repair. The relocation of Garage Door Experts ABC to 1140 Empire Central Dr., STE 433 in Dallas positions the company for greater customer convenience and access to the many services the business provides. Individuals can visit the company's new website to obtain a free quote and receive 10 percent off all services to celebrate the company's move to its new location. About Garage Door Experts ABC Garage Door Experts ABC is a family owned business providing garage door repair and installation services. Media Contact: Eric Holmgren 214-761-3350 Media Relations Contact Eric Holmgren
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1a1e6933-f1f6-3891-80bf-913f38d6db21" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-09T21:03:32Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:45:10.816Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.sbwire.com/press-releases/garage-door-experts-abc-announces-relocation-and-10-percent-off-services-663592.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="752" endPos="783" type="organization-company" surface="Garage Door Experts ABC repairs" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="785" endPos="793" type="trigger" surface="replaces" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="860" endPos="867" type="product-class" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1558" endPos="1569" type="product-class" surface="edge sensor" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="4" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="2" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="1" label="trigger" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
