<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2013 (63) - BMW 5 Series 520d SE 4dr Step Auto [Start Stop] £21,393 Loading Images... Date Registered: Sep 2013 Mileage: 19,745 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £21,393 Colour: Blue Body Style: Saloon Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE EC Combined (mpg) 60.1 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 68.9 EC Urban (mpg) 49.6  &gt; 60 MPG 32 Insurance Group 184 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 0 CO2 (g/km) History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE Insurance Group 32, Satellite Navigation, Bluetooth Telephone Hands Free Facility, Black Dakota Leather, 17 Alloys, Auto Start-Stop, Brake Energy Regeneration, Sport Steering Wheel, Parking Distance Control - Rear, DAB Digital Radio, Headlamp Wash, ''We Can Guarantee The Future Value Of This Car Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01332 425785 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating BMW is renowned for building cars that are great to drive but sometimes at the expense of comfort. read more High-class luxury car feel Superbly refined and quiet Outstanding handling Generous passenger room Forgiving ride Amazingly frugal 520d version Steering lacks some of the feel you'd expect from a BMW Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Bluetooth Connection DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Heated front seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01332 425785 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V socket in rear centre console ABS/EBD Aluminium brake calipers Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Body coloured door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Check control system DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric + heated aspheric door mirrors Electric front and rear windows with fingertip open/close + anti-trap all round Electromechanical parking brake Enhanced bluetooth telephone functionality with USB audio interface + voice control <NODE id="2556" />Fogging sensor<NODE id="2570" /> for front windscreen Front centre armrest Front cupholders x 2 Front/rear Parking distance control Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated front seats Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist iDrive controller and display with 6.5 monitor Illuminated glovebox with lock Isofix rear child seat preparation Luggage compartment release button in drivers A pillar Luggage compartment with electric unlocking via key remote control Multi-function controls for steering wheel On board computer Outside temperature display Personal Profile <NODE id="3113" />Rain sensor<NODE id="3124" /> with auto light activation system Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear centre armrest with 2 cupholders + storage Rear headrests Securing rings in luggage compartment Service interval indicator Speed limiter Tyre puncture warning system Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio/CD/MP3 DAB Digital radio Exterior / Styling Body colour door handles Body coloured bumpers Body coloured side sills Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Front fog lights Headlight range control-electric Run flat tyres Shark fin roof aerial Twin chrome exhaust tailpipes Safety / Security Advanced Head Protection System front + rear <NODE id="3788" />Crash Sensor<NODE id="3800" /> - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Driver/front passenger side airbags Driver/Passenger airbags (Impact dependent) Engine immobiliser Front head restraints with anti-whiplash Front passenger airbag deactivation Fuel cut off safety device Inertia reel front seatbelts+pretensioners Keyless ignition Locking wheel bolts <NODE id="4137" />Occupancy sensor<NODE id="4153" /> for passenger seat Rear door child safety locks Remote central locking Remote control Thatcham category 1 alarm Three inertia reel rear seatbelts Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01332 425785 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 123
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/3463b2d1-a363-3c0a-aa55-8555e03b26f6" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-18T12:38:54Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:55:03.861Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39762907/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="2556" endPos="2570" type="product-class" surface="Fogging sensor" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="3113" endPos="3124" type="product-class" surface="Rain sensor" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="3788" endPos="3800" type="product-class" surface="Crash Sensor" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="4137" endPos="4153" type="product-class" surface="Occupancy sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
