<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Lin Evans wrote: Roland, We had a member here who still stops by every now and then who trolled this forum for months. Every time an image from a Merrill was posted, one could almost guarantee that he would pop up and complain about purple blotching. Not once, not twice, not three times, but in nearly every post he was like clockwork. Forum rules plainly state that if you have a complaint about a particular camera, etc., that you state it once and have evidence to substantiate your view. Everyone who uses a <NODE id="513" />Merrill sensor camera<NODE id="534" /> knows that in shadows with insufficient exposure you could extect some magenta/purple blotching. It was a subject beaten to death. The behavior was the epitome of trolling and flame baiting yet he was allowed to continue unabated. This is why some no longer post on the Sigma forum. They become sick and tired of hearing the same sermon from the same people who somehow believe that if they shout long enough and loud enough everyone will accept their point of view and pat them on the back for being so astute. That is the reason we have rules - to prevent continual bashing, flame baiting and trolling. Perhaps you believe that intent is the operant word here. It's not. The operant word is behavior. Trolling is defined by behavior not by intent. Without rules we have anarchy. Perhaps you believe that is O.K., but some of us disagree and want posters to adhere to the forum rules. Therein lies the difficulty. There is no need to analyze intent, only demonstrated behavior. If it walks like a duck, quacks like a duck and looks like a duck then it indeed is most probably a duck.... I do not disagree with that rules are needed. And I know there are difficult people. And, as far as I know, the moderators do clean it up today and remove stuff. So, it looks somewhat better than it really is. But, it is a matter of being a bit balanced. The guy you mentioned above is probably not a Troll. It rather sounds like idée fixe. A rather common treat in forums, that we might get all of us, once in a while. And note, the guy may have a totally valid point. And that, even if you do not agree. In this case, the <NODE id="2147" />Foveon sensors<NODE id="2161" /> DO have problems with green/magenta discolorations and even blotches. It is well known. I have seen it in several pictures I have taken myself. Its just that you, and probably others, cannot stand it being repeated over and over. So, you get annoyed. Maybe you shall think like this. Just a suggestion. The guy think it is important and cannot really stop looking for the discoloration and mention it. Maybe being kind and understanding is the right reaction? Or maybe just telling that you know, but you work around it. And, if nothing helps, just ignore it. Its not like it is important - is it? -- hide signature -- /Roland Kalpanika X3F tools: https://github.com/kalpanika/x3f
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/d03f6d93-888e-324b-8d43-a420a6f783dc" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-07T01:23:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:54:17.844Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.dpreview.com/forums/thread/3945613?page=4" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="513" endPos="534" type="product" surface="Merrill sensor camera" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="2147" endPos="2161" type="product-class" surface="Foveon sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
