<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Jump to Navigation Home › Global Study on <NODE id="42" />Torque Sensors<NODE id="56" /> Market, 2015 to 2021 The global torque sensor market is expected to witness significant growth over the forecast period, due to emerging applications of the torque sensor, increasing demand for precise torque measurement technology, and high demand from the automotive application segment. New York City, New York, United States., January 19, 2016 - (PressReleasePoint) -   According to the latest market report published by Persistence Market Research, titled ' Global Market Study on Torque Sensor: Rotary Torque Sensor Expected To Be the Most Valuable Product Type Segment throughout the Forecast Period ' , the global torque sensor market is estimated to be valued at US$ 1,105.9 Mn by the end of 2015, and is anticipated to expand at a CAGR of 9.3% from 2015 to 2021 to reach US$ 1,889.9 Mn by 2021.   The torque sensor is a device used for measuring the torque of rotating systems such as electric motors, engine, gearbox, draft shaft, etc. Torque measurement and monitoring are an important parameter in all machines and engines.   The global torque sensor market is expected to witness a significant growth during the forecast period (2015-2021). Various factors, such as emerging applications of torque sensors, rising demand for precise torque measurement technology, and high demand from the automotive application segment, are driving the growth of the global torque sensor market currently. Furthermore, trends that follow with the growth of torque sensor market include: development of non-contact &amp; wireless sensors, growing adoption of quality standard specifications (such as ISO 9000), and imposition of strict government regulations related to machine safety in developed countries.   Request Sample Report: http://www.persistencemarketresearch.com/samples/5069   The global torque sensor market is segmented on the basis of product type, mechanical configuration, application, and region. On the basis of product type, the global torque sensor market is segmented into different types of torque sensor products. The rotary torque sensor segment is expected to remain dominant throughout the forecast period, with high revenue contribution. By the end of 2015, the rotary torque sensor segment is expected to hold more than 53% share of the global torque sensor market. However, by 2021, the segment is expected to lose its market share to other product types segments.   In terms of mechanical configuration, the flange style segment is expected to expand at the highest CAGR over the forecast period. However, in 2014, revenue generated by the flange segment was low as compared to the other segments.   On the basis of application, the automotive &amp; transportation application segment held the largest share of the global torque sensor market in 2014, and it is expected to remain dominant throughout the forecast period. Factors which are driving the growth of the global torque sensor market in the automotive &amp; transportation application segment include increasing adoption of torque sensors in various automotive systems, the introduction of new types of torque sensors by key players, and increasing demand for electric-powered steering systems in vehicles.   The report provides in-depth information about various factors and trends affecting each market segment and provides analysis and insights about the potential of the torque sensor market in specific regions. On the basis of region, the global torque sensor market is segmented into five regions. Among these, APAC is expected to dominate the market, accounting for 31.9% value share of the market by the end of 2015, and it is expected to remain dominant till 2021. However, the Middle East &amp; Africa market is anticipated to expand at the highest CAGR during the forecast period.   View Detail Report With TOC: http://www.persistencemarketresearch.com/market-research/torque-sensors-market.asp   Key market players in the global <NODE id="3972" />torque sensor<NODE id="3985" /> market include <NODE id="4001" />ABB Ltd.<NODE id="4009" />,<NODE id="4010" /> ATI Industrial Automation, Inc.<NODE id="4042" />, <NODE id="4044" />FUTEK Advanced Sensor Technology, Inc.<NODE id="4082" />, <NODE id="4084" />Interface Inc.<NODE id="4098" />, <NODE id="4100" />Honeywell International Inc.<NODE id="4128" />, <NODE id="4130" />Crane Electronics Ltd.<NODE id="4152" />, <NODE id="4154" />Kistler Holding AG<NODE id="4172" />, <NODE id="4174" />HBM GmBH<NODE id="4182" />, <NODE id="4184" />Sensor Technology Ltd.<NODE id="4206" />, and <NODE id="4212" />Datum Electronics Limited<NODE id="4237" />. Key market players are focusing on product innovations and launch of new products to cater to the emerging needs of the customers. For example, in June 2013, ATI Industrial Automation, Inc. launched Wireless F/T, for up to six ATI multi-axis force/torque transducers, which can be powered by internal battery as well as an external power source. In April 2015, Crane Electronics Ltd. launched RFm, which enables reading of torque and angle values in real time and converts them into digital values.   Request Customized TOC: http://www.persistencemarketresearch.com/toc/5069   About Us Persistence Market Research (PMR) is a U.S.-based full-service market intelligence firm specializing in syndicated research, custom research, and consulting services. PMR boasts market research expertise across the Healthcare, Chemicals and Materials, Technology and Media, Energy and Mining, Food and Beverages, Semiconductor and Electronics, Consumer Goods, and Shipping and Transportation industries. The company draws on its multi-disciplinary capabilities and high pedigree gree team of analysts to share data that precisely corresponds to clients’ business needs.  PMR stands committed to bringing more accuracy and speed to clients’ business decisions. From ready-to-purchase market research reports to customized research solutions, PMR’s engagement models are highly flexible without compromising on its deep-seated research values. Press Contact: Addie Thomes 305 Broadway 7th Floor, New York City 18009610353 ****** *e**i**e**e**r**t**s**r** om Email partially hidden to block spam. Please use the contact form here. Contact Addie Thomes
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/d7edb744-82e1-324c-9428-486a01e4af44" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-19T12:52:20Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:57:13.677Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.pressreleasepoint.com/global-study-torque-sensors-market-2015-2021" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="42" endPos="56" type="product-class" surface="Torque Sensors" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="3972" endPos="3985" type="product-class" surface="torque sensor" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="4001" endPos="4009" type="organization-company" surface="ABB Ltd." />
<Entity id="3" startPos="4010" endPos="4042" type="organization-company" surface=" ATI Industrial Automation, Inc." />
<Entity id="4" startPos="4044" endPos="4082" type="organization-company" surface="FUTEK Advanced Sensor Technology, Inc." />
<Entity id="5" startPos="4084" endPos="4098" type="organization-company" surface="Interface Inc." />
<Entity id="6" startPos="4100" endPos="4128" type="organization-company" surface="Honeywell International Inc." />
<Entity id="7" startPos="4130" endPos="4152" type="organization-company" surface="Crane Electronics Ltd." />
<Entity id="8" startPos="4154" endPos="4172" type="organization-company" surface="Kistler Holding AG" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="4174" endPos="4182" type="organization-company" surface="HBM GmBH" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="4184" endPos="4206" type="organization-company" surface="Sensor Technology Ltd." />
<Entity id="11" startPos="4212" endPos="4237" type="organization-company" surface="Datum Electronics Limited" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="12" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="13" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="14" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="15" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="16" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="17" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="11" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="18" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="19" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="20" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="9" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="21" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
