<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (15) - BMW 1 Series 118d SE 5dr Step Auto [Nav] [DCP] £16,599 Loading Images... Date Registered: Mar 2015 Mileage: 12,721 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £16,599 Colour: Blue Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE EC Combined (mpg) 67.3 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 76.3 EC Urban (mpg) 55.4  &gt; 67 MPG 19 Insurance Group 143 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 110 CO2 (g/km) £20 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE SAVE 9071 off new list price, Sat. Nav.,Cruise Control,Air Conditioning,Reversing Sensors Rear,16 inch Wheels,Bluetooth,DAB Radio,Alloy Wheels,Cloth Trim,Driver comfort pack - 1 Series Hatch,Metallic paint, 20 Annual Tax, 67.3 MPG,All vehicles come with the balance of the manufacturer's warranty, are inspected by trained technicians and are history checked. Test drives and part-exchange are available, and you can choose, buy and drive away the same day. For more details on this or one of over 4000 other cars at Motorpoint, the UKs leading Car Supermarket, search Motorpoint.co.uk. (If you wish to enquire about this vehicle please quote 679771) Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01633 730571 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Beauty may be in the eye of the beholder but you would have to be a bit of BMW fan to believe the original 1-Series was a good looking hatchback. read more Better looking than the previous model Fun to drive Superb fuel economy with diesel engines Cramped in the rear Deals will be few and far between Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Navigation system Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01633 730571 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power socket in centre console 12V power socket in passenger footwell 2 cupholders 4 grab handles 60/40 split rear seats ABS/EBD Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Black door sill finishers with BMW designation BMW Assist BMW emergency call BMW Navigation system BMW teleservices Body coloured door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Door armrests Drive Performance Control DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric front windows + one touch + anti-pinch Electric rear windows Electrically adjustable door mirrors Engine start/stop button Folding rear seat head rests Front door storage bins Front folding/sliding centre armrest with storage Front head restraints Front isofix attachment + airbag deactivation Glovebox Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated door mirrors Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist Isofix rear child seat preparation Leather gear knob and handbrake grip 'Lights On' warning buzzer Load restraint lashing eyes Multifunction steering wheel with audio controls Oil level indicator On board computer On board diagnostics Outside temperature display Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear wash/wipe Service interval indicator Speed limiter Storage compartments in front/rear door panels Telematics system Traffic message channel (TMC) Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio with CD player Digital Audio Broadcast (DAB) Tuner Exterior / Styling Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Brake force display Chrome exhaust tailpipe Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Follow me home headlights Front fog lights Safety / Security Child locks on rear doors Crash sensor Driver/Passenger airbags (Impact dependent) Drivers knee airbag Electronic immobiliser Front side airbags ITS head airbags for front/rear Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Remote central locking Seat belt force limiter Thatcham Cat.1 alarm Three 3 point rear seatbelts Tyre pressure monitor Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01633 730571 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 110
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/07705f53-3819-35fb-9abd-43844739f79d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-08T06:46:25Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:38:08.567Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39877304/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
