<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Energy management: Meter data management systems 01/13/2016 Sponsored by Energy meters : A new Leaderboard Report from <NODE id="119" />Navigant Research<NODE id="136" /> examines the strategy and execution of 11 leading meter data management systems (MDMSs) vendors, providing industry participants with an objective assessment of these companies’ relative strengths and weaknesses in the global MDMS market. With billions of data points logged each day from more than 500 million installed smart electric meters, the demand for enhanced MDMSs is growing. Competitive vendors in this market are now investing in major upgrades, offering data analytics and enhanced support for utility operations as well as advanced capabilities 'These players are well-established, often managing millions of smart meter deployments with increasingly advanced meter data management (MDM) platforms,' says Paige Leuschner, research associate with Navigant Research. 'Itron is entrenched in this market with its MDM contracts and innovative product roadmap, though Landis+Gyr, Oracle, and Siemens eMeter are all in close pursuit.' Though leading vendors are working to broaden their MDMS offerings, according to the report, several are also looking past the concept of MDM altogether in favor of multivariate data management systems. These systems are expected to allow data from distributed sensors, smart inverters, appliances, and other devices to be collected, organized, managed, and analyzed alongside smart meter data. The report, Navigant Research Leaderboard Report: Meter Data Management Systems, examines the strategy and execution of 11 vendors that offer MDMSs and rates them on 12 criteria. Each company considered in this report has a solid offering with core MDMS capabilities. Vendors are differentiated by additional platform features, MDMS customers, international marketing and sales, and the vision, strategy, and roadmap for their MDM solution. Using Navigant Research’s proprietary Leaderboard methodology, vendors are profiled, rated, and ranked with the goal of providing industry participants with an objective assessment of these companies’ relative strengths and weaknesses in the global MDMS market. An Executive Summary of the report is available for free download on the Navigant Research website . About Navigant Research Navigant Research, the dedicated research arm of Navigant, provides market research and benchmarking services for rapidly changing and often highly regulated industries. In the energy sector, Navigant Research focuses on in-depth analysis and reporting about global clean technology markets. The team’s research methodology combines supply-side industry analysis, end-user primary research and demand assessment, and deep examination of technology trends to provide a comprehensive view of the Energy Technologies, Utility Transformations, Transportation Efficiencies, and Buildings Innovations sectors. About Navigant Navigant Consulting, Inc. is an independent specialized, global professional services firm that combines deep industry knowledge with technical expertise to enable companies to defend, protect and create value. With a focus on industries and clients facing transformational change and significant regulatory and legal issues, the Firm serves clients primarily in the healthcare, energy and financial services sectors that represent highly complex market and regulatory environments. Professional service offerings include strategic, financial, operational, technology, risk management, compliance, investigative solutions, dispute resolutions services and business process management services. The Firm provides services to companies, legal counsel and governmental agencies. The business is organized in four reporting segments – Disputes, Investigations &amp; Economics; Financial, Risk &amp; Compliance; Healthcare; and Energy. More information about Navigant can be found at navigant.com. * The information contained in this press release concerning the report, Navigant Research Leaderboard Report: Meter Data Management Systems, is a summary and reflects Navigant Research’s current expectations based on market data and trend analysis. Market predictions and expectations are inherently uncertain and actual results may differ materially from those contained in this press release or the report. Please refer to the full report for a complete understanding of the assumptions underlying the report’s conclusions and the methodologies used to create the report. Neither Navigant Research nor Navigant undertakes any obligation to update any of the information contained in this press release or the report. For more information about Navigant Research or other products, click here to go to Utility Products’ Buyers Guide. Sponsored by
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/a4014c3a-6ca6-34bf-8018-e72fff3ec941" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-14T08:08:18Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:37:22.138Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.utilityproducts.com/articles/2016/01/energy-management-meter-data-management-systems.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+UtilityProducts-TestMeasurementProducts+%28Utility+Products+-+Test+%26+Measurement+Products%29" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="119" endPos="136" type="organization-company" surface="Navigant Research" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
