<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>THE MOST FROM THE COAST ! Coastweek website XINHUA NEWS SERVICE REPORTS FROM THE AFRICAN CONTINENT DHAKA Bangladesh (Xinhua) -- A vendor stands in front of his beef stall in a market in Dhaka, capital of Bangladesh. Beef sales in Bangladesh were greatly reduced in 2010 after the outbreak of anthrax. According to official statistics 254 people had then been confirmed to have infected anthrax after taking animal meat or having contact with animals, mostly cows. BRUSSELS Belgium (Xinhua) -- Belgian medical staff are seen outside the Great Mosque of Brussels in the capital of Belgium. Several envelopes containing white powder, suspected of anthrax, had been placed close to the Great Mosque of Brussels located in the Cinquantenaire Park, local media reported. XINHUA PHOTOS - HUANG YANAN and ZHOU LEI U.S. military could hold twelve accountable over anthrax scandal WASHINGTON United States (Xinhua) -- A dozen U.S. military individuals, including a brigadier general, could be held accountable for failing to taking actions that could have prevented the shipment of live anthrax spores to a number of laboratories in the U.S. and abroad in the past decade, according to a military investigation report released Friday. The investigation focused on a lab at the Dugway Proving Ground, a U.S. army facility in Utah, from where it found at least 17 lots containing low concentrations of live anthrax spores were send to 194 laboratories in the U.S. and nine foreign countries between 2004 and 2015. Although no individual or institution was directly responsible for the errors, we did find through evidence that a combination of events, including gaps of science, institutional issues and personally accountability, when taken together each contributed to this event, Army Maj. Gen. Paul Ostrowski, who led the probe, told a news briefing in Pentagon. With respect to individual accountability, we saw failures to take action, we saw best practices by lab technicians not being used, and so the intent is to ensure that the secretary of the Army and the leadership of the Army has an opportunity to adjudicate that. The report identified three current leaders and two former leaders at Dugway who failed to take appropriate action in response to past mishaps and allowed a culture of complacency to exist at the lab. It also identified four personnel who failed to adequately execute oversight responsibilities and to ensure compliance with lab protocols and army regulations. In addition, three laboratory technicians failed to exercise due care in the performance of their duties. Specifically, the report singled out Brig. Gen. William E. King IV, who commanded Dugway as a colonel from July 2009 to July 2011, saying he repeatedly deflected blame and minimized the severity of incidents. When asked to explain what will happen to those that could be held accountable, Ostrowski said: It doesn’t necessarily mean remove and replace. If we have a situation where we have an individual who needs to be retrained, I will say he needs to be held accountable for retraining. Ostrowski also mentioned gaps in science, including a lack of research on the effectiveness of inactivating anthrax using gamma irradiation and post-irradiation viability testing. At the news conference, Pentagon officials also outlined a number of recommendations in response to the anthrax accident, including eliminating Dugway’s missions of producing biological agents for export to other facilities. The recommendations also included new procedures for the inactivation and testing of anthrax and a central process to track and monitor all requests and transfers for biological products. The anthrax scandal was first revealed in May last year, when a private U.S. company reported a low concentration of live anthrax spores in a shipment from Dugway that should have only contained dead spores. The investigation claimed that the event did not pose a risk to public health. . PREVIOUS REPORTS - FROM YEAR 2015: Pentagon orders immediate safety review at nine military labs WASHINGTON United States (Xinhua) -- The U.S. Department of Defense has directed an immediate safety review at all nine labs and facilities involved in the handling of select agents and toxins. The review follows the discovery of live anthrax outside a containment area at a military lab in the state of Utah and incorrect or incomplete record keeping at two other military labs, the department said. The safety review ensures labs will follow appropriate protocols for handling materials, including proper training, record-keeping, and standard operating procedures, it said in a statement. The department also said it has expanded the existing suspension of production, handling, testing, and shipment of anthrax to include critical reagents and other agents and toxins. The suspension applies at all four military labs involved in these activities, including the Utah lab, it said. These measures will remain in place pending completion of the ongoing review and investigation until the Army determines it is appropriate to resume operations, the department said. The safety problem was first revealed in May when a private lab in Maryland found it received samples containing live Anthrax from the Utah lab. In response, the department launched a comprehensive review of all policies, procedures and processes affecting the use and shipment of anthrax. Recently, the department said it had sent live anthrax samples to 50 states and nine countries. . Pentagon under pressure to fix loopholes in anthrax shipment BEIJING China (Xinhua) -- The U.S. military faces pressure both at home and abroad to correct safety lapses in its anthrax shipment process as Congress has held a hearing to investigate the issue. A probe by the U.S. Department of Defense (DOD) released on July 24 found that a U.S. military lab in Utah had failed to neutralize live anthrax spores and shipped the toxic samples to researchers in 86 laboratories in the country and seven other nations over the past decade. The DOD found that live spores were sent to labs in 20 U.S. states plus the District of Columbia, as well as countries including Japan, Britain, South Korea, Australia, Canada, Italy and Germany. Anthrax spores, which are difficult to kill, are neutralized with doses of radiation. Samples are then taken and cultured to see if they continue to grow. If not, they are considered dead. The Pentagon revealed in its 38-page report that scientific information on inactivating anthrax was inadequate to formulate effective protocols to carry out the task, leaving each defense lab to follow its own procedures. The lab at Dugway Proving Ground, Utah, the one blamed for faulty specimen killing and poor testing in the DOD report, should have realized its procedure was inadequate, but it continued using the same process for inactivating anthrax samples, according to health officials testifying at Tuesday’s congressional hearing. The failure of inactivation was evident because growth was being detected on multiple production runs, Dan Sosin, a public health official at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), told the congressional hearing. This hearing is astounding, honestly, Representative Larry Bucshon told witnesses at the testimony. This is anthrax. We should have had policies for decades. It’s ridiculous, he said, blaming the recurring lab safety misconducts on a lack of accountability. At the hearing, the Government Accountability Office (GAO) emphasized the need for a single federal agency to oversee high-containment labs and to develop national standards for lab construction, operation and maintenance—a detailed proposal concerning improvements in federal oversight, which the institution has repeatedly recommended over the years. Marcia Crosse, the GAO’s director for health care, told the hearing that while none of the recent mishaps have resulted in illness, lax biosafety procedures put scientists and potentially the public at risk. We’ve been lucky so far, she said. The incidents you are examining today are part of a long series of safety lapses. With respect to the countries having received active anthrax samples shipped from the United States, South Korea said it will push for a new regulation that requires U.S. Forces Korea (USFK) to notify Seoul anytime an anthrax sample is brought into the country, regardless of whether it’s live or inactive. The statement, issued by South Korea’s Defense Ministry the same day as its U.S. counterpart released the probe outcomes, also vowed a thorough investigation into the unauthorized delivery of the active anthrax sample in April to the USFK’s laboratory in Osan, about 55 kilometers south of Seoul, the South Korean news agency Yonhap reported. . More labs receive potentially live anthrax samples from U.S. military lab: Pentagon WASHINGTON United States (Xinhua) -- At least 51 labs in 17 U.S. states, plus the District of Columbia and three foreign countries have received potentially live anthrax samples, the U.S. Department of Defense has said. That almost doubles the figure revealed last week, but Deputy Secretary of Defense Bob Work told a press briefing the number may rise as the investigation continues. Work said his department found no indication the anthrax shipments sent from an army lab in Utah were a deliberate act. Work confirmed that the Pentagon Force Protection Agency, the Pentagon’s police force, is one of the locations that have received the anthrax samples, which was used to help calibrate sensors to detect chemical or biological agents. The three countries that have received suspect samples were South Korea, Australia and Canada. Pentagon officials insisted there is no known risk to the general public. Last Friday, the department revealed 24 labs in 11 states as well as South Korea and Australia have received suspect samples. . U.S. military accidentally ships live Anthrax to lab: reports WASHINGTON United States (Xinhua) -- The U.S. military has accidentally sent live Anthrax to a private lab in Maryland, U.S. media has reported. The U.S. Defense Department is currently investigating the inadvertent transfer of samples containing live anthrax from a military lab at the Dugway Proving Grounds in Utah, Pentagon spokesman Steve Warren was quoted as saying. Warren added the incident posed no public health risk. Reports said that the anthrax sample was prepared at the Dugway facility as part of routine research and then shipped to labs in Maryland and eight other states, including Texas, New Jersey, New York, California and Virginia. So far, the live sample was only found in Maryland, which received it on May 22. . U.S. military lab may have shipped live anthrax to Pentagon: report WASHINGTON United States (Xinhua) --The Pentagon itself might be one of the locations that have received shipment of live anthrax from a military lab in Utah by mistake, U.S. media has reported. The U.S. Department of Defense is now investigating whether anthrax samples shipped to the Pentagon Force Protection Agency, the Pentagon’s police force, contained live spores, Pentagon officials told CNN. The anthrax sent to Pentagon was reportedly to be used to help calibrate sensors to detect chemical or biological agents. Currently, only one lab in the U.S. state of Maryland has reported actually receiving live anthrax from the Dugway Proving Ground in Utah. The Pentagon and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention are currently investigating if live anthrax shipments were made to facilities in as many as 12 states, as well as Canada, South Korea and Australia. CNN reported that more than 30 shipments already shipped to these locations will be tested. Pentagon officials insisted there is no threat to public health because all the anthrax shipments were shipped and handled under controlled circumstances. . Pentagon blames inadequate testing for live anthrax blunder WASHINGTON United States (Xinhua) -- A Pentagon investigation found that inadequate killing and testing of anthrax specimens were among the main causes of why a U.S. Army lab mistakenly shipped live spores to labs at home and abroad, according to a report released here. According to the 38-page report by the Pentagon, though being regarded as the country’s largest producer of inactivated anthrax for biodefense research use, the Army’s Dugway Proving Ground in the state of Utah did poorly in its testing to ensure potentially deadly specimens were killed before shipping them to labs at home and in other seven countries, including Japan, the Republic of Korea, the United kingdom, Australia, Canada, Italy and Germany. By any measure this was a massive institutional failure with a potentially dangerous biotoxin, Deputy Secretary of Defense (DOD) Robert Work said in a briefing. We are shocked by these failures. DOD takes full responsibility for the failures. The investigation was initially triggered by a sample sent from the Dugway Proving Ground in April. As the subsequent testing were conducted, investigators found that live anthrax had already been sent to 86 facilities across the country and abroad. Work said during briefing that the number was likely to rise because some samples that were sent to third labs had not been tracked down. So far, no one was sickened but eight lab workers who came in contact with the spores were put on medication as a precaution and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommended that three laboratories be temporarily closed for decontamination. . United States scientists urge curbs on creating dangerous pathogens in labs: report WASHINGTON United States (Xinhua) -- A group of prominent scientists have called for limits to lab experiments that could create dangerous pathogens such as the highly pathogenic strains of flu, the U.S. journal Science’s ScienceInsider blog has reported. Three recent safety incidents involving smallpox, anthrax and bird flu in some of the top U.S. labs are a reminder of the  fallibility of even the most secure labs, the report said, citing a statement from a group calling itself the Cambridge Working Group. An accidental infection with any pathogen is concerning. But accident risks with newly created ‘potential pandemic pathogens’ raises grave new concerns, said the statement. Laboratory creation of highly transmissible, novel strains of dangerous viruses, especially but not limited to influenza, poses substantially increased risks that an accidental infection could trigger outbreaks difficult or impossible to control. The group urged that experiments that could create potential pandemic strains should be curtailed until there has been a quantitative, objective and credible assessment of the risks, potential benefits, and alternatives. The scientists also called for a process akin to Asilomar, a 1975 summit that came up with guidelines for recombinant DNA technology. The 18 signatories included scientists who have stridently opposed the so-called gain-of-function experiments, including virologist Michael Osterholm of the University of Minnesota and epidemiologist Marc Lipsitch of Harvard University. Others included Nobelist Richard Roberts of New England Biolabs, former Harvard School of Public Health Dean Barry Bloom, and activist Edward Hammond of the Third World Network. The ScienceInsider report said the Cambridge Working Group hopes more scientists will sign their statement. Concerns about gain-of-function experiments first emerged in 2011 after two research teams genetically modified the H5N1 avian flu virus to make it more transmissible in mammals. The controversial research sparked a year-long voluntary moratorium on the H5N1 experiments, although supporters of such studies say knowing which mutations help the virus spread in humans is useful for surveillance efforts and developing vaccines. . South Korea to probe United States base for anthrax delivery blunder SEOUL South Korea (Xinhua) -- South Korea’s Defense Ministry has said that it will conduct an on-spot investigation into a U.S. air base in Osan for a wrong delivery in April by a U.S. military laboratory of live anthrax samples to the Osan Air Base. The joint task force will visit the Osan Air Base of the U.S. Forces Korea (USFK), some 50 km south of Seoul, at an earliest possible date to thoroughly probe the accidental delivery of the deadly anthrax samples, the ministry said in a press release. The task force, composed of military and diplomatic officials from both sides, was launched on July 11 to look into the case. The ministry said the joint investigation team will investigate into whether the treatment of anthrax samples was conducted according to rules, whether anthrax spores remained at the air base and the ways of treating and destroying anthrax agents. Based on the on-spot investigation, the ministry will take measures to prevent the recurrence of such accidents. The ministry’s announcement came after the Pentagon unveiled a report on the accidental delivery, which said a military laboratory in Utah had sent live anthrax samples in the past 10 years to 86 facilities in the U.S. territory as well as in seven other countries, including the Osan Air Base. . South Korea and United States to hold meeting on 'wrong' anthrax delivery SEOUL South Korea (Xinhua) -- South Korea and the United States will hold a meeting for a wrong delivery in April by a U.S. military laboratory of live anthrax samples to a U.S. military base in South Korea, Seoul’s foreign ministry has said. The Ministry of Foreign Affairs said in a press release that the accidental delivery of the deadly anthrax agents will be discussed on Wednesday afternoon in the ministry’s headquarters in central Seoul. Military and diplomatic officials from the two sides will discuss the accident under the U.S.-Korea Status of Forces Korea ( SOFA) Joint Committee, headed by Shin Jae-hyun, director-general for the ministry’s North American affairs and Terrence J. O’ Shaughnessy, vice commander of the U.S. Forces Korea (USFK). The Pentagon said in May that a military laboratory in Utah sent live anthrax samples to over 20 laboratories in U.S. states, Australia and South Korea, including the Osan Air Base located some 50 km south of the capital Seoul. The two allies also formed a joint working group to probe into the incident and work on measures to prevent the recurrence. . Suspected anthrax alert reported at mosque in Belgium capital BRUSSELS Belgium (Xinhua) -- Several envelopes containing white powder, suspected of anthrax, reached the Great Mosque of Brussels located in the Cinquantenaire Park, the television channel RTBF reported. Firefighters, ambulances are on site and perimeter security is installed near the mosque, a Xinhua reporter noted on the spot. For now, the nature of the powder has not yet been determined but the laboratory of civil protection are already on the scene for analysis with Anthrax device. According to a spokesman for the Brussels fire brigade, two police and others people who were inside are being decontaminated. . Namibia to prosecute farmers for failure to vaccinate animals WINDHOEK Namibia (Xinhua) -- The Namibian government has said farmers who do not vaccinate their animals against diseases will be taken to court. Agriculture acting permanent secretary Abraham Nehemia said that the Animal Health Act of 2011 makes it mandatory for farmers to have their animals vaccinated. Namibia is in the process of vaccinating heifers aged between six and 12 months against anthrax, while those in the foot and mouth disease prone areas are required to vaccinate their animals three or two times a year. For lung diseases, farmers should vaccinate their animals once a year. Vaccinations are free. The farmer has an important role in ensuring that this status is maintained and this press release is a reminder to all Namibian livestock keepers about the compulsory vaccines that have to be administered to their cattle annually in terms of the Animal Health Act (Act 1 of 2011), Nehemia said. Nehemia said farmers should keep receipts or empty vaccines containers as proof to be shown to animal health technicians when they happen to visit their farms. He further said only healthy and fully vaccinated animals will be allowed to move to markets or abattoirs. It is important for livestock keepers to present all their cattle at the specified times and venues to ensure high vaccine coverage and prevent lapses in immunity and potential outbreaks of these devastating diseases in the country, he cautioned. . Dangerous animal infections hit Bulgaria in 2015: official SOFIA Bulgaria (Xinhua) -- In 2015, Bulgaria was hit by four very dangerous animal infections that spread into humans, including avian influenza, West Nile fever, anthrax and brucellosis, an official said here. Prof. Boyko Likov, Director of the Risk Assessment Center at the Bulgarian Food Safety Agency said the highly pathogenic avian influenza H5N1 affected pelicans and poultry in January in the districts of Burgas and Silistra in southeastern and northeastern Bulgaria respectively. In June this year, West Nile fever was detected in a seven-year-old child in Sofia, and in 25 horses and five hens in six districts in northern Bulgaria, Likov said while presenting a report at the 8th Scientific conference of the Bulgarian Focal Point of the European Food Safety Authority. Later on, anthrax in animals and humans in Varna, Dobrich and Targovishte districts in northeastern Bulgaria caused the death of two people after slaughtering sick cow and sheep in July and September respectively, Likov said. The last death from anthrax before these two was 18 years ago, in 1997, at slaughtering of a sick sheep, Likov said. Perhaps the most unpleasant surprise came in August, when brucellosis in sheep and goats has been found in one town and five villages in Kyustendil district in southwest Bulgaria, and in a village in Pleven district in central north Bulgaria, leading to the infection of 40 people, Likov said. The infection probably came from Greece or Macedonia, he said. The previous widespread of brucellosis happened in 2005-2008, infecting 120 people in 12 districts, Likov said. Then, the source of infection were goats from Greece, and we found the negative epizootic aspects of the free movement of goods between the member states of the European Union, Likov said. In 2014, Bluetongue disease was the most serious epizootic problem in Bulgaria, spreading in 2,322 settlements in all regions of the country, and about 37,000 sheep and 300 cattle died, Likov said. In 2015, a mass vaccination was carried out, and there were no new cases, he said. . South African police investigates suspected anthrax case CAPE TOWN South Africa (Xinhua) -- South African police have launched an investigation after 15 people hospitalized for possible anthrax contamination. Scare erupted after the 15 people, including five police officers, came into contact with an envelope containing suspicious white powder in the eastern port city of Durban on Wednesday, police said. The envelope, delivered to an unidentified business around midday, contained a warning: You think you are clever, let’s see what you can do about this. Ten employees of the business - next door to a preschool - and five police officers had to be decontaminated, using special liquid, before being sent to hospital, according to the Daily News. This was the third in a series of anthrax scares in Durban over the past few years, with the first two at the old Durban International Airport, which had been proven fake. . Cattle anthrax outbreak reported in northeast China SHENYANG China (Xinhua) -- An outbreak of anthrax in livestock has been put under control in northeast China’s Liaoning Province, said the provincial animal authorities. Five cattle and one mule died from the disease on July 21 in Xifeng county, Tieling city, said the Liaoning Provincial Bureau of Animal Health and Production. An emergency response was immediately activated and five other cattle were killed,it added in a brief statement. The area was disinfected and the dead livestock were properly disposed of. Anthrax commonly infects all warm-blooded animals, in particular cattle. Humans can catch anthrax by a direct contact with infected animals or by eating contaminated meat. . Peru health director confirms 32 anthrax cases LIMA Peru (Xinhua) -- Peruvian health authorities have confirmed 32 human anthrax cases in the northwestern city of Piura, the region’s health director has said. Jesus Juarez said 49 human cases of anthrax have been reported in the city, 972 km north of the capital Lima. The verified ones have shown typical symptoms of anthrax. The authorities also confirmed that 90 percent of the anthrax cases had physical contracts with infected livestock. Local health workers have been sent to identify potential cases among residents. They were taking tests on the samples from suspected ones. The Piura region has also seen the death of six animals from anthrax over the past month, which set alarm among local residents. The Peruvian government has been monitoring all cases to take preventive measures to stop the spread of anthrax. Anthrax has made periodical appearance in the state of Piura. The regional health authorities issued an epidemic alert in 2008. . Anthrax breaks out in western Zambia LUSAKA Zambia (Xinhua) -- Anthrax has broken out in western Zambia and authorities have since called for cooperation from livestock farmers to tackle the disease, state-run news agency has reported. Anthrax, a serious disease that attacks cattle and other livestocks and is sometimes caught from them by human beings, has broken out in three districts of the province namely Luampa, Kaoma and Nkeyema, according to the Zambia News and Information Service (ZANIS). Western Province Permanent Secretary Mwangala Liomba expressed concern over the outbreak of the disease in the three districts and urged health authorities to put in place measures to ensure that the disease does not spread to other districts. According to the official, 18 people have so far been diagnosed and treated for anthrax after they ate suspected anthrax infected meat but could not reveal the number of animals affected because getting information from the farmers was still difficult. Meanwhile, Provincial Medical Officer Andrew Silumesi said health authorities have started seizing meats from butcheries as a way to contain the disease. The health authorities have also started sensitizing food retailers, market traders and food handlers from restaurants and butcheries on issues related to food safety and hygiene following the outbreak of anthrax. The official however said national regulatory bodies should strengthen protection measures that encourage prevention, early detection and response to food-borne disease outbreaks in line with international food standards, guidelines and code of practices. . Anthrax kills three South Sudanese in northwest Uganda KAMPALA Uganda (Xinhua) -- Three South Sudan nationals have died of the deadly anthrax in northwestern Uganda, state media has reported. The first two deaths occurred at Arua Hospital and one at Koboko Health Centre IV in Koboko district bordering South Sudan, health officials said. Darlington Akusa, a medical officer at Arua Regional Referral Hospital was quoted by state owned New Vision saying the patients contracted the disease from South Sudan but crossed into Uganda in search of better health services. It is suspected that patients with gastrointestinal anthrax get it from contaminated milk or meat. The medical officer cautioned people not to eat wild animals while the health ministry has advised people in the affected area to report to health centers if they develop symptoms associated with anthrax. An outbreak in South Sudan definitely puts our animal population at risk due to epidemiological location, said Willy Nguma, the Arua district veterinary officer. There should be strict quarantine on animals moving from South Sudan to Uganda and people should be on the lookout. Don’t eat meat of animals that die of anthrax and report cases promptly, he said. The disease is often fatal unless treated early. An outbreak of anthrax in Queen Elizabeth National Park killed 200 hippos between August and October in 2004, also leaving those who ate the carcasses dead. Anthrax affects wild and domestic animals and humans exposed to infected animals or tissue from infected animals. Signs and symptoms usually occur within seven days after exposure and vary depending on how disease was contracted. Remember: you read it first at coastweek.com ! TO ADVERTISE ON THIS WEB SITE: www.coastweek.com
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/c3aa7c1b-b324-35eb-954d-e2886224e710" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-19T00:58:01Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:49:31.473Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.coastweek.com/3903-USA-military-could-hold-12-accountable-over-anthrax-scandal.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
