<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Featured Company Featured Company NXP 'Smarter World Tour' Begins Its European Journey GlobeNewswire Thursday, January 7th 2016 The Iconic Smarter World Tour Truck Will Bring the Internet of Things Experience to Our Customers With Nearly 100 Stops, in 16 European Countries, During the Course of 2016. PARIS, Jan. 07, 2016 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- NXP’s Smarter World Tour is starting its journey in Europe today. The Smarter World Tour is a highly visible, 36 tons, 2 levels, fully mobile semi-truck trailer designed by Luigi Colani which turns into a large and spacious mobile tradeshow. The aim of the NXP Smarter World Tour in Europe is to allow us to engage with our customers, partners, as well as universities and communities, and let them discover and experience first-hand the breadth of innovative solutions and technology expertise of the new NXP. The truck features 138 connected demonstrations on-board, highlighting technologies and products that are driving the Internet of Things (IoT) today and connected products of tomorrow, from the world’s smallest microcontrollers to the most complex networking infrastructure through the most secured NFC solutions. The demonstrations are divided into 6 major areas: Secure Connected Vehicle Smart Cities &amp; Energy Smart Home &amp; Building Smart Networks Secure Mobile, Medical &amp; Wearables Start-ups &amp; Communities NXP engineers will be on-hand to guide groups and demonstrate the practicality of an Internet of Things that is already here and what’s to come tomorrow. Our visitors will be able to test the demonstrations, many of them being live, and end-user products, all based on our semiconductors solutions. 'The Smarter World Tour is set to make a major impact on our customers and partners this year. So far, our iconic truck has toured NXP sites in Europe, and everybody who had a chance to see it and experience the demonstrations it embeds had truly been amazed. We can’t wait to bring it to our customers and share with them the breadth of technology expertise, capabilities and end-to-end solutions the new NXP is now able to provide to them, from the sensor to the network to the cloud' said Steve Wainwright, General Manager Sales and Marketing EMEA, NXP Andrew Bickley, Arrow Technology Marketing Director – Wireless Technologies commented: 'The NXP Smarter World tour is a fantastic way to bring demonstrations of IoT enabling technologies directly to engineers. Through it, we can show exactly how NXP and Arrow can help accelerate the development and adoption of IoT solutions and services. 'The EBV IoT is one of the key initiatives in EBV's strategy for the next years. The NXP truck offers a unique and innovative way to present our IoT solutions together with one of our key partners. It brings NXP and EBV at the doorstep of our customers and will astound them with true technical insights.' said Thomas Staudinger, Vice President Vertical Segments and Technical Marketing, EBV Elektronik. 'Securing connected IoT devices from unauthorized access and control is paramount for protecting against calamitous events in the future.' said Jeremy Flann, Vice President, EMEA Sales, Green Hills Software. 'To enable this protection, Green Hills is pleased to be bringing its world leading expertise for securing the IoT to NXP’s 2016 Smarter World Tour in Europe.' Green Hills is the exclusive Operating System and Security Sponsor for the NXP Smarter World Tour in EMEA 'Avnet Memec Silica is committed to not only promote IoT solutions but demonstrate IoT capability from the edge to the Enterprise with the highest level of embedded security. NXP through their global product and solution offering is a key partner of us in this global strategy. This will be demonstrated through Avnet Memec Silica Visible Things platform available soon in the truck' said Philippe Fremont, European Vice president of Technical at Avnet Memec silica Mike Buffham, Global Director of SEPO, Farnell element14, said: 'The Internet of Things is a key technology enabler for us.  Working with our business units Embest and AVID we are able to provide turnkey solutions to some of the world’s leading semiconductor companies to design and manufacture unique development kits and tools to test and prototype applications for the Internet of Things.  We are delighted to be partnering with NXP on this tour to bring the technology of tomorrow to engineers today.' (C) Copyright 2016 GlobeNewswire, Inc. All rights reserved.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/73101054-bfe8-3ddf-8c47-ba5adac8a29c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-07T09:44:53Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:18:43.531Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.virtual-strategy.com/2016/01/07/nxp-%E2%80%9Csmarter-world-tour%E2%80%9D-begins-its-european-journey" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
