<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2014 (64) - BMW X1 xDrive 18d M Sport 5dr £18,999 Loading Images... Date Registered: Sep 2014 Mileage: 6,308 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £18,999 Colour: White Body Style: Estate Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport EC Combined (mpg) 51.4 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 58.9 EC Urban (mpg) 43.5  &gt; 51 MPG 22 Insurance Group 143 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 144 CO2 (g/km) £145 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport SAVE 10631 off new list price, Climate Control,Leather Trim,Reversing Sensors Rear,Bluetooth,18 inch Wheels,DAB Radio,Alloy Wheels, 51.4 MPG,All vehicles come with the balance of the manufacturer's warranty, are inspected by trained technicians and are history checked. Test drives and part-exchange are available, and you can choose, buy and drive away the same day. For more details on this or one of over 4000 other cars at Motorpoint, the UKs leading Car Supermarket, search Motorpoint.co.uk. (If you wish to enquire about this vehicle please quote 673912) Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01633 730571 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Audio remote control Central locking DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Leather seat trim PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01633 730571 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12v power point in centre console 12v socket in front centre armrest storage compartment 4 foldable grab handles - rear with clothes hook 4 lashing points to secure luggage 40/20/40 split folding rear seat ABS/EBD Ambient temperature display Anthracite headlining Anti roll bar front and rear Automatic Stability Control (ASC) BMW emergency call BMW teleservices Body colour door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console with cupholders Dash mounted storage compartments Door sills with M logo Double hinged removeable loadspace cover DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Dual zone automatic air conditioning Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electrically adjustable and heated door mirrors Fingertip control / anti-trap function on electric window Front and rear electric windows Front centre armrest/sliding cover Front sports seats Front/rear adjustable head restraints Heat insulating tinted glass Heated windscreen washer jets Hill descent control Illuminated glovebox Isofix rear child seat preparation Leather gearknob/gaiter/handbrake grip Luggage area underfloor compartment M leather multifunction steering wheel Nevada leather upholstery On board computer Performance Control Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Rake/reach adjustable steering wheel Rear park distance control Rear wiper Service interval indicator Servotronic PAS Stop/start button Storage compartments in doors Tyre puncture warning system Entertainment Auxiliary socket for external MP3 player BMW professional radio with CD player DAB Digital radio Exterior / Styling Adjustable headlights Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Follow me home headlights Front fog lights Low rolling resistance tyres M aerodynamic bodystyling Run flat tyres Welcome home function Safety / Security 3 rear 3 point seatbelts Central locking including boot and fuel flap with deadlocks Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Driver/Front Passenger airbags Driver/front passenger side airbags Engine immobiliser Front and rear head airbags Front passenger airbag deactivation Front seatbelt force limiters Locking wheel nuts Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Rear door child safety locks Remote control Thatcham category 1 alarm Tyre pressure monitor Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01633 730571 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 144
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/7af40a7d-5e71-3cf3-af84-92a30117ba73" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-16T02:30:19Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:21:42.33Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39483197/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
