<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>News Patent Issued for Clipper Mechanisms and Related Devices (USPTO 9242752) Journal of Engineering | Thursday, 04 February 2016 22:10 (EST) By a News Reporter-Staff News Editor at Journal of Engineering -- Tipper Tie, Inc. (Apex, NC) has been issued patent number 9242752, according to news reporting originating out of Alexandria, Virginia, by VerticalNews editors. The patent's inventors are Griggs, Samuel D. (Raleigh, NC); May, Dennis J. (Pittsboro, NC); Poteat, William M. (Fuquay-Varina, NC); Brown, Derek L. (Apex, NC); Gupton, David R. (Wake Forest, NC). This patent was filed on October 9, 2013 and was published online on January 26, 2016. From the background information supplied by the inventors, news correspondents obtained the following quote: Certain types of commodity and/or industrial items can be packaged by placing the desired product(s) in a covering material and then applying a closure clip or clips to end portions of the covering material to secure the product(s) therein. For non-flowable piece goods, the piece goods can be held individually in a respective clipped package, or as a group of goods in a single package. The covering material can be any suitable material, typically a casing and/or netting material. Generally described, when packaging a piece good product in netting, the product is manually pushed through a netting chute. The product can include, by way of example, a non-flowable semi-solid and/or solid object such as a meat product including whole or half hams, turkey, chicken, and the like. The netting chute holds a length of a netting sleeve over the exterior thereof. A first downstream end portion of the netting is typically closed using a first clip. As the product exits the netting chute, it is covered with the netting. An operator can then orient the product inside the netting between the discharge end of the chute and the clipped first end portion of the netting. The operator can then pull the netting so that the netting is held relatively tight (typically stretched or in tension) over the product. The operator then uses his/her hands to compress or gather the open end of the netting (upstream of the product) and then manually applies a clip to the netting, typically using a Tipper Tie.RTM. double clipper apparatus. A clip attachment apparatus or 'clippers' are well known to those of skill in the art and include those available from Tipper Tie, Inc., of Apex, N.C., including product numbers Z3214, Z3202, and Z3200. Examples of clip attachment apparatus and/or packaging apparatus are descried in U.S. Pat. Nos. 3,389,533; 3,499,259; 4,683,700; and 5,161,347, the contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference as if recited in full herein. The double clipper concurrently applies two clips to the netting proximate the open (upstream) end of the package. One clip defines the first end portion of the next package and the other defines the trailing or second end portion of the package then being closed. A cutting mechanism incorporated in the clipper apparatus can sever the two packages before the enclosed package is removed from the clipper apparatus. U.S. Pat. No. 4,766,713 describes a double clipper apparatus used to apply two clips to a casing covering. U.S. Pat. No. 5,495,701 proposes a clipper with a clip attachment mechanism configured to selectively fasten a single clip or two clips simultaneously. The mechanism has two punches, one of which is driven directly by a pneumatic cylinder and the other of which is connected to the first punch using a pin and key assembly. The pin and key assembly allows the punches to be coupled or decoupled to the pneumatic cylinder drive to apply one single clip or two clips simultaneously. U.S. Pat. No. 5,586,424 proposes an apparatus for movement of U-shaped clips along a rail. The apparatus includes a clip feed for advancing clips on a guide rail and the arm is reciprocally driven by a piston and cylinder arrangement. The contents of each of these patents are hereby incorporated by reference as if recited in full herein. Supplementing the background information on this patent, VerticalNews reporters also obtained the inventors' summary information for this patent: Embodiments of the present invention provide apparatus, subassemblies and/or other devices, systems, methods and computer program products for automatically packaging a product in a covering material and/or applying clips thereto. In certain embodiments, the product can be manipulated and packaged so that at least one clip is automatically applied to enclose the product in the covering material. Particular embodiments automatically package a discrete object or objects in netting. Certain embodiments are directed toward systems for automatically enclosing a semi-solid or solid product in a covering material. The systems include: (a) an elongate product chute having an outer surface and opposing receiving and discharge end portions with an interior cavity extending therethrough; (b) a product pusher mechanism having a pusher head that is configured to controllably automatically advance into and retract from the product chute to thereby advance a product from a position upstream of the product chute and through the product chute so as to exit out of the discharge end portion of the product chute; and © a clipper mechanism disposed downstream of the product chute, the clipper mechanism configured to automatically apply at least one clip to a covering material that encloses the product from the product chute. Other embodiments are directed toward methods of automatically packaging an object in a covering material such as casing and/or netting. The methods include: (a) automatically pushing at least one object through a product chute; (b) pulling a covering material upstream of the product chute off an exterior surface of the product chute to automatically enclose the object in the covering material as the object exits the product chute; and then © applying a clip to the covering material to secure the object in the packing material. The pushing can include automatically extending a pusher head into the product chute to contact the object and force the object through the product chute and then retracting the pusher head from the product chute. The applying a clip may include automatically gathering the covering material together and applying at least one clip to the gathered covering material. In particular embodiments, the applying step can include applying two proximately positioned but spaced apart clips substantially concurrently to the gathered covering material. Other embodiments area directed to pivotable dual clipper assemblies for attaching closure clips to a product held in netting. The clipper assemblies include: (a) a retractable clipper mechanism having a clipper body configured to deliver clips to a clip window and attach the clips to netting; and (b) a pair of clipper gathering plates attached to the clipper body so that the clipper gathering plates retract with the clipper mechanism. In operation, the clipper gathering plates gather netting upstream of a product held therein prior to attachment of clips to the gathered netting by the clipper mechanism. Still other embodiments are directed to automatic pivotable clipper mechanisms for attaching closure clips to product held in a covering material. The mechanisms include: (a) a clipper body; (b) a curvilinear clip rail attached to the clipper body having opposing top and bottom end portions and defining a generally downwardly extending clip feed direction; © a clip entry window in communication with the bottom end portion of the clip rail and a clip closure delivery path in communication with a punch mechanism that is adapted to wrap a clip from the clip rail about a covering material; (d) a first clip pusher configured to selectively engage with clips held on the clip rail to force the clips in the feed direction; (e) a first clipper gathering plate attached to the clipper body on a first side of the clip entry window, the first clipper gathering plate configured to extend a distance below the clip rail and generally outwardly therefrom toward the covering material; and (f) a second clipper gathering plate attached to the clipper body on an opposing side of the clip entry window from that of the first clipper gathering plate so as to be spaced apart from the first clipper gathering plate. The second clipper gathering plate can be configured to extend a distance below the clip rail and generally outwardly therefrom toward the covering material. In operation, the clipper mechanism pivots from a rest position to an active clipping position and the first and second clipper gathering plates pivot in concert with the clipper mechanism. Additional embodiments are directed toward brake assemblies for applying pressure to a covering material that is automatically fed over a product. The devices include a pair of spaced apart arms, each having respective gripping members. The arms are configured to move toward each other a distance sufficient to cause the gripping members to contact an outer surface of an intermediately positioned product chute with an interior cavity and to move away from each other a distance sufficient to cause the gripping members to avoid contact with the outer surface of the product chute. The braking assemblies thereby controllably selectively apply a braking force onto covering material held between the outer surface of the product chute and the gripping members. In particular embodiments, the gripping members have a curvilinear profile when viewed from the side. The arms can be each pivotably attached to a common center frame member. The brake assembly can also include an actuation cylinder that is attached to each arm and extends between the arms so that the arms are configured to automatically controllably pivot in concert toward and away from each other. The brake assembly may be configured for braking netting. The device may, hence, further include a netting support roller positioned upstream of the arms so as to contact the underside of the product chute to tension the netting as the netting exits the product chute. In particular embodiments, the brake assembly is used in combination with a product chute with netting held on the outer surface of the product chute. The product chute can have sidewalls that are substantially curved and the gripping members can have a side profile with a curved contour that substantially corresponds to that of the product chute sidewalls. Yet other embodiments are directed toward methods of braking netting traveling over the outer surface of a product chute. The methods include: (a) selectively moving first and second arms with gripping members thereon toward and away from a product chute; and (b) applying a braking force to netting traveling over an exterior surface of the product chute when the arms move a sufficient distance toward the product chute to press the netting against the product chute. Still other embodiments are directed toward automated netting gathering assemblies that include a pair of spaced apart laterally extendable and retractable netting gathering plates disposed downstream of a netting product chute, wherein in operation the netting gathering plates travel toward an axial line of netting to gather the netting material. In particular embodiments, the assemblies can also include a pair of pivoting netting gathering plates positioned on an opposing side of the axial line of the netting. The pivoting netting gathering plates can be configured to cooperate with the laterally retractable and extendable gathering plates to converge the netting material and gather the netting material after a product held in the netting material passes by the netting gathering plates. Still other embodiments are directed toward netting/product chutes having an interior cavity and an exterior surface adapted to hold netting thereon. The chute has a non-circular cross-sectional profile. In particular embodiments, the chute includes an entry portion that has a larger cross-sectional area than an intermediate portion thereof. For example, the chute can have an elongate funnel-like configuration. The chute can include a mounting bracket attached thereto. The mounting bracket may have a planar substantially horizontal mounting platform and a vertical segment with a support channel configured to snugly receive and hold a bottom portion of the product chute. The mounting bracket may be configured as a quick disconnect to allow changeover to a different product chute held on a similarly configured mounting bracket. Yet other embodiments are directed toward a packaging apparatus for packaging at least one discrete object in a netting material. The apparatus includes a product table positioned downstream of a clipper mechanism and a vertically extendable and retractable product holding member disposed downstream of the clipper mechanism proximate an upstream portion of the product table. In operation, the product holding member can be configured to controllably travel down while the netting material is being clipped and then controllably rise to allow the enclosed netted product to travel downstream thereof onto the product table. Additional embodiments are directed toward pivotable clipper assemblies for attaching at least one closure clip to a product held in netting. The clipper assemblies include: (a) a pivotable clipper mechanism having a clipper body configured to deliver clips to a clip window and attach the clips to netting; and (b) a first cutting cartridge mounted to the pivotable clipper mechanism. The first cutting cartridge includes an actuation cylinder with a rod that advances and retracts a knife and an anti-rotation block attached to the rear of the knife intermediate the knife and rod to inhibit the knife and cylinder rod from rotating. In operation, the first cutting cartridge pivots with the clipper mechanism. In particular embodiments, the clipper assemblies may also include a proximity sensor mounted to the cartridge to provide data to control the timing of the actuation of the cylinder to automatically controllably advance the knife to sever the netting. In still other embodiments, the clipper mechanism may include a groove formed therein. The first cartridge can include a cartridge platform configured to slide into the groove in the clipper mechanism to thereby releasably mount to the clipper mechanism. In addition, the clipper assembly can include a second cutting cartridge assembly releasably mountable to the clipper mechanism. The second cartridge can have a cartridge platform configured and sized to slide into the groove in the clipper mechanism. The second cutting cartridge can include a hot knife element and a heat source in communication therewith. The second hot knife element can be connected to a corresponding actuation cylinder to controllably advance and retract. The second cutting cartridge can also pivot with the clipper mechanism. Yet additional embodiments are directed toward automated product pusher assemblies for pushing product through a product chute that dispenses covering material from an outer surface thereof so that the covering material receives a product discharged from the product chute. The assemblies include: (a) a pusher head having a forward portion and axially extending guidewalls disposed on opposing sides of the forward portion, the pusher head configured and sized to enter into the product chute and push an object undergoing packaging through the product chute; and (b) a pusher actuation cylinder attached to the pusher head assembly to direct the pusher head assembly to automatically and controllably linearly travel between a downstream position and an upstream position. Other embodiments are directed toward computer program products for operating an automated clipped netting packaging apparatus. The automated packaging apparatus includes an automated product pusher mechanism that advances and retracts from a product chute and an automated clipping apparatus that applies at least one closure clip to netting thereat. The computer program product includes a computer readable storage medium having computer readable program code embodied in the medium. The computer-readable program code includes: (a) computer readable program code that automatically controllably actuates a pusher actuation cylinder to push a product pusher in a downstream direction; and (b) computer readable program code that automatically controllably actuates a clipper mechanism to position a clipping apparatus in a clipping position in response to product pushed by the product pusher out of the product chute covered in netting. In particular embodiments, the computer program product can also include code that: (a) automatically controllably actuates netting gathering plate actuation cylinders to laterally translate the plates toward the clipper mechanism; and/or (b) automatically controllably actuates a package holding member to raise the holding member above a product support floor to maintain a product held in netting in alignment with the clipper mechanism. These and other objects and/or aspects of the present invention are explained in detail in the specification set forth below. For the URL and additional information on this patent, see: Griggs, Samuel D.; May, Dennis J.; Poteat, William M.; Brown, Derek L.; Gupton, David R.. Clipper Mechanisms and Related Devices. U.S. Patent Number 9242752, filed October 9, 2013, and published online on January 26, 2016. Patent URL: http://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;d=PALL&amp;p=1&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsrchnum.htm&amp;r=1&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;s1=9242752.PN.&amp;OS=PN/9242752RS=PN/9242752 Keywords for this news article include: Computers, Legal Issues, Tipper Tie Inc. Our reports deliver fact-based news of research and discoveries from around the world. Copyright 2016, NewsRx LLC DISCLOSURE: The views and opinions expressed in this article are those of the authors, and do not represent the views of equities.com . Readers should not consider statements made by the author as formal recommendations and should consult their financial advisor before making any investment decisions. To read our full disclosure, please go to: http://www.equities.com/disclaimer You have to be logged in to leave a comment.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0caf880e-ef73-3cf6-b237-cb756dd3944c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-05T23:06:01Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:40:05.294Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.equities.com/news/patent-issued-for-clipper-mechanisms-and-related-devices-uspto-9242752" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
