<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2014 (64) - Peugeot 208 1.4 HDi Active 3dr £8,316 Loading Images... Date Registered: Dec 2014 Mileage: 7,123 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £8,316 Colour: Silver Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: Active EC Combined (mpg) 74.3 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 83.1 EC Urban (mpg) 64.2  &gt; 74 MPG 11 Insurance Group 68 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 98 CO2 (g/km) £0 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Active Insurance Group 11, Touch Screen Media, Bluetooth Connectivity, iPod/USB Connectivity, Front Fog Lights, Remote Central Locking, Electrically Adjustable And Heated Exterior Mirror, Metallic Paint, 60/40 Split Rear Folding Seats, Electric Windows, Height Adjustable Drivers seat, Airbags, Anti-Lock Braking System ( ABS), Electronic Brakeforce Distribution ( EBD) , ISOFIX, Rear Child Locks, Rear Headrests, Immobiliser, 15 Alloy Wheels, Vehicle Mileage Check, Physical Car Available For Viewing Today, Part Exchange Taken As Full Deposit, Flexible Finance Options Available, Comprehensive Health Check, Complimentary Accident Assistance Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01384 500678 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating The Peugeot 208 hatchback has every chance of becoming a firm favourite with small hatchback buyers. Excellent fuel economy Low emissions Stylish looks and interior Comfortable around town Semi-automatic transmission is jerky Stingy entry level model Unsettled ride Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Cruise control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01384 500678 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 1/3 to 2/3 split folding rear seats 3 rear head restraints ABS/EBFD/EBA Auxilliary 12V power socket Body coloured door mirrors Cloth upholstery Cruise control + speed limiter Driver seat height adjust Electric operated/heated door mirrors EPAS ESP External temperature gauge Height adjustable front headrests Intermittent rear wash/wipe Isofix on outer rear seats Manual air conditioning One touch electric front windows Reach + rake adjustable steering column Refrigerated glovebox Service interval indicator Traction control Trip computer Entertainment 4 speakers + 2 tweeters Auxiliary input socket DAB Digital radio Peugeot connect with USB and bluetooth Steering wheel mounted remote controls Exterior / Styling Automatic activation of hazard warning lights Body colour door handles Body coloured bumpers Chrome front fog light surround Daytime running lights Follow me home headlights Front fog lights Full size spare wheel Honeycomb radiator grille LED rear lights Safety / Security 3 rear 3 point seatbelts Child safety lock Driver and passenger airbags Front and rear curtain airbags Front side airbags Immobiliser Passenger airbag deactivation system Remote central locking + deadlocks Seatbelt warning lamp and buzzer Tyre pressure sensor Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01384 500678 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 98
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/2c196881-41cb-3028-95be-330a8ea193b8" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-21T14:48:12Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:51:55.368Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39474048/ds" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
