<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Inclination and <NODE id="16" />tilt sensors<NODE id="28" /> targets heavy industry January 26, 2016 // Julien Happich <NODE id="87" />MEMSIC<NODE id="93" /> Inc.'s MTLT series of inclination and tilt sensors are appropriate for a wide range of static and dynamic applications in construction and industrial markets such as boom tilt monitoring, bucket loader roll back protection, PV/CSP solar tracking systems and others. Samples of the first three family members in MTLT series, the<NODE id="421" /> MTLT110S-R<NODE id="432" />, <NODE id="434" />MTLT105S-R<NODE id="444" /> and <NODE id="449" />MTLT105D-R<NODE id="459" /> are currently available for evaluation. All three products of the series are IP67 rated inclinometers with an integrated RS-232 interface and flying lead cable operating from a 9 V to 32 V single supply. The MTLT105S and MTLT110S are designed for applications needing less than 0.5 degree and less than 1.0 degree accuracy, respectively, over the full operating temperature range. The MTLT sensors also include programmable tilt alarms for tilt safety applications. The alarm can be programmed to be triggered to activate when the tilt exceeds a specified threshold. The tilt alarm can also be used to lock out controls or trigger an alarm or warning light. It is an all-in-one tilt safety solution eliminating the need for an external microprocessor to interpret tilt angles. The MTLT family achieves the best price and performance by utilizing Micro Electro-Mechanical System (MEMS) sensors, extensive over temperature calibration, and MEMSIC's SmartSensing technology providing users with unmatched sensor fusion and performance in critical motion sensing applications. Each unit is fully calibrated over temperature providing confidence in safety applications. Visit MEMSIC at www.memsic.com All news
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/3ae3483a-75f5-3b30-a6a3-11d378de2fa4" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-27T13:06:39Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:57:30.597Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.electronics-eetimes.com/en/inclination-and-tilt-sensors-targets-heavy-industry.html?cmp_id=7&amp;news_id=222927284&amp;vID=209" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="16" endPos="28" type="product-class" surface="tilt sensors" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="87" endPos="93" type="organization-company" surface="MEMSIC" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="421" endPos="432" type="product" surface=" MTLT110S-R" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="434" endPos="444" type="product" surface="MTLT105S-R" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="449" endPos="459" type="product" surface="MTLT105D-R" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="5" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="2" label="product" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="6" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="7" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="1" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
