<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>TV | By Joan E. Solsman on January 27, 2016 @ 9:00 am Follow @joan_e Starry Related CEO Chet Kanojia takes on broadband giants like Comcast, possibly lending a helping hand to cord-cutting The leaders behind defunct streaming-TV site Aereo unveiled an Internet service business Wednesday, poised to upset giants like Comcast and Time Warner Cable as Aereo attempted to upend broadcast TV. The business, called Starry, serves as a cheap, high-speed Internet service with no data caps, plus a separate hardware element to better connect a customer's house with a refashioned router. At an event in New York launching the company publicly, CEO Chet Kanojia called the company's message so not Comcast. Also Read: Supreme Court Sides With Broadcasters Against Aereo Starry is taking on Internet service providers with the same simple, cheap proposition that broadcast TV companies found to be so threatening in Aereo. Starry, however, may ultimately shore up streaming video providers of any stripe. Be it Netflix of CBS' online-subscription option All Access, alternatives like Starry could make it easier for consumers to switch more of their entertainment diet to online watching. But Starry may also make cutting the cable pay-TV cord more attractive, and that could hurt service providers like Comcast and also programmers, who rely on pay-TV revenue for financial livelihood. Also Read: Aereo Files for Bankruptcy: Read CEO Chet Kanojia's Letter With the exception of tiny competitors like Google Fiber in limited markets, high-speed Internet is plugged into the greatest number of U.S. households by cable companies like Comcast or Time Warner Cable. Because of the way the cable industry developed, these companies have virtual monopolies in whatever market they operate, crimping consumers' Internet options in their hometowns. Starry Internet, the service, touted itself as an alternative to the broadband that pipes an internet connection into your home, providing high-speed connectivity over the air with radio frequencies. Starry Internet will launch its first test service in the Greater Boston area this summer, with additional cities to be announced throughout the year. Kanojia said the company's wider opportunity to take this technology to global markets, but he said he has no idea about that timeline. Also Read: Comcast Cable CEO on Altice's $10B Cablevision Play: 'Good to See Others Recognize the Value in the Cable Market' The company didn't detail its subscription cost but indicated Starry would be cheap because costs of deployment are low. Instead of digging trenches to lay wire everywhere it wants to operate, it will pepper its service area with six-foot tall posted panels calls arrays that shoot connectivity like a laser beam at a device in a subscriber's home. That keeps Starry's deployment costs down. It pegged those costs at about $25 for every passed home, an industry term that refers to how expensive it is to make service available right outside your door. That figure for traditional provider can be hundreds to thousands of dollars. Its hardware side, Starry Station, refashions the Wi-Fi router with a touchscreen display, to provide better details about how the device and service is functioning, as well as serve as a hub for Internet-connected devices. Starry Station, which looks like a white skinny pyramid, costs $349.99. Preorders to reserve one will last until Feb. 5, after which it will be available for sale on Starry.com. The company did not specify how much the service will cost consumers monthly. Email 13 Gadgets and People to Get Excited About at 2016 CES (Updating Photos) 2016 International Consumer Electronics Show CES K-1 Assistive Devices are 3D-printable, functional, prosthetic hands that are donated to people in need. 3D Systems The Ōura smart ring is a wellness computer paired with an app designed to help track your sleep and adjust your daily activities to optimize them. Ouraring Secretive California automaker Faraday Future unveiled its 1,000-horsepower electric concept car Monday night. Integrating a partnership with Chinese media firm LeTV, it provides a peek at the company's first production vehicle, set to go on sale in two years.  Faraday Future Cerevo's Tipron is a cute scooting robot that transforms into an Internet-connected projector. Its articulated head and neck allow it to project an 80-inch screen at different heights and angles, and it folds itself to a compact size when your movie is finished. Cerevo Prizm is a twist on the music player. A tool you plug into any speaker, it identifies who is in the room, what their music preferences are and the current mood -- and decides what's best to play. Prizm Sphero's BB-8 is a Stars Wars-inspired wearable wristband that will let you use gestures to control and puppeteer the Force Awakens droid. Getty Images Shaken or stirred? Somabar is a Wi-Fi connected robotic bartender that can make more than 300 different cocktails. Somabar Seaboard Rise's keyboard remodels the portable piano with a soft, sensor-embedded surface that responds to even light touches, and a thin lightweight form that makes it easy to take on the go. Roli Sick of hunting for a AAA battery when your remote goes dead? The Pilot ECO USBCell is a USB plug-in battery that fits the standard AA or AAA size. The first battery of its kind on the market, it can plug into virtually any USB port to recharge. Pilot Sengled Voice integrates a microphone, speaker and LED bulb. Owners can control devices via voice commands, and it can enhance home security and safety by detecting the sound of glass breaking or a baby crying. Sengled The Alcatel CareTime kid's smartwatch is equipped with its own SIM card for children to call for help with the five pre-set numbers their parents approve and a GPS tracker that allows parents to set safety boundary on Google Map and get alert if their kids exit that area. Getty Images Entourage star Adrian Grenier greeted the audience at the Dell Consumer Press Dinner on Jan. 7 Getty Images Sony President and CEO Kazuo Hirai spoke to members of the media during a press event for CES 2016 at the Mandalay Bay Convention Center in Las Vegas on Jan. 5, 2016 Getty Images President and COO of Samsung Electronics America Tim Baxter spoke to members of the media during a press event for CES 2016 at the Mandalay Bay Convention Center on Jan. 5, 2016 in Las Vegas, Nevada.  Getty Images Sony Electronics President and COO Mike Fasulo spoke to members of the media during a press event for CES 2016 at the Mandalay Bay Convention Center on January 5, 2016 in Las Vegas, Nevada. Getty Images Funimation Founder and CEO Gen Fukunaga and COO Mike DuBoise pose with characters as they arrive at the FunimationNow 2016 CES launch party on Jan. 7 Getty Images Nick Cannon (far right) was joined by Alex Hissom, Andrea Wynn, Wynn Resorts Chairman and CEO Steve Wynn for the Encore Player's Club grand opening celebration at Wynn Las Vegas on Jan. 6 during CES. Getty Images Bob Marley's son, Rohan arrives at the House of Marley booth during CES 2016. Getty Images http://twitter.com/share?text=Aereo Team Unveils Cheap, High-Speed Wi-Fi Service Called Starry&amp;via=TheWrap&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.thewrap.com%2Faereo-team-unveils-cheap-high-speed-wi-fi-service-called-starry%2F&amp;t=Aereo Team Unveils Cheap, High-Speed Wi-Fi Service Called Starry http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.thewrap.com%2Faereo-team-unveils-cheap-high-speed-wi-fi-service-called-starry%2F&amp;t=Aereo Team Unveils Cheap, High-Speed Wi-Fi Service Called Starry
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0c80d79a-a0d1-3c4d-8d6a-169d7a206e6f" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-28T13:47:20Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:40:01.24Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.tvnewscheck.com/link/91872/aereo-team-unveils-cheap-highspeed-wifi-service" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
