<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>TMC NEWS TMCNET eNEWSLETTER SIGNUP Advanced<NODE id="43" /> CO2 Sensors<NODE id="55" /> Market to Grow at 42% CAGR Driven by <NODE id="93" />NDIR CO2 Sensors<NODE id="109" /> to 2019 [January 13, 2016] Advanced CO2 Sensors Market to Grow at 42% CAGR Driven by NDIR CO2 Sensors to 2019 PUNE, India , January 13, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- The Global Advanced CO2 Sensors Market 2015-2019 research report studies eminent trends, such as the rising need for better air pollution measurement systems, to drive market growth during the forecast period. This market is an integral part of the global <NODE id="523" />sensors<NODE id="530" /> market and is heavily influenced by the augmented demand for location-based advanced CO2 sensors market, which results in its impressive CAGR of nearly 42% by 2019. Complete report on advanced CO2 sensors market spread across 58 pages, analyzing 4 major companies and providing 25 data exhibits is now available at http://www.reportsnreports.com/reports/456412-global-advanced-co2-sensors-market-2015-2019.html . Advanced CO2 sensors help to monitor the intensity of CO2 in different mediums like air or water and can adjust automatically to changes in temperature, humidity, and altitude. Recent innovations in the electronic industry have resulted in the increased emission of hazardous gases, which leads to global warming. Therefore, in order to effectively measure and monitor the intensity of CO2 in the atmosphere, environmental scientists across the globe are increasingly adopting advanced CO2 sensors. Segmentation by Type and Analysis of the Advanced CO2 Sensors Market cover NDIR CO2 sensors and <NODE id="1539" />Chemical CO2 sensors<NODE id="1559" />. The non-dispersive infrared (NIDR) CO2 sensors segment is set to account for nearly 89% of the total market share by 2019. The long lifespan, stability, and high humidity and dirt-withstanding nature of IR sensors are responsible for its high market share during the forecast period. In terms of revenue contribution, the EMEA region is expected to dominate this market during the forecast period followed by the Americas and the APAC region. The rising incorporation of advanced CO2 sensors in smart buildings is a major factor that is expected to result in this region's high revenue share between the period of 2014 and 2019. Order a copy of Gobal Advanced CO2 Sensors Market 2015-2019 report @ http://www.reportsnreports.com/Purchase.aspx?name=456412 Key vendors in this advanced <NODE id="2345" />CO2 sensors<NODE id="2356" /> market are - <NODE id="2370" />Digital Control Systems<NODE id="2393" />, <NODE id="2395" />GE<NODE id="2397" />, <NODE id="2399" />Honeywell<NODE id="2408" /> and <NODE id="2413" />Johnson Controls<NODE id="2429" />. Other prominent vendors analyzed in this market study are AirTest Technologies, Balluff GmbH, Balluff GmbH, Pepperl+Fuchs GmbH, SICK AG, Siemens Industry, SenseAir AB, Hans Turck GmbH &amp; Co. KG, Vaisala Inc., and Veris Industries Inc. This global advanced CO2 sensors market is highly fragmented as most of the vendors in this market are yet to establish themselves as prominent players with extensive product offerings. Since this market is still in its nascent stage, analysts estimate intense competition between vendors to drive market growth during the forecast period. Another related report on sensors is Global Wireless Sensors Market 2015-2019. Global wireless sensors market to grow at a CAGR of 20.58% in terms of revenue over the period 2014-2019. This market is expected to be driven by a number of factors that will help the market to grow during the forecast period. These factors include the rapid adoption rate of smart devices. These smart devices assist in easy network setup using technologies such as Bluetooth and Wi-Fi support, thus eliminating the need for setting up additional gateways or bridges. The Key players in <NODE id="3573" />wireless sensors<NODE id="3589" /> market are <NODE id="3601" />ABB<NODE id="3604" />, <NODE id="3606" />Honeywell<NODE id="3615" />, <NODE id="3617" />Yokogawa Electric<NODE id="3634" />, <NODE id="3636" />Emerson<NODE id="3643" />, <NODE id="3645" />GE<NODE id="3647" /> and <NODE id="3652" />Siemens<NODE id="3659" />. Other prominent vendors in the market are: Ambient Micro, Aruba Networks, Atmel, BAE, Bosch, Cisco Systems, Draegerwerk, Dust Networks, EnOcean, Freescale, Gastronics, Industrial Scientific, Microsemi, Microstrain Sensing Systems, Mitsubishi Electric, OmniVision, OMRON, Rockwell Collins, Schneider, Silicon Laboratories, STMicroelectronics, Thermo Fisher Scientific, and Vishay Precision Group. Browse Complete Report at http://www.reportsnreports.com/reports/431250-global-wireless-sensors-market-2015-2019.html . Explore other new reports on Semiconductor and Electronics Market at http://www.reportsnreports.com/market-research/semiconductor-and-electronics/ . About Us:    ReportsnReports.com is an online market research reports library of 500,000+ in-depth studies of over 5000 micro markets. Not limited to any one industry, ReportsnReports.com offers research studies on agriculture, energy and power, chemicals, environment, medical devices, healthcare, food and beverages, water, advanced materials and much more. Connect With Us on:   Contact: Ritesh Tiwari UNIT no 802, Tower no. 7, SEZ Magarpatta city, Hadapsar Pune - 411013 Maharashtra, India . + 1 888 391 5441 sales@reportsandreports.com SOURCE ReportsnReports
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/fc274e6d-63ae-33f2-a78f-52bbed263976" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-16T21:39:52Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:11:00.552Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.tmcnet.com/usubmit/-advanced-co2-sensors-market-grow-42-cagr-driven-/2016/01/13/8302026.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="43" endPos="55" type="product-class" surface=" CO2 Sensors" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="93" endPos="109" type="product-class" surface="NDIR CO2 Sensors" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="523" endPos="530" type="product-class" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1539" endPos="1559" type="product-class" surface="Chemical CO2 sensors" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="2345" endPos="2356" type="product-class" surface="CO2 sensors" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="2370" endPos="2393" type="organization-company" surface="Digital Control Systems" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="2395" endPos="2397" type="organization-company" surface="GE" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="2399" endPos="2408" type="organization-company" surface="Honeywell" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="2413" endPos="2429" type="organization-company" surface="Johnson Controls" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="3573" endPos="3589" type="product-class" surface="wireless sensors" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="3601" endPos="3604" type="organization-company" surface="ABB" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="3606" endPos="3615" type="organization-company" surface="Honeywell" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="3617" endPos="3634" type="organization-company" surface="Yokogawa Electric" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="3636" endPos="3643" type="organization-company" surface="Emerson" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="3645" endPos="3647" type="organization-company" surface="GE" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="3652" endPos="3659" type="organization-company" surface="Siemens" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="16" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="17" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="18" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="7" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="19" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="20" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="11" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="21" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="22" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="15" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="23" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="24" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="25" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="9" label="product" />
<Entity id="13" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
