<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>So I had a chance to put my car on a dyno on Friday. There aren’t too many places here in DFW that (a) Have a 4WD dyno that you can run the turbo on, and (b) actually know what they are doing and are familiar with these cars. The shop I used was very knowledgeable, and one of the techs there has a 996TT that has been modded extensively. It’s a Mustang 4WD Dyno, they had to take off the front underside panel in order to access the correct tie-down location. They strapped it down and set a large fan in front, as well as a fan in the back on the engine with the lid open. Two smaller side fans were pointed at the intercooler ducts. My understanding is that the Mustangs typically read slightly lower than other dynos..not sure if that true or not. As a recap, a few specifics on the car: 07 997.1TT 6MT UMW tune Speedtech “sport quiet” exhaust w/ 200 CEL cats GT2RS intercoolers Sachs 2.5 764 clutch kit New plugs/coils 5K miles ago. 93 octane pumpgas (we get good fuel here in TX) I previously had a OTS tune from a popular vendor, which seemed ok, but I was intrigued by the idea of custom tuning. I started talking to Kevin in early December and we did a fair amount of data logging so I could see how the old tune was working vs stock. It was interesting to see how the timing and knock retard were very different vs the stock map.. and I learned about the Durametric and its limitations on reporting timing retard and sample rates. The more data I saw the more I wanted to know about what the numbers mean. I also used datazap.me to plot various parameters while playing with the logger tool. Certainly not necessary, but I love to get my hands dirty in the data With Kevin’s tool you get 25 samples/second and can see timing and retard by cylinder, along with all the other good data. And it's much easier than using a laptop in the car. So during this process we uncovered a few issues, it seemed my lambda was a little sluggish so I put in a new set of wideband O2 sensors, and also I fixed a few minor boost leaks, and also found and fixed the “blown-off” FPR pressure line.. (I tie-wrapped it.) All was accomplished by Kevin looking at logs and me poking around the car on the lift in my garage. Once we got all this sorted out then I loaded the new tune and did some more logging to make sure things were in line.. They did 2 pulls, both in 4th gear sport mode, the best was the second run at 520awhp and 582awtq. These are weather corrected numbers (which I believe is pretty much standard). The shop has a weather station that provided the data to the dyno. I noticed on the dyno computer screen the graph was smooth, but when they printed it out for me it was a little more jagged; my printout has no smoothing applied (Filter value=1) which is I believe why it’s that way.. some shops will apply a filter value that smooths out the edges on the print. I datalogged both runs.. boost maxed very briefly at 1.39bar but was mostly in the 1.1 - 1.2 range and dropping slightly at the higher RPM.. timing retard was good, not too high and overall timing was steady and didn’t jump around (unlike the OTS tune I had), my lambdas look good and crisp (.84 to .86 at full load).. My first run started and ended with high IATs (36C) but they did drop a fair amount during the run itself.. The shop didn’t get the intercooler fans setup until just before the test, so that I'm sure is why.. the car sat warming up for a while. Second run started with IATs at 28C. Clearly the fans are no match to the real airflow while driving at &gt;60MPH.. The key here is to have a good custom tune that leaves a margin for the uh-ohs and is not on the ragged edge.. That’s what I wanted. A few pics and the dyno report from the 2nd run, as well as a video I took. Not that great of a video, I had to stand in the observation room and watch thru the glass. Overall, I’m very pleased, and Kevin’s customer support is top notch. I know the dyno reports aren't worth much but I now have a baseline for any future mods. For whatever reason I cant figure out how to embed the video.. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5cfJ...ature=youtu.be googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-13'); }); Last edited by saabin; Yesterday at 02:55 PM.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/7aa461f2-5c0c-3c42-817f-4919eda6193e" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-17T15:35:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:21:35.651Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.6speedonline.com/forums/997-turbo-gt2/381341-friday-dyno-fun.html#1" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
