<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2013 (13) - Land Rover Freelander 2 2.2 SD4 HSE Auto 5-Door £24,989 Loading Images... Date Registered: Mar 2013 Mileage: 24,892 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £24,989 Colour: Blue Body Style: 4 X 4 Vehicle Trim / Variant: HSE EC Combined (mpg) 40.4 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 49.6 EC Urban (mpg) 32.5  &gt; 40 MPG 27 Insurance Group 190 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 185 CO2 (g/km) £225 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: HSE Insurance Group 27, 1 Registered Keeper, Franchise Approved, Leather, Ebony Black, 19'' alloy wheels, Privacy glass, Cold Climate Pack, DAB (Digital Audio Broadcasting), Heated seats, Parking aid, Satellite navigation system, Clearview Pack, Electric panoramic sunroof, Daytime running lights, 'Say What You See' voice control, 60/40 split folding rear seat, Anti-lock braking system, Auto-dimming interior mirror, Automatic climate control, Automatic headlights, Bluetooth Telephone Connectivity, Driver &amp; passenger airbags, Dynamic Stability Control (DSC), Electric heated door mirrors, Electric windows, Electronic Brake-Force Distribution ( EBD) , Electronic Parking Brake, Electronic Traction Control (ETC), Emergency Brake Assist ( EBA), ISOFIX child anchorage bracket Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01246 642014 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating Land Rover has taken all its off-road knowledge and put it into an upmarket package to create the excellent Freelander 2. Premium feel Practical family car Off-road ability Chunky styling Refined on the move Premium prices compared to similar off roaders Narrow boot Average Owner Review Its load area and wide doors. Fantastic towing capacity and ground clearance. Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Climate control Cruise control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Electric sunroof Electrically adjustable drivers seat Electrically adjustable passenger seat Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Headlight washers Heated door mirrors Heated front seat Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Leather seat trim Navigation system PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Telephone Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642014 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power point front/rear 12V power point in luggage area 3 position memory for driver's seat and driving mirrors 3 rear headrests 60/40 split folding rear seat ABS / hill descent control / electronic traction control Auto climate control with air filtration and air quality sensing for auto recirculation Auto dimming rear view mirror with humidity sensor Auto-dipping door mirrors in reverse gear Auxiliary heater CBC - (Cornering brake control) Cruise control Digital clock Driver information module DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Electric adjustable/heated/folding door mirrors Electric front/rear windows Electronic brake force distribution Electronic parking brake Emergency brake assist Front centre console storage box Front head restraints Front Parking Aid Grained leather 6 way driver 4 way passenger electric seat adjustment + leather steering wheel + front and rear armrests Heated front seats Heated steering wheel Height adjustable driver's seat Luggage cover Map pockets on front seats Navigation system with TMC One shot lowering/closing on front windows PAS Personal telephone integration system with bluetooth Pollen filter Rear centre armrest with 2 cupholders + storage Rear parking aid Rear wash/wipe Roll stability control Service interval indicator Stop/start button Terrain Response Tilt/reach adjustable steering wheel Two rear outer seat isofix location points Entertainment Auxiliary Audio Jack DAB Digital radio Meridian audio system with radio/single cd player/MP3/825W amp + 17 speakers Steering wheel mounted audio/cruise controls Exterior / Styling Automatic headlights + automatic windscreen wipers Clearview Pack - Freelander 2 Cold Climate Pack - Freelander 2 Daytime running lights Design pack - Freelander 2 Electric Sunroof - sliding front glass and fixed glass rear Panoramic roof LED headlamp signature Safety / Security 5 x 3 point seatbelts Drivers knee airbag Dual stage Driver/Passenger Airbags Front seatbelt pretensioners + load limiters Front side airbags with curtain airbags Locking wheel nuts Perimeter alarm Remote central locking/doors+fuel cap+tailgate Robust passive engine immobilisation Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01246 642014 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 185
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/4cb5a4c6-310e-3bd5-85a0-1c360368bd14" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-10T22:55:25Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:04:15.397Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39749254/ds" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
