<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Panasonic to Invest $1.6 Billion in Tesla's Battery Gigafactory Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 19, 2016 C O N T E N T S: Image Courtesy: link: http://electrek.co/2016/01/07/panasonic-confirms-invest-billion-tesla-gigfactory/ author: electrek.co description: Tesla is not officially at CES KEY TOPICS Panasonic has agreed to invest up to $1.6 billion in Tesla's massive battery manufacturing facility Gigafactory, located in Nevada. [1] Panasonic has given the first indication of the expected size of its investment in collaborator-competitor Tesla's battery Gigafactory, which according to the company's president could be up to US$1.6 billion. [2] It has come to light that Japanese electronics company Panasonic PCRFY has agreed to invest up to $1.6 billion in electric car company Tesla's TSLA Gigafactory, a huge lithium ion battery manufacturing plant (for more information on. [3] Panasonic recently announced its intention to invest 50 billion yen ($412 million) in China to build a lithium-ion battery factory expected to go online in 2017. [4] That's why the Japanese company plans to invest as much as $1.6 billion into the massive battery factory that Tesla is building in Nevada at the moment, which is expected to cost around $5 billion by the time it's completed. [5] Panasonic Corp. President Kazuhiro Tsuga said the company will spend up to $1.6 billion on an advanced battery factory with electric-car maker Tesla Motors Inc., an investment it hopes to cement its future in automotive electronics. [5] The Gigafactory which produces lithium-ion battery is expected to cost between between $4 and $5 billion. [6] Under this partnership, the two companies will build a $1 billion lithium-ion battery facility, likely posing serious competition to Tesla's plans of dominating the EV market. [1] Panasonic has agreed to invest up to $1.6 billion in Tesla?s massive battery manufacturing facility Gigafactory, located in Nevada. [3] Author: mashable.com Category: Technology News ID: 763202 Date: 17.01.2016 This article is added by: Adam G Headline: Report: Panasonic promises $1.6 billion toward Teslas battery-making Gigafactory Keywords: report, panasonic, promises, billion, teslas, battery, making, gigafactory, This news Report: Panasonic promises $1.6 billion toward Teslas battery-making Gigafactory is just exerpt of its original. [7] Considering that total project development costs for the Gigafactory are expected to be somewhere around $4-5 billion, the chunk being fronted by Panasonic is really quite significant showcasing how serious the Japanese company takes Tesla's goals/projections. [8] Panasonic is investing $1.6 billion in Tesla's Gigafactory in Nevada. [6] Panasonic confirmed today that it plans to invest between $1.5 billion and $1.6 billion in the Gigafactory. [4] Panasonic President Kazuhiro Tsuga said the company is planning an investment of $1.6 billion into Tesla?s advanced battery factory in a hope of cementing its position in future automotive electronics, says a report from The Wall Street Journal. [9] Panasonic confirmed being a partner in Tesla's battery factory early in the development of the project, but other than some estimates from Tesla, the electronic giant never committed to a dollar amount in investment until today. [4] Throughout its project to build a massive battery Gigafactory near Reno, Nevada, Tesla has had assistance from its current battery supplier, Panasonic. [10] Unlike the Gigafactory, which is expected to produce cylindrical battery cells, Panasonic's new Chinese factory will produce rectangular-shaped batteries. [4] The Gigafactory will start producing cells later this year, but it already started producing battery packs for Tesla's stationary energy storage products. [4] Panasonic, meanwhile, says it could invest as much as $1.6 billion in Tesla's Gigafactory, which is expected to cost around $5 billion. [11] Panasonic hasn't previously disclosed the amount it plans to invest in the $5 billion project, which will provide the economy of scale to lower the prices of Tesla electric cars. [10] Tesla Motors Inc is on track to construct a massive $5 billion battery pack manufacturing facility – the Gigafactory – in Nevada. [3] Tesla Motors Inc (NASDAQ:TSLA) is looking forward to hire employees for its stationary energy storage unit, which will be diversifying the use of battery packs produced at the $5 billion Gigafactory currently under construction in Nevada. [3] The electric car company and its partners are investing about $5 billion in total to get its giant battery plant, called the Gigafactory, up and. [12] Japanese electronics maker Panasonic said it would spend up to $1.6 billion on an advanced battery factory with electric-car maker Tesla Motors, the first time it has detailed the full scope of its involvement. [3] Report: Panasonic promises $1.6 billion toward Tesla's battery-making Gigafactory. [13] Wall Street Journal reports that Panasonic's President Kazuhiro Tsuga has said that his firm will invest up to $1.6B in Tesla's Gigafactory. [14] The credits are proportional to whatever Tesla invests in the Gigafactory, and there's no liability on Tesla's part if it doesn't meet any particular goal for the Gigafactory investment. [15] In June 2015, news broke that Tesla has teamed up with Panasonic Corp – in a deal in which later will invest $500M and send hundreds of its workers to the Gigafactory. [14] At CES in Las Vegas, Panasonic ( OTCPK:PCRFY ) President Tsuga confirmed that the company will spend up to $1.6 billion on the Tesla (NASDAQ: TSLA ) Gigafactory located in Sparks, Nevada. [15] Tesla and Panasonic are jointly investing up to $5 billion in the Gigafactory. [9] Panasonic has committed up to $1.6 billion for the Gigafactory. [15] Undoubtedly, Panasonic will ramp up its commitment as needed to support battery production, not only for the Model 3, but early on for the Model S and X, providing some much needed cost reduction in Tesla's current offerings. [15] Panasonic hasn't previously disclosed the amount it plans to invest in the $5 billion project, which will provide the economy of scale to lower the prices of Tesla electric cars. [16] Tesla's road to a cheaper electric car has always appeared to lead straight to Reno, where the electric automaker is building a $5 billion gigafactory designed with enough capacity to reduce the. [12] Construction of Tesla's $5 billion Gigafactory is in full swing. [3] By (Stephen Edelstein) Today, the company that sold the most plug-in electric cars worldwide in 2015 isn't one of the usual suspects, the 2017 Ford Fusion Hybrid and Fusion Energi plug-in hybrid get some updates, and Panasonic commits $1.6 billion to the Tesla battery Gigafactory. [17] By (Stephen Edelstein) Throughout its project to build a massive battery Gigafactory near Reno, Nevada, Tesla has had assistance from its current battery supplier, Panasonic. [17] POSSIBLY USEFUL The Japanese consumer electronics giant and Tesla are jointly funding an up to $5 billion battery plant in Nevada. [18] The $5 billion battery factory is expected to reach full production capacity by 2020. [1] Tesla made clear its plan to remain in control of the project and to contribute the majority of the estimated $4 billion to $5 billion investment required to build its massive battery factory. [4] LAS VEGAS–Panasonic Corp. President Kazuhiro Tsuga said the company will spend up to $1.6 billion on an advanced battery factory with electric-car maker Tesla Motors Inc., an investment it hopes to cement its future in automotive electronics. [18] According to MarketWatch, the Japanese electronics company has promised up to $1.6 billion toward the construction of Tesla Motors' lithium-ion battery-producing Gigafactory in Nevada. [19] The company will reportedly be putting up to $1.6 billion into the Gigafactory being developed in concert with the noted electric vehicle (EV) manufacturer, according to Tsuga. [8] Panasonic and Tesla signed an official agreement regarding the Gigafactory in July 2014. [8] According to previously-released terms, about half of the Gigafactory is to be devoted to cell production supervised by Panasonic. [10] Volkswagen and General Motors have similar lithium-ion battery production deals with South Korean LG. Back in Nevada, however, Tesla and Panasonic face another threat. [19] The battery partnership between Panasonic and Tesla faces risk from rival companies. [1] Panasonic also faces rising competition from South Korean battery makers that have contracts to supply electric and hybrid vehicles coming from General Motors Co. and Volkswagen AG. [5] Even if Panasonic is only confirming an amount in the low-end of the estimate, it's still a welcomed commitment from a major player in battery manufacturing. [4] Though, Panasonic faces stiffer competition from Korean battery suppliers Samsung SDI and LG Chem. [10] To date, lithium-ion battery producers have struggled to remain profitable - especially as oil prices continue to drop. Regardless of how it all pans out for Tesla, Panasonic and the others, it's clear that the future of mobility will at least be electrically driven. [19] Panasonic has been quite silent before on its investment in this $5 billion project which is a step towards making Tesla cars affordable. [6] The $1.6 billion investment Panasonic revealed at CES is significantly higher than the $92 million it had previously discussed. [10] Tesla is not officially at CES this year, but Panasonic brought a Model S to its booth. [4] It will be several years before that factory is humming at full steam, and for Panasonic the wait. [18] Panasonic hasn?t previously disclosed the full size of its investment. [18] The battery investment is one element of Osaka-based Panasonic's drive to become a major auto parts supplier, taking advantage of the computerization of the automobile and forecasts for robust global demand for light vehicles in coming decades. [8] Through this project, Tesla plans to further lower battery production cost by 30%, and reach a delivery mark of half a million auto units. [1] Considering Tesla both increased the planned floor space and said that the project is more space efficient than initially expected, it is fair to assume that the planned production output is now more than the initial 35 GWh of battery cells and 50 GWh of battery packs. [4] The factory is specially build to reduce the production cost of Tesla's EV battery and Powerwall packs. [6] The other half will be occupied by suppliers and assembly lines for cell modules and battery packs. [10] The latter will supply battery cells and many other components for the 2017 Chevrolet Bolt EV as part of a far-reaching partnership with General Motors. [10] We learned late last year that Tesla?s Gigafactory will be nearly 40% larger than expected, but the company has yet to update the production output since the unveiling of the project. [4] The Tesla gigafactory is expected to be operational by 2016 or 2017. [6] Tesla is expected to sell 500,000 units annually by 2020, once the gigafactory is completed. [6] Panasonic's continued involvement in the Gigafactory project is reportedly part of plan to grow the company's presence in the automotive sector. [10] To make the EVs more affordable for the masses, Tesla Motors plans to launch Model 3, and for that it has been counting on its Gigafactory. [1] The company has delayed each of its new-vehicle launches, and the added variable of the Gigafactory could make the Model 3 launch more complex than previous models. [10] Now, the company–which also owns a small stake in Tesla–says it will spend up to $1.6 billion on the Gigafactory. [10] Tesla CEO Elon Musk had estimated that Panasonic?s contribution will be $1.5 billion to $2 billion. [4] This fiscal year, it is expected to contribute Yen1.3 trillion ($11 billion), about 15% of the company's revenue, but will grow to nearly 25% of revenue by the end of the decade. [8] Faraday Future will be breaking ground on its $1 billion, 3-million-square-foot production facility backed by Chinese tech giant Letv. [19] The project is believed to cost between $4 and $5 billion to complete and won't be online for several years. [19] As Tesla's are as well the company is aiming for sales of 500,000 vehicles a year by 2020 after all. [8] According to MarketWatch, Panasonic president Kazuhiro Tsuga said that the company is waiting for an increase in demand for Tesla's EVs; if Tesla's vision becomes a mass-market hit, the company would get more opportunities to grow. [1] We are sort of waiting on the demand from Tesla, Panasonic President Kazuhiro Tsuga told MarketWatch. [19] That estimate came from Panasonic president Kazuhiro Tsuga, speaking to MarketWatch at the recent Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas. [10] Panasonic is already a major player in the automotive electronics market, but it wants to make sure that the transition to electric vehicles won't threaten its position. [5] Panasonic aims to increase annual revenue to Yen10 trillion by its fiscal year ending in March 2019. [8] The statement was released by Panasonic Corp. President Kazuh. [6] If it does meet that goal, Tesla will likely account for the largest portion of Panasonic's planned automotive-market growth. [10] Panasonic's sales to auto makers are expected to nearly double over the next four years. [8] Sales to carmakers accounted for about 15 percent of Panasonic's revenue in 2015, but the total revenue is expected to double over the next four years, representing 25 percent of the total. [10] The company has expressed its belief that electric vehicles could be a major source of growth in the future, and it's believed that Panasonic's automotive business could account for 25% of its revenue by 2020. [5] Even if gas prices stay low and the break-out for EVs is delayed for a few years the scale of the gigafactory will drop prices opening new markets. [8] Tesla's vehicle growth projections are huge, but low gasoline prices have damped overall demand for electric vehicles. [5] Panasonic President Kazuhiro Tsuga made the comment while talking with the WSJ at CES in Las Vegas. [4] Yesterday Nikkei Asian Review quoted an unnamed Tesla official said that Panasonic will be the initial exclusive supplier of battery packs to the Model 3, expected to launch in 2017. [2] Panasonic is also getting tough competition from South Korean battery makers, which have contracts from automakers such as General Motors and Volkswagen for the supply of electric and hybrid vehicles, says The WSJ. Panasonic intends to become a major auto parts supplier, and battery investment is just one element of its goal. [9] Apart from sending key talent to assist Tesla at at the Gigafactory, Panasonic has increased its investment by more than 220% within 6 months. [14] According to MarketWatch, the Japanese electronics company has promised up to $1.6 billion toward the construction of Tesla Motors? lithium-ion battery-producing Gigafactory in Nevada. [13] Strong demand, meanwhile, has prompted Tesla to shift Powerwall production to the Gigafactory it is building in Sparks, Nevada. [11] Tesla broke ground on its Gigafactory – so called because it will be able to produce 35 GWh of batteries when it reaches full production in 2020 – in June 2014. [11] The criticism that the Gigafactory is too small to achieve its cost savings goals for battery production is not supportable by any cost model of which I'm aware. [15] Musk has said its Gigafactory will provide economies of scale that he expects to drive down the per kWh cost of its battery pack by more than 30%. [11] The Tesla Gigafactory is a lithium-ion battery factory scheduled to open in late 2016 or early 2017. [14] Tesla claims the Gigafactory will be the largest lithium-ion battery manufacturing facility in the world. [14] In addition to its stationary batteries, the Gigafactory will produce batteries for the Tesla Motors' Model 3, which will be marketed as an affordable car, priced at about $35,000. [11] The Gigafactory will supply the batteries that Tesla needs in its cars, as well as PowerWall and PowerPack units. [14] Once again, the bears have gone off half-cocked on Tesla with superficial, or non-existent, analysis to support their view that Tesla's goals for the Gigafactory and the Model 3 are unachievable. [15] It would be hard not to, since the tax incentives are scaled to the magnitude of Tesla's investment in the Gigafactory. [15] Talking about this year's final quarter sales figures for Tesla, Robinson said existing premium models, such as the Model X is not hugely tied with the Gigafactory. [2] Tesla is making a huge Gigafactory, which is expected to become the biggest building on earth on completion. [9] Other interpretations include that the size indicates that Tesla is too cash strapped to build the Gigafactory to the needed size, or that Tesla is engaged once again in some form of deception regarding the Gigafactory. [15] The current size of the Gigafactory has been interpreted by Tesla bears in all manner of negative ways. [15] The bears have correctly pointed out that the current Gigafactory is about 1/6th the area that Tesla has proposed for the final facility in 2020. [15] The focus on the Gigafactory and its presumed shortcomings was understandable on the part of the Tesla bears. [15] The Gigafactory has taken a lot of criticism from the Tesla bears since its inception. [15] The ANL cost model indicates that far from being underfunded, the Gigafactory has sufficient funding, with Panasonic's commitment, to meet the fundamental goals of 500,000 unit annual production in 2020 (if not much sooner), and the 30% or better cost savings. [15] Panasonic's commitment, as well as the ANL cost model, show that the Gigafactory goals are quite achievable. [15] Far from being underfunded, Panasonic's commitment means that funding is sufficient to complete the Gigafactory and meet its production and cost reduction goals. [15] Panasonic's commitment demonstrates that the Gigafactory concept is sound technically and financially. [15] Overall, the ANL model supports the size, expected cost savings, and planned expenditure for the Gigafactory in its approximate current configuration. [15] The simplest explanation is that the Gigafactory, in its current size, is already adequate to meet the key cost savings and production capacity goals of the Gigafactory for 2020. [15] Growing demand prompted the company to accelerate its plans, and early in the fourth quarter it relocated production to an automated assembly line at the Gigafactory. [11] At the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas this week, company president Kazuhiro Tsuga told the Wall Street Journal that it could spend up to that amount on the much-awaited Nevada facility, which is expected to cost around US$5 billion. [2] What of Tesla's originally announced plans to spend $4-5 billion on the much larger 900,000 square meter facility? I suspect that those numbers were very early WAGs (Wild Ass Guesses) of the cost, probably made in ignorance or perhaps disbelief of the ANL model. [15] The ANL model result for the total facility investment is $1.8285 billion. [15] Nevada provides a 5% tax credit for Tesla capital investment in the site, up to the first $1 billion, with a 2.8% credit for the next $2.5 billion. [15] Image: Kyodo/Associated Press By Nick Jaynes2016-01-16 11:00:14 UTC Panasonic is doubling down on its investment both in Tesla &amp; the electrified future of mobility. [13] This is also very close to what Panasonic has committed, less the cost of the building provided by Tesla. [15] The factory will take several years before it starts full operations, but this wait will come at a huge cost for Panasonic, which has struggled to make money from its lithium-ion business. [9] Tsuga told WSJ reporter Mike Ramsey that Panasonic was sort of waiting on demand from Tesla and said that if the automaker could help inspire the mainstream adoption of electric vehicles, it would change the world and provide growth opportunities. [2] Latest news reports suggest that the deal has gotten better as Panasonic makes a big bet on Tesla Motor's success. [14] Currently sales to carmakers has accounted for 15% of Panasonics total sales, and the plan is to increase this to 25% over the next few years. [20] This should remove any doubts about whether Panasonic is truly committed to the project. [15] Collaborator-competitors: Panasonic also makes its own residential stationary storage systems, shown here at a trade show in Australia. [2] The cost savings percentage assumes the commonly held opinion that Tesla battery packs cost about $260/kWh of capacity. [15] The scientists developed an end-to-end model (dubbed BatPaC for Battery Performance and Cost Model) of battery production cost taking into account details of battery design, as well as the design of the manufacturing plant and production rate. [15] The total cost to the original equipment manufacturer calculated by the model includes the materials, manufacturing, and warranty costs for a battery produced in the year 2020 (in 2010 US$). [15] #Tesla #Automotive Tesla?s Special Session Cost Nevada Less Than Faraday?s Tesla?s battery factory was lured to. [21] Tesla is an automaker (and soon to be battery maker) that is changing the way the game is played. [14] They baselined a plant capable of producing 100,000 battery packs per year. [15] Kilowatt-hours (kWh) is a measure of energy capacity in the battery pack. [15] The model designs the battery for a specified power, energy, and type of vehicle battery. [15] Both the model and the report have been publicly peer-reviewed by battery experts assembled by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. [15] This report details the Battery Performance and Cost model (BatPaC) developed at Argonne National Laboratory for lithium-ion battery packs used in automotive transportation. [15] At the time this report is written, this calculation is the only publicly available model that performs a bottom-up lithium-ion battery design and cost calculation. [15] The cost of the designed battery is then calculated by accounting for every step in the lithium-ion battery manufacturing process. [15] In the BatPaC model I assume a 50 kWh battery providing approximately a 200 mile range for a smaller and lighter Model 3. [15] ...The Gigafactory is much more closely tied with the success of the Model 3, the ‘affordable' model. mid-US$30,000s – they're really planning on selling a large volume of those cars and by 2020 they want to be making half a million cars, Robinson said. [2] The Gigafactory is scheduled to produce 50GWh of batteries annually per year by 2020. [2] A separate report from Japan's Nikkei Asian Review news site appeared to confirm that the Tesla-Panasonic Gigafactory will be the only supplier of those batteries. [2] While the WJS report mentioned that stationary storage devices are already being produced at the Nevada Gigafactory, it made scarce to no other mention of home, commercial or utility-scale stationary storage. [2] A key factor that will help Tesla Motors (NASDAQ:TSLA) maintain its lead in the EV market is the Gigafactory it is building in Reno, Nevada. [14] It is expected that over the next four years, Panasonic?s sales to automakers will nearly double to account for 15% of the company?s revenue for the fiscal year, contributing 1.3 trillion ($11 billion), and by the end of the decade, it is expected to grow to nearly 25% of revenue. [9] Last August, Musk said the company had received reservations for well over $1 billion worth of Powerpacks and Powerwalls all without any marketing or advertising. [11] They didn't just assume that Tesla was going to invest $5 billion and then hand over a pile of tax credits. [15] The cost for the project is expected to be approximately $5 billion. [14] According to the article, Tesla's capital investment for the period from October 2014 to June 2015 was $186 million, making it eligible for $9.3 million in tax credits. [15] Most of Tesla's rivals have huge assembly lines or deals with OEMs to roll out the cars with ease and speed. [14] Tesla Motors Gigafactory in Nevada will get hundreds of employees from the Japanese electronics group Panasonic this fall to boost production at the plant, which is expected to start sometime next year, says a report from Reuters. [3] NEW YORK (TheStreet) - Shares of Tesla Motors are advancing 2.31% to $254.89 on reports that its Gigafactory in Nevada will receive hundreds of Panasonic workers to make electric car batteries at the plant, according to Reuters. [3] With the development of its Gigafactory in Nevada, in association with Panasonic, it plans to build a lot more batteries. [12] Tesla Motors Inc (NASDAQ:TSLA) has inked a deal with Panasonic Corporation (OTCMKTS:PCRFY) in its attempts to step up auto investment at the company?s Gigafactory. [3] Panasonic also faces rising rivalry from South Korean battery makers that have agreements to supply electric and hybrid vehicles coming from General Motors and Volkswagen AG. The battery investment is one element of Panasonic?s drive to become a leading auto parts supplier, taking advantage of the computerization of the automobile and forecasts for strong worldwide demand for light vehicles in coming decades. [22] It is set to produce battery packs for future Tesla cars as well. [3] Tesla and state officials in Nevada have decided on a final incentive agreement for the lithium-ion battery plant or the so-called gigafactory. [12] U.S. electric automaker Tesla Motors is to build a new 5-billion-dollar Gigafactory in Nevada, the states governor announced Thursday billing it as the worlds largest lithium-ion battery plant, The plant, plans for which were announced in July. [3] Tesla Motors remains on track to qualify for $1.3 billion in incentives for its Gigafactory project in northern Nevada, even as the company pushed back on the initial average wage estimate it gave to the state. [3] Tesla Motors, Inc. TSLA is constructing a $5 billion Gigafactory in Nevada to produce lithium-ion batteries, in collaboration with vari. [3] Tesla Motors Inc (NASDAQ:TSLA) stock dropped 3.36% Friday on rumors that the construction of the companys $5 billion lithium ion-producing Gigafactory had been delayed. [3] Tesla Motors, Inc. (TSLA) has denied media reports of a delay in the construction of its $5 billion Gigafactory. [3] Now, the companywhich also owns a small stake in Teslasays it will spend up to $1.6 billion on the Gigafactory. [16] A good portion of what we come to rely on in the future could be created here at Tesla's Gigafactory. [12] Tesla Motors, Inc.' s (TSLA) Gigafactory will be the largest and most advanced battery factory in the world. [3] The fast-paced construction of Tesla?s lithium-ion battery factory is visible in a video, showing Tesla?s huge Gigafactory from a Quadcopter Drone in High Definition (HD). [3] It's safe to say the Tesla Motors gigafactory is the most-watched manufacturing project in the United States, if not the world. [3] Opus One's already tested Tesla's Powerwall batteries in its lab and plans to be part of a venture distributing the batteries, which were first announced last spring by Tesla CEO Elon Musk. [23] Some people buy Tesla's fast-accelerating electric vehicles not for their performance but rather for their eco-friendly, polar bear-saving powertrains Ironically, once these buyers have plunked down the $100,000 (on average) for their Tesla, they are then forced to choose between interiors fitted with the skin of deceased cows or regular old cloth. [24] Ontario's Veridian Connections has launched a test project that will make it among the first utility to use Tesla's Powerwall batteries in a microgrid installation. [23] Tesla's utility-scale energy storage product is much bigger. [23] Panasonic hasn?t earlier revealed the full size of its investment. [22] Panasonic President Kazuhiro Tsuga said the company is planning an investment of $1.6 billion Th. [3] Under the deal, Panasonic is expected to dispatch hundreds of its employees to the Nevada. [3] The $5 billion project is coming to life outside Reno, Nevada. [3] The $5 billion facility, projected to be completed in 2017, is intended to produce 500,000 lithium ion batteries annually. [3] Although the massive battery factory is not even close to opening its doors, the effect on Reno's economy and public image can already be felt. [3] CARSON CITY, Nev. (AP) – A special legislative session to lure electric carmaker Faraday Future to Nevada cost about twice as much as one to attract Tesla's battery factory, even though the deal itself was a fraction of the size. [25] It will be several years before that factory is humming at full steam, and for Panasonic, the wait will be costly because its lithium-ion battery business has struggled to make money. [26] NEWARK, N.J. Panasonic Eco Solutions Company announced the company's expansion of larger solar panels into North America's fast-growing residential solar market. [27] Statistically ICE cars suffer from 90 fires per billion miles driven Teslas have logged 1.2 billion miles(at least) and have had 7 fires. [28] Elon had warned that without investment in battery plants the EV market would have. [28] If each one had the smallest 70 KWH battery pack, that's still 3.54 million KWH of capacity. [28] It put LG Chem ( NASDAQOTH:LGCLF ) ahead of Panasonic, Tesla Motors' battery partner, for lithium ion batteries in both transportation and for grid storage. [29] The choice of LG Chem is curious since Panasonic supplied the initial batteries and is supplying Tesla Model S batteries as well. [29] This isn't to say that Musk, Tesla, and Panasonic can't build the next generation of batteries in the Nevada desert or that it won't be less costly and higher energy density than LG Chem and other competitors. [29] Tesla Motors ( NASDAQ:TSLA ) has made arguably the biggest bet on the future of electric vehicles and energy storage of any company, with the $5 billion Gigafactory it's building in Nevada. [29] Lithium-ion batteries are so important to the company that it has taken manufacturing into its own hands, building a Gigafactory just outside Reno, Nevada. [29] The Japanese technology company has already invested $2 billion in India in the past year and the pace of investments could accelerate in the future, its chief executive said. [30] According to MarketWatch, the Japanese electronics company has promised up to $1.6 billion toward the construction of Tesla Motors' lithium-ion battery-prod. [30] International tourism arrivals - or the number of people visiting countries other than their own - grew 4.4% to 1.18 billion last year, according to the World Tourism Organization (UNWTO). [31] A typical off grid battery bank needs to power the needs of a small family in a modest-sized, energy-efficient home for only a few days is the size of a refrigerator, weighs over a ton, lasts less than 10 years and costs over $3,000. [29] Given their high cost, home batteries today appeal primarily to affluent early adopters, but with rapid advances in battery technology, they could become as ubiquitous as refrigerators in a decade. [29] As that post pointed out, here at Schneider Electric we agree that lithium-ion (Li-ion) battery technology presents some exciting possibilities but it?ll take lots of infrastructure and intelligence surrounding the batteries in order to make it truly useful. [29] Solar City successfully pushed to get regulations changed in CA to allow behind the meter residential batteries with 2-way power flow over a year ago, and has been selling battery + PV in drips &amp; drabs there ever since, but expect to be selling batteries included in most of their installations well before 2020. [29] Now if your vehicle requires 20KWH each day and you are willing to purchase enough battery storage to enable only drawing power during the hours where renewables can charge your batteries then you deserve a huge discount. [29] The batteries (of whatver kind) there for storage and the supercaps for quick charging (being replenished in the lull between cars driving up to the station, people going in to pay, etc. from the battery storage) I find it not very problematic that storage is taking a bit to get into gear. [29] Battery safety Batteries are dangerous, even your car battery! Here are some safety guidelines. [29] Industrial batteries are amazing things, commonly found in forklifts, mining vehicles and large renewable energy installations, and each battery gives out 2 volts. [29] When building USB portable batteries, the makers incorporate internal power cells from other companies, and the marketing for the resulting battery pack almost always reflects the total of the raw specifications for those internal cells. [29] If you are going to use NiFe batteries, I recommend that you size both your solar array and off grid battery bank at about twice the normal capacity, and be certain that all your charger equipment has specific settings just for NiFe. [29] I usually advise clients to avoid NiFe and go for industrial lead-acid batteries instead, but I can?t deny that the idea of a battery that can last decades is very attractive. [29] Would people allow their battery to degrade more with V2G, especially with Leaf? Until there are batteries not affected by charge/discharge cycles, I don't know how many will opt for V2G. I suppose if there's really good battery warranty, it's possible. [29] Recent high-profile events involving electric cars and airplanes that employ Li-ion batteries as main or auxiliary power sources lend further urgency to improved Li-ion battery safety 6, 7. [29] While Li-ion materials and chemistry have been well understood for over two decades, the engineering science of large Li-ion batteries remains elusive, as evident from the recent battery fire accident on Boeing Dreamliner 787. [29] We demonstrate the effectiveness of this technique by fabricating Li-ion battery cells with internal reaction temperature sensors and testing them under a short-circuit condition, a common safety failure scenario for Li-ion batteries. [29] It is hard to play with the battery charging subsystem of a solar power installation to get a feel for how it works until you actually take the leap and buy a solar panel, charge controller and cables and hook it all up to the batteries. [29] DONALD SADOWAY: It reconstitutes itself every time that it recharges, which means that, unlike other batteries, which will reduce their run time with use, our battery just keeps on running. [29] The capacity of the battery charging system (solar panels, batteries and charge controller) and of the AC power system (the inverter). [29] In a nutshell, the two subsystems battery charging (batteries + panels + charge controller) and AC power (inverter(s)) combine to do the same job as plugging a generator into the shore power connector on the side of the rig. [29] In industrial applications batteries are hit hard (50 percent DOD or worse) on a daily basis, but most off grid battery banks are designed to provide more gentle power for a couple days to a week, and in the process never fall below 30 percent DOD, or even better 20 percent. [29] Absorbed Glass Matt (AGM) batteries are the latest in the sealed leadacid battery world. [29] Because the gases emitted by batteries are both explosive and toxic, you should never install any kind of electrical equipment inside a battery enclosure. [29] Lift batteries only by their built-in handles, or use a battery lifter. [29] The short, thick wires that interconnect the batteries in an off grid battery bank and then connect it to the rest of the power system are critical for both safety and performance, and must be sized and installed correctly. [29] That means one or more batteries in the off grid battery bank are getting less charging current than the rest, which over time will cause premature battery failure. [29] Apple investigates battery percentage issues on iPhone 6s Apple (Yesterday) – Apple has confirmed it is investigating a bug in its operating software which displays the incorrect battery percentage on some models of its flagship. [32] Apple admits bug in iPhone 6S battery meter Apple (Yesterday) – Until the bug is corrected through future software updates, Apple took to its website to offer step-by-step instructions for how to adjust your phone to. [32] Early detection and protection technologies are essential elements of large Li-ion battery systems for vehicle, aircraft and grid energy storage applications 9, 10. [29] Battery technology is improving in leaps and bounds (thanks to EV's and grid storage demands). [29] Remember that you should never discharge any battery to over 50 percent DOD, so if your calculations show you need 10 kWh of backup storage for your home, you really need to purchase a 20 kWh off grid battery bank. [29] Michael Rundle, Wired's UK editor, got a tour of the Tesla factory recently conducted by none other than Diarmuid O'Connell, Tesla's vice president of business development. [17] When Tesla's factory hit's full production in 2017 the world price for car-type lithium ion batteries it likely to take quantum step down. [29] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (32 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) Related
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0db924b3-bfdb-3bcf-b500-7320e77f17b6" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-19T19:28:39Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:40:28.557Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/panasonic-to-invest-1-6-billion-in-teslas-battery-gigafactory/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
