<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Bring Simulation to Everyone Put the power of simulation in the hands of those who need it with COMSOL Multiphysics and the Application Builder. Check out the online showcase to learn more: http://goo.gl/SCXVDI *************************************************** Dear Reader , Here is your customized Phys.org Newsletter for January 21, 2016: Spotlight Stories Headlines - First materials to be woven at the atomic and molecular levels created - Two giant planets detected around an evolved intermediate-mass star - New theory suggests magnesium could be the key to understanding Earth's magnetic field - Study zeros in on plate tectonics' start date - Dark 'noodles' may lurk in the Milky Way - New finding may explain heat loss in fusion reactors - IBM boosts cloud offerings with Ustream buy - Scientists discover method to potentially repair nerve damage - Material may offer cheaper alternative to smart windows - Biologists find sexuality, not extra chromosomes, benefits animal - Defending your computer from cyber-attacks, Sun Tzu style - Study helps fill in gaps in our visual perception - New experiments challenge economic game assumptions - Molecular-like photochemistry from semiconductor nanocrystals - Mitochondrial trouble makers unmasked in lupus Astronomy &amp; Space news | Two giant planets detected around an evolved intermediate-mass star (Phys.org)—HD 47366 is an evolved star almost twice as massive as our sun. Located about 260 light years from the Earth, the star is approximately 1.6 billion years old, and, as it turns out, hosts two giant planets with a mass nearly two times that of Jupiter's each. A research paper detailing the new findings was published online on Jan. 18 in the arXiv journal. | | Dark 'noodles' may lurk in the Milky Way Invisible structures shaped like noodles, lasagne sheets or hazelnuts could be floating around in our Galaxy radically challenging our understanding of gas conditions in the Milky Way. | | Hubble image: Dazzling diamonds Single stars are often overlooked in favour of their larger cosmic cousins—but when they join forces, they create truly breathtaking scenes to rival even the most glowing of nebulae or swirling of galaxies. This NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope image features the star cluster Trumpler 14. One of the largest gatherings of hot, massive and bright stars in the Milky Way, this cluster houses some of the most luminous stars in our entire galaxy. | | The aliens are silent because they're dead Life on other planets would likely be brief and become extinct very quickly, say astrobiologists from The Australian National University (ANU). | | Predicting planets: The highs and lows In the mid-19th century, astronomers hypothesised an extra planet in our solar system, orbiting between the Sun and Mercury. | | Five brightest planets gather in pre-dawn sky for heavenly show Our five closest planetary neighbors are putting on a heavenly show. | | Explore galaxies far, far away at internet speeds No need for hyperdrive: Scientists have released an expansion pack for a virtual tour of the universe that you can enjoy from the comfort of your own computer. The latest version of the publicly accessible images of the sky, which can be viewed using an interactive Sky Viewer tool, roughly doubles the size of the searchable universe from the project's original release in May. | | David Bowie 'constellation' – the surprising truth The death of David Bowie has caused people to remember the artist in many different ways. Only recently a request for a Bowie Constellation was reportedly put forward by Belgian radio channel Studio Brussels and the MIRA Public Observatory. Can this be done at all? And where can we see it? | Technology news | Study explores how backing for clean technology should be designed Governments often offer subsidies to consumers for clean-technology products, from home solar panels to electric vehicles. But what are the right levels of subsidy, and how should they be calculated? As a new paper co-authored by MIT researchers shows, governments can easily make subsidies too low when they ignore a basic problem: Consumer demand for these products is usually highly uncertain. | | Linux kernel vulnerability traced to keyring implementation Security watchers this week focused on the zero-day vulnerability which was found inside the Linux kernel. Geektime's Gabriel Avner and Yaneev Avital reported Tuesday that the Israeli cyber security firm Perception Point found the Linux code vulnerability. The news was not trivial. And it was not good. | | Defending your computer from cyber-attacks, Sun Tzu style We want our computers to perform the way we expect. But what if the key to defeating malware is introducing a bit of chaos? | | IBM boosts cloud offerings with Ustream buy Technology world centenarian IBM has boosted its Internet cloud offerings with the takeover of live video streaming services firm Ustream. | | GM unites car-sharing services under new brand 'Maven' The final destination is a mystery, but General Motors is taking another step on its fast-moving journey into new ways of getting around. | | Virtual reality takes porn 'to the next level' Just ask Anna Lee: Woody Allen's Orgasmatron, his then-futuristic vision of self-initiated sex from the 1973 movie Sleeper, has finally become a reality. Virtual reality, that is. | | UberX to pick up at Los Angeles International Airport Passengers arriving at Los Angeles International Airport will be allowed to leave in an UberX car starting Thursday morning. | | Visualize sounds and tune instruments precisely and intuitively A novel process for analyzing and visualizing sound has been designed by the Laboratoire Sciences et Technologies de la Musique et du Son (CNRS/IRCAM/French Ministry of Culture and Communication/UPMC). The SnailAnalyser-Tuner is a patented CNRS technology that offers novel ways of tuning a musical instrument, working on intonation, and visualizing music and sounds in real time. Beyond the marked scientific advance that it constitutes, this software program is innovative for musicians and all those who work with sound. It is suitable for both amateurs and professionals. It will be launched on January 21, 2016 and will be presented in Paris at the Salon Musicora on February 6-7, 2016. | | Are intelligent agents the beginning of the end for journalism as we know it? Algorithms are now generating sports reports and financial news, and making fewer errors in the process than human reporters do. Is this the beginning of the end for journalism as we know it? | | New reconstruction method improves facial recognition for forensic purposes Researchers of the Services, Cybersecurity and Safety department of the University of Twente have invented an improved reconstruction method for facial recognition based on camera images. This method yields a better score in ninety percent of the examined cases, and helps forensic investigators with their daily work. The researchers recently published their results in the academic journal IET Biometrics. | | Facebook gets in game with new sports hub Facebook announced a drive Thursday to be a place for sports with a new online hub for news and sharing on sporting events. | | Review: Dawn of VR era upon us A new era is dawning for virtual reality. New systems that will hit store shelves in coming months are going to offer amazing and immersive experiences that will blow you away. | | Review: IPad Pro just might replace your laptop Every time a new iPad is introduced, I have the same conversation with myself. | | Renault CEO: company did not cheat on emissions technology Renault-Nissan's CEO says the automaker did not cheat on its emissions technology in its cars, 15,000 of which it is recalling in Europe because they spew out excessive levels of harmful gases. | | GM debuts car-sharing, 'personal mobility' brand General Motors said Thursday it was launching a US car-sharing service under a new personal mobility brand dubbed Maven. | | France to 'modify' AZERTY keyboard to improve French writing The French are known for being sticklers about the correct use of language, but they have discovered something is getting in the way of perfect prose: the AZERTY keyboard. | | In Tech: Minecraft for schools, Amazon Dash, data encryption Microsoft is buying the educational version of Minecraft and has plans to create a bigger and better version of the popular world-building video game that's designed for classrooms. | | Viacom slashes exec pay amid lawsuit over Redstone's health Viacom Inc. on Wednesday pre-released details about executive pay that show an 85 percent drop in compensation for its ailing 92-year-old executive chairman, Sumner Redstone, amid legal battles questioning his health and competence. | | Regulating IV infusion with innovative blind cave fish-inspired sensor Inspired by the blind cave fish, researchers at the <NODE id="8919" />Singapore-MIT Alliance for Research and Technology<NODE id="8969" /> (<NODE id="8971" />SMART<NODE id="8976" />) have developed <NODE id="8993" />Micro-Electro-Mechanical Systems (MEMS) flow sensor<NODE id="9044" /> so tiny and sensitive that it can be implanted into the IV or intravenous set-up, to aid in regulating the velocity of the fluid flow with minimal intervention by the nurses, thereby reducing their workload while increasing their productivity by 30%; and significantly decreasing the complications of drug infusion via IV therapy. These sensors can also be incorporated into marine underwater robots, lending them sensitivities to wakes, akin to the blind cave fish itself, so that the robots can manoeuvre in a highly energy-efficient manner. | | Young Chinese scale Great Firewall to flood Taiwan media The Facebook page of Taiwan's president-elect was flooded Thursday with tens of thousands of pro-China comments following a campaign by young mainlanders to jump the country's Great Firewall into normally forbidden overseas social media to express displeasure over the recent election. | | Industry 4.0 and additive manufacturing At the World Economic Forum (WEF) in Davos a key topic is focusing on the Digital Transformation of Industries. The fourth industrial revolution is imminent. It goes by the name Industry 4.0 and is expected to fundamentally change, among other things, the production methods and business models currently used in industrialized countries. Experts estimate that Industry 4.0 will result in virtual data merging with real production equipment. The resulting smart factory will bring customers and suppliers closer together, as production orders will be sent by the customer directly to the machine, and the production data will be transferred to the distribution partner in real time. Manufacturing will become leaner and faster and respond to customers' needs. | | Fewer chemicals for textile printing Could textile printing be on the verge of a major breakthrough? For years, conventional processes—known as rotary screen printing—have required a high amount of chemicals to be applied on the textile, involving excessive amounts of water and energy. The process involves a different screen for each colour required in the final design, and a certain amount of print paste needs to be produced to ensure quality throughout the whole lot. This paste remains in the screens, eventually becomes waste and has to be cleaned using water, which then needs to be treated. In total, it is estimated that 90 percent of chemicals used in dyeing operations do not stay on the fibre. | | Report shady businesses to new scam tracker With the help of technology, scam artists are enhancing their usual bag of tricks. For instance, some oily operators are not only impersonating the authorities, they're also manipulating caller ID systems to make it appear like they're phoning from police stations. | | Assessment aims to maximize greenhouse gas reductions from bioenergy A study reported in the journal Energy used a new method, never before applied to the energy sector, to assess the sustainability index of various sources of energy, both conventional and renewable. | | New 'moonshot' effort to understand the brain brings AI closer to reality Harvard's John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences (SEAS), Center for Brain Science (CBS), and the Department of Molecular and Cellular Biology have been awarded over $28 million to develop advanced machine learning algorithms by pushing the frontiers of neuroscience. | Medicine &amp; Health news | Brain scans may identify children who are vulnerable to depression, before symptoms appear A new brain imaging study from MIT and Harvard Medical School may lead to a screen that could identify children at high risk of developing depression later in life. | | Scientists unravel defects in rare hereditary disease myotubular myopathy Tiny deviations in the body's cells can sometimes have severe consequences. Researchers from Berlin have discovered why cells from patients suffering from the rare muscular disease myotubular myopathy cannot function properly. Through the paper published in Nature, it has become clear how a dynamic cellular process essential to muscle development and function is regulated by means of minute changes of certain membrane lipids. | | Neuroscientists develop new tools to safely trace brain circuits Scientists at Columbia University's Mortimer B. Zuckerman Mind Brain Behavior Institute have developed a new viral tool that dramatically expands scientists' ability to probe the activity and circuitry of brain cells, or neurons, in the mouse brain. These findings highlight an innovative feat of molecular engineering that allows the creation of a more complete map of the brain's cellular circuits and will help researchers on their way toward unraveling the mysteries of the brain. | | Why are habits so hard to break? Getting hooked changes the brain, scientists find By now, you might have discovered that taming your sweet tooth as a New Year's resolution is harder than you think. | | Study explains why mistakes slow us down, but not necessarily for the better Taking more time to make decisions after a mistake arises from a mixture of adaptive neural mechanisms that improve the accuracy and maladaptive mechanisms that reduce it, neuroscientists at New York University have found. Their study, which addresses a long-standing debate on the value of deliberation after errors in decision-making, also potentially offer insights into afflictions that impair judgments, such as Alzheimer's Disease and Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD). | | Guidelines for human genome editing Human genome editing for both research and therapy is progressing, raising ethical questions among scientists around the world. | | Study helps fill in gaps in our visual perception A Dartmouth College study sheds light on how the brain fills in the gaps of how we visually perceive the world around us. | | Mitochondrial trouble makers unmasked in lupus New findings expose how mitochondria might instigate lupus-like inflammation. | | New test could predict dementia risk during routine GP visits It may be possible to assess the risk of developing dementia by analyzing information gathered during routine visits to the family doctor, according to research published in the open access journal BMC Medicine. | | First-of-its-kind study finds parental debt affects children's socioemotional well-being Certain types of debt that parents take on may have adverse effects on children's socioemotional well-being according to a new study by researchers at the University of Wisconsin at Madison and Dartmouth published by the journal Pediatrics. The study sheds new light on the link between debt and family well-being, as previous research on debt has typically focused on how debt affects the mental health and well-being of adults and has yet to explore how parents' debt may impact a child's well-being. (Pls note: The journal link will not be live until 1/21/16 at 12:01 am. A pdf of the study/journal article is available upon request). | | Changing dosing instructions from teaspoon to milliliter could reduce the risk of dosage errors by 50% You grab for the cough syrup for some relief from that nasty lingering cold, what do you measure the dose with? Many of us use teaspoons or table spoons to measure out doses for ourselves and our children but this results in dosage errors! This new study finds that errors in estimating doses can be mitigated by changing the serving measurements on the dosage facts panel from teaspoons to milliliters. | | Cells from cow knee joints used to grow new cartilage tissue in laboratory In an effort to develop a method for cartilage tissue engineering, researchers at Umeå University in Sweden successfully used cartilage cells from cow knee joints. By creating a successful method with conditions conducive to growing healthy cartilage tissue, the findings could help lead to a new treatment cure for osteoarthritis using stem cell-based tissue engineering. This is according to a doctoral dissertation at Umeå University. | | Low cost ways to increase healthy food selection in food pantries Can adjustments in the presentation of food make a difference in the choices, especially among people living in poverty? Are clients at food pantries likely to make the healthiest food choices? New research published in the Journal of the Association for Consumer Research suggests that food pantry clients deal with a number factors that can lead to a less healthy choice and that simple adjustments in the pantry set-up may help increase healthy choices. | | Benefits of cystic fibrosis drug ivacaftor reported in pre-school children for the first time The oral drug ivacaftor appears to be safe and could be beneficial to young children between the ages of 2 and 5 with a specific type of cystic fibrosis, according to new research published in The Lancet Respiratory Medicine journal. The findings also suggest a potential window of opportunity in early life when organ damage could be mitigated. | | Drug industry to fight superbugs together with governments Dozens of makers of medicines and diagnostic tests have joined together in an unprecedented effort to tackle superbugs—infections that increasingly don't respond to drugs and threaten millions of people in countries rich and poor. | | Brain study reveals mindfulness could help prevent obesity in children Mindfulness, described as paying attention on purpose and being in the present moment with acceptance, could be an effective way to help children avoid obesity. New research published in the journal Heliyon suggests that the balance in brain networks in children who are obese is different compared to healthy-weight children, making them more prone to over-eating. | | Migraines worsen as women approach menopause Migraine headaches heat up as women approach menopause, according to a new study from researchers at the University of Cincinnati (UC), Montefiore Headache Center, Albert Einstein College of Medicine and Vedanta Research. | | Study examines link between HPV and risk of head and neck cancers Researchers at Albert Einstein College of Medicine have found that when human papillomavirus (HPV)-16 is detected in peoples' mouths, they are 22 times more likely than those without HPV-16 to develop a type of head and neck cancer. The study was published online today in JAMA Oncology and was led by Ilir Agalliu, M.D., Sc.D., and Robert D. Burk, M.D. | | Nonrecommended screenings for prostate, breast cancer in older individuals An estimated 15.7 percent of individuals 65 or older may have received nonrecommended screenings for prostate and breast cancers because they had limited life expectancies of less than 10 years, according to an article published online by JAMA Oncology. | | WHO confirms second new Ebola case in Sierra Leone (Update) A new case of Ebola has been confirmed in Sierra Leone, officials said Thursday, the second since west Africa celebrated the end of the epidemic last week. | | Smarter diagnosis for lipoedema A new handheld device and app will help clinicians diagnose lipoedema – a condition characterised by swollen limbs – earlier and better monitor the success of treatment options. | | The consequences of controlling parenting on college students College students whose parents lay on the guilt or try to manipulate them may translate feelings of stress into similar mean behavior with their own friends, a new study by a University of Vermont psychologist has found. | | Antimicrobial wash reduces health risks in fresh produce Sometimes it takes time to find a winning formula. That's how it was with First Step+ 10, according to Joshua Gurtler, an Agricultural Research Service scientist at the Eastern Regional Research Center, in Wyndmoor, Pennsylvania. | | Study suggests stem cells may repair dying retinal cells Researchers at St. Erik Eye Hospital and Karolinska Institutet have for the first time successfully transplanted human retinal pigment epithelial cells derived from stem cells into eyes that are similar to human eyes. The researchers have developed a unique method of creating mature cells differentiated from embryonic stem cells. When transplanted into the retina of human-like animals, the cells protected against experimental macular degeneration. | | New knowledge on why patients with type 2 diabetes present olfactory problems In a study in type 2 diabetic rats, researchers at the Karolinska Institutet have identified alterations in specific nerve cells that are important for odor identification. The findings might explain why type 2 diabetic patients often experience smelling problems and potentially open up a new research field to develop preventive therapies against neurodegenerative diseases in type 2 diabetic patients. | | Study unravels link between surgery, diabetes remission Researchers and doctors have known for years that patients who receive bariatric surgeries – gut surgeries with the goal of weight loss – often experience remission of type 2 diabetes. Clinicians find that diabetes remission begins within days after such surgeries, well before weight loss occurs. | | Limiting e-cigarette flavors may benefit public health Flavor variety is an important component in young smokers' decisions to switch to e-cigarettes, new research from Weill Cornell Medicine indicates. The investigators say their findings provide critical insight into what attracts teens to the products and may also help policymakers develop strategies to regulate e-cigarettes in a way that reduces teenage use without compromising a critical method for adults to quit or reduce cigarette smoking. | | New depression model outperforms psychiatrists A simple questionnaire filled out by depressed patients can help identify whether a particular medication is likely to help them, according to a new study by Yale University researchers published Jan. 20 in the journal Lancet Psychiatry. | | Where women live influences decisions about breast cancer treatment New joint research has found that the distance to cancer services may be influencing the treatment intentions of regional Queensland women diagnosed with breast cancer. | | How pharmacy researchers are making medicine more precise In the pediatric bone marrow transplant clinic, pharmacist Janel Boyle's past and present collide. | | Why we're losing the fight against antibiotic resistance Doctors often tell patients to take a course of antibiotics, because a partially treated infection may result in relapse with antibiotic-resistant bacteria. But where does this advice come from? | | Should women exercise during and after pregnancy? Michelle Bridges was this week branded irresponsible and accused of providing a poor message to new mums following an Instagram post of her workout one month after giving birth. | | Biopsy robot combines MRI and ultrasound Researchers at the University of Twente in The Netherlands are working on a biopsy robot that combines the best features of MRI and ultrasound, aiming to improve the diagnosis of breast cancer and muscle diseases. | | Simple test could improve treatment for biggest leukaemia killer A simple blood test capable of detecting trace levels of leukaemia cells remaining after intensive chemotherapy has been developed by scientists at the National Institute for Health Research (NIHR) Biomedical Research Centre at Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust and King's College London. | | Parental nagging won't shift teen weight If you want to encourage your overweight or obese teenager to eat better and exercise more, nagging and verbal pressure won't work, research says. | | Examining genetic diversity of T. cruzi from California kissing bugs Trypanosoma cruzi is a protozoan parasite that can cause an insidious onset of Chagas disease, a fatal cardiac disease in humans and dogs. The parasite is transmitted via triatomine insects, commonly called kissing bugs. In Latin America T. cruzi is recognized as an economically important parasite; however, there is limited research regarding its spread and virulence in the USA. As a result, while the genetic diversity of the T. cruzi parasite has been well studied in Latin America less is known about the strains endemic to the USA. | | NYC pedestrian traffic makes for safer street crossings: Google street view study Researchers at Columbia University's Mailman School of Public Health have developed a novel method to assess how the streetscape affects the chances pedestrians will be injured by drivers. Using Google Street View the researchers assessed the pedestrian environment at more than 500 New York City street intersections. Findings show that using Google's images instead of visiting collision sites in person resulted in substantial efficiency gains in conducting research on pedestrian safety. The study is published online in the American Journal of Public Health. | | Clot buster treatment safe, effective for patients who required living assistance pre-stroke Intravenous clot busting may be safe and effective in patients who required daily living assistance prior to stroke, according to new research in the American Heart Association's journal Stroke. | | Most Americans support smart guns, survey finds Nearly 60 percent of Americans, if they buy a new handgun, are willing to purchase a smart or childproof gun—a weapon that is only operable in the hands of an authorized user—new Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health-led research suggests. | | Government funds nearly two-thirds of US health care, study reports Tax-funded expenditures accounted for 64.3 percent of U.S. health spending - about $1.9 trillion - in 2013, according to new data published today [Thursday, Jan. 21] in the American Journal of Public Health. The Affordable Care Act will push that figure even higher by 2024, when government's share of U.S. health spending is expected to rise to 67.3 percent. | | Glowing tumors could help surgeons cut out cancer A breast cancer patient is wheeled into the operating room. She is connected to an IV that sends dye molecules into her blood that travel to her tumors. The surgeon inserts a small camera into the patient's chest and her breast tissue appears on a nearby monitor. The cancer cells are glowing a bright green. Such optical probes, which are meant to improve tumor removal, are already in phase I and phase II clinical trials in humans and could be a common procedure in the next 5-10 years. A review of their progress is published January 21 in the premier issue of Cell Chemical Biology, previously known as Chemistry &amp; Biology. | | Investment in neighborhood parks may curb obesity rates, save costs It may sound simple, but adding a neighborhood park or playground can lower children's obesity rates and improve their physical fitness, says new research from Ball State University. And parks might reap immediate and long-term savings in health care. | | New biomarkers may influence drug design and alternative treatments of cancer, study shows Researchers have discovered gene-targets (biomarkers) that may enable alternative treatments or the potential design of new drugs that target metastasis-promoting tumor genes. | | Testosterone influences regulation of emotions in psychopath's brain Brain research has demonstrated that psychopaths exhibit reduced control over their emotional actions. Researchers from the Donders Institute at Radboud University Nijmegen discovered that the quantity of testosterone a person produces influences the parts of the brain responsible for regulating emotions. The findings provide starting points for the treatment of psychopaths. The results were published in the online journal eNeuro. The article by Karin Roelofs and her group was realised thanks to a Vidi grant from NWO's Talent Scheme. | | A single 15-minute, hand-exercise session improves manual dexterity and movement in patients with Parkinson's disease Researchers from the University of Granada (UGR) have proven that a single 15-minute, hand-exercise session greatly improves manual dexterity and movement in patients with Parkinson's disease, helping them to carry out tasks such as writing or buttoning. | | More evidence preterm birth could raise autism risk (HealthDay)—According to a new study, very premature infants may have an increased risk of being diagnosed with autism by age 4, although the research questions just how high the odds are. | | Zika virus likely to spread to southern US, experts predict (HealthDay)—As cases of the mosquito-borne Zika virus are spreading across central and South America and the Caribbean, experts say it's only a matter of time before the disease, which has been linked to an alarming increase in birth defects in Brazil, is transmitted within the United States. | | Anxiety disorders  just in your head? This was her third trip to the emergency department in two days. She had been home watching TV when all of a sudden her heart started racing, she felt her face flush, her hands tingle and it was hard to catch her breath. | | How one company is helping detect infections like norovirus No one wants to eat something and get sick. But foodborne illnesses, like the cases linked to Chipotle restaurants, can easily land you in the doctor's office. | | Important brain network for processing sensory perceptions elucidated Every day, we constantly absorb information through our sensory organs, which the brain then needs to process correctly. The information initially reaches the main relay center, the thalamus, and then travels to the cerebral cortex. The neurons in the so-called higher-order thalamus form the connecting lines between both areas of the brain. Prior to this, their role in sensory processing was unknown. Scientists at the Technical University of Munich (TUM) have now shown for the first time in an animal model that they enhance and temporarily store sensory information. | | A predictive risk map for the nematode parasite Mansonella perstans in Uganda Infection with the nematode parasite Mansonella perstans is one of the most neglected of the neglected tropical diseases. Although symptoms are usually mild, the infection can cause swelling, fever, headaches and abdominal pain and an optimal treatment has not yet been determined. The parasite is transmitted by biting midges found in many areas of sub-Saharan Africa however the exact species of the vector is unknown. A team of researchers from the University of Copenhagen, the Swiss Tropical and Public Health Institute and Uganda Ministry of Health, used data from a survey of 76 schools across Uganda to model areas of high risk of M. perstans infection and examine its overlap with other common parasitic infections. This study will be published in PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases. | | Immune system maintains a memory of past infections by priming genes for future encounters Our ability to fight off recurrent infections, such as colds or flu, may lie in the 'immunological memory' found in a newly discovered class of gene regulatory elements, according to research from the University of Birmingham, supported by the BBSRC and Bloodwise. | | Computer modeling provides insight into cellular-level effects of schizophrenia risk genes Numerous genetic variants associated with risk for schizophrenia have been identified. However, little is known about how these genes have their effects in the brain. | | New study holds hope for improving outcomes for children exposed to methamphetamine Despite continuing reports that methamphetamine abuse during pregnancy can lead to behavioral and emotional problems in children, pregnant women continue to abuse the illicit drug. Nearly one-fourth of pregnant women seeking treatment at federal facilities were methamphetamine users. | | New study shows aged garlic extract can reduce dangerous plaque buildup in arteries The supplement Aged Garlic Extract can reverse the buildup of deadly plaque in arteries and help prevent the progression of heart disease, according to a new study scheduled for publication in the Journal of Nutrition. | | Chronic stress and anxiety can damage the brain, increase the risk of major psychiatric disorders A scientific review paper warns that people need to find ways to reduce chronic stress and anxiety in their lives or they may be at increased risk for developing depression and even dementia. | | Why sports wins and sunshine may lead you to gamble The fact that your favorite sports team unexpectedly won yesterday won't improve your chances of winning the lottery and yet it might increase the likelihood that you'll buy a ticket, according to new research published in Psychological Science, a journal of the Association for Psychological Science. | | Mixed emotions a sign of emotional depth, not indecision, say researchers Experiencing mixed emotions shows emotional complexity, not indecision, and people living in different parts of the world vary in their ability to distinguish between multiple feelings they're having at once, according to new research. | | No evidence that water birth poses harm to newborns, new study finds There is no evidence that water births, where a baby is intentionally born under water in a tub or pool, poses any increased harm to the child, Oregon State University researchers have found. | | Study shows how certain drugs alter metabolism of pancreatic cancer cells UT Southwestern Medical Center researchers have found that cancer drugs known as CDK4/6-inhibitors alter the metabolism of pancreatic cancer cells, revealing a biologic vulnerability that could be exploited for therapeutic gain. The findings were published today in Cell Reports. | | Immune response differences might determine severity of West Nile Virus disease While most West Nile Virus (WNV) infections in humans are asymptomatic and go unnoticed, the virus causes serious and sometimes fatal neurologic illness in some people. A study published on January 21st in PLOS Pathogens suggests that an exaggerated and abnormal immune response contributes to the development of neurologic symptoms following West Nile virus infection. | | Targeted school closure policies may help the fight against pandemic influenza Targeted school closure policies may help mitigating the spread of pandemic influenza, while entailing lower social costs than more traditional policies, such as nationwide school closure. This emerges from a modeling study published in PLOS Computational Biology led by Laura Fumanelli. | | Should India's quacks be trained to deliver basic patient care? Should unqualified practitioners be trained to deliver basic patient care to alleviate India's doctor shortage, asks a special report published by The BMJ today? | | Moms, you think babies are tough? Wait until middle school Mothers are deeply invested in the well being of their children, so when children go through trying times so do their moms, according to a new study by Arizona State University researchers Suniya Luthar and Lucia Cicolla. | | Brazil trying to develop vaccine against Zika virus President Dilma Rousseff says Brazil is trying to develop vaccine against the Zika and dengue viruses. | | When it comes to newborns, age matters Knowing if an infant was born on time or prematurely can make all the difference in deciding what medical care the baby needs. | | Americans 100 and older are living even longer now (HealthDay)—The more than 72,000 Americans who have celebrated 100 birthdays or more are now surviving longer, a new federal report shows. | | Check your risk for diabetes, CDC urges (HealthDay)—No one is excused from diabetes. That's the message behind a new public education campaign targeting the 86 million American adults with what's known as prediabetes. | | Four methods can diagnose fetal nasal bone hypoplasia (HealthDay)—Four methods can be used for diagnosing fetal nasal bone (NB) hypoplasia in the second trimester in order to predict Down's syndrome, according to a study published online in the February issue of the Journal of Clinical Ultrasound. | | Slowing noted in growth of cancer expenditures (HealthDay)—From 1998 to 2012, cancer care expenditures increased at an annualized rate of 2.9 percent, although the growth slowed from 2007, according to a study published online Jan. 15 in Cancer. | | Cystectomy plus chemo ups survival in bladder cancer (HealthDay)—For patients with locally advanced bladder cancer, cystectomy plus adjuvant chemotherapy is associated with improved survival versus cystectomy alone, according to a study published online Jan. 19 in the Journal of Clinical Oncology. | | Depressive symptoms linked to coronary artery calcium (HealthDay)—Depressive symptoms seem to be associated with coronary artery calcium (CAC) in older men and women, according to a study published in the Feb. 1 issue of The American Journal of Cardiology. | | Profound hypothermia best avoided in initial reperfusion (HealthDay)—For hearts donated after circulatory death (DCD), avoidance of profound hypothermia during initial reperfusion (IR) improves functional recovery, according to a study published online Jan. 18 in the American Journal of Transplantation. | | Mutations in TUBB8 linked to form of female infertility (HealthDay)—For a small number of women with a rare form of infertility, mutations in a particular gene may be the cause, according to a study published in the Jan. 21 issue of the New England Journal of Medicine. | | Cocktail of factors from fat-derived stem cells shows promise for critical limb ischemia Critical limb ischemia (CLI) describes an advanced stage of peripheral artery disease characterized by obstruction of the arteries and a markedly reduced blood flow to the extremities. CLI identifies patients at high-risk for major amputation. The estimated annual incidence of CLI ranges between 500 and 1000 new cases out of one million people per year, with the highest rates among the elderly, smokers, and those with diabetes. CLI is considered to be a critical public health issue. Attempts at revascularization are often unsuccessful. | | Antibodies may provide 'silver bullet' for Ebola viruses There may be a silver bullet for Ebola, a family of hemorrhagic viruses, one of which has killed more than 11,000 people in West Africa in the past two years. | | Study shows different genetic drivers of colorectal cancer in older and younger patients A University of Colorado Cancer Center study being presented Saturday at the 2016 Genitourinary Cancers Symposium shows genetic differences between colorectal cancer (CRC) in young and old patients, possibly pointing toward different treatments and strategies in combating the young form of the disease. Comparing 9 tumors from younger patients (median age 31) with 9 tumors from older patients (median age 73), showed distinct genetic differences between younger and older patients with colorectal cancer, says Christopher Lieu, MD, investigator at the CU Cancer Center and assistant professor of medical oncology at the University of Colorado School of Medicine. | | Sierra Leone vaccinates people quarantined after Ebola death Sierra Leone authorities Wednesday announced a vaccination programme for people quarantined following a new Ebola death last week just as west Africa declared an end to the epidemic. | | Nose spray offers pain relief in childbirth Pain relief during childbirth may soon be delivered via a self-administered nasal spray, thanks to research from University of South Australia midwifery researcher, Dr Julie Fleet. | | Innovation in elder-care on the horizon When it comes to senior citizens, it can difficult to strike a balance between maintaining an independent lifestyle and ensuring that help will be there when needed. Mobile phones aren't always within reach, and in some instances elderly people can find themselves lying on the floor, alone, injured and unable to get back on their feet. Professor Ingrid Zukerman from Monash University and her team are working on a non-intrusive home monitoring device, which sends out alerts to carers in the case of abnormally long periods of inactivity. | | Doctors outside the VA need to know more about the veterans they treat Each year the military discharges over 240,000 veterans to reintegrate into civilian society. It's a professional transition, but it's also a personal one. | | Parental support has positive effect on children's eating behaviours Parental support programmes in areas with the greatest needs can have a positive effect on the consumption of unhealthy food and drink and on weight increases in obese children. This according to a randomised study conducted by Karolinska Institutet and the Stockholm County Council, Sweden, published in the International Journal of Behavioural Nutrition and Physical Activity. | | The beta-1 adrenergic receptor and RAGE work together to break hearts Cardiomyopathies result from a remodeling process that can be initiated by a variety of pathological stresses. Activation of the β-1 adrenergic receptor (β1AR) typically occurs in response to stress to rapidly increase cardiac output; however, prolonged stimulation of this receptor results in cardiomyocyte death and maladaptive cardiac remodeling. Studies have also shown that the pattern recognition receptor RAGE is activated in the heart following ischemic injury. | | One new tuberculosis disease case confirmed in rural Alabama Public health officials say another case of tuberculosis has been confirmed amid an outbreak in rural Alabama that has killed three people since 2011. | | Identification of a driver of fibrosis in chronic kidney disease Chronic kidney disease can develop in response to a variety of insults and is characterized by progressive renal fibrosis and atrophy of kidney tubule. Therapeutic options are limited and the disease is often not detected until later stages. A new study in the inaugural issue of JCI Insight identifies the Wnt pathway modulator Dickkopf-3 (DKK3) as a driver of kidney fibrosis. | | MHC class II molecules on graft endothelium promote acute rejection A limitation of organ transplant is acute rejection of the graft by the host immune system. Graft rejection is mediated by the development of CD8+ cytotoxic T cells that target donor MHC class I molecules, and in animal models, these cells have been shown to develop in secondary lymphoid organs. However, in humans, there is evidence that cytotoxic T cells mature within the graft without trafficking to secondary sites. | | Kidney fibrosis in older transplants links to failure Clinically, kidney fibrosis can be used to assess stage, progression, and prognosis for both kidney transplants and kidney disease. There is debate as to whether kidney fibrosis is a maladaptive, injury-triggered process that inherently progresses to kidney failure or an adaptive wound-healing process that stabilizes the injury site. | | MD Anderson, AbbVie connect to advance cancer immunotherapy The immunotherapy platform at The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center and the global biopharmaceutical company AbbVie will join forces to find new ways to unleash the immune system's potential to fight cancer. | | Morbidly obese patients may benefit from bariatric surgery prior to knee replacement Previous research studies have linked obesity to adverse outcomes and increased costs following total knee replacement surgery (TKR). A new, computer model-based evaluation appearing in the Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery, supports bariatric surgery in morbidly obese patients with end-stage osteoarthritis (loss of cartilage and joint pain, caused by aging and use) prior to TKR. | | Low reflective ability is risk for professionalism lapses during medical school and beyond Might it be possible to identify and then reach out to help medical students whose actions may put them at risk of lapses in professionalism in medical school and beyond? Professionalism lapses are the most common cause for disciplinary action against practicing physicians. | | Sri Lanka bans foreigner kidney transplants after organ racket tip Sri Lanka banned kidney transplants for foreign nationals on Thursday following reports of an organised organ harvesting racket involving patients and donors from neighbouring India. | | Mitochondrial DNA levels in the blood may predict risk of developing kidney disease The health of blood cells' energy-producing mitochondria may predict a person's risk of developing chronic kidney disease (CKD), according to a study appearing in an upcoming issue of the Journal of the American Society of Nephrology (JASN). The findings could lead to improvements in the prevention and treatment of CKD. | | Researchers launch a new model of healthcare that links nursing and dentistry Primary care within a dental practice? | | Dramatic decline in complaints by imprisoned transgender patients after staff LGBT training A new study of the quality of healthcare provided to transgender patients in the New York City correctional system revealed significant areas for improvement and reported a greater than 50% decrease in patient complaints after the healthcare staff at 12 jail clinics received Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender (LGBT) training. Within 6 months of implementing a revised transgender health care policy, patient complaints dropped to zero, according to the study results published in LGBT Health. | | Study identifies important regulator of chronic, low-level inflammation A new study by a team of Rosalind Franklin University researchers headed by Carl White, PhD, assistant professor of physiology and biophysics, has discovered that the degree of chronic inflammation caused by obesity is highly dependent on levels of the signaling molecule, hydrogen sulfide, which alters the activity of a calcium channel, Orai3. These findings establish the possibility of targeting Orai3 as a novel treatment for the treatment of obesity-related inflammation, which has the added benefits of reducing insulin resistance and the likelihood of of developing type 2 diabetes. | Biology news | Why don[... snipped ...] |
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/4cff1208-cac2-3443-8a95-55ed8983fc7a" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-22T01:15:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:04:21.652Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://mabsj2.blogspot.com/2016/01/science-x-newsletter-thursday-jan-21.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="8919" endPos="8969" type="organization-company" surface="Singapore-MIT Alliance for Research and Technology" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="8971" endPos="8976" type="organization-company" surface="SMART" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="8993" endPos="9044" type="product" surface="Micro-Electro-Mechanical Systems (MEMS) flow sensor" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="3" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="2" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
