<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT><NODE id="0" />Heilind<NODE id="7" /> Expands in <NODE id="19" />Sensor Market<NODE id="32" /> with Addition of New Role Heilind Electronics, one of the world’s leading distributors of electronics components, has expanded its presence in the sensor market with the addition of Glen MacGibbon as Vice President of Business Development - Sensors. Glen MacGibbon, Heilind's New VP of Business Development - Sensors Wilmington, MA (PRWEB) January 06, 2016 As part of its ongoing evolution in the sensor business, leading electronics distributor Heilind Electronics has announced the hiring of Glen MacGibbon in the newly created position of Vice President of Business Development - Sensors. Glen comes to Heilind with 27+ years in sensors, most recently as VP of Sales driving both the Industrial and Channel Markets for TE Connectivity -- where he was responsible for developing and growing <NODE id="826" />TE<NODE id="828" /> Sensor Solutions. Prior to TE, he was Executive Vice President of Sales and Marketing with Measurement Specialties (before it was acquired by TE in October 2014). Glen also obtained valuable experience through his prior positions at AMP, Pennwalt, and <NODE id="1081" />DuPont Electronics<NODE id="1099" />, and holds both a BS in Mechanical Engineering and an MBA. In his new role, MacGibbon will report to Heilind Vice President Alan Clapp. 'Glen’s expertise and proven track record make him the perfect candidate to drive Heilind’s sensor business. This is the next-generation connectivity that will fuel an increasing number of applications. With Glen’s direction, I look forward to making Heilind the go-to distributor for sensors and other smart technology.' The addition of this new position will not only give Heilind Electronics an advantage in the growing sensor marketplace, but will also facilitate the company’s overall growth and product diversity. About <NODE id="1762" />Heilind Electronics<NODE id="1781" /> Founded in 1974, <NODE id="1799" />Heilind Electronics, Inc.<NODE id="1824" /> ( <NODE id="1827" />http://www.heilind.com<NODE id="1849" /> / http://www.heilindasia.com ) is one of the world's leading distributors of connectors, relays, <NODE id="1947" />sensors<NODE id="1954" />, switches, thermal management and circuit protection products, terminal blocks, wire and cable, wiring accessories, and insulation and identification products. <NODE id="2115" />Heilind<NODE id="2122" /> has locations throughout the <NODE id="2152" />U.S<NODE id="2155" />., <NODE id="2158" />Canada<NODE id="2164" />, <NODE id="2166" />Mexico<NODE id="2172" />, <NODE id="2174" />Brazil<NODE id="2180" />, <NODE id="2182" />Germany<NODE id="2189" />, <NODE id="2191" />Singapore<NODE id="2200" />, <NODE id="2202" />Hong Kong<NODE id="2211" />, and <NODE id="2217" />China<NODE id="2222" />. Follow Heilind on Facebook at facebook.com/Heilind and on Twitter at twitter.com/Heilind . Share article on social media or email: View article via:
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/e52aa6bc-ec75-34b1-a411-c040fbce35d7" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-06T18:49:44Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:02:14.208Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/01/prweb13151132.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="0" endPos="7" type="organization-company" surface="Heilind" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="19" endPos="32" type="industry" surface="Sensor Market" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="826" endPos="828" type="organization-company" surface="TE" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1081" endPos="1099" type="organization-company" surface="DuPont Electronics" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1762" endPos="1781" type="organization-company" surface="Heilind Electronics" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1799" endPos="1824" type="organization-company" surface="Heilind Electronics, Inc." />
<Entity id="6" startPos="1827" endPos="1849" type="url" surface="http://www.heilind.com" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="1947" endPos="1954" type="product-class" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="2115" endPos="2122" type="organization-company" surface="Heilind" />
<Entity id="9" startPos="2152" endPos="2155" type="location" surface="U.S" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="2158" endPos="2164" type="location" surface="Canada" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="2166" endPos="2172" type="location" surface="Mexico" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="2174" endPos="2180" type="location" surface="Brazil" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="2182" endPos="2189" type="location" surface="Germany" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="2191" endPos="2200" type="location" surface="Singapore" />
<Entity id="15" startPos="2202" endPos="2211" type="location" surface="Hong Kong" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="2217" endPos="2222" type="location" surface="China" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="17" NAME="CompanyFacility">
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
<Entity id="13" label="location" />
<Entity id="9" label="location" />
<Entity id="11" label="location" />
<Entity id="14" label="location" />
<Entity id="15" label="location" />
<Entity id="16" label="location" />
<Entity id="10" label="location" />
<Entity id="12" label="location" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="18" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="1" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="19" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="7" label="product" />
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="20" NAME="CompanyWebsite">
<Entity id="6" label="website" />
<Entity id="5" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="21" NAME="Identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="8" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
<Entity id="4" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
