<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2015 (65) - BMW 1 Series 5-Door £21,950 Reduced by £993 was £22,943 Loading Images... Date Registered: Oct 2015 Mileage: 123 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Petrol Price: £21,950 Colour: White Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport EC Combined (mpg) 52.3 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 60.1 EC Urban (mpg) 42.2  &gt; 52 MPG 19 Insurance Group 136 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 126 CO2 (g/km) £110 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport Insurance Group 19, Business Navigation System, Bluetooth Telephone Preparation, 18 Alloys, Sun Protection Glass, Multi Function Steering Wheel, Front Centre Armrest, Run Flat Tyres, Sports Seats, Front Foglights, <NODE id="667" />Rain Sensor<NODE id="678" /> Wipers with Auto Headlight Activation, 12v Auxiliary Power Socket, DAB Digital Radio, M Sport Suspension, M-Aerodynamic Bodystyling, M-Steering Wheel, Airbags, Electric Windows, Immobiliser, ''We Can Guarantee The Future Value Of This Car, Please Call For Accurate Mileage Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01423 582187 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01423 582187 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power socket in centre console 12V power socket in passenger footwell 4 grab handles 60/40 split rear seats ABS/EBD Automatic Stability Control (ASC) BMW emergency call BMW teleservices Body coloured door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Door armrests Door sill finishers with illuminated M designation Drive Performance Control DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric front windows + one touch + anti-pinch Electric rear windows Electrically adjustable door mirrors Engine start/stop button Folding rear seat head rests Front folding/sliding centre armrest with storage Front head restraints Front sports seats with electric side bolster adjustment Glovebox Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated door mirrors Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist Individual anthracite headlining Isofix rear child seat preparation Leather gear knob and handbrake grip 'Lights On' warning buzzer Load restraint lashing eyes M sports leather steering wheel Multifunction steering wheel with audio controls Oil level indicator On board computer On board diagnostics Outside temperature display Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear wash/wipe Service interval indicator Speed limiter Storage compartments in doors Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio with CD player DAB Digital radio Exterior / Styling Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Brake force display Chrome exhaust tailpipe Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Follow me home headlights M aerodynamic bodystyling Run flat tyres Safety / Security Automatic drive away locking facility Child locks on rear doors Crash sensor Driver/Passenger airbags (Impact dependent) Drivers knee airbag Electronic immobiliser Front passenger airbag deactivation Front side airbags ITS head airbags for front/rear Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Remote central locking Seat belt force limiter Thatcham Cat.1 alarm Three 3 point rear seatbelts Tyre pressure monitor Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01423 582187 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 126
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/ef27f82b-4da0-399e-9c29-5ed848050f9a" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-14T22:00:17Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:06:05.214Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39376110/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="667" endPos="678" type="product-class" surface="Rain Sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
