<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Username or Email Address ℃ Riyadh Technology &amp; IT NEWS Technology &amp; IT is sponsored by: Posted on: Sunday 17 January, 2016 2:49 am Sony Professional Responds to Market Gap for Smarter and More Efficient Security Solutions Responding to the evolving market need for visual security solutions addressing end-user pinch points, Sony Professional Solutions MEA will be showcasing its 4K based security solutions at Intersec. At the region's largest exhibition for the Security and Safety industry, the company aims to address industry-wide concerns including storage limitations, surveillance loss due to network downtime, and impact of low light on image quality. The security segment continues to witness growth in the Middle East region and the customer requirements have also shown significant changes. As the industry evolves, the end-users demand more efficiency, affordability and exceptional performance which makes 4K the new standard in a growing number of applications. Sony has been a front runner in 4K technology and now we are taking this a step further by making surveillance smarter, more efficient, and cost effective, said Aydin Tolan, Business Head Visual Presentation Solutions Sony Professional Solutions MEA. Intersec is a key event in the regional security calendar and a brilliant platform for us to show our latest security solutions to multiple industry influencers and demonstrate how Sony addresses industry issues and envisions the future of video security. <NODE id="1485" />Sony<NODE id="1489" /> security cameras combine high performance <NODE id="1532" />4K Exmor R™ CMOS sensor<NODE id="1555" />, lens and image processor, to provide extraordinary imaging performance and unprecedented low light sensitivity, enabling Sony cameras to capture excellent images that are beyond the reach of conventional 4K security. End-users can effectively protect data even during network downtime with Sony's Edge Storage. Cameras that support an Edge Storage function are able to detect when the network drops and, during any outage, can record video to the memory cards (such as SD and micro SD cards) attached to the camera. Once the network is re-established, the recording solution identifies the missing segments and retrieves the video from the memory card to essentially fill in the blanks on the central recording archive. Usually, when opting for higher resolution security solutions, there is a trade-off between bandwidth usage and sensitivity. Sony Professional provides tailored solutions to ensure that high quality video output is achieved without compromising planned storage and bandwidth requirements. Intelligent coding, a new encoding method, developed by Sony, ensures high picture quality, while efficiently conserving storage resources. Along with 4K imaging, Sony cameras are equipped with a unique optical image stabilization technology with gyroscope sensors that detect and correct camera shake which often results from external factors such a variations in the weather. Image stabilization enables teams in the control room to have access to better video recording which is not impacted by environmental changes. At Intersec 2016, Sony will be displaying these features of its 4K security solutions in a control room scenario to enable visitors to experience the future of video security. The control room will also feature, Sony VPL GTZ1 projector, which combines Sony's proven 4K SXRD™ with a laser phosphor light source, to deliver unmatched colour brightness and superb picture quality. Sony will be exhibiting at Intersec Stand SA-C23 Sheikh Saeed Arena, Dubai International Convention &amp; Exhibition Centre, Dubai. Posted on: Sunday 17 January, 2016 2:49 am Sony Professional Responds to Market Gap for Smarter and More Efficient Security Solutions Responding to the evolving market need for visual security solutions addressing end-user pinch points, Sony Professional Solutions MEA will be showcasing its 4K based security solutions at Intersec. At the region's largest exhibition for the Security and Safety industry, the company aims to address industry-wide concerns including storage limitations, surveillance loss due to network downtime, and impact of low light on image quality. The security segment continues to witness growth in the Middle East region and the customer requirements have also shown significant changes. As the industry evolves, the end-users demand more efficiency, affordability and exceptional performance which makes 4K the new standard in a growing number of applications. Sony has been a front runner in 4K technology and now we are taking this a step further by making surveillance smarter, more efficient, and cost effective, said Aydin Tolan, Business Head Visual Presentation Solutions Sony Professional Solutions MEA. Intersec is a key event in the regional security calendar and a brilliant platform for us to show our latest security solutions to multiple industry influencers and demonstrate how Sony addresses industry issues and envisions the future of video security. Sony security cameras combine high performance 4K Exmor R™ CMOS sensor, lens and image processor, to provide extraordinary imaging performance and unprecedented low light sensitivity, enabling Sony cameras to capture excellent images that are beyond the reach of conventional 4K security. End-users can effectively protect data even during network downtime with Sony's Edge Storage. Cameras that support an Edge Storage function are able to detect when the network drops and, during any outage, can record video to the memory cards (such as SD and micro SD cards) attached to the camera. Once the network is re-established, the recording solution identifies the missing segments and retrieves the video from the memory card to essentially fill in the blanks on the central recording archive. Usually, when opting for higher resolution security solutions, there is a trade-off between bandwidth usage and sensitivity. Sony Professional provides tailored solutions to ensure that high quality video output is achieved without compromising planned storage and bandwidth requirements. Intelligent coding, a new encoding method, developed by Sony, ensures high picture quality, while efficiently conserving storage resources. Along with 4K imaging, Sony cameras are equipped with a unique optical image stabilization technology with gyroscope sensors that detect and correct camera shake which often results from external factors such a variations in the weather. Image stabilization enables teams in the control room to have access to better video recording which is not impacted by environmental changes. At Intersec 2016, Sony will be displaying these features of its 4K security solutions in a control room scenario to enable visitors to experience the future of video security. The control room will also feature, Sony VPL GTZ1 projector, which combines Sony's proven 4K SXRD™ with a laser phosphor light source, to deliver unmatched colour brightness and superb picture quality. Sony will be exhibiting at Intersec Stand SA-C23 Sheikh Saeed Arena, Dubai International Convention &amp; Exhibition Centre, Dubai.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1cd29318-dfd6-3035-b80f-24c52593e684" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-17T05:32:23Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:46:12.334Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.eyeofriyadh.com/news/newsdetail.php?newsid=62100" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1485" endPos="1489" type="organization-company" surface="Sony" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1532" endPos="1555" type="product" surface="4K Exmor R™ CMOS sensor" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="2" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
