<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>News Tire Pressure Sensor Modules, Tire Pressure Monitoring System, Wheel, Methods and Computer Programs for Providing Information Related to a Tire... Computer Weekly News | Thursday, 04 February 2016 18:30 (EST) Tire <NODE id="219" />Pressure Sensor<NODE id="234" /> Modules, Tire Pressure Monitoring System, Wheel, Methods and Computer Programs for Providing Information Related to a Tire Pressure in Patent Application Approval Process (USPTO 20160016445) By a News Reporter-Staff News Editor at Computer Weekly News -- A patent application by the inventors Peine, Andre (Muenchen, DE); Lange, Thomas (Muenchen, DE), filed on July 17, 2015, was made available online on January 28, 2016, according to news reporting originating from Washington, D.C., by VerticalNews correspondents. This patent application has not been assigned to a company or institution. The following quote was obtained by the news editors from the background information supplied by the inventors: Tire Pressure Monitoring Systems (TPMS) are designed to monitor the air pressure inside of pneumatic tires on various types of vehicles. Therefore pressure sensors are used in the tires and the system may report the tire pressure information to the driver of the vehicle. Wireless transmission can be used to transmit information on the pressure data to a centralized receiver component in the vehicle. Such a configuration can enable the system to report or signal pressure losses of the tires to the driver. Some known TPMSs provide localization information on the tire or wheel on top of pressure information so as to indicate to a driver of a vehicle the position of a wheel having a pressure loss. Regulations on TPMS requirements become existent in more and more countries. Automotive manufacturers therefore tend to provide TPMS as standard equipment. At least some TPMS are battery powered, where the lifespan of such a battery determines the lifespan of the TPMS. For example, some national regulations require the lifespan of a TPMS to be at least seven years, which may render power efficiency to an important design objective for TPMS, especially when further functionalities, such as additional measurements, are also to be implemented in a TPMS module. In addition to the background information obtained for this patent application, VerticalNews journalists also obtained the inventors' summary information for this patent application: Embodiments provide pressure modules, a system, a wheel, methods and computer programs for providing information related to a tire pressure of a wheel of a vehicle. Embodiments make use of a separation of a TPMS into two modules, where a first module covers a lower velocity range of the tire and a second module covers a higher velocity range of the tire. Operating the modules in active and in inactive states may allow operating the first module in an energy efficient inactive state above a velocity threshold while the second module may be operated in the active state above the velocity threshold. Embodiments provide a first tire pressure sensor module configured to provide information related to a pressure of a tire of a vehicle. The first tire pressure sensor module comprises a pressure sensor configured to determine the information related to the pressure of the tire. The first tire pressure sensor module further comprises a controller configured to selectively operate the first pressure module in an active state and in an inactive state, wherein an energy consumption of the first pressure module is lower in the inactive state than in the active state. The controller is further configured to control an output of the information related to the pressure of the tire in the active state. The controller is further configured to operate the first pressure module in the inactive state based on determining that information related to a velocity of the tire indicates a velocity above a threshold. Embodiments may therefore provide a first tire pressure sensor module or TPMS module, which can be operated in an energy efficient mode above a velocity threshold, which may enable energy saving or battery lifetime extension. Such improved energy efficiency may also allow for lower capacity batteries or smaller sized batteries while keeping an expected lifespan or lifetime. In some embodiments the first tire pressure sensor module may further be configured for valve mounting or it may be comprised in a valve for the tire. Embodiments may therefore provide an energy efficient valve pressure sensor. The first tire pressure sensor module may further comprise a battery. Embodiments may enable an extended battery lifespan or lifetime for a valve mounted pressure module. In further embodiments the first tire pressure sensor module may comprise a rechargeable energy device and a power interface, which is configured to charge the rechargeable energy device. Moreover, embodiments may provide a first tire pressure sensor module, which comprises a rechargeable energy device, such that a lifespan or lifetime of the tire pressure sensor module may be further extended through recharging, which may in particular be advantageous for valve mounted tire pressure sensor modules as its battery may last longer, may be of smaller size and/or lighter weight, respectively. In some embodiments the power interface may be configured to be coupled with another or a second pressure sensor module. The other tire pressure sensor module may then be configured to charge the rechargeable energy device through the interface. Embodiments may enable recharging of a first tire pressure sensor module through a second tire pressure sensor module. Embodiments further provide a second tire pressure sensor module, which is configured to provide information related to a pressure of a tire of a vehicle. The second tire pressure sensor module comprises a pressure sensor configured to determine the information related to the pressure of the tire. The second tire pressure sensor module further comprises an energy harvester, which is configured to supply power to the tire pressure sensor module. The second tire pressure sensor module further comprises a controller configured to operate the second tire pressure sensor module in an active state and in an inactive state. An energy consumption of the second tire pressure sensor module is lower in the inactive state than in the active state. The controller is further configured to control an output of the information related to the tire pressure in the active state. The controller is further configured to operate the second tire pressure sensor module in the active state based on determining that information related to a velocity of the tire indicates a velocity above a threshold. Embodiments may provide a tire pressure sensor module, which provides or controls the output of information related to a tire pressure above a velocity threshold of a tire and may be operated in an energy efficient mode below said threshold. In some embodiments the second tire pressure sensor module may be configured for wall or tread mounting inside the tire. Embodiments may provide a tire mounted or in-tire TPMS or tire pressure sensor module, which provides information related to a tire pressure above a velocity threshold for the tire. In embodiments, the second tire pressure sensor module may hence use energy generated through the movement or deformations of the tire and use said energy as a power supply. In some embodiments the second tire pressure sensor module may hence be operated without a battery. In further embodiments the second tire pressure sensor module may further comprise an interface configured to supply power to another tire pressure sensor module. In other words, the second tire pressure sensor module may be able to power itself and another tire pressure sensor module when the tire velocity is above the threshold. Embodiments may hence provide an operating mode, in which the system is power supplied from the motion of the tire above the threshold, such that the system is operated without relying on any other permanent energy supply such as a battery. In some embodiments the second tire pressure sensor module may further comprise a sensor configured to determine information related to a dynamic driving condition of the vehicle. The second tire pressure sensor module may allow taking further measurements relating to the dynamic driving condition of the tire or a vehicle the tire is attached to. In some embodiments the controller may be further configured to determine the information related to the dynamic driving condition of the vehicle using the sensor when the tire pressure sensor module is in active state. In other words, above the velocity threshold the second tire pressure sensor module may allow taking additional measurements, e.g. using power supplied through the motion of the vehicle or tire and possibly also charging another pressure module. For example, the sensor may be configured to determine information related to at least one element of the group of a temperature of the tire, a dynamic behavior of a contact area of the tire, a shape of the contact area of the tire, a pressure distribution of the contact area of the tire, a deformation of the contact area of the tire, or an acceleration of the tire. Embodiments further provide a system for determining information related to a pressure of a tire comprising a first tire pressure sensor module as described above and a second tire pressure sensor module as described above. Embodiments provide a tire pressure monitoring system, which comprises a first pressure sensor module at a first location of a tire, and which comprises a second pressure sensor module at a second location of the tire different from the first location. The second pressure sensor module is powered by an energy harvester. The TPMS system is configured to transmit, in a first rotating state of the tire, pressure information sensed by the first pressure sensor module to an electronic control unit and, in a second rotating state of the tire, pressure information sensed by the second pressure sensor module to the electronic control unit. In some embodiments the second pressure sensor module may be powered by an energy harvester. Alternatively or additionally, the second pressure sensor module may be mounted inside of the tire. Embodiments further provide a wheel for a vehicle comprising a tire and a system for determining information related to a pressure of the tire according to the above. In some embodiments the first tire pressure sensor module may be configured to provide information related to a tire pressure in a first lower velocity range of the wheel and the second tire pressure sensor module may be configured to provide information related to a tire pressure in a second higher velocity range. In embodiments there may be some overlap of the first and second velocity ranges of the tire. Hence, in some embodiments in the lower velocity range the first tire pressure sensor module may provide the information related to the pressure of the tire and in the second velocity range, where energy may be supplied through an energy harvester using the motion of the tire, the information related to the tire pressure may be provided by the second tire pressure sensor module. Embodiments may hence provide a concept or system for determining information related to a tire pressure with improved energy efficiency, or with reduced overall power need with respect to a battery. In some embodiments the first velocity range of the wheel starts at or above zero velocity. In other words, a first battery powered tire pressure sensor module may cover a lower velocity range between zero or standstill of the tire and a velocity threshold and the second tire pressure sensor module may cover a higher velocity range starting at a velocity greater than zero, covering the threshold in case of overlap, and up to the highest velocities of the tire, the vehicle the tire is attached to, respectively. Embodiments further provide a method for providing information related to a pressure of a tire of a vehicle. The method comprises sensing the information related to the pressure of the tire and selectively operating in an active state and in an inactive state. Energy consumption is lower in the inactive state than in the active state. The method further comprises controlling an output of information related to the tire pressure in the active state. The method further comprises operating in the inactive state based on determining that information related to a velocity of the tire indicates a velocity above or below a threshold. Embodiments further provide a method, which comprises sensing a tire pressure with a first sensor module mounted at a first location of a tire, and transmitting first tire pressure information based on the sensing of the tire pressure with the first sensor module to an electronic control unit at least in a first time interval. The method further comprises operating the first sensor module in an inactive state at least in a second time interval, and sensing the tire pressure at least during the second time interval with a second sensor module. The second sensor module is mounted at a second location of the tire, wherein the second location is different from the first location. The method further comprises transmitting second tire pressure information based on the sensing of the tire pressure with the second sensor module to an electronic control unit at least during the second time interval. The second sensor module may be powered by an energy harvester and/or the second sensor module may be mounted inside of the tire. Embodiments further provide a computer program having a program code on a non-transitory media for performing, when the computer program is executed on a computer or on a processor, a method for providing information related to a pressure of a tire of a vehicle, as described above. In general, embodiments also provide one or more computer programs having a program code for performing one or more of the above described methods, when the computer program is executed on a computer, processor, or programmable hardware component. A further embodiment is a computer readable storage medium storing instructions which, when executed by a computer, processor, or programmable hardware component, cause the computer to implement one of the methods described herein. Embodiments further provide a vehicle comprising such a system as described above. BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS Some other features or aspects will be described using the following non-limiting embodiments of apparatuses and/or methods and/or computer programs by way of example only, and with reference to the accompanying figures, in which FIG. 1 shows block diagrams of embodiments of a first and a second pressure sensor module; FIG. 2 illustrates a view chart on state changes in an embodiment; FIG. 3 shows an embodiment of a first pressure sensor module for valve mounting; FIG. 4 shows an embodiment of a second pressure sensor module for tire mounting; FIG. 5 depicts a flow chart of an embodiment of a method for determining information related to a tire pressure; and FIG. 6 depicts a flow chart of another embodiment of a method. URL and more information on this patent application, see: Peine, Andre; Lange, Thomas. Tire Pressure Sensor Modules, Tire Pressure Monitoring System, Wheel, Methods and Computer Programs for Providing Information Related to a Tire Pressure. Filed July 17, 2015 and posted January 28, 2016. Patent URL: http://appft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO2&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsearch-adv.html&amp;r=5364&amp;p=108&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;d=PG01&amp;S1=20160121.PD.&amp;OS=PD/20160121&amp;RS=PD/20160121 Keywords for this news article include: Patents, Computers. Our reports deliver fact-based news of research and discoveries from around the world. Copyright 2016, NewsRx LLC DISCLOSURE: The views and opinions expressed in this article are those of the authors, and do not represent the views of equities.com . Readers should not consider statements made by the author as formal recommendations and should consult their financial advisor before making any investment decisions. To read our full disclosure, please go to: http://www.equities.com/disclaimer You have to be logged in to leave a comment.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/4ebb3d1d-847d-39b7-b790-3caddf2f3276" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-05T20:52:09Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:05:00.706Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.equities.com/news/tire-pressure-sensor-modules-tire-pressure-monitoring-system-wheel-methods-and-computer-programs-for-providing-information-related-to-a-tire" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="219" endPos="234" type="product-class" surface="Pressure Sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
