<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>3.6 litre 0 7 1 5 3 8 Mileage Diesel Oct 2010 Automatic 4 X 4 25 MPG £113 Cost to fill 574 Tank range (miles) 50 Insurance group £505 Road tax 5 Seats Vehicle Overview Vehicle Trim / Variant: VOGUE SE Metallic Black, Here we have a brilliantly presented Range Rover Vogue SE V8, complete with upgraded 22'' Revere alloy wheels and a number of extras such as:, Upgrades - 12 Months Warranty included, 22'' Diamond Turned Revere Alloys, Navigation System, Factory Fitted Electric Side Steps, Supercharged Design Pack, Cooled/Heated front seats, DAB (Digital Audio Broadcasting), Heated Rear Seats, Electric Front Seats - Memory Driver Side, Electric Glass Sunroof, Television Function, Harman Kardon Upgraded HiFi, 1 owner, Next MOT due 24/09/2016, Last serviced on 12/11/2015 at 69,888 miles, Full service history, Excellent bodywork, Black Full leather interior - Excellent Condition, Tyre condition Excellent, Four wheel-drive, Standard Features - Air Bag Driver, Air Bag Knee, Air Bag Passenger, Air Bag Side, Alarm, Anti-Lock Brakes, Armrest, Ashtray/Lighter, Central Door Locking, Centre Rear Seat Belt, Electric Windows (Front/Rear), Electronic Brake Force Distribution, Electronic Stability Programme, Exterior Lighting (Xenon Headlights), Extra Storage, Gear Knob Leather, Head Restraints, Heated Front Screen, Immobiliser, In Car Entertainment (Radio/CD), Mirrors External, Mirrors Internal, Paint Metallic, Parking Aid (Rear Parking Camera), Power-Assisted Steering, <NODE id="1476" />Rain Sensor<NODE id="1487" />, Satellite Navigation, Seat - ISOFIX Anchorage Point, Seats Heated (Driver/Passenger), Spare Wheel, Steering Wheel Leather, Sunroof Electric (Glass Tilt/Slide), Tinted Glass, Towing Equipment (General), Traction Control System, Upholstery Leather. 5 seats, ALL OUR CARS COME HPI CHECKED AND CLEAR. COMPETITIVE FINANCE QUOTES AVAILABLE ALONG WITH PART EXCHANGE AND NATION WIDE DELIVERY AVAILABLE. PLEASE CALL OR VISIT OUR WEB SITE www.stoneacrespecialist.c o.uk FOR FURTHER INFORMATION. Please Note: Viewing is appointment only at weekends., 26,900 Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted to this car... ABS Alarm Alloy wheels Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Cruise control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Electric sunroof Electrically adjustable drivers seat Electrically adjustable passenger seat Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Headlight washers Heated door mirrors Heated front seat Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Leather seat trim Navigation system PAS Passenger airbag Passenger airbag Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Side airbags Telephone Traction control Traction control Trip computer TV Equipment fitted to this car... This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 4 channel ABS Acoustic glass Adaptive cruise control Adaptive dynamics Asymmetric split fold rear seat Belgravia leather facia topper panel CBC - (Cornering brake control) Driver's lumbar support Driver's seat height adjustment DSC-Dynamic Stability Control DTC - Drag torque control Dual view touch screen EBD + Brake Assist Electric adjustable front seats Electric adjustable steering column Electric windows with one touch open Electrochrome rear view mirror + powerfold door mirrors Electrochromic door mirrors Electronic air suspension/variable ride height Electronic parking brake Electronic traction control Front and rear head restraints Front centre armrest Green tinted glass Heated and cooled front seats Heated electric door mirrors Heated rear seats Heated windscreen Hill descent control Homelink (garage door opener) Isofix child seat preparation Leather handbrake grip Loadspace cover Memory function for drivers seat &amp; Entertainment DAB Digital radio Portable audio system Exterior / Styling 20 V spoke alloy wheels Bi-xenon adaptive headlights Body coloured bumpers Brushed tread plates with RR lettering Electric tilt/slide sunroof Front fog lights Full size spare wheel Headlamp wash/wipe Safety / Security 3 rear 3 point seatbelts Cat. 1 remote alarm with interior protection, tilt sensor and battery back-up Driver and passenger airbags Driver/front passenger head+thorax airbag Drivers knee airbag Front seatbelt pretensioners with force limiters Front side airbags Immobiliser Locking wheel nuts Remote central locking Technical Specifications... The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. 25 MPG £113 Cost to fill 574 Tank range (miles) 50 Insurance group £505 Road tax 5 Seats 3.6 litre Diesel Oct 2010 Automatic 4 X 4 Black Emissions CO2 (g/km) 294
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/4cdac040-f196-3058-a08a-0d825c7c159e" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-11T12:05:24Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:04:18.596Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.driving.co.uk/car-40196154/rlw" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1476" endPos="1487" type="product-class" surface="Rain Sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
