<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Product Details Company Profile Electric Glass Bottle Filling Machine , Beverage / Drinking Water Bottling Equipment PET/Glass Bottle Filling Machine/Beverage Filling Plant for Drinking Water Quick Detail: Model: CGF36-26-12 3 in 1 Monoblock Full line including: Rinser-Filler-Capper 3 in 1 machine, Lamp Checker, Labeling Machine, Film Shrink Machine/Carton Packing Machine Bottle Type: 200ml to 1.5L/2L-10L Bottle Material: PET/PP/PE/HDPE Plastic Bottle Cap Type: Screw cap, Pressing Cap, Sport cap Place of Origin: Zhangjiagang city, China near Shanghai Bottle Shape: Round/Square/Rectangular/Irregular Capacity: 12,000 to 14,000 bottles per hour Brand: BJM Application: Pure water/Mineral water/Drinking water/Non-carbonated water/Beverage/Codiment etc Rinser Head: 24pcs Filler Head: 24pcs Capper Head: 8pcs Specifications: Application Pure water/Mineral water/Drinking water/Non-carbonated water/Beverage/Codiment etc Suitable bottle Type PET bottle with size 200ml to 1500ml/2L to 10L Bottle Height Bottle height. Φ160—φ340mm Bottle Diameter Bottle dia.φ50-φ90mm Suitable cap type Plastic Screw Cap/Pressing Cap/Sport Cap Supply Capacity 12,000 to 14,000 bottles per hour(500ml bottle) Filling Type Mico Low Negative filling type Filling Temperature ambient/Room Temperature Voltage 220/380V(Custom made) Power 50HZ/60HZ(Custom made) Automatic Grade Fully Automatic Driven Type Electric Material High quality SUS304 stainless steel After-sales Service Engineers available to service machinery overseas Description: 1, The rinser, filler and capper 3 in 1 job can be finished by one machine automatically, the bottle goes through rinsing, filling and capping with little abrasion, and the transferring is stable, and bottle changing is easier. 2, The water filling equipment is used in filling mineral water, purified water, still water etc in bottles made of polyester and plastics. The handle of the machine can be freely and conveniently turned to adjust the machine to fill various types of bottles. 3, The machine operation is faster and more stable because the micro gravity filling operation of the new type is adopted. There the output and benefit of the machine is higher than the machinery of the same specifications. 4, The full line water filling equipment includes: Washing-filling-capping 3 in 1 machine, lamp checker, label shrinking machine, code printer, hot shrink packing machine/carton packing machine and conveyors. It is a full automatic production line. 5, Spares contact with the liquid are all of excellent stainless steel or food level plastic. The electric system is of international brand and achieves the national food sanitary standard. Main equipment supplier Main motor Siemens Liquid level sensor France Pump South Pump(China Famous Brand) Touch screen Taiwan PLC Mitsubishi Inverter Mitsubishi Photoelectric switch Omron Contactor, Circuit breaker Snyder France Bearing NSK Japan Seal ring U.S Material contact valve, tank, pipe SUS304/316L All Parts we can custom made for requirement for each customer, like Grundfos Pumps, Sew Motor, Festo Electric Appliance, etc. Competitive Advantage: Full line production from Blowing machine to Water Packing Machine; Water Filling Machine uses neck handling by grippers bottle transmission, Fully automatic rinsing, filling and capping by PLC control; No bottle no rinsing; International brand Electrical components; All material contact parts are made of qualified stainless steel, wearable, stable with less malfunction; Using starwheel as its drive mechanism, which realize automatically rinsing, filling and capping. Benjamin Machinery pays great attention to technology, such as beer processing and filling technology, high-viscosity filling technology, glass bottle water filling technology. And we will try our best to satisfy your requirement, your message will be highly appreciated. Welcome to Benjamin Machinery. Benjamin machinery Co.,Ltd Benjamin Machinery, is a rapid growing enterprise who is a professional manufacture and supplier for Water &amp; Beverage &amp; Liquid Filling Packaging Machine. It is located in Zhangjiagang city near Shanghai China, established in 2008. In the last 5 years, Benjamin made more than 100 turkey lines in Canada, Middles East, Africa, Southeast Asia, Latin America etc all round the world. We are always keeping very kind relationship with many strong water, beverage factories in China and Foreign Country, like BIMBO, AMAZON, LAYAN, ALSAQIAH. In the business concept of  Easy Operation, Good Use; Quality Upmost, Service Supreme, the company has established a complete quality assurance system and committed to a good faith in beverage packaging market domestically and internationally. Its leading products include washing filling capping machine (3-in-1), filling capping machine (2-in-1), sterilizing washing filling capping machine (4 in 1), filling sealing machine (2-in-1) for water, carbonated soft drink, tea and juice, beer, wine, and various types of beverage and condiment, gallon drum series machine set, water treatment production line, automatic cleaning system, various complete sets of sterilization equipment, washing filling capping production line, and complete equipment of fruit juice, tea, wine and beverage. Benjamin has a professional technical group, who in charge of domestic and oversea machine installation, maintenance, training employees for our current and potential customers. We have a good relationship with domestic famous institute who can provide us with authoritative analysis and report of new technology and research in beverage filling field. The ISO 9001 international quality management system is at the heart of our factory’s manufacturing standards. Benjamin providers not only a diverse product line, but our reliability adds value to your purchase, helps you cut costs, and improves your productivity. Benjamin’s innovative machine design will strengthen your competitive edge and maximize your time budget. Looking forward to the future, Benjamin Machinery will keep improving its advantages and innovating its technology, and devote to providing customized turnkey solutions for liquid product manufacturers to repay the most to customer’s investment. Send your message to this supplier Inquiry Cart 0
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/dd129d59-1da8-39f2-8c9c-5d531abf8419" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-11T19:22:45Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:59:11.294Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.ccnmag.com/product-search/pz6661f5c-cz510fedf-electric-glass-bottle-filling-machine-beverage-drinking-water-bottling-equipment.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
