<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Research and Markets: Industrial Automation Control Market in APAC 2016-2020 - Surge in Demand for Chemical &amp; Petrochemical Products World News: 11:29 GMT Tuesday 12th January 2016 . [ Research and Markets via Businesswire via SPi World News ] Research and Markets (http://www.researchandmarkets.com/research/6z4drf/industrial) has announced the addition of the Industrial Automation Control Market in APAC 2016-2020 report to their offering. The report predicts the industrial automation control market in APAC to grow steadily at a CAGR of 8% during the forecast period. The surge in the demand for chemical and petrochemical products from APAC is the primary growth driver for this market. The high adoption of automation control solutions across chemicals plants in China, Japan, South Korea, India, and Taiwan has been contributing to the growth of the market. The use of cloud-based SCADA systems is a trend emerging in the global SCADA market. Generally, SCADA systems are installed to control and monitor <NODE id="1013" />sensors<NODE id="1020" /> and transmitters installed in the facility. A controller or operator sits insides the facility and controls applications with the help of a human machine interface (HMI). The integration of cloud computing technology with SCADA systems enables operators to control applications via the Internet. According to the report, the concept of MAC arose from end-users that demand complete solutions from automation manufacturers. MAC handles coordination, installation, and maintenance of all automation and related activities and reduces the number of people required. MAC is also responsible for coordinating with other automation manufacturers to provide automation solutions or products that are not available to them. Further, the report states that limited awareness of the underlying benefits of implementing APC solutions is hindering market growth. Companies Mentioned: ABB Honeywell Rockwell Automation Schneider Electric Siemens Emerson Electric GE Metso Mitsubishi Heavy Industry Omron Yokogawa Electric Toshiba. Key Topics Covered: PART 01: Executive summary
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/d98afc28-f781-31b7-9515-1a53c6133287" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-13T03:45:50Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:57:50.122Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.sectorpublishingintelligence.co.uk/news/1341430/research+and+markets+industrial+automation+control+market+in+apac+20162020++surge+in+demand+for+chemical++petrochemical+products" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1013" endPos="1020" type="product-class" surface="sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
