<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2013 (13) - BMW 1 Series 1.6 116i Sport Sports Hatch 3dr (start/stop) £13,990 Reduced by £1,000 was £14,990 Loading Images... Date Registered: May 2013 Mileage: 24,000 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Petrol Price: £13,990 Colour: White Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: Sport EC Combined (mpg) 50.4 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 60.1 EC Urban (mpg) 38.7  &gt; 50 MPG 18 Insurance Group 136 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 131 CO2 (g/km) £130 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: Sport Insurance Group 18, White, 45+MPG High Quality BMW, Last serviced on 06/03/2015 at 17,152 miles, Full dealership history, Still Under BMW Warranty Until May 2016, 5 Day Drive Away Insurance Available, HPi Clear, Low Rate Finance Available, Cruise Control, Multi Function Steering Wheel, Air Conditioning, Rear Parking Sensors, 6 Speed Manual Transmission, Radio/CD, Auxillary Input, USB Port, Electric Windows, Electric Mirrors, Alloy Wheels, Nationwide Delivery Available, Part Exchange Your Car. 5 seats, This BMW 116i offers low running costs combined with a high quality interior and is great to drive. The low running costs come from its modern petrol engine which offers in excess of 45MPG and has great real world performance. BMW's have always been known as the ''ultimate driving machine'' and this 116i is no different and although it may not have as much power as some models it can still be fun to drive. So if you are looking for a nearly new family hatchback then you must consider this BMW 116i. We are based in Yeovil Somerset with full dealer facilities. We promise NO pressure selling. All vehicles have service, warranty, MOT &amp; a clear HPI report prior to collection. Please call for more details or to arrange a test drive. We are located on the main A30 between Yeovil and Crewkerne at BA22 9ER. We promise No Pressure selling so relax and enjoy the West Country experience., West Country Cars Driven By Reputation, 13,990 p/x welcome Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01935 574791 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Passenger airbag Radio/CD Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01935 574791 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power socket in centre console 12V power socket in passenger footwell 2 cupholders 4 grab handles 60/40 split rear seats ABS/EBD Automatic Stability Control (ASC) CBC - (Cornering brake control) Door armrests Drive Performance Control DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric front windows + one touch + anti-pinch Electrically adjustable door mirrors Engine start/stop button Folding rear seat head rests Front door sill finishers in Sport designation Front door storage bins Front folding/sliding centre armrest with storage Front head restraints Front isofix attachment + airbag deactivation Front sports seats with electric side bolster adjustment Glovebox Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated door mirrors Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist Isofix rear child seat preparation Leather gear knob and handbrake grip 'Lights On' warning buzzer Load restraint lashing eyes Multifunction steering wheel with audio controls Oil level indicator On board computer On board diagnostics Outside temperature display Rain sensor including auto headlights activation Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear wash/wipe Run flat indicator (RFI) - tyre puncture warning system Service interval indicator Speed limiter Storage compartments in front/rear door panels Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio with CD player Digital Audio Broadcast (DAB) Tuner Exterior / Styling Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Brake force display Chrome exhaust tailpipe Follow me home headlights Front fog lights High gloss black kidney grille Run flat tyres Safety / Security Child locks on rear doors Crash sensor Driver/Passenger airbags (Impact dependent) Drivers knee airbag Electronic immobiliser Front side airbags ITS head airbags for front/rear Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Remote central locking Seat belt force limiter Thatcham Cat.1 alarm Three 3 point rear seatbelts Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01935 574791 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 131
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/3b573cdc-3b2b-3ab9-95c5-f90f763e4607" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-30T19:59:55Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:57:40.627Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39249292/rw" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
