<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 12, 2016 C O N T E N T S: Image Courtesy: link: https://www.qinetiq-na.com/products/unmanned-systems/talon/ author: qinetiq-na.com description: Center attack in NY City. KEY TOPICS Boston transplant Sam Tolkoff, who leads San Francisco startup NGxBio after stints at startups QinetiQ and Bluefin Robotics, said the West Coast may not necessarily have the edge in the robotics sector going forward. [1] Established in late 2009 as a boutique provider of optronics, robotics and intuitive imaging, Roboteam beat out much larger and more established U.S. firms Foster Miller, a subsidiary of British QinetiQ; and Bedford, Massachusetts-based iRobot. [2] QinetiQ North America launched a commercial robotic system for select equipment. [3] The integration of our new DM4-A2 robotic arm onto QinetiQ's DR 10-I is an excellent example of an interoperable system that meets the military's current need for a modular lightweight robot. [4] David Walsh writes the military service is working to modify a QinetiQ North America -designed unmanned ground vehicle as part of the branch's Combat Robotics System development program. [5] Powerful, modular and combat-ready, the Modular Advanced Armed Robotic System (MAARS) from QinetiQ North America is an unmanned ground vehicle (UGV) designed expressly for reconnaissance, surveillance, and target acquisition (RSTA) missions to increase the security of personnel manning forward locations. [6] RE2 and QinetiQ are working with the University of Texas at Arlington on a $1 million grant from the National Science Foundation to develop a robotic nursing assistant. [7] QinetiQ NA's Modular Advanced Armed Robotic System is equipped with day and night cameras, a hostile fire detection technology and a high-intensity siren speaker and is designed to carry machine guns, laser dazzlers or grenade launchers. [5] Three years later, Virginia-based QinetiQ brought its improved Modular Advanced Armed Robotic System to the 2007 AUSA event. [8] Roboteam is muscling into an increasingly crowded market, which includes big players like iRobot, Boston Dynamics and QinetiQ, as well as a host of Silicon Valley startups with names like Fetch Robotics and Adept Technology. [9] Will, Simon, and KJK spent today at QinetiQ North America's office in Pittsburgh today as part of our participation in the Army-funded Robotics Collaborative Technology Alliance (RCTA). [10] In addition to the FASCAN International interrogation arm, the Husky 2G is also equipped with the TORC Robotics 360 Situational Awareness camera system and QinetiQ North Americas QNET, which provides the vehicle with lightweight protection from rocket-propelled grenades (RPGs). [11] Prior to joining Neya, Mr. Stancil served as a project manager at QinetiQ North America where he lead the development of automated capability and control for several of the military?s fielded robotic EOD platforms including QinetiQ?s DragonRunner, TALON, and MAARS unmanned systems. [12] Four robotics companies HDT Robotics, iRobot, Northrop Grumman and QinetiQ have already ran their machine gun-armed robots through a live-fire demo at Fort Benning in what has been dubbed the Robotic Rodeo. [13] POSSIBLY USEFUL RE2 Robotics is developing the next generation of robotic manipulator arms, intuitive controllers, and software that enable your robot to better interact with the world – whether on the ground, in the air, or underwater. [14] RE2 is dedicated to developing interoperable technologies that easily integrate onto the industry?s leading robotic platforms, stated Jorgen Pedersen, president and CEO of RE2. [14] Beware the Valley of Death Robotics startups typically take their technology out of development with help from the Department of Defense or early investments from venture capitalists. [1] Navigating this valley of death is a right of passage for robotics startups, said Cynthia Breazeal, MIT Media Lab professor and co-founder of robotics startup Jibo. [1] In the still-new robotics market, that?s an even bigger tendency. [1] Tolkoff said he?d bet on Boston and Pittsburgh over the Valley for robotics. [1] WALTHAM, Mass., Feb. 4, 2015 /PRNewswire/ –QinetiQ North America (QNA) announced today the launch of a new, commercial robotic system that transforms manned industrial vehicles into unmanned robots. [15] The DM4-A2 is compliant with the Advanced Explosive Ordnance Disposal Robotic System (AEODRS) architecture, meaning that it interoperates physically, electrically, and logically with other AEODRS Capability Modules. [14] PITTSBURGH, PA – May 19, 2015 – RE2, Inc., a leading developer of modular robotic manipulation systems, announced today that the company has developed a new high-performance robotic arm. [14] The integration of our new DM4-A2 robotic arm onto QinetiQ?s DR 10-I is an excellent example of an interoperable system that meets the military?s current need for a modular lightweight robot. [14] The DM4-A2 robotic arm is highly modular, lightweight, and power-dense. [14] While the author was test-driving the Dragon Runner, a smaller tracked robot with an arm also made by Qinetiq, a service dog in training walked by. [16] QNA is headquartered in Waltham, Massachusetts and operates as the U.S. arm of QinetiQ Group's Global Products division. [15] The QinetiQ BATS provides the QinetiQ robot user with the greatest ease, speed, and versatility of any gripper tool on the market. [17] About QinetiQ North America QinetiQ North America (QNA) is a subsidiary of QinetiQ Group plc, the FTSE250 company listed on the London Stock Exchange (LSE: QQ.L). [15] RE2 recently integrated the DM4-A2 onto the IOP compliant Dragon Runner? 10 Interoperable (DR 10-I) by QinetiQ North America. [14] Dan Deguire, director of engineering and product development for QinetiQ North America's Unmanned Systems. [15] QinetiQ North America delivers world-class technology and revolutionary products to defense, security and commercial markets worldwide. [18] QinetiQ North America, ranked number 4 in the list, makes what are called TALON robots that are used for explosive ordinance disposal, reconnaissance, communications, CBRNE (Chemical, Biological, Radiological, Nuclear, Explosive)/hazmat, security, defense and rescue missions. [19] The robot was used to detect radioactive materials released by Japan's Fukushima Daiichi Nuclear power plant in the aftermath of the massive 2011 earthquake and tsunami, said Tom Phelps, the company's director of robotics products in North America. [20] The Boston Business Journal just released its Largest Robotics Companies in Massachusetts list, adding that the state is home to more than 100 companies and 10 universities that specialize in robots. [19] Three Waltham companies made the Boston Business Journal's list that focused on robotics companies in Massachusetts. [19] Boston Engineering ranked No. 9 in the list, with the BBJ stating, Boston Engineering, a Waltham-based business which specializes in unmanned robotics systems, including ground vehicles and underwater vehicles, grew its Massachusetts workforce to 75 employees this year from 45 in 2013 - representing growth of nearly 67 percent. [19] Job Qualifications: Aurora Flight Sciences is looking for a Robotics and Computer Science Engineer to work on and help architect autonomy software and algorithms for robotics systems in aerospace applications. [18] Does this work inspire you? Become part of the next generation – robotic – Minimally Invasive Surgery platform and join a very innovative and dynamic environment! Medtronic/Covidien is invested in the development of advanced mechatronics products and systems for Minimally. [18] RE2 is dedicated to developing interoperable technologies that easily integrate onto the industry's leading robotic platforms, stated Jorgen Pedersen, president and CEO of RE2. [4] About RE2, Inc. RE2 robotics is developing the next generation of mobile robotics technologies that enable your robot to better interact with the world. [4] Devens Robotica 2015, the first of what will be an annual event, brought together more than 50 companies with cutting-edge robotics technologies. [20] Ready to get started? Begin here and here, where I profile one small up-and-comer in the robotic software space that has been making headlines and snapping up software companies. [21] At least 87 other countries have used military robotics of some sort, ranging from the UK to China, which has an especially fast-growing drone fleet, as shown off at its recent arms trade show. [22] Participants watched demonstrations of military rovers, commercial drones and various other inventions while also attending workshops on such topics as intelligent automated vehicles to maritime robotics to how to protect the skies from drones. [20] The College of Computer and Information Science and The College of Engineering at Northeastern University invite applications for multiple open positions in robotics at all levels. [18] In what DefenseOne.com is calling the next level in battlefield autonomy, the U.S. Marine Corps recently conducted a high-tech robotic scavenger hunt. [21] Familiarity with machine vision, automation, robotics technologies. [23] Who is passionate about drones, 3D scanning, solar, and loves to tinker with the latest hardware used in autonomous robotics. [23] The qualifying engineer will have a background in computer science, mechanical engineering, or aero/astro engineering, and experience in software development for control of robotic systems. [18] The company?s FDA cleared CorPath System is the first robotic system that offers interventional cardiologists precise procedure and stent control during vascular interventions. [19] The Waltham company CorPath Vascular Robotic System was ranked number 10 in the BBJ?s list. [19] PITTSBURGH, PA –(Marketwired – May 19, 2015) – RE2, Inc., a leading developer of modular robotic manipulation systems, announced today that the company has developed a new high-performance robotic arm. [4] Demonstrated unmanned rovers included Talon V, a robot developed by QinetiQ, a British company with an office in Waltham. [20] Chris Reading, a mechanical engineer with QinetiQ, mans a robot that is designed for disabling improvised explosive devices during Devens Robotica 2015 on Wednesday. [20] Sure, arguments will flare as to whether General Atomics' Predator or Northrop Grumman's Global Hawk is the better spy plane, and whether iRobot or QinetiQ makes the better bomb-disposal robot. [21] It is the surging demand for mobile robots in field applications, which will drive the Asia Pacific mobile robotics market in the years to come. [24] Surging demand for AGVs in industrial applications and demand for drones in defense are the two main factors that propel the Asia Pacific mobile robotics market. [24] The report titled ‘ Mobile Robotics Market – Global Industry Analysis, Size, Share, Growth, Trends and Forecast 2013 – 2019 s' is available for sale on the company website. [24] In 2012, with a share of 34.2%, Asia Pacific was the largest regional player in the overall mobile robotics market. [24] According to this TMR report, the key factors driving the global mobile robotics market are integration of mobile robots with mobile technologies, surging venture capital investments in service robotics companies, and increasing funds and grants by governments. [24] The surging demand for UAVs and high demand for AGVs in distribution and warehousing applications will stimulate the global mobile robotics market during the forecast period. [24] Application-wise, the global mobile robotics market is segmented into industrial applications and service applications. [24] Top-Down ? Evaluate High level architectures provide a solid basis to inform enterprise level decision ? UAS Control Segment (UCS) ? Future Airborne Capability Environment (FACE) ? STANAG 4586 (Unmanned Aerial System messaging) ? Joint Architecture for Unmanned Systems (JAUS – ground and maritime robotics) ? Determine ideal, concept architecture: blue-sky 2. [25] In the services segment, mobile robotics are used in fields such as entertainment, healthcare, and defense amongst other areas. [24] Mobile robotics are mainly used in industrial activities such as warehousing distribution and logistics, inspection activities, painting and de-painting, and assembly operations. [24] The U.S. Marine Corps is examining land-based robotic technologies in order to help infantry soldiers with their patrolling, explosive disposal and combat missions, Defense Systems reported Tuesday. [5] James Piniero, a robotics project lead at the Marine Warfighting Lab told Defense Systems. [5] Walsh reports the Robotic Vehicle-Modular initiative is meant to utilize a platform from Polaris Defense and TORC Robotics. [5] Another prominent factor driving the global mobile robotics market is the decreasing price of cameras and sensors and also the availability of open source platforms. [24] Scarcity of experts in the R&amp;D segment is a key restraint in the global mobile robotics market. [24] The segment for UGVs inclusive of AGVs holds the largest share in the global mobile robotics market. [24] TMR, a market intelligence firm in its report states that by 2020, the global mobile robotics market, which in 2012 was valued at US$6249.6 million, is anticipated to reach US$14202.2 million by the end of the forecast period. [24] Business is our middle name; so here at Robotics Business Review, we believe that business, just as it has so aptly demonstrated since 1962, will ultimately be the force that drives all emerging robotics' technology forward. [7] Taking stock of those myriad changes, sorting through how each affects the new revolution and our future, and reporting on them to you our members is the job of Robotics Business Review. [7] Robotics business and the business of robotics are our prime focus. [7] In 2009, the Pentagon canned that project, putting the immediate future of the XM-1219 Armed Robotic Vehicle into doubt. [8] Robotic ground vehicles could haul gear or rescue wounded soldiers, blow up tanks, scout ahead of troops, plant landmines, put out fires or even just explode on command. [8] This year, Maryland-based Neany brought an armed robotic jet ski to the exposition hall. [8] Robotic arms could prevent injuries from routine duties and have wide application. [7] Why a common control software architecture Core Team 17 MAR 2015 JGRE CCA Study Team ? Douglas Gregory: Neya Systems ? David Barnhard: Kutta Technologies ? Kurt Bruck: QinetiQ North America ? Bill Huff: JHNA Team members representing the NAMC – not their individual companies. [25] Under four recently awarded task orders, QinetiQ North America?s Systems Engineering Group will continue to provide the Marine Corps Systems. [26] UK's air traffic services provider NATS has won a seven year contract extension to continue its work with QinetiQ. [26] QinetiQ has won a £153 million work contract from the UK Ministry of Defence (MOD) to deliver technical services to. [26] QinetiQ has won a contract from the U.S. Army on December 18 to build, refurbish and modernize two TALON IV. [26] The Israeli Micro-Tactical Ground robot (MTGR) has won a recent U.S. Air Force contract, following a tough competition against several U.S.-Developed systems which have already been widely used by the U.S. military, such as iRobot SUGV and QinetiQ NA Dragon Runner. [27] The top players operating in the global military ground robots market are Northrop Grumman, Vanguard, Lockheed Martin, Qinetiq, iRobot Kongsberg, Romotec, and General Dynamics. [28] According to the Global Marine Trends 2030 report produced by QinetiQ, maritime autonomous systems will be critical in the next 15 years. [29] The best part of the visit was testing our current prototype in the QinetiQ robot proving grounds, which includes a wide variety of ground surfaces and obstacles to really test the operator's capabilities during teleoperation. [10] QinetiQ (2009) Fast, powerful and versatile, high payload robot technology. [30] Big congratulations to Kyle for taking a new job as a robotics engineer at Barrett Technology, Inc., the maker of the WAM robot arm and the Barrett hand. [10] Its argument juxtaposes a critical assessment of the development of humanlike and animal-like robotic companions with a consideration of human relations with machinelike robots in working teams. [30] He is a roboticist with over fifteen years of robotics and technical expertise, including software development, electrical and mechanical engineering, machine vision, and autonomous self-driving vehicles. [31] Huntsville Center has been a leader in the development of robotics for work at ordnance clean-up sites around the country and at installations worldwide since 2005, and Bob Selfridge, Huntsville Center chief geophysicist and robotics technical lead for the vegetation clearance program, said newly developed second generation robotics equipment is certainly the safest and most economical way to clear the 80 year-old munitions range. [32] Our group had two papers accepted to this great robotics conference; Kyle presented his master's thesis work on the design and control of the iTorqU 2.1, and Joe presented the methods he developed for modeling haptic textures from recorded acceleration signals. [10] The title of Professor Kuchenbecker's presentation was Human-Inspired Robotic Grasp Control with Tactile Sensing, work completed by Joe Romano during his time at Willow Garage, working with Kaijen Hsiao, Gunter Niemeyer, Sachin Chitta, and KJK. The talk was well received, with interesting questions about how the approach could be adapted to other robotic platforms beyond the PR2. [10] Entitled Healing Patients Through Robotics, it describes work we are doing to give the doctor a sense of touch during robot-assisted surgery. [10] Joe Romano gave his MEAM Department Seminar today, entitled Enhancing Autonomous Robotic Manipulation via Haptic Perception. [10] In the following session, Katherine gave the talk for the paper Joe Romano and she wrote, entitled Methods for Robotic Tool-Mediated Haptic Surface Recognition. [10] Our ICRA paper won the Best Cognitive Robotics Paper Award which comes with a $1000 prize! The paper is entitled Using robotic exploratory procedures to learn the meaning of haptic adjectives, and the authors are Vivian Chu, Ian McMahon, Lorenzo Riano, Craig G. McDonald, Qin (Karen) He, Jorge Martinez Perez-Tejada, Michael Arrigo, Naomi Fitter, John Nappo, Trevor Darrell, and Katherine J. Kuchenbecker. [10] Haptic feedback, or the feeling of a surface through robotic technology, has many applications. [10] While many young companies have benefited from a flurry of recent innovation, from cheap off-the-shelf sensors to an open-source robotic operating system, Roboteam uses proprietary technology. [9] This is Penn's Summer Academy in Applied Science and Technology for high school students, and it offers concentrations in Biotechnology, Computer Graphics, Computer Science, Nanotechnology, and Robotics. [10] Many novice and experienced robotic surgeons got to try it, as did some representatives from Intuitive Surgical – the last one walked away saying it was FABULOUS. Professor Kuchenbecker also gave a talk about our technology on Friday afternoon in a session on the future of surgery and got a very positive response. [10] The ‘AirMule' Vertical TakeOff and Landing (VTOL) Unmanned Air Vehicle (UAV) successfully completed its first untethered flight at the Megiddo airfield in northern Israel on December 30th, the developer Tactical Robotics Ltd announced. [27] Today was RoboFest: A Celebration of Robotics at the GRASP Laboratory at Penn. RoboFest was organized as a Symposium and Open House honoring Ruzena Bajcsy, the GRASP Lab founder and Recipient of the 2009 Benjamin Franklin Medal in Computers and Cognitive Science. [10] It's National Robotics Week! To celebrate, the GRASP Lab hosted a whole bunch of high school students for a tour and demo session. [10] Joe's Penn Robotics GRASP Lab t-shirt also makes a great appearance. [10] Several members of the Haptics Lab spent some time on Hill Field today, helping Professor Dan Lee and the rest of his team set up a robotic obstacle course. [10] It was great to have another haptics / medical robotics professor on campus, and we hope to build a good relationship with Dr. Desai's lab at the University of Maryland. [10] We had a fun time visiting the University of Utah for tours of their robotics labs and attending the conference's opening reception. [10] Kyle and Jamie are Robotics masters students, and Bill is a Ph.D. student in Mark Yim's lab. [10] This morning several members of the lab attended an IEEE short course taught by Dr. Ralph Hollis, a professor in the Robotics Institute at Carnegie Mellon University. [10] There was a very informative Sunday workshop on Understanding the Human Hand for Advancing Robotic Manipulation with many fascinating talks, and the tour of the UW robotics labs (especially those of Blake Hannaford and Yoky Matsuoka ) was fabulous. [10] Today we gave a lab tour to ten local high school students who are on campus for Penn's IT and Robotics Summer Mentorship Program. [10] Penn recently created a series of four multimedia features about robotics here in the GRASP Lab. [10] Huntsville Center is using this innovative robotic range clearance process at Fort Bragg, North Carolina before construction can begin on the installation's new $40 million live-fire aerial range that will soon provide Army rotary wing aircraft aerial bombing and target practice. [32] Prior to joining Sidley, Carl was director of commercialization, in-house counsel, and senior robotics engineer at a robotics company in the Pittsburgh area. [31] He's taking a few weeks off before moving to Boston to begin his job as a Robotics Engineer at Heartland Robotics. [10] He and his group engineer soft, robust, capable robotic hands. [10] The growth in interconnected intelligent systems will require personnel to learn to work seamlessly with robotics systems. [29] Professor Kuchenbecker has spent the last several days at the Robotics: Science and Systems Conference in Seattle, Washington. [10] More good news! Our flexible tool force sensing paper has been accepted to the IASTED International Conference on Robotics and Applications (RA), which will be held November 4-6, in Cambridge, Massachusetts. [10] Later in the day, Dr. Desai gave a talk in the MEAM seminar series entitled Image-guided Surgical Robotics: From Macro-scale to Meso-scale. [10] This award was given for his paper entitled Objective Assessment of Robotic Surgical Skills using Instrument contact Vibrations and Predictive Regression Models. [10] David Lee gave a great talk entitled Robotic Surgery: Past, Present, and Future in today's GRASP seminar. [10] Will McMahan is at the Annual Meeting of the American Urological Association (AUA) today, presenting a poster entitled VerroTouch: Vibrotactile Feedback for Robotic Minimally Invasive Surgery. [10] As shown in the photos below, he gave a fascinating talk entitled A Developmental Approach to Robotic Intelligence. [10] Wolf, who previously ran the robotics division at an intelligence-gathering company, started Roboteam with a few hundred thousand shekels in an apartment belonging to his partner?s grandmother. [9] Vivienne Clayton completed her masters in Mechanical Engineering and Applied Mechanics, while Alex Anon and Kent deVillafranca completed masters degrees in Robotics. [10] Today the squad has more than 15 robotic platforms at its disposal, including Roboteam?s MTGR. [9] The invasion of Iraq by U.S. forces in response to the 9/11 terror attakcs had no support from robotic systems on the ground. [28] The robotic systems we developed are efficiently performing the work at Fort Bragg while reducing risks associated with buried UXO. [32] It was fascinating to learn about the work Professor Taylor and his team have been doing on robotic systems to enable surgeons to operate on back of the retina in the human eye! Professor Taylor also talked about some of the other projects going on the the ERC-CISST and the LCSR at JHU, including their Surgical Assistant Workstation, which looks very useful for our VerroTouch project. [10] Our haptography work is funded by this grant, and Prism highlighted the potential for haptic feedback (good vibrations) to improve robotic surgery and medical simulation. [10] Her presentation was entitled Haptics: Touch Feedback for Robotic Surgery and More, and it was attended by about fifty women engineers, including undergraduates, graduate students, and professionals. [10] Our booth was entitled Adding Haptics to Robotic Surgery, and it was fantastic. [10] Our recently accepted Surgical Endoscopy article is now available online! The title is In vivo validation of a system for haptic feedback of tool vibrations in robotic surgery, and the authors are Karlin Bark, William McMahan, Austin Remington, Jamie Gewirtz, Alexei Wedmid, David I. Lee and Katherine J. Kuchenbecker. [10] He referenced our EuroHaptics 2010 paper and showed images of VT from it and said it was one of his favorite examples of haptics in robotic surgery, saying you can actually feel it when two tools hit one another! VerroTouch also got a shout out at the IMSH conference Karlin attended last week, where it was mention by Dr. Bosseau Murray, the anesthesiologist collaborating with us on haptography for medical training and simulation. [10] The proposed title of his thesis is Haptic Perception for Telerobotic and Robotic Systems Via Tactile Acceleration Signals. [10] The workshop was entitled Magnetic Actuators for Robotic Systems, and it was held at the Sheraton Hotel in University City. [10] The Urology Times just published a nice news article summarizing our group's recent work on VerroTouch, which adds vibrotactile and audio feedback of tool vibrations to robotic surgery systems. [10] When the Pentagon recently selected a company to supply a portable, stair-climbing robot that can sniff out booby traps, top brass shunned market leaders like iRobot Corp. and QinetiQ North America. [9] The several types of military robots available in the market are General Dynamics Next-Generation, QinetiQ North America Talon Robots Universal Disrupter Mount, Explosive Observation Robot and Ordnance Disposal, and Soldier Unmanned Ground Vehicle from iRobot. [28] She had two missions to accomplish: take a look at the Westin hotel and visit QinetiQ North America. [10] KJK's visit to the Technology Solutions Group at QinetiQ also went really well. [10] The British defense tech company, QinetiQ, designed robots for the express purpose of extinguishing fires involving cylinders of the industrial gas, acetylene. [33] They carried out model prediction control for QinetiQ underwater robot with ARX model as the prediction model. [34] The Devens Interoperability Playground (IOP) will address an unmet need for field testing and independent certification of robotics systems such as driverless cars, first responder tools, delivery drones, agricultural robots and water safety patrol surface and subsurface vehicles. [35] The group included senior leaders from MassDevelopment, the state?s finance and development agency, the Mass Technology Leadership Council (MassTLC), the state?s largest technology association and organizer of the Mass Robotics Cluster, the Association for Unmanned Vehicle Systems International (AUVSI-NE), the leading international organization for unmanned systems and robotics, the MITRE Corporation, Draper Laboratory, and others from the robotics community. [35] Ofer Shochet Entrepreneur, Technologist and Founder, Golem Robotics Dr. Ofer Shochet is an entrepreneur and a technology visionary, specializing in the development and successful implementation of future technologies in various companies at various fields of technologies. [12] Carl Vause CEO, Soft Robotics Inc. Carl Vause is CEO of Soft Robotics Inc. Prior to Soft Robotics, Carl held a variety of senior positions in technology and medical device companies, most recently Vice President of Marketing at OmniGuide Surgical. [12] Aadhar holds a Bachelors of Science in Electrical Engineering from the Georgia Institute of Technology, where his focus was Artificial Intelligence and Robotics, and a Masters in Business Administration from the Harvard Business School. [12] He has served on the editorial boards of the IEEE Transactions on Robotics and Automation, IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering, ASME Journal of Mechanical Design, the ASME Journal of Mechanisms and Robotics and the Springer Tract in Advanced Robotics (STAR). [12] Richard Margolin Founder and Director of Engineering, RoboKind Robotics Mr. Margolin received his BS in mechanical engineering from the University of Texas at Arlington, and studied cognitive and computational neuroscience at Trinity College, Hartford, CT. Prior to founding RoboKind he was Director of Hardware for Hanson Robotics where he designed and built the world?s most lifelike interactive robots. [12] His robotics and AI practice includes workplace safety standards, privacy requirements, robot collaboration and human displacement, anti-discrimination law, and legislative and regulatory developments. [12] Marco Mascorro CEO and CTO, Fellow Robots With 8+ years experience in robotics, Marco worked previously with BMW, Rolls-Royce and MINI, Singularity University, as well as in Japan to develop humanoid robots for rescue and exploration. [12] It is possible that Asimov's 3 Laws of Robotics have been overridden by Forest Gump's Law of Stupid Is As Stupid Does! A half crazed lunatic might even praise a killer robot for its performance and not hesitating when ordered to kill and slaughter unarmed women and children. [13] Bill Culley Co-Founder and President, Empire Robotics, Inc. Bill Culley is an entrepreneur and engineer, and is cofounder of Empire Robotics, the company commercializing one of the newest technologies poised to have a significant impact across industrial robotics. [12] After his graduation, he worked as the General Manager of a technology transfer and investment company before joining Kinova in its early days to develop the service robotics market. [12] Alan Ludwiszewski General Manager, Vecna, Inc. Alan Ludwiszewski, General Manager for Vecna?s Robotic Logistics Solutions, has over 20 years? experience in bringing innovative, multidisciplinary technology solutions to market. [12] Typical areas of application are robotics, industrial automation and security technology. [33] Through this period of time, Bob has been involved with numerous applications of Harmonic Drive products in the field of motion control including factory automation and robotics. [12] He focuses his practice on intellectual property counseling, particularly in the fields of alternative energy, medical devices, consumer products, and electromechanical engineering including robotics and control systems. [12] Historically, QNA has developed products in robotics, armor, controls and sensors to solve some of the most difficult problems faced by government and industry. [36] Nuzha Yakoob Product Manager, Festo Corporation Nuzha Yakoob is currently the Product Manager for the electromechanical, motion control and robotics products and solutions from Festo. [12] In his role at MathWorks, he focuses on robotics product management, product marketing, industry marketing, and business development. [12] Through his passion for robotics, he continues to have an eye towards identifying new opportunity and driving business growth and requirements for product development. [12] Brian has held numerous product development positions in an array of industries, including biotech, pharma, and now robotics. [12] In the spirit of public-private sector collaboration, and in recognition of the economic development value of robotics and unmanned systems in MA/New England, the three sponsoring organizations: AUVSI-NE, MassTLC and MassDevelopment signed a Memorandum of Understanding signifying their commitment to pursue this effort and promote the concept with their respective memberships and organizations. [35] The Inter-Operability Playground (IOP) at Devens is a first-of-its-kind collaboration center where robotic and unmanned systems of all types can be field tested, calibrated, commercialized and demonstrated. [35] Today a group of leading public and private sector organizations descended upon the town of Devens, the former military base, with an eye towards the future, and towards solidifying Massachusetts? position at the forefront of the robotics revolution. [35] South Korean machine wins U.S. robotics challenge sponsored by U.S. military agency. [37] Harvest has developed and deployed an autonomous mobile robotic platform that assists workers with difficult, repetitive material handling. [12] Formerly the Global Director of Sales Marketing for RMT Robotics, Bill developed working relationships with several multinational, blue chip manufacturing, warehousing and logistics companies, partnering with them to implement large scale, full integrated, robotics based materials handling solutions. [12] In 2014 and 2015 Kinova was listed as one of the 50 most influential public private companies in the global robotics industry by the Robotics Business Review. [12] Dan was the publisher of RoboticsTrends.com, an online portal covering the intelligent, mobile robotics market, and launched Robotics Business Review. [12] His expertise ranges across a spectrum of industries and technologies, including mobile robotics, embedded systems, and data analytics. [12] Richard Erb Executive Director, RoboUniverse Conference and Expo Richard Erb brings more than 15 years of experience organizing trade shows in the telecom, information technology and robotics industries. [12] In his current position with RoboUniverse, Richard is a catalyst for building community and introducing RoboUniverse events as end user focused open format world-class robotics business, technology and applications-focused trade shows. [12] We expect our campus and Ann Arbor to be among the first test beds for the technology, and the new robotics facility will help us lead the way. [35] Robotic technology is working to reduce the exposure of human firefighters to extreme fires, such as wildfire, airplane, derailed trains, fuel explosions, chemical leaks, and nuclear meltdowns. [33] He originated and co-chairs Littler?s Robotics, Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Automation Practice Group, providing legal advice and representation to the robotics industry, as well as employers deploying this technology in the workplace. [12] He is the founder of LocoRobo Inc., a technology non-profit whose mission is to advance programming education using robotics. [12] He also directs the robotics track of the AlphaLab Gear hardware startup accelerator, which he helped launch in partnership with Innovation Works. [12] It's creator, Scott Peters, from Construction Robotics told MIT's Tech Review that it won't put people out of work. [38] I seldom refer to articles from CNN, Jeff Zucker's golden shower of sorta news, but I will in the case of a new piece,  The Future of War Will Be Robotic, published on the cable channel's site by Peter W. Singer, whose work I greatly admire. [39] Eric Foellmer Marketing Manager, Rethink Robotics Eric Foellmer is the Manager of Product Marketing and Marketing Communications at Rethink Robotics, a pioneer in the Collaborative Robotics space. [12] Yanliang is the first product manager of MathWorks Robotics System Toolbox released in March 2015. [12] Bill Torrens Clearpath Robotics Bill Torrens joined Clearpath Robotics in 2014, charged with the responsibility to identify and manage opportunities in Clearpath?s industrial materials handling business vertical. [12] Mr. Spencer is an active contributor to the robotics community in Seattle area through his participation in the Seattle Robotics Society, 4H Robotics Club programs through Washington State Cooperative Extension and the National 4H in Washington, DC. Mr. Spencer received his Bachelors degree from Cornell University School of Agriculture and Life Sciences in 1980. [12] In second place (with a prize of $1 million) was the Institute of Human and Machine Cognition from Florida – while a team from Carnegie Mellon University and the National Robotics Engineering Center won third place and a prize of $500,000. [37] Developed by students at Dartmouth's Thayer School of Engineering, the new robotic dummies were designed to allow players to practice tackling without injuring one another in the process. [40] Yanliang obtained his B.S. in computer engineering, and Ph.D. in robotics from Nanyang Technological University, Singapore, in 2006 and 2010, respectively. [12] John holds a B.S. degree in mechanical engineering from the University at Buffalo and has publications in robotic manipulation, granular packing, learning algorithms, and machine design. [12] Adidas's other partners in the project include Johnson Controls, robotic assembly expert KSL Keilmann and scientists from the Technical University of Munich and the University of Aachen. [40] Conceived as a robotics Inter-Operability Playground for supporting the multiple systems that must communicate and coexists in the future, the proposed facility would include lab facilities, indoor and outdoor controlled test space, a command and control center, and future demonstration area. [35] Jeff Burnstein President, Association for Advancing Automation (A3) Jeff Burnstein is the President of the Association for Advancing Automation (A3), the parent group of the Robotic Industries Association (RIA), AIA – Advancing Vision + Imaging, and the Motion Control Association (MCA). [12] Arron Acosta CEO and Co-Founder, Rise Robotics Arron Acosta is the CEO and Co-founder of Rise Robotics, a company that pio-neers new, affordable ways to design and make robotic components without sacri-ficing performance or power. [12] Halvor was listed one of Norways top 100 leadership talents the same year, and since then he has led Rocketfarm to become specialists in combining existing hardware with brilliant software for the purpose of making new revolutionary robotic solutions to any industry. [12] Top on the agenda was the creation of a controlled robotic test facility and Inter-Operability Playground with ground, air, water, residential, rural, indoor, and outdoor testing environments. [35] Jon started his career in robotics and prototype development for the machine design industry. [12] Even though these robotics applications look very different, the core problem is the same, Eustice said. [35] In automation and robotics, many applications are characterized by high energy and high torque at the same time. [33] ROBO-STOX is the first and only index tracking the global robotics and automation market. [12] The difference between the two feature sets is that RealSense is not limited to photography and mapping, but a robust platform for the new age of autonomous mobility, robotics, virtual reality and yes IoT. [40] The octoMATION Platform and the invention of The Bio Mimic concept octoGRIPPER are still the foundation for making Next Generation Robotics. [12] Ofer is the founder of Golem Robotics, a startup in the world of Robotics, a lecturer at the COMAS Design school, serves as a Board member at Velo 3D Inc. and is an advisory board member at RoboUniverse Expo. [12] Rodney Brooks Founder, Chairman and CTO, Rethink Robotics A mathematics undergraduate in his native Australia, Rodney received a Ph.D. in Computer Science from Stanford in 1981. [12] His technical focus is on integrated robotic systems including real-time sensor processing, mobility planning, and intuitive robot control. [12] Energid?s Actin software drives sensor-guided manipulation, autonomous grasping and straightforward control of complex robotic systems for medical, energy, transportation, and industrial applications. [12] Brian Stancil Director Robotic Systems, Neya Systems Brian has spent the last decade developing autonomous capability for a wide range of unmanned ground vehicles from man-transportable systems to large multiple-ton platforms. [12] David Askey Co-Founder and Chief Business Development Officer, Energid David Askey is responsible for strategic initiatives, guidance, and market development of vision-based robotic systems. [12] Exciting hands-on demonstrations will take place June 16 and June 17 including vehicles from: CyPhy Works ( http://cyphyworks.com/ ), QinetiQ (qinetiq.com), Autoliv (autoliv.com), Harvest Automation ( https://www.harvestai.com/ ), and iRobot ( http://www.irobot.com/ ). [35] QinetiQ North America (QNA) is a subsidiary of QinetiQ Group plc, the FTSE250 company listed on the London Stock Exchange (LSE:QQ.L). [36] I am very impressed with both the products and the people at QinetiQ North America, Yorsz said. [36] Mr. Yorsz has a wealth of experience and demonstrated successes in the government and commercial markets, QinetiQ North America Chairman of the Board Len Moodispaw said. [36] Waltham, Mass. -based QinetiQ North America announced Jan. 20 the appointment of Jeff Yorsz as the company's new president. [36] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (40 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) Related Related Articles
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/cee68630-4a3d-32d6-bd05-8933a4fb695d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T17:50:09Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:53:46.988Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/qinetiq-robotics/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
