<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2012 (12) - BMW M5 4.4 M5 Auto 4-Door £34,990 Loading Images... Date Registered: May 2012 Mileage: 51,000 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Petrol Price: £34,990 Colour: Black Body Style: Saloon Vehicle Trim / Variant: M5 EC Combined (mpg) 28.5 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 37.2 EC Urban (mpg) 20.2  &gt; 28 MPG 47 Insurance Group 560 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 232 CO2 (g/km) £490 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: M5 Insurance Group 47, Anti-Lock Brakes,Driver, Passenger And Front Side Air Bags,20In M Double-Spoke Stl. 343M Alloy Wheels,Cruise Control,Traction Control System,Reversing Assist Camera,Driver Information System,All Round Tinted Glass,Electric/Heated Door Mirrors,Immobiliser, Heated Washer Jets,Rain Sensor,Drivers Armrest,Steering Wheel Mounted Controls,Black Extended Merino Leather,Electronic Brake Force Distribution,Heated Rear Screen,High Beam Assist,Hill Holder,Internet, Loudspeakers System - BMW Professional,Metallic Paint,Mobile Application Preparation, Radio/CD/MP3/DVD,Sun Protection Glass,Telephone USB Audio Interface,Tyre Repair Kit,Full Merino Leather interior Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01223 636127 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating The Holy Grail, if you like, is for BMW to outstrip its own very high standards and build the best ‘M’ car ever. read more Breathtaking performance, superb handling, comfortable, excellent equipment levels Very thirsty, high emissions Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Bluetooth Connection Cruise control DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Electric sunroof Front electric windows Headlight washers Heated door mirrors Heated front seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Navigation system PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01223 636127 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 4 Zone automatic air conditioning ABS/EBD Adaptive drive with variable damper control Aluminium brake calipers Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Bluetooth telephone preparation with telematics BMW ConnectedDrive - Assist BMW ConnectedDrive - Online Body coloured door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Check control system Cruise control with brake function Door sill finishers with illuminated M designation DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric + heated aspheric door mirrors Electric adjustable steering column Electric folding and auto dimming door mirrors Electric front and rear windows with fingertip open/close + anti-trap all round Electromechanical parking brake Fogging sensor for front windscreen Front cupholders x 2 Front sliding armrest with two storage compartments Front/rear Parking distance control Green tinted heat insulating glass Head up Display Heated door mirrors Heated front seats Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist iDrive Controller and Display with 10 monitor Illuminated glovebox with lock Isofix rear child seat preparation Luggage compartment release button in drivers A pillar Luggage compartment with electric unlocking via key remote control M leather multifunction steering wheel Navigation System Professional Multimedia On board computer Outside temperature display Personal Profile Rain sensor with auto light activation system Rear centre armrest with 2 cupholders + storage Rear headrests Securing rings in luggage compartment Service interval indicator Servotronic PAS Speed limiter Tyre puncture warning system Voice control system Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio/CD/MP3 DAB Digital radio USB/audio interface Exterior / Styling Adaptive headlights Body colour door handles Body coloured bumpers Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Electric tilt/slide glass sunroof Headlight washer jets M aerodynamic bodystyling M mobility system (flat-tyre repair system) M side gills with M5 logo Run flat tyres Shark fin roof aerial Twin chrome exhaust tailpipes Xenon headlights + auto headlight adjust Safety / Security Advanced Head Protection System front + rear Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors Driver/front passenger side airbags Driver/Passenger airbags (Impact dependent) Engine immobiliser Front head restraints with anti-whiplash Front passenger airbag deactivation Fuel cut off safety device Inertia reel front seatbelts+pretensioners Keyless ignition Locking wheel bolts Occupancy sensor for passenger seat Rear door child safety locks Remote central locking Remote control Thatcham category 1 alarm Three inertia reel rear seatbelts Tyre pressure monitoring system Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01223 636127 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Emissions CO2 (g/km) 232
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0c1dc2ca-4a2a-305b-86d0-011a0befd716" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-16T09:50:53Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:39:52.035Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39584303/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
