<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Received: 13 October 2015 Accepted: 6 January 2016 Published: 19 January 2016 Abstract Background Firmicutes have the capacity to remove excess nitrate from the environment via either denitrification, dissimilatory nitrate reduction to ammonium or both. The recent renewed interest in their nitrogen metabolism has revealed many interesting features, the most striking being their wide variety of dissimilatory nitrate reduction pathways. In the present study, nitrous oxide production from Bacillus licheniformis, a ubiquitous Gram-positive, spore-forming species with many industrial applications, is investigated. Results B. licheniformis has long been considered a denitrifier but physiological experiments on three different strains demonstrated that nitrous oxide is not produced from nitrate in stoichiometric amounts, rather ammonium is the most important end-product, produced during fermentation. Significant strain dependency in end-product ratios, attributed to nitrite and ammonium, and medium dependency in nitrous oxide production were also observed. Genome analyses confirmed the lack of a nitrite reductase to nitric oxide, the key enzyme of denitrification. Based on the gene inventory and building on knowledge from other non-denitrifying nitrous oxide emitters, hypothetical pathways for nitrous oxide production, involving NarG, NirB, qNor and Hmp, are proposed. In addition, all publically available genomes of B. licheniformis demonstrated similar gene inventories, with specific duplications of the nar operon, narK and hmp genes as well as NarG phylogeny supporting the evolutionary separation of previously described distinct BALI1 and BALI2 lineages. Conclusions Using physiological and genomic data we have demonstrated that the common soil bacterium B. licheniformis does not denitrify but is capable of fermentative dissimilatory nitrate/nitrite reduction to ammonium (DNRA) with concomitant production of N2O. Considering its ubiquitous nature and non-fastidious growth in the lab, B. licheniformis is a suitable candidate for further exploration of the actual mechanism of N2O production in DNRA bacteria and its relevance in situ. Keywords Dissimilatory nitrate/nitrite reduction to ammonium (DNRA) Fermentation Nitrate respiration Denitrification Ammonification Nitrite detoxification Background Denitrification and dissimilatory nitrate/nitrite reduction to ammonium (DNRA) are two key processes, performed by a wide range of Bacteria and Archaea as well as some Eukaryotes [ 1 ], responsible for removal of excess nitrate from the environment. Denitrification is the modular step-wise reduction of fixed nitrogen, nitrate or nitrite to a gaseous form, either nitric oxide (NO), nitrous oxide (N2O) and/or dinitrogen gas (N2). DNRA retains nitrogen in the environment, although N2O, contributor to both climate change and ozone depletion in the stratosphere, can also be produced as side product. Comprehensive understanding of the identities and activities of microorganisms as well as cellular mechanisms involved in nitrate removal are crucial for improving models that predict fluxes of nitrate, nitrite and N2O [ 2 ]. Although several Firmicutes have been known for a long time to be nitrate reducers and N2O emitters [ 3 – 8 ], their ecological relevance has been minimalized over the past two decades based on molecular community surveys using primers not targeting their divergent denitrification [ 9 – 12 ] or DNRA genes [ 13 ] (note that recent primers for DNRA do indeed target Firmicute genes [ 14 ]). Nevertheless, Firmicutes and specifically Bacillus can be dominant in ecosystems with important nitrate removal activities such as soil [ 15 ], animal manure compost [ 16 ] and advanced wastewater treatments [ 17 ]. Renewed interest in Bacillus has revealed many interesting features like (i) the widespread occurrence of nitrate reduction and denitrification in the genus [ 18 ], (ii) the gene inventory for both denitrification and DNRA in one microorganism [ 19 , 20 ], (iii) a novel type of copper-A-dependent, electrogenic nitric oxide reductase (CuANor) [ 21 – 24 ], or (iv) membrane-bound denitrification [ 25 ] with a novel organization for the periplasmic nitrate reductase [ 19 , 26 ]. The most striking observation however is the wide variety of dissimilatory nitrate reduction pathways in members of this genus. The model organism Bacillus subtilis uses the cytoplasmic nitrate reductase NarGHI and nitrite reductase NirBD to anaerobically reduce nitrate to ammonium [ 27 , 28 ], while Bacillus selenitireducens produces ammonium via the periplasmic nitrite reductase NrfA [ 14 , 29 ]. Bacillus vireti can do the same but with concomitant N2O production via CuANor that can be converted to the harmless N2 with a NosZ-type reductase [ 30 ]. On the other hand, Bacillus azotoformans and Bacillus bataviensis are canonical denitrifiers, the latter lacking the final reductase, but both also encode the NrfA nitrite reductase, making them potential ammonium producers [ 19 ]. In addition, these two organisms demonstrate an unusual high level of gene redundancy, i.e. multiple genes or gene copies encoding the same function (B. azotoformans encodes three nitrate, two nitrite, four NO and three N2O reductases) [ 19 ]. Considering the modularity of denitrification and DNRA, a multitude of enzyme combinations for nitrate reduction are imaginable, even within one microorganism. Bacillus licheniformis, a close relative of B. subtilis, is widely distributed as a saprophytic organism in the environment, has numerous commercial and agricultural uses (e.g. production of peptide antibiotics, chemicals and proteases, mitigation of fungal pathogens) and some strains, with abortifacient potential or toxin production, might pose a threat to public health. Certain B. licheniformis isolates have been described as denitrifiers [ 5 , 18 , 28 ], mostly based on their ability to produce gas from nitrate anaerobically. Many genomes from B. licheniformis have been sequenced and described to date [ 31 – 36 ]. However, their lack of genes encoding either a copper- or cytochrome cd 1 -dependent nitrite reductase (NirK or NirS respectively), the key enzyme of denitrification, has gone unnoticed, probably because of limited interest in their anaerobic nitrogen metabolism. We have sequenced and analyzed the genomes of three B. licheniformis strains previously reported to produce N2O [ 18 ], and confirmed the lack of nirS or nirK in their genomes. In addition, physiological data was gathered demonstrating that B. licheniformis does not denitrify but is capable of fermentative dissimilatory nitrate/nitrite reduction to ammonium with concomitant production of N2O. Both types of data were combined to propose hypothetical pathways for N2O production, which present new alternative routes for nitrate reduction and N2O production in members of the genus Bacillus. Methods Strains and DNA extraction B. licheniformis LMG 6934, LMG 7559 and LMG 17339 were obtained from the BCCM/LMG bacteria collection. Strains were grown aerobically in trypticase soy broth (TSB) at 37 °C. Cells were harvested after overnight growth and DNA was extracted by the method of Pitcher et al. [ 37 ], slightly modified as described previously [ 38 ]. Genome sequencing &amp; annotation Library preparation and genome sequencing was performed by Baseclear B.V. For sequencing, paired-end strategy on the Illumina Genome Analyzer IIx was used yielding average read lengths of 75 bp for LMG 7759 and LMG 17339 and 50 bp for LMG 6934. Automatic trimming (based on a threshold of Q = 20 and maximum 2 ambiguous bases) and assembly was performed using CLC Genomics Workbench 6.5. The k-mer and bubble size parameters were varied to maximize the N50 and the number of contig of the resulting assembly for each genome. For the consensus sequence, conflicts were resolved by using quality scores and insertion of ambiguity codes. Functional annotation and metabolic reconstruction was performed with the Rapid Annotation Subsystem Technology (RAST) server [ 39 , 40 ], using RAST gene calling and allowing frame shift correction, backfilling of gaps and automatic fixing of errors. Assigned functions were checked with pBLAST [ 41 ] and InterProScan [ 42 ]. Missing genes were searched for in the genome with PSI-BLAST using homologous amino acid sequences. The average nucleotide identity (ANI) was calculated with the ANI calculator ( http://​enve-omics.​ce.​gatech.​edu/​ani/​ ) [ 43 ]. Growth experiments Anaerobic growth experiments were performed in TSB and mineral medium (MM), amended with 10 mM potassium nitrate as electron acceptor. Mineral medium was as described by Stanier et al. [ 44 ], including 10 mM phosphate buffer, 2.3 mM (NH4)2SO4, 0.4 mM MgSO4•7H2O, 0.04 mM CaCl2•2H2O, 2.3 mM (NH4)2SO4, 27 μM EDTA, 25 μM FeSO4•7H2O, 10 μM ZnSO4•7H2O, 25 μM MnSO4•H2O, 3.8 μM CuSO4•5H2O, 2 μM Co(NO3)2•6H2O, 0.196 μM (NH4)6Mo7O24•24H2O, supplemented with 30 mM glucose as electron donor. Serum vials (120 ml) were rinsed with 1 M HCl overnight to remove growth inhibiting substances, and subsequently washed four times and rinsed with distilled water before use. Serum vials with 50 ml medium were sealed with black butyl-rubber stoppers. After autoclaving, the headspace of the serum vials was replaced via five cycles of evacuating and refilling with helium. Serum vials were inoculated (1 % v/v) with a suspension of optical density OD600 of 1.0 ± 0.05. Each growth experiment was performed in triplicate and non-inoculated media in duplicate were included to check for potential nitrosation reactions in sterile medium. After inoculation, serum vials were incubated at 37 °C, 150 rpm, for 72 h. Preliminary end-point analyses demonstrated that all three strains did not produce N2 (later confirmed by absence of nosZ gene from the genomes, see further) so their dissimilatory nitrate reduction metabolism was explored without addition of acetylene to the headspace. Statistical differences in growth rate and yield of LMG 6934 between TSB and TSB amended with 10 mM nitrate were assessed using the independent t-test after Levene’s test for equality of variances, and main and interaction effect of medium and strain on end-product concentration using factorial ANOVA and Least Significant Difference post-hoc testing in SPSS23. Analytical procedures Samples of 1 ml were taken from cultures through the rubber septum of serum vials with sterile syringes for growth determination and colorimetric determination of ammonium, nitrate and nitrite. Growth was determined by measuring the optical density OD600 of 100 μl sample in duplicate in microtiter plates and standardized to 1 cm pathlength using PathCheck Sensor of the spectrophotometer (Molecular Devices, Spectramax plus 384, USA). For colorimetrics, 500 μl from remaining sample was pretreated with 2.5 ml of 2 M potassium chloride by shaking 1 h at 150 rpm and subsequent filtration (0.2 μm) to extract inorganic nitrogen and remove interfering compounds. Filtered samples were centrifuged at 13000 rpm for 2 min to remove the cells and kept frozen at -20 °C until colorimetric determination. Ammonium concentration was determined with the salicylate-nitroprussidine method (absorption at a wavelength of 650 nm) [ 45 ], nitrite and nitrate concentrations were determined with Griess reaction [ 46 ] and Griess reaction with cadmium [ 47 , 48 ] respectively. For end-point measurements, ammonium production was corrected per strain for the amount of ammonium assimilated based on OD600 values obtained. Standard curves covered ranges suitable for the tested media and were strictly linear with an R2 of 0.99. For determination of N2O, 1 ml sample of the headspace of serum vials was taken with sterile syringes, and was injected into the gas chromatograph (Compact GC with EZChrom Elite Software, Interscience, Netherlands, 2012). N2O concentrations were corrected for pressure and solubility based on Henry’s law. Accession numbers The Whole Genome Shotgun projects of B. licheniformis LMG 6934, LMG 7559 and LMG 17339 have been deposited at DDBJ/EMBL/GenBank under the accession numbers AZSY00000000, AZSX00000000, and AZSZ00000000 respectively. The versions described in this paper are the first versions. Results Dissimilatory nitrate reduction metabolism Three genotypically distinct B. licheniformis strains (Coorevits, A. &amp; De Vos, P., personal communication) from various origins were selected for determination of their dissimilatory nitrate reduction metabolism based on a previous study that demonstrated their capacity to produce N2O [ 18 ]. B. licheniformis LMG 6934 was originally isolated from garden soil, LMG 7559 from flour and LMG 17339 from silage. Growth of LMG 6934 (Fig. 1a ) under anaerobic headspace in TSB amended without and with nitrate (11 mM) commenced after a short lag phase of approximately 3 h, a steep exponential phase followed, with maximal growth achieved after 8.5 h, after which cells sporulated very quickly without a stationary phase (Fig. 1a ). Between 6.5 and 7.5 h, growth slowed down probably due to a depletion of the preferential carbon source in the medium with a shift to another electron donor, as this was observed both for fermentative and respiratory growth. The anaerobic growth rates were comparable with and without nitrate as electron acceptor (μnitrate/h = 0.189 ± 0.004 h−1 and μferm = 0.179 ± 0.011 h−1 (p = 0.264)), but with significantly different maximal growth yield (OD600 of 1.05 ± 0.02 with nitrate and 0.75 ± 0.06 without nitrate (p = 0.002)) reflecting the different ATP yield of a respiratory and a fermentative life style. In the presence of nitrate (Fig. 1b ), growth was initially supported by nitrate reduction (μ1 = 0.19 ± 0.004 h−1), with concomitant nitrite production. All nitrate was converted to nitrite but the maximal nitrite peak was probably missed between 5 and 6.5 h of incubation, which was deduced from the onset of N2O production (0.2 mM N-N2O at 6.5 h). When nitrate was almost depleted (at 6.5 h, 0.62 mM residual nitrate), nitrite was reduced (μ2 = 0.16 ± 0.02 h−1), which continued after maximal growth at 8.5 h was achieved and sporulation had started (μ3). This suggested that nitrite reduction did not support growth during the μ2 phase, but rather fermentation was responsible for growth after nitrate depletion. During nitrite reduction, a continuous increase in N2O was observed, with a maximum of 1.3 ± 0.07 mM N-N2O at the end of the incubation (accounting for 12 % of all reduced nitrite), and 0.5 ± 0.18 mM of nitrite remaining in the medium (Fig. 1b ). Due to technical constraints and interference of amines from degradation of proteins in the TSB during bacterial growth, ammonium was not monitored during these growth experiments. Fig. 1 Anaerobic growth (OD600) of B. licheniformis LMG 6934 in TSB (a) and nitrate, nitrite and N2O concentrations (mM)(b) over time. Error bars show standard deviation (n = 3). Different growth phases based on primary metabolism in TSB amended with nitrate are marked: μ1, respiratory growth with nitrate as electron acceptor; μ2, fermentative growth after nitrate is depleted; μ3, sporulation. Dashed curve visualizes N deficit caused by the lack of ammonium data To compare the dissimilatory nitrate reduction metabolism of LMG 6934 with those of LMG 7559 and LMG 17339 and to confirm ammonium production from nitrite, end-point experiments after a 72 h-incubation in anaerobic conditions were performed in TSB and mineral medium with 30 mM glucose, both amended with nitrate. Maximal growth of LMG 7559 and LMG 17339 was achieved within 11 h, again immediately followed by a rapid sporulation (data not shown). In mineral media with glucose, most nitrate was converted to ammonium (31.8 to 89.1 %; Fig. 2 ), confirming the ammonium-producing capacity of all three strains (for TSB, the nitrogen deficit was attributed to ammonium production, which could not be measured). A significant strain effect on the ratios of end-products was observed (p ≤ 0.008) (Fig. 2 ), which after decomposition appeared to be mostly attributed to differences in ammonium and nitrite concentrations. In addition, the amount of N-N2O produced from nitrate was substantially lower in mineral medium than in TSB for all strains (15.8–32.9 % for TSB vs 10.9–24.1 % in MM) (p = 0.023). Only for LMG 17339, the medium also had a significant effect on ammonium and nitrite (p ≤ 0.024). Both strain and medium effect were quite unexpected, as the three strains are closely related and the major carbon source in TSB, namely glucose, is also used in the mineral medium. Fig. 2 Percentages of end-products of anaerobic nitrate reduction by B. licheniformis strains in TSB and mineral medium with 30 mM glucose (MM), amended with 10 mM nitrate. Error bars represent standard deviation (n = 3). The larger error bars for LMG 7559 result from differences in one of the three replicates. Measured concentrations of ammonium were corrected for loss through assimilation. N deficit in TSB experiments was attributed to ammonium production, which could not be measured, and visualized as such for convenience of comparison Genome analyses Draft genomes of the three B. licheniformis strains were obtained, the genome statistics are given in Table 1 . The gene inventory for assimilatory and dissimilatory nitrate reduction and related transport and regulation was almost identical for the three genomes (Table 2 ). Details will be given for LMG 6934 and differences with LMG 7559 and LMG 17339 will be highlighted. Table 1 Genome characteristics of three analyzed B. licheniformis genomes. Number of coding sequences is based on annotation obtained via RAST LMG 6934 LMG 7559
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/bc2ed349-73b4-30f0-8b28-bf6e0895c3a5" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-19T23:44:36Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:46:41.441Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-016-2382-2" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
