<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Recent Research on Smart Guns Related Content: Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 6, 2016 Image Courtesy: link: http://gizmodo.com/this-scifi-smart-gun-could-be-the-colt-45-of-the-futur-1686110748 author: gizmodo.com description: This Smart Gun Could Be the See up to 10 related YouTube videos at end. KEY TOPICS The National Rifle Association, in its statement criticizing Obama's executive actions, didn't comment on smart guns specifically but generally argued that the presidential action would not have prevented recent mass shootings. [1] A recent poll presented at a smart-gun conference in Seattle by the political consultancy Penn Schoen Berland found that 54 percent of gun owners under the age of 45 are willing to consider swapping out their conventional pistols for smart guns. [2] Turns out that the sale of smart guns could actually restrict gun sales, at least in New Jersey, where a 13-year-old law mandates all regular handguns sold in the state be smart guns if and when they become available for sale anywhere else in the country. [3] Under the current N.J. law, once smart guns become available anywhere else in the nation, New Jersey has three years before smart guns become the only type of handgun permitted for sale in the state. [4] In 1997, gun control proponents encouraged New Jersey lawmaker Loretta Weinberg to introduce the Childproof Handgun Act, which said that three years after a personalized gun was offered for sale anywhere in the U.S., New Jersey firearm retailers would be required to sell only smart guns. [5] New Jersey's 2002 Childproof Handgun Law has spurred much of the outcry over attempts to sell smart guns in the U.S., because it said that once personalized handguns are available anywhere in the country, all handguns sold in New Jersey must be smart guns within 30 months. [1] Acknowledging how this law has actually inadvertently impeded smart guns from coming onto the marketplace, New Jersey State Senator Loretta Weinberg, who sponsored the original mandate, tells 60 Minutes that as early as next week, she will ask her state's legislature to repeal the law and replace it with one mandating at least one smart gun be for sale wherever weapons are sold in her state. [3] Gun dealers across the country cited the Jersey law as reason to withhold selling smart guns, because that would trigger the mandate in New Jersey, and if there?s anything that?s anathema to gun owners, it?s a government mandate. [6] The chill on smart guns in the United States is to some degree the unintended consequence of a 2002 New Jersey law that would phase out the sale of conventional guns in that state; the law requires New Jersey gun dealers to sell only smart guns once they become available in retail stores anywhere else in the country. [2] When one Maryland dealer announced he would try to sell one smart gun he was immediately attacked with email and phone call threats by people who believed that he could have triggered a New Jersey ban on regular handguns that don't possess smart-gun technology. [3] Metro IAF and will be hosting a smart gun trade show in New Rochelle, N.Y., later this month so that New York and New Jersey mayors and law enforcement officials can try out smart guns from manufacturers like Armatix, iGun Technology Corp. and SAR, who'll be on hand to answer questions. [4] The National Rifle Association and other gun-rights groups cited the New Jersey law as evidence that the real motive behind the smart gun idea was to ban all other kinds of firearms. [5] The National Shooting Sports Foundation, the main firearms industry trade association, in a statement, says it has never opposed development of smart gun technology. [1] Even if there were a perfectly reliable smart gun, the mandate is unacceptable, says Larry Keane, general counsel of the National Shooting Sports Foundation, the main trade group representing the firearm industry. [5] As manufacturers worked on the technology, the law also sparked some unintended consequences: When gun sellers on both coasts began offering the country's first smart gun, the Armatix iP1, for sale, they were met with an avalanche of hate mail, violent threats and recriminations. [4] The first gun store to offer the iP1, the Oak Tree Gun Club outside Los Angeles, dropped plans to carry the smart gun last March after a backlash from local members and gun rights activists determined to stop the New Jersey smart gun-only law from being triggered. [4] It hasn't resulted in the sale of smart guns and instead moved gun rights activists to intimidate gun shops around the country not to carry them because that would start the countdown clock for the New Jersey law. [4] Last May, a Maryland gun seller, Andy Raymond of Engage Armaments, also dropped plans to sell the smart gun, even going so far as to sleep in his Rockville store, fearing it would be burned down as had been threatened by Second Amendment activists determined to stop the New Jersey smart gun-only law from being triggered. [4] Speaking at a New Hampshire town hall last Friday, May 8, 2015, Gov. Chris Christie singled out New Jersey's smart gun law as a defining example of legislative overreach by the Democratically controlled state legislature that's hampered his ability to expand Second Amendment rights. [4] As long as the state law is on the books, it's unlikely that gun-rights enthusiasts there–or elsewhere–are going to have to worry about smart guns, either. [5] This new law forces gun dealers to offer a smart gun, but still provides a choice for gun owners to buy whatever they want. [2] Gun store owner Andy Raymond gained passing fame last year for posting an Internet video about his abortive attempt to sell so-called smart guns, a type of digitally equipped firearms designed to thwart unauthorized users. [5] One success of gun-rights activists over the past decade has been their campaign to block the advent of smart guns, firearms that use biometric and other sensor technologies to prevent them from being fired by anyone other than their owners. [2] Weinberg said that whatever form the new smart gun legislation takes, The intent is what the intent was when we passed the bill: Furthering the development of the technology and making sure that those who purchase handguns have the safest possible product in the marketplace to prevent children from getting killed accidentally, and to prevent bad guys who might want to steal guns from getting them. [4] The whole problem with the mandate was that it forced buyers in New Jersey to buy a smart gun, says Ralph Fascitelli, the president of Washington CeaseFire, a prominent Seattle group working to reduce gun violence. [2] The New Jersey law shows that smart guns aren't about saving lives, says Robert Farago, publisher of the Truth About Guns blog. [5] Senate majority leader Sen. Loretta Weinberg is considering repealing the'smart gun' law she authored in 2002, now that it's being used by Second Amendment activists to intimidate gun stores nationwide into not selling smart guns. [4] Recognizing that the statute has become a tool used by gun-rights advocates to block smart gun development, Weinberg says she's inclined to lead an effort to repeal the law. [5] Weinberg made the announcement Sunday night in a 60 Minutes story in which she accused the National Rifle Association of using the 2002 law as a tool to block smart guns nationwide. [2] The law badly backfired by becoming fodder for gun-rights activists, who argued that smart guns are part of a government plot to track and ultimately ban all guns. [2] The industry's big worry is that support for smart gun technology would turn into a mandate that all guns need to be smart. [1] The New Jersey Smart Gun Mandate, passed in 2002, required the adoption of smart guns in New Jersey once they were available for sale anywhere in the country. [6] Teret at Johns Hopkins says that firearm accidents have indeed been declining and smart guns aren't a panacea to gun violence. [1] Lesley Stahl reports on smart guns, firearms advocates believe can lower the number of accidental shootings and suicides in the U.S., on the next edition of 60 Minutes, Sunday, November 1 at 7 p.m. ET/PT. [3] Some high profile Silicon Valley investors are betting that smart guns can disrupt the firearms industry. [2] Many Second Amendment advocates view smart guns as a step toward draconian restrictions on firearm ownership. [5] Mossbacher believes the smart gun technology is so superior that most consumers would eventually to embrace it the same way that they did airbags and anti-lock brakes on cars. [4] Andy Raymond demonstrates the Armatix iP1, a.22-caliber smart gun that has a safety interlock, at Engage Armaments in Rockville, Md., last year. [1] Last year, the German start-up Armatix attempted to crack the U.S. market with its $1800 iP1 pistol, a smart gun that operates with a radio-frequency-emitting watch. [2] Andy Raymond, co-owner of Engage Armaments, was hit by backlash from gun-rights supporters when he tried to sell smart guns last year. [5] Why can't you buy a smart gun in the United States today? One reason is gun-shop owners won't sell them. [3] Even though smart guns are widely available overseas, no American gun retailers sell them–in no small part due to threats and harassment aimed at any who have tried. [2] Greenwald said that instead of mandating only smart guns be sold, he hoped to provide an economic incentives to boost their sales to accomplish the same end. [4] Raymond, a passionate gun advocate, wasn't willing to risk his life for a few sales and decided to strip his shelves of smart guns. [5] Fascitelli believes that within a decade smart guns could capture a third of the $3 billion U.S. handgun market. [2] Gun control advocates have pushed smart guns since the mid-1990s as a way to reduce accidental shootings and suicides. [5] In simplest terms, if federal law enforcement and the military start buying lots of smart guns - and that's a big if - Teret thinks it would be just the incentive that manufacturers, venture capitalists and other investors need to consider such guns as a viable product. [1] A replacement bill that she plans to introduce on Thursday would instead require all of the state's gun dealers to offer at least one model of smart gun for sale. [2] As punishment for offering smart guns, he explained in the video, some of his detractors threatened to kill him and burn down his store in Rockville, Md. That's a great thing for gun rights, when you threaten to shoot somebody, Raymond said. [5] He believes a new generation of tech-savvy people, especially young parents, will embrace the hi-tech smart guns eventually, even overcoming the politics currently holding them back. [3] Spokesman Avery Palmer referred NPR to the group's 2013 fact sheet on smart guns, which runs through a variety of reservations about their effectiveness, including the possibility that it may attract more, not fewer, people to gun ownership. [1] Skeptics also questioned whether smart guns would be susceptible to malfunction, like a balky computer. [5] Asked whether that meant the group also opposed Obama's smart gun initiative, Palmer said the center didn't yet have enough detail on the proposal to determine the group's position. [1] He designed the high-powered rifle that killed Osama bin Laden, and he is sometimes compared to Steve Jobs because of his singular determination to transform dumb guns into smart guns. [6] Technology has ameliorated so many other problems in recent centuries that pursuing smart guns is both a noble and logical course. [7] The legislation is absolutely ridiculous given a recent report about the chapter 11 restructuring of a smart gun company, which gun grabbing politicians, like Markey and Warren have endorsed. [8] The law, which was signed by Gov. James McGreevey, included a mandate ordering New Jersey gun stores to stock only firearms equipped with special user-recognition technology within three years after the first smart gun was made available for sale in the United States. [9] Smart guns have been stymied by a 2002 New Jersey law that would actually require such technology in all guns sold in the state as soon as it was commercially available. [10] I'm aware of New Jersey's law that says that within one year(?) of the first smart gun being sold Only smart guns will be legal to sell in a state where it is a death sentence to comply with their laws about acquiring a gun. [11] Among those who shared their opinions and knowledge of the smart gun industry were King County Sheriff John Urquhart, and Sen. Loretta Weinberg, D-N.J., who is known for introducing a controversial law that would require all firearms sold in her state to have smart capabilities within 30 months of the technology's proliferation. [7] Anthony Colandro, the owner of a shooting range in Woodland Park and one of New Jersey?s most vocal firearms rights proponents, said state legislators should keep their hands off the issue of smart guns. [9] Although the weapons have broad support among gun owners, the staunchest supporters of the Second Amendment say smart guns only make it easier for the government to control the sale and use of lawful firearms. [11] In April 2014, conservative media distorted comments made by then-Attorney General Eric Holder about smart gun technology similar to Mossberg's - it would use a bracelet rather than a ring - to claim that the government wanted to track gun owners using the technology. [12] In contrast to the successful demonstration of the technology on Fox News, the NRA's radio show, Cam &amp; Company has spread false information about the failure rate of the technology, featured content suggesting smart guns are a dumb idea and that gun owners won't trust an electronic firearm to save the day, and hosted guests to claim the technology doesn't work. [12] Hosted by the Washington Technology Industry Association and anti-gun violence group Washington CeaseFire, the event showcased speakers from advocacy groups, smart gun device manufacturers, law enforcement, media and politics. [7] A panel comprised of Boinus; Margot Hirsch, president of Smart Tech Challenges Foundation ; and Juliet Leftwich, legal director of the Law Center to Prevent Gun Violence, hosted a question and answer session to address the challenges facing the proliferation of smart guns today, like whether a smart gun manufacturer would be held legally accountable should a biometric scanner malfunctioned and an unauthorized user shoot himself or someone else. [7] In Trenton, the governor even signed a law ordering New Jersey?s firearms dealers to sell only so-called smart guns once the first one hit the market. [9] In 2013, the Justice Department released a far more optimistic appraisal of smart gun technology, finding at least three firearms to be on the cusp of commercial use. [11] These attacks are baseless - market-ready smart guns have a similar mechanical failure rate compared to firearms that do not have the technology. [12] Smart guns are not available in New Jersey - or anywhere else in America - even though consumer studies suggest that as many as two-thirds of gun owners would opt for high-tech locking systems on their firearms if they were reliable. [9] Ever fearful of a slippery slope toward more government regulation, gun advocates around the country have directed vitriol toward stores carrying smart guns: California?s Oak Tree Gun Club, for example, drew their ire after stocking the Armatix iP1, a $1,800 futuristic-looking German-made.22-caliber pistol, because the gun?s availability in California could trigger enforcement of the New Jersey law. [10] Boinus was more conservative in his estimates, saying he would rather be last to market with a technology that works well and is accepted by gun owners, rather than alienate the market further than the smart gun industry has already. [7] McNamara talked about his company's smart gun technology, and also said he could have a product ready for market within a year, given support from the gun industry and proper funding. [7] Proponents of smart guns promote the technology as a way to prevent unauthorized users - such as children or someone trying to access a law enforcement officer's gun - from accessing a weapon. [12] A scheduled, but never-to-occur phone appearance by Rick Patterson of the Sporting Arms and Ammunition Manufacturers' Institute ( SAAMI ) is a telling representation of the gun industry's interest in the current state of smart gun technology – they didn't even bother to phone it in. [7] Mossberg's explanation of the unfounded reasons people oppose smart gun technology sounds like a summation of the attacks on the technology from the NRA's media arm, NRA News. (Interestingly, Mossberg's family operates O.F. Mossberg &amp; Sons, a sponsor of the NRA News web series Noir.) [12] The people who hate technology, smart guns, they think that big bad government can shut my guns down. [12] The NRA's publication American Rifleman also promoted the conspiracy theory that a criminal, a hacker or even a government agency could turn your gun on or off anytime they wanted if smart gun technology was adopted. [12] The NRA argued that smart gun technology was actually an attempt by the government to not only regulate gun ownership but also track how guns are used. [9] As NJIT and other labs worked on the technology, however, some of the nation?s most vocal gun-rights advocates, led by the NRA, mounted a campaign to boycott any gun dealer that tried to sell smart guns. [9] A nationally representative survey commissioned by organizers of the Seattle Smart Gun Symposium in January found that two-thirds of Americans believe dealers should offer guns fitted with technology that makes them more secure. [11] The technology isn't ready for prime time, Urquhart said, adding that while smart guns could be helpful in preventing criminals from using an officer's own gun against him, the technology would need to be 100 percent reliable before he felt comfortable putting it in the hands of his officers. [7] The National Rifle Association claims that it does not oppose the development of smart gun technology, but in practice it often raises unfounded concerns that the technology is unreliable or could be disabled by hackers. [12] Smart guns have been in development for decades, but the technology still has to overcome extreme skepticism from gun buyers–and law enforcement may be the key. [10] Fox &amp; Friends ‘ treatment of smart gun technology stands in sharp contrast to previous coverage of the technology on Fox &amp; Friends ; the show was one of many conservative media outlets to push the conspiracy theory about Holder and gun tracking bracelets. [12] Fox &amp; Friends presented emerging smart gun technology as fascinating, reliable, and not vulnerable to hacking in a segment that highlighted a shotgun that can only be fired by an authorized user who wears a special ring. [12] While the market for mogul-overboard systems ultimately proved niche, Mossberg realized the same technology could improve his smart gun. [10] Throughout the day, event organizers made repeated references to a video they wanted to show that would demonstrate how smart gun technology works. [7] Speakers imparted insightful analysis of smart gun technology and legal issues, but the discourse was peppered with facile analogies that demonstrated a knowledge gap and cultural denial that does not bode well for the movement. [7] Gun owners are as clear on their objections to smart guns as they are on their dedication to traditional firearms. [7] Eighty-seven percent of gun owners polled said they think gun dealers should be allowed to sell smart guns, he noted. [7] Perhaps, he said, smart guns may have to be sold in another country first before gun owners in America warm up to them. [9] During a lull, someone in the audience asked what RFID meant – many were still struggling to understand the basic mechanisms behind smart guns while others had already moved on to the intricacies of tort law. [7] In addition to organizing the New Rochelle event, they've met with state and local politicians as well as police chiefs to educate them about smart guns and, more importantly, to ask them to sign a letter to gun manufacturers requesting information on their smart-gun offerings. [10] It will take interest from big-city or state police forces to nudge the smart gun from prototype to mass-produced product, which is why Metro IAF has made sign-ons from such jurisdictions a priority. [10] Neither the Pentagon nor state authorities have embarked on formal and extensive testing of smart guns. [9] They also oppose implementing new smart gun technologies that can help reduce the tragic number of accidental shooting deaths each year, many of which have taken the lives of young children. [8] The premise of smart guns, as illustrated by James Bond in the 2012 action-thriller Skyfall, is that they can only be used by the owner and never against him. [7] The inventor, the sheriff, the gun store owner and a U.S. attorney all believe smart guns should not be mandatory. [13] 4 in 10 gun owners - and 54 percent of those between 18 and 44 - said they would consider swapping the guns currently in their homes for new, safer smart guns when they come on the market. [11] What is striking about this debate over smart guns is that they don?t look all that different from the millions of ordinary handguns and rifles that are so common across America. [9] Panelists and audience members spoke passionately about smart guns in an American nation that leads first-world nations in handgun deaths, behind only a handful of South and Central American nations. [7] Have you priced a decent handgun recently? The so called smart gun is overpriced and in testing found to not be 100% reliable. [11] Smart guns have long been hard-to-find novelties, spurned by firearm enthusiasts and ignored by larger gunmakers for lack of demand. [10] The Armatix iP1 and other so-called smart guns have become the latest flash point in the long-running battle between gun rights and gun control. [11] But if you are going to have a gun in the home – and we do respect the Second Amendment and somebody's right to have a gun – we wish it could be a smart gun, a user-authorized gun. [7] Mosbacher convened the officers in New Rochelle to demonstrate not just any kind of guns, but specifically smart guns - so called for the safety measures that limit who can actually fire them. [10] The poll also revealed, as expected, that smart gun mandates caused extreme polarization. [7] Had Nancy Lanza owned a smart gun, perhaps she, her son and the 26 people he shot in 2012 at Sandy Hook Elementary School in Newtown, Conn., might have lived. [11] Some smart guns use radio-frequency identification (RFID) that pairs with a ring or bracelet, some use finger and palm scanners, while others use a grip analysis algorithm. [7] In the hours that followed, many topics surrounding smart guns were approached and many questions were fielded, but finding conclusions or consensus began to feel like a photographer's pursuit of the sunset. [7] Lost in the political posturing over gun control is the frustrating story of the scientists who tried to create smart guns. [9] Politician and event moderator Alex Alben suggested at one point that the smart gun should strive to be as reliable as a television remote control. [7] An Armatix iP1.22-calibre pistol smart gun pistol and iW1 Radio-frequency identification active wrist watch. [11] The result was that U.S. gun manufacturers backed away from developing a marketing plan for smart guns. [9] The activists? hope is that once enough police express interest in smart guns, manufacturing will be spurred by demand from large municipal buyers, and eventually the gun-buying public will warm to these products. [10] It?s hard to gauge the true market potential of smart guns for police. [10] While Americans today have become accustomed to computers in every aspect of their lives, Mossberg remains measured in his outlook for smart guns. [10] In recent months, lawmakers in New Jersey and California have sought to restructure smart gun laws to help coax development by removing the stick of an arbitrary mandate to exclusively use the technology on handguns moving forward. [14] Recent assessments of smart gun technology have been promising. [15] Recently, the Washington Technology Industry Association and the gun control group Washington Ceasefire co-hosted the Seattle International Smart Gun Symposium, which discussed the state of the firearm technology that attempts to limit operation to authorized users. [16] That law mandates that all guns sold in New Jersey would have to be smart guns after three years of a smart gun becoming commercially available anywhere in the U.S. The result has been nothing but disastrous for the smart gun industry. [17] The smart gun bill, termed the Handgun Trigger Safety Act of 2015, mandates that within five years of it becoming law only personalized handguns must be sold. [14] Resurrected are the Handgun Trigger Safety Act, which mandates a move to user-authorized or personalized handguns, commonly referred to as smart guns and a bill that would add $60 million in funding to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to study gun violence as a health care issue. [14] If there is a chance for smart gun technology to succeed in the U.S., it probably lies with the major manufacturers of firearms - handgun manufacturers like Smith &amp; Wesson (albeit S&amp;W may feel once burnt, twice shy on the subject), and Sturm, Ruger. [18] Media reports on these happenings quickly blamed the National Rifle Association and its members for smart guns' failure to sell, citing a 2002 New Jersey law that would forbid sale of non-smart guns in-state, once any other state in the Union begins selling smart guns. [18] Case in point, New Jersey State Senate Majority Leader Loretta Weinberg, who spoke at the Seattle event, now says that she wants to repeal the smart gun mandate law she authored in 2002. [16] New Jersey, for example, passed a law in 2002 that established that once a smart gun was available for sale anywhere in the United States, all new hand guns in New Jersey three years thereafter must be smart guns. [15] During the forum, the results of a public opinion survey done for Washington Cease Fire by a polling firm with known Democratic ties was released showing that 58 percent of non-gun owners and 38 percent of gun owners believed that all firearms sold should be mandated by law to be smart guns. [16] In 2000, Smith &amp; Wesson promised the Clinton Administration it would try to develop smart gun technology that would permit only a gun's owner to operate the firearm. [18] These numbers, showing a supermajority of potential firearms purchasers have little or no interest in buying a smart gun, suggest it will be very difficult to convince manufacturers to build, or gun store owners to sell, a smart gun in the near future. [18] Officially, neither the National Rifle Association nor the main trade group for the domestic firearm industry, the National Shooting Sports Foundation, opposes smart guns. [19] One would think that politicians learned the lesson of smart gun mandate legislation after the infamous and failed New Jersey smart gun mandate law became law in 2002. [17] The bill would mandate all guns manufactured in the U.S. incorporate smart gun technology within five years of the bill?s enactment and all guns distributed in commerce incorporate the technology (including retrofitting existing guns) after ten years of the bill?s enactment. [17] This technical malfunction actually provides something of a metaphor for the state of smart gun technology itself. [16] Mandating gun manufacturers without smart gun technology in their core competency (biometrics, radio frequency identification, electronics, battery storage) to now make smart guns or go out of business is akin to telling the automobile industry that all cars must be electric because Tesla is on the market. [17] Yardarm?s headquarters sit on the outskirts of Silicon Valley, and its technology similarly occupies the fringes of the smart gun industry. [20] One possibility, she continues, would be to replace it with a statute that would simply require that if smart guns are available, New Jersey firearm dealers would have to offer at least one such model for sale. [19] Earlier this year, a California bill that would have required the state?s Department of Justice to survey the market and recommend ways to make smart guns more readily available didn?t make it out of a state Senate committee. [20] Some analysts, including Richard Feldman of the Independent Firearm Owners Association, argued that the company's support for smart guns played a major role in its demise. [15] The problem arises, rather, from gun enthusiasts themselves, many of whom fear that smart guns are a step toward gun control, that the technologies are intrinsically unreliable, and that they are being foisted upon gun owners by ignorant do-gooders who aim to ban all guns that lack these features. [19] Low utility That brings us to the second big objection gun owners have against smart guns like the Armatix iP1 - batteries. [18] Sheriff John Urquhart of Washington?s King County said that smart gun technology is not ready for officers yet. [16] Costing $1,798 for a package of one iP1 smart gun, and one RFID smartwatch (which must be worn to operate the gun), Armatix's smart gun costs more than four times Glock's new G43 concealed-carry handgun. [18] Smart guns like the iP1 can only be fired by an authorized user - not by a five-year-old looking to play cops and robbers, not by a thief hoping to sell it on the street, and not by an anti-government patriot hoping to water the tree of liberty with his blood and brain matter. [15] The iP1 is a so-called smart gun, also known as a personalized or authorized-user-recognition weapon. [19] Pistol-grip rifles are now a military standard across the world, and the new Colt-made Canadian smart gun is a glimpse into the future of firearms. [21] Yes, fears that smart gun sales elsewhere could trigger a ban on dumb gun sales in New Jersey is certainly part of the problem. [18] If we really want improved gun safety with smart guns, legislators must abandon mandates and find ways to incentivize their uptake in the marketplace. [17] I do not think there is one CEO in the smart gun industry that supports mandate legislation. [17] One industry front-runner was Armatix GmbH, a German company founded by former Heckler &amp; Koch engineer Ernst Mauch that, until recently, made the only smart gun on the American market. [20] Last year, when Maryland gun store Engage Armament very publicly tried to offer Germany's Armatix iP1 smart gun for sale, it was similarly forced to backpedal. (And Armatix itself filed for bankruptcy protection in May.) [18] When Andy Raymond, co-owner of Engage Armament in Rockville, Maryland, announced that his store would sell the Armatix iP1 smart gun, he had no idea that he, his business and even his bulldog Brutus would end up in danger. [15] Though, Raymond told the Times he would rather be shot by a smart gun than try to sell another one. [15] By that time, the two manufacturers that had been pursuing smart guns most avidly–Colt?s and iGun–had each shelved their projects. [19] They might try to create a new market targeting safety-conscious gun owners with a smart gun product. [18] A 2013 poll conducted by the National Shooting Sports Foundation, in contrast - which better reflects the market for potential gun buyers in particular - found widespread reluctance to even consider buying a smart gun. [18] Sandia National Laboratories, a subsidiary of Lockheed Martin, conducted studies in both 1996 and 2001 that determined that law enforcement could not depend on smart guns to fire when necessary. [15] If Engage Armament had sold the iP1 smart gun, its retail price would have been $1,800, in a market where you can buy a gun for a fraction of that price. [15] Though no other smart gun is as far along as the iP1, t here are a host of others in development. [19] Critics have leveled many accusations at the iP1, arguing that, for example, you don't want to wake up in the middle of the night to hear a burglar breaking in, and have to remember where you left your smart gun. and then have to also remember where you left the smartwatch that you need to unlock your smart gun. [18] Gun lobbyists argue that the existence of a functional smart gun anywhere might lead to a mandate for smart guns everywhere. [15] What does a cowboy's favorite revolver and a smart gun worthy of a Schwarzenegger movie have in common? Well, they're both made by Colt, but they're also both do-it-all weapons. [21] A properly functioning smart gun holds out the prospect of eradicating, like smallpox, those unbearable horror stories we still come across about twice a month. [19] Even if it?s repealed, smart guns will still pose a threat to the gun industry. [19] Smart guns also played a cameo role in a massive litigation assault on the gun industry, patterned on the tobacco litigation. [19] In 2005, Mauch left H&amp;K, and in 2006 he joined Armatix, where he commenced work on a smart gun for the U.S. civilian market. (In late April, as this story was going to press, Mauch abruptly left the company under circumstances that are not yet clear.) [19] If someone wants to buy a smart gun, that is fine, that is their right he said. [15] For instance, reliability of smart guns is market segment specific, e.g., the right tech for stopping hunting accidents is fundamentally different from preventing child or adolescent misuse of guns in the home. [17] This whole discourse of smart everything, which has really taken off with smartphones, it makes sense to talk about smart guns but most of these technologies have been getting smart for a really long time, Slayton said. [22] Many gun groups opposed smart guns before it was ever conceived. [19] Well, there are some antigun groups that oppose smart guns for the same reason they oppose all guns. [19] Proponents of smart guns turned to legislation and litigation to force the industry?s hand. [19] Whatever you think of smart gun prices, and smart gun utility, there's one thing most Americans agree on: No one wants to buy one. [18] Will American gunowners ever buy a smart gun ? The short answer appears to be no. (Although the longer answer may be maybe.) [18] The hope is that smart guns could reduce the toll of murdered police officers, killed when their service revolvers are wrested away from them. (From 2004 to 2013, according to FBI statistics, 33 police officers were murdered with their own weapons.) [19] When the company decided to develop its own smart gun prototype, it used a bit of subterfuge. [15] A highly contested mandate law known as the 2002 Childproof Handgun Law of New Jersey, which states that only smart guns be sold in the state within 3 years of a smart gun being sold anywhere in the country, has invited fierce opposition by pro-arms groups and 2 nd amendment groups, and indirectly stymied availability and discouraged product investment. [23] There's a law on the books in New Jersey now that says that once this technology becomes available in the U.S. within three years every gun sold in New Jersey has to be a smart gun, she explains. [24] One problem has been an unfortunate 2002 New Jersey law stipulating that three years after smart guns are available anywhere in the United States, only smart guns can be sold in the state. [25] Smart gun supports call the technology an important safety measure that can help disable stolen or lost guns, and ultimately reduce unauthorized use of firearms and unnecessary deaths that occur each year. [26] As the President stated, the federal government is the single largest purchaser of firearms in the country, so this has the potential to make a huge impact on the advancement of smart gun technology. [27] NRA was already being falsely accused of blocking smart gun development, and the expensive, small-caliber Armatix was failing on its own due to fears that sale of the gun would trigger New Jersey?s infamous mandate requiring similar technology in all guns. [28] NRA opposes government mandates of expensive, unproven technology, and smart guns are a prime example of that. [28] TRENTON – Senate Majority Leader Loretta Weinberg today hailed action taken by President Obama to advance the use of smart gun technology. [27] Up to now, smart gun distribution has been stalled by a controversial New Jersey Law as well as limited availability. [29] Among other potential benefits, I think a sophisticated commitment by gun rights advocated to smart gun technologies could in some ways expand gun rights to people now too often denied their rights by overly broad federal firearm restrictions. [25] The blog is designed to bring all the voices concerned with smart gun technology to one central place, where citizens, developers, public health and elected officials can get the latest information on this fast evolving topic and formulate and express educated opinions. [23] New smart gun technology featuring proven Radio-frequency-identification technology and operable only by the authorized user can similarly reduce gun deaths as well. [29] Filed in the state Senate last month, the new bill details various specifications that a smart gun sold in California state would have to adhere to before it could be given to another person. [26] A California state senator introduced a measure that would make it illegal to give another individual a smart gun that fail to meet certain requirements, according to a report by Guns.com. [26] Senate Bill 678, which is scheduled for hearing with the Public Safety Committee on April 14, would mandate a list of 10 requirements before a smart gun can be given to an individual. [26] It?s also a recognition from the White House of the importance of the work we are doing here to spur the availability of smart guns and to provide consumers with the choice of purchasing a safer firearm. [27] Earlier this year the Group sponsored the largest gathering of smart gun developers and field experts yet and it plans to host a second global smart gun event early next year. [23] Of keen near term interest are the opinions of police leaders regarding the potential of a 9mm smart gun for the 900,000 law enforcement personnel across to country. [23] They?re not going to save all lives, but why wouldn?t we want to make guns as safe a consumer product as possible? David Hemenway, a public health expert at Harvard, says that the way forward is for police departments or the military to buy smart guns, creating a market and proving they work. [25] The Smart Gun News Blog will include updates on the latest industry news as well as regular interviews with leading smart gun developers such as Ernst Mauch and Robert McNamara as well as public health leaders such as David Hemenway of Harvard and Steven Teret of Johns Hopkins who both are strong advocates of smart gun adoption. [23] Host Leslie Stahl interviewed Ron Conway, a Silicon Valley investor who funds 15 separate companies working on smart gun tech, who said: This is going to happen outside the gun industry. [28] Then on Nov. 3, Mother Jones magazine called smart guns, The Guns the NRA Doesn?t Want Americans to Get. [28] Calling the prototype a smart gun worthy of a Schwarzenegger movie, Gizmodo's Adam Clark Estes wrote the new Colt-made Canadian smart gun is a glimpse into the future of firearms. [30] Smart guns could also go a long way to reducing the approximately 10,000 gun injuries annually to children and teens, as well as the chances of significant injury to the 5800 law enforcement officials who are assaulted annually. [23] Finally add as potential beneficiaries of new smart gun technology, victims of crime and domestic violence who are killed with a firearm not owned by the perpetrator. [31] I?m referring to a meeting this past week in Seattle, hosted by the Washington Technology Industry Association devoted to the issue of smart guns and featuring an appearance by Loretta Weinberg, the New Jersey State Senator who authored the nation?s first smart-gun legislation requiring all new guns in New Jersey to be equipped with smart-gun technology within 30 months after the first smart gun was sold anywhere in the United States. [32] The President has also directed the departments to review the availability of smart gun technology on a regular basis, and to explore potential ways to further its use and development to more broadly improve gun safety. [33] Smart guns utilize proven technology such as RFID (radio frequency identification) to ensure a firearm is operable only by the authorized user. [31] Such validation should, in turn, stimulate state and local law enforcement across the country to use smart guns and eventually a consumer swap-out of traditional firearms for safer smart guns. [31] Despite this very low level of knowledge, 14% of gun owners in the same survey stated they were likely or somewhat likely to purchase smart gun technology. [34] That may be true, but there is also evidence that gun owners are equally uninformed or unaware of smart gun technology. [34] To begin, there is the simple issue of whether or not the technology actually works, and while there are several smart guns that allegedly have been tested under real-life conditions, even smart-gun proponents like King County Sheriff John Urquhart voiced concerns at the conference about whether he could trust this and other electronic gun accessories to operate in ways that would not impede the overall effectiveness of a police officer?s gun. [32] What is a smart gun? A smart gun is a gun outfitted with a technology application that prevents a gun from being fired without user authentication. [34] The problem with smart gun technology is that, unlike other new technologies, it?s coming from outside the industry rather than from within. [32] The folks who met in Seattle, while supportive of smart guns, were not unsparing in their concerns about possible technical and legal problems that such technology represents. [32] The comparison between iGun and Safe Gun Technology, two of the market players, illustrates a critical point for all to consider as we learn more about smart guns. [34] Much has been made in the liberal media about the NRA?s opposition to smart gun technology, but for once I have to say that taking the NRA to task over this issue may be a little bit overblown. [32] Despite the promise of smart guns, their distribution has been stalled by politics and concern over reliability, especially those smart guns that utilize a more sophisticated and sensitive biometric technology. [31] Issue a Presidential Memorandum directing the Department of Defense, Department of Justice, and Department of Homeland Security to take two important steps to promote smart gun technology. [33] The National Shooting Sports Foundation commissioned a national survey in fall of 2013 to assess gun owner attitudes towards smart guns. [34] Significantly, more than four out of five gun owners of all ages believe gun dealers should be able to sell smart guns. [31] I am considering a repeal of the so-called smart gun mandate based on concerns from gun safety groups that I respect. [35] Our work is already generating results pending repeal of the New Jersey smart gun mandate that had the unintended consequence of stifling smart gun development and distribution. [35] President Barack Obama is flexing his executive muscle, ordering the federal government to study how smart guns could stem violence. [36] Opponents of smart guns cite government mandates as their main concern. [37] Safe Gun Technology?s smart gun solution can be used to prevent these types of shootings and deaths. [34] The next best thing, then, is to have guns that will not operate when in the wrong hands: smart guns that children and teens cannot operate, smart guns that will not fire if stolen or taken out of a police officer's hands by a criminal, and smart guns that can’t be used by violent partners or the frantically suicidal. [31] The results inversely skew with age, as 54 percent of gun owners under 45 would consider switching to a smart gun. [31] Smart gun companies must be laser-focused on which gun owner segment they are trying to satisfy. [34] If 20% of gun owners reported familiarity with smart guns and 14% of gun owners indicated a buying interest, then doesn't this market show potential? That does not discount or marginalize real concerns about performance and reliability. [34] The safest home is the one without a gun, but for the 40% of American homeowners who still wish to exercise their second amendment rights, smart guns are the best option. [35] Page 2 of 2 – The president can accelerate this move by encouraging the various federal law enforcement groups including the FBI, the Transportation Security Administration and the U.S. Border Patrol to test smart guns. [31] In the world of science fiction, smart guns have already gained traction in recent pop culture. [38] There is, according to recent polls, considerable appetite in the American public for laws that would make smart guns the only legal form of firearms. [39] One reason for the opposition is a 2002 New Jersey law that mandates that selling handguns without personalized technology would become illegal three years after the sale of the first smart gun in the country. [40] Already, New Jersey law mandates that once smart guns are nationally available, distributors have three years to sell their remaining stock of traditional guns. [39] Basically, the Childproof Handgun Law of 2002 says that once personalized handguns are available anywhere in the country, all handguns sold in New Jersey must be smart guns within 30 months. [41] Smart gun technology allows a handgun to only be operated by an authorized user. [42] If there were some seat belt equivalent for firearms, perhaps it would be smart gun technology, which allows only authorized users to unlock and fire them. [40] Markey, a Massachusetts Democrat, has pushed to require all new guns to incorporate smart gun technology so they can be fired only by their owners or other authorized users. [43] Despite the skepticism among gun enthusiasts, a survey from two years ago by the National Shooting Sports Foundation found that 14 percent of gun owners said they would consider purchasing a smart gun, which amounts to millions of people. [40] A poll conducted earlier this year found that 40 percent of gun owners would consider replacing their gun(s) with a smart gun (with more than 50 percent of those among 18 to 44-year-olds). [40] According to a fact sheet released Monday, the administration wants these three federal agencies to review the availability of smart gun technology on a regular basis, and to explore potential ways to further its use and development to more broadly improve gun safety. [39] Simply getting smart gun technology to market is one of the biggest hurdles for a startup like SGTi, which is currently running an Indiegogo campaign to fund the next round of development. [40] While the law may have been intended to promote smart guns, the reality is that it did the opposite. [41] Smart guns could curtail the number of suicides, and cut down on the resale of stolen guns; estimated to be 230,000 every year. [41] Despite the opposition and a lack of interest among gun manufacturers, some startups are aiming to bring viable smart guns to the market. [40] The danger here is not that smart guns will be sold, or even that they will become wildly popular. [39] In March 2000, Smith Wesson agreed to a settlement that included a promise that the company would provide safety locking devices, invest in smart gun technology to limit use to the proper owner, limit magazine capacity for its new firearms, cut off dealers and distributors with a history of selling to criminals, and prevent authorized dealers from selling at gun shows where any arm sales are permitted without background checks. [44] That?s because of a New Jersey law passed in 2002 known as the Childproof Handgun Law, which says that all guns sold in New Jersey must be state-approved smart guns within three years of a smart gun being sold anywhere in the country. [45] The main reason is that they're afraid it will open the door to laws that require smart gun technology, and said technology may be unreliable and/or expensive, which will place a burden on their membership. [46] The effect is it makes it a lot harder to enact smart gun laws, Law Center to Prevent Gun Violence senior staff attorney Laura Cutilletta said in an interview. [44] Preparing reports and conducting periodic reviews? It's not much, really, but it would be significant if the government moved to smart gun technology. [46] The goal was to make smart guns mandatory as soon as the technology existed. [45] I'm at a total loss about why the NRA (or anyone for that matter) is against smart gun technology. [46] Officially, no smart gun has been sold in the U.S. yet - meaning if Raymond had sold one, it would have triggered the clause in New Jersey. [45] The problem though is that New Jersey will be instantly screwed once the first smart gun in the country is sold. [45] Smart guns, like the one shown here, may provide one technological solution to gun violence. [47] Once smart guns get a foothold, it could be game over for the old way of shooting and killing people. [46] There has been renewed interest in smart guns since the Newtown school shooting, which reinvigorated the gun-control debate. [45] An 18-year-old Real Life Vigilante invented a smart gun that allows only authorized users to fire their weapons. [45] If I lose my designated weapon, smart gun tech might leave me defenseless. [46] POSSIBLY USEFUL New Jersey Senate Majority Leader Loretta Weinberg, the principal sponsor of the law, is expected to announce soon a compromise that will still mandate that New Jersey gun dealers carry smart guns–but along with and not instead of traditional firearms. [6] Why are you trying to take my firearm and add something to it that's going to make it more prone to failure? he asks, referring to the possibility that technology might malfunction, like the batteries in the smart devices could drain, causing the gun to fail. [3] Teret says smart, or personalized, guns have faced a stalemated kind of supply-demand: Manufacturers best-positioned to make and market these new guns don't want to go all-in on the idea without a reassurance of big orders, while no big buyer would put in such an order for an unestablished technology. [1] Just as you can?t buy a car anymore that uses leaded gasoline, smart guns–also known as personalized guns or childproof guns–has Second Amendment enthusiasts worried that standard firearms would become obsolete. [6] The billionaire angel investor Ron Conway formed the Smart Tech Challenges Foundation in 2013 to create the Googles, the Facebooks, the Twitters of gun safety. [2] The notion of a gun smart enough to tell who's holding it isn't new. [1] The law was intended to spur the market for the technologically innovative weapons, whose backers believe they could enhance safety and help reduce certain types of gun violence, such as attacks with stolen firearms and the all too common accidental shootings deaths of children. [2] Opponents of the law said the technology wouldn't work reliably and would compromise the safety of legal gun owners when confronted by armed criminals. [4] He argues that such laws punish responsible gun owners who secure their weapons safely away from children or thieves and that manufacturers include safety mechanisms on guns. [3] It?s beyond time for the technology to emerge, says Stephen Teret, co-director of the Center for Law and the Public?s Health at Johns Hopkins University and an expert on gun policy. [6] Guns made in the United States haven?t changed in a century, he says, and if the manufacturers don?t keep up with the rapidly advancing technology for safer firearms, They?re at threat of becoming dinosaurs. [6] The law appeared to have no effect until 2013 when a German firm, Armatix, tried to introduce a personalized handgun in two gun shops, one in California and the other in Maryland. [6] Proponents have said the law was needed to help change the grim fact that guns kill more preschoolers than police officers each year across the nation. [4] The technology is there, and the politics have begun to shift with the leading Democratic presidential candidate, Hillary Clinton, making gun safety a centerpiece of her campaign. [6] In the 1990s after the Columbine school shooting, when Bill Clinton was president, Smith &amp; Wesson, a leading gun manufacturer, said it would introduce safer firearms. [6] 83 percent of gun owners, it found, want gun dealers to be able to sell the weapons. [2] Weinberg, now the majority leader of the New Jersey Senate, disputes allegations of a plot to disarm gun owners. [5] They could also help prevent the almost 20,000 suicides each year carried out with guns belonging to other people, often a parent or grandparent, while also eliminating the danger law enforcement officials face of having their gun turned on them as they do their job. [6] Guns of the Old West, they like them the way Davy Crockett used them. years ago, he says. [3] Speaking in Dover, N.H., at a 2016-themed town hall meeting last week, Gov. Chris Christie had singled out the Childproof Gun Law for special scorn, holding it up as the epitome of Democratic legislative overreach. [4] Conway recently announced plans to fund the development of a biometric gun lock; a version of the technology may eventually be integrated into a gun. [2] The first Armatix gun that he designed was priced at $1,800 for a.22-caliber versus $400 for a traditional firearm. [6] Activists say smart-gun development has been slow because the gun lobby doesn?t want it and stokes fears that creating safer guns could lead to government buy-backs of traditional firearms or even outright confiscation. [6] Says Greenwald, many consumers who might not otherwise purchase a handgun out of concern for the safety of their children might pay more for a gun that guaranteed it. [4] Reached by NJ Advance Media, Weinberg confirmed that the talks were starting, saying, I have been approached by various gun safety people, who I respect, to reach a compromise. [4] People who want to disarm gun owners want to create a safer society. but the road to hell is paved with good intentions. [5] Maryland gun store owner Andy Raymond initially jumped at the chance to offer the gun, but backed out after activists threatened to kill him and burn down his store. [2] Several manufacturers have tried to introduce Americans to the concept, but the market here has been less than friendly over concerns that they are unreliable and would lead to more gun control. [1] Yet, these guns are not mass-produced or sold in the United States, in part because of fears they are a backdoor to greater gun control. [3] Armatix engineer Ernst Mauch recently quit the company and visited the United States to explore creating a new start-up to build a lower-cost version of the gun for Americans. [2] Another basic argument Sanetti makes is that Americans like guns the way they were. [3] In 2000, rival Smith &amp; Wesson promised to make all of its guns available with high-tech safety features. [2] According to the Centers for Disease Control's most current data available, 505 people were killed in gun accidents in 2013, 108 of them children. [4] It's coming from people who, frankly, really want to put as many obstacles to a gun going off as they can, he tells Stahl. [3] What we need now are people willing to invest and bring to market these guns. [6] A dozen years ago, he was deeply shaken when a 6-year-old boy accidentally shot a friend with a gun made by the company he was running. [6] Tech investors and Sandy Hook families propose a $15 million assault on gun violence. [2] The company never found a single retail outlet willing to sell its gun. [2] Ever since, the mainstream gun industry has steadfastly refused to pursue the technologies. [2] Kessler calls those objections a symptom of the irrational paranoia that fuels the gun rights lobby. [6] If anyone takes the gun away from you, it doesn?t function in the hands of someone else. [6] No one can tell you with any level of certainty how many of the 33,000-plus gun deaths will be avoided by personalized guns, he says. [1] Gun enthusiasts called for a boycott; the company was brought to its knees financially, and its president fired. [6] Actually, it?s not quite that simple, but Mauch has designed a gun suitable for law enforcement, and he tells stories of personally testing it in the humidity of Panama, the heat of Yuma, Arizona, and the cold of Alaska. [6] One of the biggest concerns from law enforcement officers cited by that 2013 DOJ report was reliability - the concern that a battery-powered or computer-chip-driven gun wouldn't fire when it should. [1] TRENTON - Leading Democratic state lawmakers are seriously considering scrapping New Jersey's longstanding but never-implemented law requiring all handguns sold in the state feature smart gun technology that allows only the weapon's owners to fire them, NJ Advance Media has learned. [4] With Congress unwilling to act to curb gun violence, and state legislatures often acting like wholly owned subsidiaries of the gun lobby, safety advocates are turning to technology to save lives with a renewed push for so-called smart guns that can only be fired by their rightful owner. [6] The law required that 30 months after a viable smart weapon came to market, all new guns sold in the state had to be equipped with mechanisms to limit unauthorized use. [11] The Law Center to Prevent Gun Violence tracks important studies proving that smart laws can and do work to prevent gun violence. [48] In the face of political stalemate, even ardent backers of gun control legislation are pinning their hopes on smart technology. [11] The gun industry and gun rights activists are wary of smart weapons. [11] The biggest reason the new technologies raised concern among gun enthusiasts was because of smart guns? most enthusiastic boosters: politicians and activists trying to reduce gun violence. [10] Ironically, the state law that initially provided a boost to the NJIT project - the Childproof Handgun Law of 2002 - was enacted as a political attempt by progressive Democrats and some Republicans to outflank the National Rifle Association and other firearms rights lobbyists who opposed most gun control laws. [9] Instead of making guns safer, the technology - and the mandate in the New Jersey law - was viewed as an intrusion on personal liberty and privacy. [9] The NRA has also promoted the conspiracy theory that the government could use the technology to take control of private firearms to implement a de facto ban on gun ownership. [12] The staunchest supporters of the Second Amendment say guns like the Armatix iP1 only make it easier for the government to control the sale and use of lawful firearms. [11] Colandro, who has testified before legislative committees on gun laws, said he is not necessarily against high-tech safety systems for firearms. [9] Stag Arms president Mark Malkowski, a vocal opponent of tougher gun laws, was named the National Shooting Sports Foundation?s Business Person of the Year in 2014. [10] The technology could save some of the 650 Americans each year between the ages of 10 and 19 who, according to published estimates, use relatives' guns to take their own lives. [11] They fear, among other concerns, that the advent of guns with high-tech safety mechanisms will prompt state governments to mandate their use. [11] The lawmakers say they want to replace or change the Childproof Gun Law with a measure that encourages rather than requires gun shops to sell smart guns - and provides economic incentives for Garden State consumers to buy them. [4] Law enforcement is best-placed to assess the state of the art, said Mosbacher, Our police and our military are some of the biggest purchasers of weapons, and we hope to use that purchasing power to press gunmakers directly (to begin offering smart guns). [4] Instead of arguing for mandating the smart gun's use, he says he wants the state's largest purchasers of firearms to reach that decision on their own. [4] If smart guns–which attempt to verify the ID of its user–became widespread, they could prevent most tragic accidents involving children, which now average one a week. [6] The New Jersey attorney general actually ruled that the iP1 does not, strictly speaking, meet the law's standard for a perfectly personalized firearm, but that little-noticed determination hasn't eased passionate gun advocates' hatred of the weapon. [10] The Democrats say they support a less stringent law that would require New Jersey gun stores to sell at least one smart-gun model. [9] However such actions will not result in safety, but probably will result in more dead people like Carol Bowne, who was stabbed to death in cold blood because New Jersey couldn't get her a gun permit within the allotted 30 days. [8] After President Obama announced executive actions to curb gun violence, Fox Host Bill O'Reilly claimed that there is not a gun crime epidemic and downplayed the fact that more than 8,000 people were victims of firearm murders in 2014. [12] Mosbacher and his colleagues, disappointed by the failure of legislative action on gun violence after Newtown, decided to try popularizing smart-gun technology with police instead of contending with gridlocked legislatures and skeptical civilians. [10] Gun owners, he said, want to be able to choose when to activate safe technology, when to turn it off and whom to designate as an authorized user. [11] Those concerns were underscored in a report by Sandia National Laboratories in 1996 - and reaffirmed in 2001 - that law enforcement officers could not depend on personalized gun technology to fire when necessary. [11] Most speakers were either unwilling or unable to address the possibility that today's technology is decades from being advanced enough to fight the intractable fanaticism of the American gun enthusiast. [7] Gun ownership is an American faith second only to Christianity, and the technology community is ill-equipped to fight that crusade. [7] An informal survey conducted by Government Technology in an online forum called Reddit Guns revealed a mindset typical of the average gun enthusiast. [7] There's new hand gun technology that the inventor says will save lives and will make stolen guns useless to criminals. [13] Without that law no one would care if you are stupid enough to want and buy a vastly overpriced.22LR hand gun that fails at least 20% of the time, you would be welcome to do just that. [11] Many types of gun laws are effective at reducing gun deaths and injuries, keeping guns away from criminals and other prohibited people, and fighting illegal gun trafficking. [48] Public health experts say the iP1 could shift the demographics of gun ownership in the United States by attracting people who have been too afraid to own firearms. [11] Speaking of Maloney, she helped advance The Firearms Risk Protection Act, which would require gun owners to purchase liability insurance. [8] Raymond, the Maryland gun shop owner, jumped at the chance to sell the weapon. [11] It?s not that gun shops won?t sell them, it?s that gun owners don?t want them. [11] Intelligun is designed to go on the 1911, the most popular handgun among gun shop owners. [13] Timothy Johnson is the guns and public safety program director at Media Matters, having previously spent time at the Brady Center to Prevent Gun Violence Legal Action Project and the Coalition to Stop Gun Violence. [12] These bills will keep guns out of the hands that of those who shouldn't have them and provide better information about what is causing gun violence and what can be done to prevent it. [8] Rabbi Joel Mosbacher of Mahwah, New Jersey, is not your typical gun impresario or champion of police firepower: In fact, he ended up putting this event together after years as an anti-gun-violence activist. [10] On May 21, several dozen officers from 10 New York-area law-enforcement agencies converged on the New Rochelle Police Department?s gun range for a small gun show highlighting some of the latest developments in firearms tech. [10] The challenge is forming strategic partnerships with larger gun companies to produce the volume of firearms that police departments would require. [10] How long would it be before the first gangland geek? came up with a device that would block the transponder of any nearby officer (or armed citizen), rendering the good guy?s weapon inoperable? wrote internationally known firearms instructor Massad Ayoob in a 2000 Guns Magazine article. [10] The single biggest gap in our nation?s gun laws is the lack of a background check requirement when. [48] The Law Center?s publications analyze the intricate and changing world of gun legislation and Second Amendment litigation across the country to clarify the truth about gun laws in America. [48] The issue of gun violence particularly impacts Latinos - who widely support gun violence prevention measures - since Latinos are disproportionately affected by fatal shootings despite being less likely to own guns themselves. [12] One point of clarity was Washington CeaseFire's mission: We in the gun safety movement wish that fewer homes had guns, because nothing correlates with home gun violence as home gun ownership, Fascitelli said. [7] The  Handgun Trigger Safety Act  is touted as a means of gun safety. [8] It?s a tried-and-true approach: Many of the biggest names in the civilian handgun market, like Glock and Smith &amp; Wesson, first established their bona fides as cop guns. [10] Despite being a complete distortion of what Holder said, NRA News hosted multiple guests to push the conspiracy theory, with one guest claiming, For some reason they feel like they need to keep an eye on where your gun is and where my gun is, and Eric Holder can do pretty much whatever he wants with government funds. [12] Enraged gun owners also lashed out against the Oak Tree Gun Club in Newhall, Calif., where the iP1 had been demonstrated and displayed in the pro shop. [11] Detached from the politics of gun control in the United States, Dietel poured his fortune into building the iP1. [11] He then passed the firearm to Mossberg, who was able to fire the gun instantly because he was wearing a ring for an authorized user. [12] The Gun Shop Project helps firearm sellers spot potentially suicidal customers, but some employees question whether that should be in their job description. [10] Media should highlight the importance that gun violence prevention measures have on Latinos when reporting on President Obama's executive actions designed to address the issue. [12] Leading up to and after the unveiling of President Obama's executive actions on gun violence, conservative media figures have made numerous misleading and false claims about them, including that they do not have popular support, will be ineffective, are unconstitutional, and will lead to mass gun confiscation. [12] On the same day President Obama announced a series of executive orders regulating gun access, his administration finalized a rule he ordered after the Sandy Hook shooting which enables health care providers to report the names of mentally ill patients to the federal background check system that screens gun buyers. [10] After a 2002 shooting at the Gutenberg-Gymnasium in Erfurt that left 16 people dead, Dietel envisioned guns with coded digital locks, similar to the ones his company installed on buildings. [11] There is not doubt in my mind that the American people will not stand for this in the same manner they didn't stand for Obama's gun grab following Sandy Hook, nor the backdoor attempt at violating the Second Amendment when the unconstitutional ATF sought to ban AR-15 ammunition. [8] SEATTLE - If today's technological revolution can save lives on American roadways and in hospitals, then maybe new technologies like biometric palm readers can put a dent in the nation's 30,000 annual gun deaths. [7] If the author of this article or the newspaper or any other individual wants to sell them to promote gun safety, they can apply for a FFL and put them on the market. [11] In 2000, rival Smith &amp; Wesson promised to make all of its new guns available with high-tech safety features. [11] Among the most recent signees is Gregory Austin, chief of police for Rye Brook, New York, who attended the New Rochelle gun fair and came away impressed - especially with the iGun, the only fully working prototype available. [10] The threatened boycotts were first aimed at New Jersey gun shops. [9] They said gun owners should have a choice about whether or not they want to get it. [13] King said not every gun owner will be able to reach the activation button on the side of the gun. [13] Elsewhere, scientists had equipped guns with radio transmitters linked to special watches, medallions or rings that would be worn by a gun?s owner. [9] If we're trying to gain the confidence of gun owners, we'd better talk to them. [7] Public health and medical experts roundly disagree, noting that gun violence is a public health issue that has reached epidemic proportions. [12] I thank Rep. Maloney for her partnership on this effort, and I recommit to stopping the hemorrhaging of lives and spirit that gun violence causes for families in Massachusetts and across the country. [8] Senator Markey issues a press release in which he stated, The epidemic of gun violence in America is not preordained, it is preventable. [8] We know the fight to end gun violence cannot be won alone–which is why we?ve spent the last. [48] A nationally respected engineering university in downtown Newark set out to design a safer gun with high-tech electronic locks to prevent it from being fired by a thief or a child who found it accidentally. [9] LOS ANGELES - German entrepreneur Bernd Dietel had a radical idea about gun safety. [11] He is less optimistic that cops on the beat will be using his weapons - though he did note that 10 percent of officers killed in the line of duty had their own gun turned against them. [10] They wont be able to steal that gun and immediately go out and use it, but they will figure out a way to make that gun operable, said Watson. [13] If they're in a shootout situation, one guy tries to use another person's gun for a number of reasons they wouldn't be able to do it to protect themselves or somebody else, said Sheriff Rich Watson. [13] The reason gun shops don't sell them is because no one will buy them. [11] Guns kept in the home are more likely to be involved in a fatal or nonfatal unintentional shooting,. [48] These types of guns are simply gun control in another form. [8] Surely they can make a gun with an LCD screen and a 6 foot cable and servo controls so it can be aimed and fired from a foxhole or behind a wall? far safer. [49] He poached engineer Ernst Mauch from Germany's leading arms manufacturer to design the gun. [11] A German gun manufacturer reportedly spent $100 million to develop a gun that would fire only when it was in range of a wristwatch embedded with a sensor. [9] The initiative, sparked by a request from the Clinton administration, was dropped after gun rights activists boycotted the company, nearly driving it out of business. [11] The project prompted sporadic boycotts of Colt by gun rights enthusiasts and was scuttled. [11] As a field soldier, I would want better lightweight body armor, a more powerful rifle, and some type of small, portable gun shot locator. [49] He also said it would keep criminals from using a police officer's gun against him or her. [13] Since police departments tend to drive the civilian gun market, it was a damning assessment. [11] We're getting quite close to having personalized guns be a reality in the United States. [11] The Trace is an independent, nonprofit news organization dedicated to expanding coverage of guns in the United States. [10] Passed in 2002 to respond to accidental child deaths from guns, the law's mandates for gun sales were supposed to kick in three years after the weapons became available for retail purposes. [4] He noted that the pro-gun culture is so powerful that even in a progressive state like Washington State, which has legalized marijuana, passed assisted suicide and sanctioned same-sex marriage, a background check bill for gun buyers favored by 87 percent of the electorate never got out of committee in the legislature. [6] Steve Sanetti speaks for gun manufacturers as the president of the National Shooting Sports Foundation (NSSF). [3] The New Jersey mandate, known as the Childproof Handgun Law, is now considered a well-meaning but misguided failure that sparked a vigorous campaign by gun-rights proponents to block the sale of smart firearms with safety locks. [9] They keep talking about doing so, but _has_ New Jersey repealed its law that says once smart guns become available then only that type can be sold? We don't want them to be available until New Jersey repeals that law. [11] There is no objection to the idea of a smart gun, Other than it being a Gun Grabbers wet dream of a way to put every manufacturer and dealer out of business. [11] Looking every bit like a weapon from a science fiction movie, the latest integrated assault rifle prototype being developed for the Canadian Armed Forces (CAF) is packed with some very smart weapons technology. [49] The San Francisco billionaire - who was an early investor in Google, PayPal and Facebook - started the Smart Tech for Firearms Challenge a year after the Newtown shootings, offering grants of $10,000 to $100,000 to develop safe, high-tech firearms. [11] Colandro also said he does not believe that the smart technology has been developed enough to be foolproof from hackers or from breakdowns in an emergency. [9] Steve Teret, a public health expert at Johns Hopkins University who has tracked the evolution of smart weapons for more than three decades, said it was only a matter of time before they were readily available. [11] Kiyani said his company could have a smart accessory ready for the American market before the year is out. [7] Along with the ability to fire new lightweight telescoped ammunition, and a secondary effects module that adds either a three-round 40 mm grenade launcher or a 12-gauge shotgun, there is also a NATO-standard power and data bus to allow the attachment of smart accessories, such as electro-optical sights and position sensors that connect to command and control networks. [49] The smartest thing about the gun? Using smart to sell it, and get just this kind of media attention. [22] When All the Police Dept and Military switch to smart guns then Ill think about it. [14] Only two states, Rhode Island and Massachusetts, mandate regular inspections of gun dealers, and the Consumer Product Safety Commission has no authority when it comes to firearms. [15] The watch, which takes less than a half-second to activate, contains an RFID transponder, whose signal is recognized by a receiver inside the gun, which then unblocks the firing pin. (Doug sells the gun over the Internet to other licensed gun dealers, who can then resell it to retail customers in accordance with state law. [19] A big clue to what had happened, though, can be gleaned from the Calguns.net website, which is still filled with angry posts from gun enthusiasts, many referencing a 13-year-old state law in New Jersey. [19] Under its provisions, once the state?s attorney general certified that a personalized gun was being sold anywhere in the U.S., the clock would start ticking, and three years later only personalized handguns could be lawfully sold in New Jersey. [19] Keane also pointed out that personalized handguns, once they hit the market, are but a single option in making a firearms safe and that the industry has already made great strides to promote proper storage of unattended guns. [14] At the time, Teret recalls, he felt that such a law would assure manufacturers or tech people thinking of getting into gun safety that there might be a viable market for such a gun. [19] Armatix filed for bankruptcy in May, days before company executives were scheduled to headline a technology fair organized by gun safety groups. [20] SANTA CRUZ, Calif. –Amid the ongoing debate over officer-involved shootings, the county sheriff?s office in this California beach town was the first law enforcement agency in the world to test new technology: a tiny sensor that records any time a deputy?s gun is fired. [20] A lifetime National Rifle Association member, Doug earns his living as a gunsmith and licensed firearms dealer, selling pistols, revolvers, assault rifles, and machine guns to law enforcement and other qualified customers. [19] A growing number of states now allow gun owners to carry concealed weapons in public places. [15] By the time Yardarm found itself in the spotlight again at the gun industry?s biggest annual event, the 2014 SHOT Show, Schaff had a new approach: target gun owners who also carry badges–law enforcement, private security and military–a group with which the NRA and other gun rights organizations wield less influence. [20] The event featured those working to develop the technology, gun control advocates, and legislators who have been proponents. [16] While Washington State gun control activists may think they are ahead of the national curve by sponsoring this event, their leaders should learn from past examples of those who have previously ventured forward on this issue. [16] Kicking off the first annual National Gun Violence Awareness Day, Sen. Edward J. Markey, Mass., and Rep. Carolyn Maloney, N.Y. recycled gun control proposals that tanked last session. [14] Coupled with the perceived momentum of National Gun Violence Awareness Day, marked by the Wear Orange campaign, lawmakers are fishing for more support the second time around despite significant GOP gains in Congress last fall. [14] The CDC peeked into gun violence as part of a White House by executive order following the mass shooting at Sandy Hook Elementary in Newtown, Connecticut, but its results were surprising to gun control advocates. [14] Controlling access to the gun, manufacturers say, will reduce accidental shootings and prevent stolen guns from being used in crimes. [20] There are highly reliable ways to prevent unauthorized access to firearms ranging from locks provided by manufacturers with new firearms purchases and cable-style gun locks by NSSF through Project ChildSafe to various types of lock boxes, secure cabinets and safes. [16] The next iteration of the weapon is supposed include networking components so that the firearm can receive data from base as well as  automated target detection and assisted target engagement, if R&amp;D goes as planned. (Read: The gun will one day aim itself.) [21] The massacre stunned the nation, which has strict laws governing gun possession and storage. [19] Telling gun owners what guns they should buy causes them to fear being forced to own guns they don?t want and - worse – fear that government would take away the guns they own or want. [17] To the gun lobby, this is a problem - not because it will trigger a government crackdown and a mandate against gun ownership, but because it might spark consumer demand or cooperation between the government, gun manufacturers and retailers. [15] These bills will keep guns out of the hands of those who shouldn?t have them and provide better information about what is causing gun violence and what can be done to prevent it. [14] If a user has set a PIN to limit other users? access to the gun, that root attack can nonetheless gain full access and lock out the gun?s owner with a new PIN. The attacker can even disable the firing pin, a computer controlled solenoid, to prevent the gun from firing. [50] He believed that the iP1, by attracting a new category of gun owner to our side, would further the pro-gun cause, as he would later explain. [19] She thought she had found the perfect one when she met James Mitchell, the owner of Oak Tree Gun Club in Newhall, north of Los Angeles. [19] It was small and light, with minimal recoil–ideal for first-time gun owners. [19] Some of the hundreds of despondent adolescents who use others? guns to commit suicide each year - about 670 of them in 2010 - might be foiled long enough to find treatment. [19] The final study found that defensive gun use was common, while mass shootings were not. [14] Padilla drove to the club, and, sure enough, all Armatix signage had been taken down, her gun was no longer displayed, and her shooting range had been painted over green. [19] Soon thereafter, Mitchell?s daughter Betsy told the online publication Gun Rights Examiner, Our facility does not carry the Armatix pistol, never has, and comment was taken out of context ? by the Washington Post [19] Mitchell was excited about the gun, she says, and wanted exclusive sales rights for California. [19] The product would court a new category of gun buyer: young parents who wanted protection but feared having a firearm anywhere near children. [19] If you're concerned about gun safety and want to ensure your kids can't get their hands on your gun, there's a much more economical way to keep that from happening. [18] When Smith &amp; Wesson promised to give its new guns high-tech safety features in 2000, the company faced boycotts and dropped the initiative. [15] Gun lobbyists feared that gun-control advocates would ban guns through the backdoor by mandating unachievable safety features. [19] This bill is flawed and counterproductive to the goals of improving gun safety. [17] Americans can buy guns, used or new, from licensed dealers and individuals, and from big box retailers or mom-and-pop shops. [15] The most formidable opponent might be Keane?s client, the American gun industry. [19] Some people really would like to make these guns mandatory. [19] Before getting off the phone he asserted that Oak Tree never sold the gun and added that a person who worked for took a photo of it in the cabinet to make it look like it was on sale. [19] No standards body, like Underwriters Lab, certifies the reliability of civilian guns. [19] The epidemic of gun violence in America is not preordained, it is preventable, said Markey in a statement. [14] That?s what happened to the last two gun dealers who tried to sell this gun. [19] Although Yardarm?s sensor would not have saved the two detectives, the possibility of cutting response time and being notified when deputies? guns are taken appealed to Wowak. [20] It?s even possible (although likely difficult), they suggest, to implant the gun with malware that would only take effect at a certain time or location based on querying a user?s connected phone. [50] Obama cries during gun remarks Every time I think about those kids, it gets me mad, Obama said. [17] Their tricks can change variables in the scope?s calculations that make the rifle inexplicably miss its target, permanently disable the scope?s computer, or even prevent the gun from firing. [50] It?s supposed to prevent the gun from firing when anyone other than the owner–a child, say–pulls the trigger. [19] The suspect then took both of the detectives? guns, which he used in a shootout with police when he returned to the scene less than an hour later. [20] The earliest they were called computers, computers were these devices used to steer guns, Slayton said. [22] It was also discovered that when guns are used in self-defense the victims consistently have lower injury rates than those who are unarmed, even compared with those who used other forms of self-defense. [14] His accuracy impugned, the author of the Post story, Mike Rosenwald, published a follow-up article, including a photo of the gun apparently on sale, along with additional quotations from his original interview with Mitchell. [19] In mid-February 2014 the gun finally went on sale, she says. [19] Gun sales, stocks soar Some experts believe Tuesday?s executive action will only heighten demand. [17] This spirals into a vicious cycle of market resistance leading to investor resistance, lack of capital, unsubstantial marketing, limited sales, no capital improvements, that itself results in undesirable products and full-circle to market resistance – exactly the opposite effect that proponents of safer guns want. [17] The result is a weapon that can allow even a gun novice to reliably hit targets from as far as a mile away. [50] With his bulging, tattooed forearms and store full of assault-style weapons, Raymond was a gun guy to the bone. [19] Such guns hold considerable promise with the potential of dramatically curtailing gun accidents, particularly among children who end up victims from the unauthorized use of guns. [17] Jim Schaff of Yardarm demonstrates the readings that pop up when a gun is holstered, unholstered, and fired at a shooting range in San Jose, California, on Thursday, September 10, 2015. [20] The fundamentals of shooting don?t change even if the gun is hacked. [50] She moved her office to Oak Tree and set up a shooting range there where customers could try out her gun. [19] Unfortunately, Markey-Maloney?s bill only serves to bolster the critics that this is a backdoor means to gun control. [17] In 2004, Dietel formed Armatix (pronounced AR-ma-tix in English, or ahr-MA-teeks in German) to make electromechanical gun locks. [19] Colt, the gun manufacturer that popularized the revolver, fared worse. [15] But as a lawyer who formerly represented manufacturers in product-liability lawsuits, I will tell you: If you put it on one model and have other models that don?t have it–for whatever reason–and that model gets involved in an accident, I assure you a plaintiffs lawyer is going to get an expert to say that that gun?s defective, because you coulda-shoulda put it on this gun. [19] On Feb. 17 the Washington Post ran a story about the landmark day, quoting Oak Tree?s Mitchell saying that the iP1 could revolutionize the gun industry. [19] Renowned gun designer and executive Ernst Mauch holds his smart-gun creation, the.22-caliber iP1. [19] As great as a self-aiming gun might sound – imagine being able to guarantee you won?t hit a school beside a target with a grenade? – it?s not as simple as pointing and letting the robots take over. [22] Other gun groups called for a boycott, and S&amp;W was struck with a whopper. [19] Gun trade group representatives also demean the iP1?s allegedly modest lethality. [19] Trade group reps, in fact, often speak as if no safer gun could possibly exist than those now in circulation. [19] From there, a hacker can treat the gun as a server and access APIs to alter key variables in its targeting application. (The hacker pair were only able to find those changeable variables by dissecting one of the two rifles they worked with, using an eMMC reader to copy data from the computer?s flash storage with wires they clipped onto its circuit board pins.) [50] The American gun companies can either get on board or they can become Kodak. [19] Inventors first began patenting ideas for personalized guns in the mid-1970s. [19] Raymond, a self-proclaimed huge Second Amendment guy, thought the gun might appeal to some of his younger customers who were into consumer electronics, the Los Angeles Times' Melissa Healy reported. [15] In a congratulatory email, an Oak Tree employee sent her a photo, Padilla says, depicting her gun tagged for sale in a display case. [19] Allied Biometrix (which has an option to commercialize NJIT biometrics gun technology) and the other companies developing personalized or smart guns share the goal of bringing reliable smart gun technology to market that can limit the function of firearms to authorized users. [17] Sen. Edward Markey (D-Mass.) and Rep. Carolyn Maloney (D-N.Y.) recently announced that they are bringing back smart gun mandate legislation with their proposed, Handgun Trigger Safety Act. [17] Unlike the more common use of smart gun, which commonly means a weapon with digital tools that would prevent the wrong person from firing it, this rifle-cum-grenade launcher is more about giving soldiers more reliable information and helping to make decisions about who and what to attack. [22] It?s still a prototype, so it?s a long way from being in the field, but the new smart gun being developed with Colt Canada could one day replace the C7, the standard military weapon that?s almost identical to the M16 everyone knows from the movies. [22] Last year alone the group has been a resource on the issue of smarts guns and gun violence to a wide variety of media outlets including the New York Times, CBC, BBC and Al Jazeera. [23] Of course, under Australia?s reformed gun regulatory scheme, a licensed firearm owner is required to be reevaluated every five years and if authorities discovery any reliable evidence of a mental or physical barrier to responsible gun ownership, the license is revoked. [51] The problem is that the NRA/survivalist/John Birch crowd has primed a influential minority of gun owners to identify any kind of technical solution that involves computerized equipment embedded into firearms as a prelude to government remote control of said firearms. [25] The President also directed the departments to regularly review the availability of the technology and explore potential ways to further its use and development to more broadly improve gun safety. [27] The goal is to make it harder to use the gun against you, explains Padilla, saying that it cannot solve all problems, but can ideally address safety issues, and can, for instance, prevent children from accidentally firing a handgun. [24] Those states that have the highest percentage of handgun ownership also have the highest percentage of gun violence, and vice versa. [29] California has a new law that allows a family to take away gun rights for up to a year for a family member with known mental-health issues. [29] Just how safe is this technology, especially when it is linked to something as deadly as a loaded weapon? Aramatix's pistol has received heavy public opposition from the NRA and gun rights activists in the U.S., and Moran discusses how the backlash stems from concern over legislation. [24] People hear of a neighbor losing a child to a gun accident, they adopt the technology, and make it the market standard within a short time. [25] This gun uses recognition technology enabling only an authorised user to fire it. [24] This toll is utterly unnecessary, for the technology to make childproof guns goes back more than a century. [25] TechKnow explores early earthquake detection systems and a new,'safer' gun with user-recognition technology. [24] Waiting periods and safety courses became mandatory for new gun owners and limits on the sale of ammunition were imposed. [51] I consider the Draconian gun control laws of France to be the most powerful factor in that massacre. [25] Shocked by the horrific magnitude of the massacre, Australian lawmakers passed sweeping new gun laws in a matter of days - 12 to be exact. [51] Gun laws are effective, but difficult to achieve in the current polarized political climate. [29] About one-third of all homes in America possess a handgun and there is no better predictive metric to reducing gun violence. [29] Beginning in the 1880s, Smith &amp; Wesson (whose gun was used in the Walmart killing) actually sold childproof handguns that required a lever to be depressed as the trigger was pulled. [25] No ordinary child under 8 years of age can possibly discharge it, Smith &amp; Wesson boasted at the time, and it sold half-a-million of these guns, but, today, it no longer offers that childproof option. [25] Guns kill more preschool-age children (about 80 a year) than police officers (about 50), according to the F.B.I. and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. [25] There is reason to believe that common ground can be found, such as the agreement achieved in 2009 between Washington Ceasefire and the National Rifle Association on taking gun rights away from people suffering from mental illness who are committed to a care facility for 30 days or more. [29] In a world with more technologically sophisticated guns, some kind of microchip might be installed in certain hunting rifles so that they only work at designated times in designated areas and perhaps then persons guilty of nonviolent felonies could be exempted from broad felon-in-possession prohibitions in order to be able to use these kinds of guns for sport. [25] As to the statistics of the use of guns, had the victims all been armed as they are in Switzerland and in Israel, there would be little gun violence. [25] Gun violence is like cancer, but it?s a public-health disease that other modern societies have addressed. [29] GUN violence is like cancer: It comes in many different varieties and there is no single panacea to eliminate it. [29] Washington Ceasefire is one of the oldest organizations dedicated to reducing gun violence. [23] Ralph Fascitelli and Jordan Royer are longtime board members of Washington Ceasefire, a 32-year-old nonprofit based in Seattle dedicated to reducing gun violence. [29] In this paranoid fantasy, once there is any kind of ability for the gun to communicate with computer networks, the new world order tyrants will be able to disarm the citizenry with the push of a button, rendering them helpless to repel the government's socialist Blank Panther jack-booted thugs. (Picture Obama's desk with a big red button in case of emergency, press to disable firearms of true patriots.) [25] When even a 17yearold kid can come up with a safer gun, why should the gun lobby be so hostile to the option of purchasing one? Something is amiss when we protect our children from toys that they might swallow, but not from firearms. [25] A 2015 study found that when guns are used to kill people in the United States, they are overwhelmingly used for murder rather than self-defense. [51] We envision an extensive public-health campaign on the same scale as the successful smoking campaign 50 years ago, aimed at getting the facts out on home gun ownership. [29] Mauch told the Post he resigned because he didn?t want to sue or attack the gun industry, but an Armatix attorney confirmed he was released for internal reasons. [28] Most importantly, perhaps, the legislation allocated $250 million for a gun buyback program, allowing for newly outlawed rifles and shotgun to be destroyed by the Australian government. [51] Canadians may not be huge on carrying guns, but when it comes to building insanely cool next-generation assault rifles, our government is leading the game. [30] The American gun death rate is almost 20 times that of other nations. [29] The smart gun will put more tools in soldiers? hands, but it?s unlikely computers will ever replace humans hands on the trigger. [22] We?re entering that age where computers are so smart there are tremendous benefits for reducing the amount of time it takes for soldier to respond, but that also means relying increasingly on computers, Dorn said. [22] In order to improve public safety, we need to do more to ensure smart and effective enforcement of our gun laws and make sure that criminals and other prohibited persons cannot get their hands on lost or stolen weapons. [33] The Attorney General convened a call with U.S. Attorneys around the country to direct federal prosecutors to continue to focus on smart and effective enforcement of our gun laws. [33] The state of New Jersey passed a unique law in 2002 forbidding the sale of non-personalized handguns beginning three years after the first personalized guns become available in the U.S. No other state has followed suit. [37] There has been a concern among some gun enthusiasts that the sale of this gun, the Armatix iP1, would activate the New Jersey law passed in 2002 forbidding the sale of non-personalized handguns in the state three years after the sale of the first personalized gun in the United States. [37] Canada did not invent the gun, nor do its citizens even have the constitutional right to carry one without a license, proper training and a thorough background check. [30] Some pro gun group leaders such as Alan Gottlieb of The Second Amendment Foundation are open minded about the topic. [23] Interviews with several beat police officers show a high daily for someone taking their gun and using it against them. [23] In 2008-2012, the report says, guns were used in 42,419 criminal homicides and only 1,108 justifiable homicides. [51] In 1998, the company's CEO, Ron Stewart, sparked outrage for implying that he supported a federal gun permit system, as well as required training for gun owners. [15] For gun enthusiasts, however, the New Jersey bill confirmed their worst fears: Gun-control types really were trying to force these expensive, newfangled, unproven devices down their throats. [19] Great thing for gun rights when you threaten to shoot somebody. [19] The departments shall, to the extent permitted by law, regularly (a) review the availability of the technology described in section 1, and (b) explore potential ways to further its use and development to more broadly improve gun safety. [52] States that have strong gun violence prevention laws and low per capita gun ownership are able to institute laws preventing gun violence precisely because gun owners don?t constitute a threat at the ballot box, the recent re-election of Connecticut?s Governor Dannell Malloy a case in point. [32] Do strong gun laws prevent gun violence or does the lack of gun violence and the lack of gun ownership make it easier to pass such laws? It?s a classic chicken-and-egg question but my state – Massachusetts – passed a very strong gun violence prevention law in 1998, and while the state now ranks near the bottom in gun violence rates today, it also ranked near the bottom before the 1998 law was passed. [32] Based on data from the CDC, the report appears to confirm a basic tenet of the gun-sense approach to gun violence, namely, that states with high rates of gun death rates have fewer gun violence prevention laws and tend to have higher per capita ownership of guns. [32] Of the 50 states, 31 rank at or above the national mean of 10.64 and the other 19 below, with the lowest 7 states being Hawaii and 6 Northeastern states which traditionally have the tightest laws and the lowest per-capita gun ownership rates. [32] The National Rifle Association has promoted paranoid if not entirely off-base views about gun safety technology in the past, even though there's an argument to be made that such technology would boost gun sales. [36] The Campaign to Stop Gun Violence and other groups, went online with a petition asking Pew to change the wording of their poll question because the current questi[... snipped ...]
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/ee84ee8e-827b-37d8-8501-c0512fc4d55a" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-06T15:51:39Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:05:50.132Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/2016/01/recent-research-on-smart-guns/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
