<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Home &gt; Precision Ag &gt; Better variable-rate management zones Better variable-rate management zones Indiana farmer uses new soil sensor technologies to improve zones and variable-rate opportunities. Jan 22, 2016 David Hest | Corn+Soybean Digest The new Veris U3000 includes two sensors that map organic matter and soil texture. A new tillage-mounted rig also is available. Photo: Veris Industries As variable-rate seeding programs have grown in popularity across the Corn Belt, Lynn Hindbaugh has held off on using the planter technology that he owns. His concern: Downside risks from poorly understood management zones. I have looked at variable-rate population maps, and I just didn't feel they were accurate enough to be confident in them, say Hindbaugh, who farms near Columbia City, in northeast Indiana. Lack of soil survey detail The main culprit, says Hindbaugh, is a poor understanding of management zones, due in part to soil surveys that don't have enough detail to stand up to precision seeding demands. That's especially important on his farm, which is rife with highly variable soils. We have had soil survey maps in this part of Indiana for 30 years now, and they have been a big help, he says. But they just aren't accurate enough. Hindbaugh hopes 2016 will be a breakout year, based on new, highly detailed soils maps. He hired a crop consultant to develop the maps on about 40% of his operation in fall 2015 using a soil evaluation rig that delineates soil types and organic matter. He plans to have soils mapped in his remaining fields in 2016 and 2017. I hope to dabble this year with variable-rate populations, he says. We'll see what we learn. RTK and old soil maps don't match The new soil maps were generated by Erich Eller of ForeFront Ag Solutions. He used a <NODE id="1783" />Veris Technologies<NODE id="1801" /> <NODE id="1802" />U3000<NODE id="1807" /> on-the-go soil sensor system. The system includes two sensors that map organic matter and soil texture. Like Hindbaugh, Eller says he has found that existing soil surveys lack the capability to make precision farming decisions. We have been running systems based on RTK that have sub-inch accuracy using maps that are plus or minus 5 acres, he says. So the technology has surpassed the old data. The U3000, which Eller pulls with a Gator, collects soil electrical conductivity (EC) readings that penetrate 2 feet into the rooting zone to delineate soil texture as it changes across a field. A dual-wavelength optical sensor measures soil color below the surface that correlates with organic matter. In addition to helping define productivity zones, the EC map helps Eller pinpoint soil samples used for variable-rate phosphorus, potassium and lime application programs. Having a detailed organic matter map is important as we look at variable-rate nitrogen and variable seeding rates, adds Eller. For every percent of organic matter, an extra 30 pounds of nitrogen is mineralized and it holds 25,000 gallons of water. That's equivalent to an inch of rain. Better data, more income » Discuss this Article 0
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/6c7663f6-4bad-3e33-87a6-c5c050f46bdd" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-22T17:01:17Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:16:12.626Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://cornandsoybeandigest.com/precision-ag/better-variable-rate-management-zones" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1783" endPos="1801" type="organization-company" surface="Veris Technologies" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1802" endPos="1807" type="product" surface="U3000" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="2" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
