<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Main / World / GST logjam: Naidu meets Sonia; seeks help to get bills passed GST logjam: Naidu meets Sonia; seeks help to get bills passed By Paul Elliott Jan 07, 2016 Parliamentary Affairs Minister Venkaiah Naidu also said the government was willing to bring forward the next parliament session to pass the proposed goods and services tax bill (GST) if Congress supports the measure. Regarding the Real Estate invoice, Naidu advised Gandhi that as determined by Congress and different events, the Bill was referred to a choose committee of Rajya Sabha and the federal government had accepted virtually all suggestions of the committee. Earlier, Prime Minister Narendra Modi had met Gandhi and former prime minister Manmohan Singh to discuss the session including the GST bill, but the meeting didn't help in the passage of the bill. Naidu later said that the Congress has said that they would discuss the matter within the party and get back to the government. Naidu conveyed that the government was ready for an early budget session if the parties agree. The next session is going to be extremely important. So, I am reasonably optimistic, as far as the next session is concerned, that we may be able to push it through, said Jaitley while addressing the officer trainees of the Indian Revenue Service on Sunday. The GST bill has been touted as the biggest tax reform since independence. The GST bill was not passed in the Winter Session of the Parliament amid the uproar over the National Herald controversy. The Constitution Amendment invoice to roll out GST is caught within the Rajya Sabha the place the ruling NDA doesn't have a majority of its personal. GST, which seeks to simplify and harmonise the indirect tax regime across the country with a single uniform rate, has been stuck for many years in a political gridlock. Leadership Toronto Raptors vs. Chicago Bulls - 1/3/16 NBA Pick, Odds, and Prediction Jan 07, 2016 After shooting less than 40 per cent themselves in their past two games, Toronto shot 45.7 per cent on Sunday. The Raptors aren't back at the Air Canada Centre until January 18, when they host the Brooklyn Nets. Suriya's 'Singam 3' is now 'S3' Jan 07, 2016 Six first look posters of Singam will be released today, and it has spread a huge wave of happiness among Suriya fans. The attempt to begin the first schedule in Kolkata was also cancelled due to bad weather conditions. Alabama chief justice orders halt to same-sex marriage licenses Jan 07, 2016 Some judges in Alabama have refused, since Obergefell , to issue same-sex marriage licenses. Supreme Court doesn't make law, the legislatures of the states and Congress do. Kerry says North Korea nuclear test 'highly provocative' Jan 07, 2016 Hydrogen bombs use a two-step process of fission and fusion that releases substantially more energy than an atomic bomb. North Korean nuke test https://t.co/zNW3xU9cZD shows danger of continuing feckless Obama/Clinton foreign policy. The latest on gadgets: Under Armour unveils fitness gadgets Jan 07, 2016 Some other big features at this year's CES are smart and electric auto technology, a virtual reality marketplace and 3D printing. To further the disucssion on innovative cars eight keynote speakers are expected to give a speech at the event, namely Dr. Small drones big at Consumer Electronics Show Jan 07, 2016 It's a belt that features smart sensor technology to track your health from waist size, to how much time you spend sitting down. The rapid advances in mobile processors has made it possible to produce sophisticated chips that use very little power cheaply. Trooper indicted in Sandra Bland traffic stop Jan 07, 2016 Bland was charged with assaulting a public servant after Encinia pulled her over for allegedly failing to signal a lane change. The video showed him shouting at Bland and failing to answer her when she asked numerous times why she was being arrested. Chevy Cruze Surprizes With a Hatch for Detroit [Auto Show Debut] Jan 07, 2016 An RS package will feature fog lamps as well as more aggressive front and rear fascias, rocker panels, and rear spoiler. The Hatch is focused on the higher end with the LT, Premier, and RS offerings. China lands flights on disputed island Jan 07, 2016 Whether China formally declares it or not, Fiery Cross Reef will function as a forward base military installation. Manila calls the reef Kagitingan, Hanoi refers to it as Da Chu Thap, and Beijing calls it Yongshu Jiao. Democratic Candidate Bernie Sanders Attacks Hillary Clinton in a Sharp Note Jan 07, 2016 When it comes to ATM fees, Sanders thinks it's unacceptable for Americans to pay $4 or $5 just to access their own money. The reality is that Congress doesn't regulate Wall Street , Sanders began. Greed is not good, he said .
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/b91b2cf6-7cc1-3e62-aedd-200a7a62a1b5" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-07T12:35:57Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:45:31.899Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://thevillagessuntimes.com/2016/01/07/gst-logjam-naidu-meets-sonia-seeks-help-to-get-bills-passed/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
