<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Big analog data of the future: From the edge to the enterprise Matej Kranj, Managing Director for ASEAN and ANZ, National Instruments | Feb. 10, 2016 Matej Kranj of National Instruments talks about how big data can benefit the manufacturing industry. This vendor-written piece has been edited by Executive Networks Media to eliminate product promotion, but readers should note it will likely favour the submitter's approach. The global big data analytics market for the test and measurement industry is projected to grow at a compound annual growth rate of 28.24 percent, or from US$421 million in 2014 to $2,401.7 million in 2021, according to a recently released report by Frost &amp; Sullivan. Seeing that more than 80 percent of the world's data is currently unstructured, this presents both challenges and opportunities. When applied to testing, big data analytics can reduce product development costs by almost 25 percent, operating costs by almost 20 percent, and maintenance costs by 50 percent. These benefits have led to the increased take up for big data analyst in the test and measurement industry over the past few years. In its Big Data and Analytics Core to Nex-Gen Manufacturing report, analyst firm IDC said 37 percent of Asia Pacific manufacturers in 2013 were already using Big Data and analytics technologies to improve production quality management in terms of cost reduction, increased productivity and attraction of new customers. Singapore has established itself as a global data management hub with more than 50 percent of the commercial carrier and carrier-neutral center space in Southeast Asia, making data analytics as an important growth sector. By the end of 2017, data analytics is expected to contribute S$1 billion in value-added to the Singapore economy. Elsewhere in the region, big data is also taking off. PLDT, a telecommunications and multimedia service provider in the Philippines recently unveiled its Big Data services in the country to help local enterprises advance their businesses through a range of digitally transformative solutions. With the proliferation of sensing and networking technologies, adding measurements to systems has never been easier and more cost-effective. In 2011 alone, more than 1.8 zettabyes of data were created and data is expected to increase 50 times by 2020; if companies don't have a sound data management strategy in place, a few years from now they'll be incapable of effectively dealing with and managing all of their data. Because of this, best-in-class measurement and analytics solutions must have two fundamental capabilities: (1) edge analytics and (2) smart enterprise management and analytics. Pushing Measurement Analytics to the Edge Over the past decade, the intelligence of data acquisition devices and <NODE id="2791" />sensors<NODE id="2798" /> has drastically increased and become more decentralised, with processing elements moving closer to the sensor. One look at the many examples of acquisition systems and nodes integrating the latest silicon and IP from companies like ARM, Intel, and Xilinx proves as much. But in addition to measurement devices getting smarter, <NODE id="3126" />smart sensors<NODE id="3139" /> have emerged that integrate the sensor, signal conditioning, embedded processing, and digital interface/bus into an extremely small package or system. Sign up for Computerworld eNewsletters .
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/3ab3d2b5-d7a0-3f0b-ac39-b2e25f172615" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-10T15:23:48Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:57:26.393Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.computerworld.com.sg/resource/applications/big-analog-data-of-the-future-from-the-edge-to-the-enterprise/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="2791" endPos="2798" type="product-class" surface="sensors" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="3126" endPos="3139" type="product-class" surface="smart sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
