<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Emerging Markets has Significantly Boosted the Photoelectric Sensors Market :Transparency Market Research Press Release - Jan 12, 2016 01:16 EST Photoelectric sensors are devices which are being utilized for detecting the shape, size, color, distance, presence or absence and any other attributes of the target entity. These devices utilize light for performing their designated task. A typical photoelectric sensor device generally consists of a light transmitter and a receiver. Infra-red light sources are used in general in these devices. The light is emitted by the transmitter towards the target and the reflected light beam is received by the photoe January 12, 2016 (Newswire.com) - Photoelectric sensors are devices which are being utilized for detecting the shape, size, color, distance, presence or absence and any other attributes of the target entity. These devices utilize light for performing their designated task. A typical photoelectric sensor device generally consists of a light transmitter and a receiver. Infra-red light sources are used in general in these devices. The light is emitted by the transmitter towards the target and the reflected light beam is received by the photoelectric receiver, thus activating the sensor output. Photoelectric Sensors are deemed to be the best substitutes for <NODE id="1319" />inductive proximity sensors<NODE id="1346" />. This is because photoelectric sensors can detect non-metal objects also, apart from their ability to function over long sensing distances. Only the optical components are present in photoelectric sensors used for remote sensing while the electronic components are generally contained in a control panel elsewhere. This is advantageous since the sensor can be developed with a minimalistic design while the controls can be designed to make it more accessible to the user. On the other hand, self contained photoelectric sensors are designed to contain both the optics and the electronic components together. These sensors are designed to perform the modulation, amplification, demodulation and other functions simultaneously. Advancement of technologies has led to decrease in size of these sensors while adding increasing embedded intelligence. The increasing demand for photoelectric sensors is mainly driven by their use in the automotive industry, food &amp; beverages and manufacturing industry. The increasing demand for information-based manufacturing and sensor-based data from production line machines are driving the demand for photoelectric sensors. Additionally data from certain industrial applications can be obtained systematically and cost effective manner only by deploying photoelectric sensors. Effectiveness of photoelectric sensors, in controlling the movement of products during the manufacturing process, has made them indispensable in manufacturing plants across all the sectors. The high economic growth coupled with increased automation of plants in emerging markets has significantly boosted the photoelectric sensors market. The market has also been boosted by increasing automation investments in US and Mexico which is again due to positive government initiatives. One of the biggest driver of this market is the advent of Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT). This is because IIoT performs analysis and decision support tasks for an organization by depending on sensor based measurements. Furthermore, the capability to function over long distances, decreasing size and increasing functionality among others has also positively impacted the market for photoelectric sensors. Lack of sensing capability of photoelectric sensors and lack of scope of product differentiation are major restraints for the photoelectric sensors market. Free Brochure Download : http://www.transparencymarketresearch.com/sample/sample.php?flag=B&amp;rep_id=8479 The global photoelectric sensors market can be segmented, based on functional types, into through beam, diffuse-reflective, retro-reflective and distance-settable. On the basis of end user, the market can be segmented into defense &amp; aerospace, healthcare, food &amp; beverages, automotive and others. Furthermore, photoelectric sensors market can be geographically segmented into North America, Europe, Asia-Pacific (APAC) and rest of the world. Some of the key companies leading the <NODE id="4289" />photoelectric sensors<NODE id="4310" /> market are <NODE id="4322" />Omron<NODE id="4327" /> (<NODE id="4329" />Japan<NODE id="4334" />), <NODE id="4337" />Rockwell Automation<NODE id="4356" /> (<NODE id="4358" />US<NODE id="4360" />), <NODE id="4363" />Schneider Electric<NODE id="4381" /> (<NODE id="4383" />France<NODE id="4389" />), <NODE id="4392" />Balluff Inc.<NODE id="4404" /> (<NODE id="4406" />US<NODE id="4408" />), <NODE id="4411" />Sick AG<NODE id="4418" /> (<NODE id="4420" />Germany<NODE id="4427" />), <NODE id="4430" />Keyence<NODE id="4437" /> (<NODE id="4439" />Japan<NODE id="4444" />), <NODE id="4447" />Hokuyo Automatic Co. Ltd.<NODE id="4472" /> (<NODE id="4474" />Japan<NODE id="4479" />), <NODE id="4482" />Takenaka Corporation<NODE id="4502" /> (<NODE id="4504" />Japan<NODE id="4509" />), <NODE id="4512" />Baumer Group<NODE id="4524" /> (<NODE id="4526" />Switzerland<NODE id="4537" />) and <NODE id="4543" />Contrinex<NODE id="4552" /> (<NODE id="4554" />Switzerland<NODE id="4565" />) among others. Transparency Market Research (TMR) is a market intelligence company, providing global business information reports and services. Our exclusive blend of quantitative forecasting and trends analysis provides forward-looking insight for thousands of decision makers. TMR’s experienced team of Analysts, Researchers, and Consultants, use proprietary data sources and various tools and techniques to gather, and analyze information. Our business offerings represent the latest and the most reliable information indispensable for businesses to sustain a competitive edge. Each TMR syndicated research report covers a different sector - such as pharmaceuticals, chemicals, energy, food &amp; beverages, semiconductors, med-devices, consumer goods and technology. These reports provide in-depth analysis and deep segmentation to possible micro levels. With wider scope and stratified research methodology, TMR’s syndicated reports thrive to provide clients to serve their overall research requirement.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/d51c3930-20df-3c6f-bf8c-4b658962a64b" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T14:50:58Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:56:08.966Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.newswire.com/news/emerging-markets-has-significantly-boosted-the-photoelectric-sensors-market" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1319" endPos="1346" type="product-class" surface="inductive proximity sensors" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="4289" endPos="4310" type="product-class" surface="photoelectric sensors" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="4322" endPos="4327" type="organization-company" surface="Omron" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="4329" endPos="4334" type="location" surface="Japan" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="4337" endPos="4356" type="organization-company" surface="Rockwell Automation" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="4358" endPos="4360" type="location" surface="US" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="4363" endPos="4381" type="organization-company" surface="Schneider Electric" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="4383" endPos="4389" type="location" surface="France" />
<Entity id="8" startPos="4392" endPos="4404" type="organization-company" surface="Balluff Inc." />
<Entity id="9" startPos="4406" endPos="4408" type="location" surface="US" />
<Entity id="10" startPos="4411" endPos="4418" type="organization-company" surface="Sick AG" />
<Entity id="11" startPos="4420" endPos="4427" type="location" surface="Germany" />
<Entity id="12" startPos="4430" endPos="4437" type="organization-company" surface="Keyence" />
<Entity id="13" startPos="4439" endPos="4444" type="location" surface="Japan" />
<Entity id="14" startPos="4447" endPos="4472" type="organization-company" surface="Hokuyo Automatic Co. Ltd." />
<Entity id="15" startPos="4474" endPos="4479" type="location" surface="Japan" />
<Entity id="16" startPos="4482" endPos="4502" type="organization-company" surface="Takenaka Corporation" />
<Entity id="17" startPos="4504" endPos="4509" type="location" surface="Japan" />
<Entity id="18" startPos="4512" endPos="4524" type="organization-company" surface="Baumer Group" />
<Entity id="19" startPos="4526" endPos="4537" type="location" surface="Switzerland" />
<Entity id="20" startPos="4543" endPos="4552" type="organization-company" surface="Contrinex" />
<Entity id="21" startPos="4554" endPos="4565" type="location" surface="Switzerland" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="22" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="3" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="23" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="5" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="24" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="7" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="25" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="9" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="26" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="11" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="27" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="13" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="28" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="15" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="14" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="29" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="17" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="16" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="19" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="18" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="CompanyHeadquarters">
<Entity id="21" label="headquarter" />
<Entity id="20" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="32" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="12" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="33" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="10" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="34" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="35" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="6" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="36" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="16" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="37" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="8" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="38" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="20" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="39" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="18" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="40" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="41" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="42" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="14" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
