<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2016 Golden Mousetrap Awards Name Finalists in 16 Categories of Product Design and Manufacturing Excellence Winners to be Announced February 9 during Awards Ceremony in Anaheim at America's Most Comprehensive Advanced Manufacturing Event January 28, 2016 -- SANTA MONICA, Calif. , Jan. 28, 2016 /PRNewswire/ --Design News today announces the finalists of the 14th annual Golden Mousetrap Awards, a program celebrating the American people, companies, and technologies that are driving progress in product design and manufacturing. The Golden Mousetrap Awards recognize new technologies and cutting-edge products within 16 areas of excellence, as well as two special honors for the Rising Engineering Star and Gadget Freak of the Year (in partnership with Allied Electronics). The winners of each category will be honored during a special awards ceremony, celebrating the next generation of talent in the engineering and manufacturing industry. The awards ceremony will be held February 9, 2016 at the Anaheim Convention Center, hosted alongside UBM's annual advanced manufacturing event, which includes the MD&amp;M West, ATX West, Electronics West, WestPack, Pacific Design &amp; Manufacturing, and PLASTEC West events and conferences, being held at the Anaheim Convention Center February 9-11, 2016 . For more information, visit: http://goldenmousetraps.designnews.com . The 2016 Golden Mousetrap Finalist Products and Manufacturers include (alphabetical by category): Automation &amp; Control Controllers Allen- Bradley ControlLogix 5580 Controller Allen Bradley Micro PLC platform Maxim Integrated ESCON module 24/2 Maxon Precision Motors MCST 3601 Motion Controller for Stepper Motors MICROMO Vision 700 Unitronics Inc. Automation &amp; Control Drives Rexroth IndraDrive Mi cabinet-free Supply and Mains Module Bosch Rexroth Corporation AKD-N Multi- Axis Servo System Kollmorgen Automation &amp; Control Fluid Power Technologies Dry Break M3 Quick Disconnect Beswick Engineering Rexroth Hagglunds CA 10-40 Hydraullic Bosch Rexroth Corporation Automation &amp; Control Industrial Network Technologies (e.g. I/O, Ethernet, Wireless) Ha-VIS preLink HARTING Inc. of North America Radioline Wireless Platform Phoenix Contact USA RZ/ T1 Real-Time Processor Renesas Electronics America Automation &amp; Control Motors and Mechanical Motion Devices QNPHD Aerotech, Inc. FDM0620 Stepper Motor MICROMO Ultra EC Brushless DC Mini Motors Portescap ClearPath All-in-One Brushless Motors Teknic, Inc. <NODE id="2463" />Automation &amp; Control Sensors<NODE id="2491" />, Vision Systems, Feedback Devices, &amp; Peripherals MAXREFDES79# Maxim Integrated BAW <NODE id="2575" />MEMS Gyroscope rate sensor<NODE id="2601" /> Qualtre, Inc. Uprox3 Turck Inc. Design Tools Hardware &amp; Software- Analysis &amp; Calculation Software Atmel START Atmel Corporation Rockwell Software Studio 5000 Software Rockwell Automation WEBENCH Advanced Tools Texas Instruments Design Tools Hardware &amp; Software- CAD/PDM/PLM Software Arena PLM 2015 Arena Solutions Omnify Empower PLM (Product Lifecycle Management) Omnify Software Electronics &amp; Test Analog/ Power Management/ Control Allen-Bradley Bulletin 1494U Visible Blade Disconnect Switch Allen Bradley Atmel SmartConnect Bluetooth Smart BTLC1000 Atmel NDM3ZS-90 CUI Inc. EZ-PD CCG2 Type-C Cable Controller Cypress Semiconductor Corp. ISL8117 Synchronous Step-DownPWM Controller Intersil Corporation ISL8273M 80A Single Channel Digital PMBus Step-Down Power Module Intersil Corporation MCP9600 Thermocouple-Conditioning Integrated Circuit Microchip Technology Inc. Electronics &amp; Test Components, Hardware &amp; Interconnects Han F+B HARTING Inc. of North America XGD Series XTREME-GUARD ESD Suppressors Littelfuse, Inc. 88 MW300/302 Wi-Fi Microcontroller SoC Marvell MAX9286 Maxim Integrated Nvidia Shield Android TV Nvidia Corporation Extremelife-60 cable Turck Inc. 221 Series Splicing Connectors WAGO Corporation Electronics &amp; Test Embedded Computing/Processing BCM47748, GNSS for IoT and wearables Broadcom Corporation (BRCM) ISL29501 Time-of-Flight Signal Processing IC Intersil Corporation 88E6390X Gigabit Ethernet switch Marvell 88PA6270 Printer SoC Marvell Renesas Autonomous Driving Development Platform Renesas Electronics America SimpleLink ultra-low power wireless MCU platform Texas Instruments Electronics &amp; Test Test &amp; Measurement M8196A 92 GSa/S Arbitrary Waveform Generator Keysight Technologies Inc. 81606A Turnable Laser Source, High- Power and Lowest SSE, Top-Line Keysight Technologies Inc. Wireless Test System National Instruments Materials &amp; Assembly 3D-Printing &amp; Rapid Prototyping, Materials, Tools &amp; Services AIRWOLF 3D AXIOM Airwolf 3D Urethane Foam Casting with 3D Printing Stratasys Direct Manufacturing Materials &amp; Assembly Fastening, Joining &amp; Assembly Components AS9100C Custom Universal Joints for Aircraft High Lift Actuation Systems (HLAS) Belden Universal Adhesives Master Bond Zapnik Sloan Technical Services Materials &amp; Assembly Materials Processing TenderPac Sealpac USA , LLC
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/5dc0bd0e-ba0c-385f-823b-78ed32c427a0" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-29T19:00:26Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:10:39.882Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.consumerelectronicsnet.com/article/2016-Golden-Mousetrap-Awards-Name-Finalists-in-16-Categories-of-Product-Design-and-Manufacturing-Excellence-4267109" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="2463" endPos="2491" type="product-class" surface="Automation &amp; Control Sensors" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="2575" endPos="2601" type="product" surface="MEMS Gyroscope rate sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
