<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Jump to Navigation Featured Company Featured Company Featured Company Featured Company Itron, Landis+Gyr, Oracle, and Siemens eMeter Score Highest in Assessment of Meter Data Management Systems Vendors, According to Navigant Research Business Wire Tuesday, January 12th 2016 Several leading meter data management system vendors are expected to evolve to offer multivariate systems, report finds A new Leaderboard Report from Navigant Research examines the strategy and execution of 11 leading meter data management systems (MDMSs) vendors, providing industry participants with an objective assessment of these companies’ relative strengths and weaknesses in the global MDMS market. With billions of data points logged each day from more than 500 million installed smart electric meters, the demand for enhanced MDMSs is growing. Competitive vendors in this market are now investing in major upgrades, offering data analytics and enhanced support for utility operations as well as advanced capabilities. Click to tweet : According to a new Leaderboard Report from Navigant Research, Itron, Landis+Gyr, Oracle, and Siemens eMeter lead the global MDMS market in terms of strategy and execution. 'These players are well-established, often managing millions of smart meter deployments with increasingly advanced meter data management (MDM) platforms,' says Paige Leuschner, research associate with Navigant Research. 'Itron is entrenched in this market with its MDM contracts and innovative product roadmap, though Landis+Gyr, Oracle, and Siemens eMeter are all in close pursuit.' Though leading vendors are working to broaden their MDMS offerings, according to the report, several are also looking past the concept of MDM altogether in favor of multivariate data management systems. These systems are expected to allow data from distributed <NODE id="1837" />sensors<NODE id="1844" />, smart inverters, appliances, and other devices to be collected, organized, managed, and analyzed alongside smart meter data. The report, Navigant Research Leaderboard Report: Meter Data Management Systems , examines the strategy and execution of 11 vendors that offer MDMSs and rates them on 12 criteria. Each company considered in this report has a solid offering with core MDMS capabilities. Vendors are differentiated by additional platform features, MDMS customers, international marketing and sales, and the vision, strategy, and roadmap for their MDM solution. Using Navigant Research’s proprietary Leaderboard methodology, vendors are profiled, rated, and ranked with the goal of providing industry participants with an objective assessment of these companies’ relative strengths and weaknesses in the global MDMS market. An Executive Summary of the report is available for free download on the Navigant Research website . About Navigant Research Contacts Navigant Research Lindsay Lorenz, +1-303-493-5477 lindsay.lorenz@navigant.com or Megan Maupin, +1-312-583-5703 megan.maupin@navigant.com Copyright (2016) Business Wire. All Rights Reserved.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/de6ed5db-0bd6-3518-83c4-942ca7ad8f4c" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T13:47:07Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:59:41.766Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.virtual-strategy.com/2016/01/12/itron-landisgyr-oracle-and-siemens-emeter-score-highest-assessment-meter-data-management-" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1837" endPos="1844" type="product-class" surface="sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
