<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>News <NODE id="5" />AllSeen Alliance<NODE id="21" /> Continues Membership Growth as AllJoyn(R) <NODE id="64" />IoT Technology<NODE id="78" /> Gains Major Market Momentum Marketwired | Wednesday, 06 January 2016 04:04 (EST) LAS VEGAS, NV -- (Marketwired) -- 01/06/16 -- CES 2016 -- The AllSeen Alliance , a cross-industry collaboration advancing the Internet of Things (IoT) through an open source software project, today announced 14 new members, a diverse group that represents an international semiconductor leader, global product manufacturers, and several start-ups and software solutions providers from around the world. The <NODE id="567" />AllSeen Alliance<NODE id="583" /> continues to experience tremendous year-over-year growth with <NODE id="646" />200<NODE id="649" /> members to-date since forming in 2013. The AllSeen Alliance is participating at CES 2016 ( Sands Expo Center booth 71836 ) showcasing Day in the Life smart home scenarios with AllJoyn Certified and AllJoyn-enabled products from members Electrolux, LG, Argenox, Heaven Fresh Canada, Initial State, EnOcean Alliance, POWERTECH, QEO (Technicolor) FreeWings Technologies, Philips Sonicare, Two Bulls among others. Click here to learn more about members exhibiting in the CES AllSeen Alliance Pavilion. Nearly two dozen products from wide-ranging members have earned AllJoyn Certification, with many on display at CES; click here for details on this news. AllJoyn® is making huge inroads, with more than 200 million products in market, and at the same time, the AllSeen Alliance continues with double digit membership growth, said Philip DesAutels, Senior Director, IoT, AllSeen Alliance. Global manufacturers like Johnson Controls, Hager Group and NXP Semiconductors are investing in AllJoyn, and we look forward to their technology and leadership contributions. For example, as a show of support, Hager Group has already stepped up to help with the Alliance's marketing and branding strategy. Johannes Hauck, Corporate Business Environment at Hager Group, is the new marketing committee co-chair effective Jan. 1, 2016. He will serve alongside Benoit Joly, Senior Vice President, Connected Home at Technicolor, who returns for a second year. Click here for Hager Group's news on joining the AllSeen Alliance. More about the new members: Product Manufacturing Companies Hager Group is a leading supplier of solutions and services for electrical installations in residential, commercial and industrial buildings. Its range of solutions and services extends from energy distribution to cable management and from security systems to building automation. Johnson Controls is a global diversified technology and industrial leader serving customers in more than 150 countries. They currently have 170,000 employees create quality products, services and solutions to optimize energy and operational efficiencies of buildings; lead-acid automotive batteries and advanced batteries for hybrid and electric vehicles; and interior systems for automobiles. Kidde is a leading manufacturer of residential smoke alarms, carbon monoxide (CO) alarms and fire extinguishers, and has been delivering advanced fire-safety technology for nearly 100 years. With the introduction of its RemoteLync line of connected home solutions, Kidde offers homeowners an accessible, easier and smarter way to know about a potential emergency when they are away. NXP Semiconductors creates solutions that enable secure connections for a smarter world. Building on its expertise in high-performance mixed signal electronics, NXP is driving innovation in the areas of connected car, security, portable &amp; wearable devices, and the Internet of Things. IoT Platforms and Solution Companies ABHRIO is a product development house with a focus on the IoT space. ABHRIO's two products are in beta -- one around home automation and security, and the second is a complete iBeacon-based platform designed using proximity-based mobile technology. Affectio is a human data analytics platform that uses mobile, wearables, and IoT to quantify users' emotion, cognition, behavior, and context in real-time and encourages repeat engagement through virtual currency and rewards to engender positive habits. Affectio helps users to better know themselves and others around them while feeling more connected. Argenox Technologies provides full wireless connectivity solutions to OEMs and companies looking to create the next generation of IoT products. Its expertise in Hardware, Software, Apps, and Manufacturing enables companies to create production-ready designs faster and better. Avempace is a fast-growing connected technologies and engineering services provider. The company specializes in IoT product development (electronics, software, mobile applications design and testing) and has its headquarters in Nabeul, Tunisia. CastleOS is a home automation controller featuring universal device support that breaks down barriers between various smart devices and protocols, providing a powerful integrated user experience. CastleOS makes advanced home automation, intelligence, and voice control easy to use and available to all homes. Elite Crest Technologies specializes in development of sports and movement enhancement applications using IOT platforms. The company is currently developing a smart clothing solution that tracks and improves sports movement, using various sensor technologies, as well as delivers actionable insights using Big Data analytics. NetBeast is a hardware independent universal software that allows technology to interact regardless of brand or technology. Netbeast builds on their developer community to grow on their support of IoT products through a scalable API that allows developers to declare new ways of connecting with brands and protocols. Ready for Sky is a high-tech company dedicated to bringing Smart technologies into people's everyday life to make it easier and more comfortable. Ready for Sky connects various devices to the Internet adding new attractive features for end users as well as for manufacturers of these devices. Smart Home Companies Cozify is a wireless smart home hub that is easy to set-up, use and expand. Cozify Hub connects smart devices from different manufacturers into one seamlessly working entity. Cozify's intuitive rule engine makes it very easy for end user to take control of their home. Evey Innovation is a home automation system company. By focusing on ease of use and installation, Evey Innovation is reinventing what it means to own a Smart Home. About The AllSeen Alliance The AllSeen Alliance is a nonprofit open source consortium dedicated to driving the widespread adoption of products, systems and services that support the Internet of Things with an open, universal development framework that is supported by a vibrant ecosystem and thriving technical community. The Alliance manages and advances an industry-supported collaborative open source software connectivity and services framework based on AllJoyn technology accepting contributions from premier members, community members and the open source community. This secure and programmable software connectivity and services framework enables companies and individuals to create interoperable products that can discover, connect and interact directly with other nearby devices, systems and services regardless of transport layer, device type, platform, operating system or brand. For more information, please visit: <NODE id="7347" />http://www.allseenalliance.org<NODE id="7377" /> . The AllSeen Alliance is a Collaborative Project at The Linux Foundation. Linux Foundation Collaborative Projects are independently funded software projects that harness the power of collaborative development to fuel innovation across industries and ecosystems. www.linuxfoundation.org . Source: AllSeen Alliance DISCLOSURE: The views and opinions expressed in this article are those of the authors, and do not represent the views of equities.com . Readers should not consider statements made by the author as formal recommendations and should consult their financial advisor before making any investment decisions. To read our full disclosure, please go to: http://www.equities.com/disclaimer You have to be logged in to leave a comment.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/b513ca68-1484-389b-b6e9-969fdbd6b795" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-06T15:31:34Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:44:00.614Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.equities.com/news/allseen-alliance-continues-membership-growth-as-alljoyn-r-iot-technology-gains-major-market-momentum" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="5" endPos="21" type="organization-company" surface="AllSeen Alliance" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="64" endPos="78" type="industry" surface="IoT Technology" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="567" endPos="583" type="organization-company" surface="AllSeen Alliance" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="646" endPos="649" type="number" surface="200" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="7347" endPos="7377" type="url" surface="http://www.allseenalliance.org" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="5" NAME="CompanyIndustry">
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="1" label="industry" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="6" NAME="CompanyNumEmployees">
<Entity id="3" label="num_employees" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="7" NAME="CompanyWebsite">
<Entity id="0" label="website" />
<Entity id="4" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
