<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Latest Report On Global Proximity - Displacement <NODE id="49" />Sensors<NODE id="56" /> Market By Grand View Research Suggest Market Growth At 9% CAGR To 2022 January 15, 2016 -- Grand View Research, Inc. - Market Research And Consulting. GrandViewResearch.com has announced the addition of Global Proximity-Displacement Sensors Market Analysis And Segment Forecasts To 2022 Market Research report to their Database Proximity sensors detect the presence of nearby objects without physical contact. They are renowned for their smartphone applications wherein accidental taps are detected on the touch screen while receiving a call. Displacement sensors track the displacement between two objects. Demand for these sensors in factories and process automation systems will propel the proximity-displacement sensors market. Full research report on Global Proximity sensors detectMarket Analysis: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/proximity-displacement-sensors-market The market is projected to exceed USD 6 billion by 2022. It would exhibit a growth rate, close to 9%, from 2015 to 2022 (forecast period). Incorporation of these sensors in automobiles and security &amp; infotainment systems is the major market driver. Rising smartphone trends and process automation in industries are also anticipated to ensure expansion of the <NODE id="1309" />proximity-displacement sensors<NODE id="1339" /> market. The high costs of these sensors can challenge the market. Inductive, capacitive, photoelectric, magnetic, ultrasonic, and LVDT (Linear Variable Differential Transformer) are the market products. <NODE id="1543" />Photoelectric sensors<NODE id="1564" /> earned USD 1.2 billion in 2014. Ultrasonic would undergo the fastest growth in the future. Commercial availability &amp; adoption of these sensors will be a major factor for the rapid growth of this product. Ultrasonic is expected to garner revenues surpassing USD 290 million by 2020, at a CAGR of around 21%. Request for sample of this research report: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/proximity-displacement-sensors-market/request Applications of the proximity-displacement sensors market include elevators, <NODE id="2090" />parking sensors<NODE id="2105" />, elevators, roller coasters, conveyors, vibration monitoring systems, ground proximity warning systems, smartphones, and anti-aircraft warfare. Parking sensors led the market in 2014. Installation of this application by original equipment manufacturers (OEMs) in automobiles makes it the highest earning segment. The end users comprise automotives, pharmaceuticals, manufacturing, construction, process automation, and food &amp; beverages. Construction is expanding due to implementation of proximity-displacement sensors in elevators &amp; escalators. It will display significant growth compared to others. North America led the proximity-displacement sensors market in 2014, followed by Europe. Automotive, construction, and food &amp; beverages industries are the key regional driver. The rising economies of Brazil, Argentina, and Mexico in Latin America would result in rapid regional growth. Prominent players of the global market consist of OMRON Corporation, Pepperl+Fuchs GmbH, Sharp Corporation, Honeywell International Inc., and Eaton Corporation. Increasing rash driving and road accidents also drive demand for the <NODE id="3223" />aforementioned sensors<NODE id="3245" />. Furthermore, demand for wearable instruments steers market incomes. View more reports of this category by Grand View Research at: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry/sensors-and-controls About Grand View Research Grand View Research, Inc. is a U.S. based market research and consulting company, registered in the State of California and headquartered in San Francisco. Thecompany provides syndicated research reports, customized research reports, and consulting services. To help clients make informed business decisions, we offer market intelligence studies ensuring relevant and fact-based research across a range of industries, from technology to chemicals, materials and healthcare. Web: www.grandviewresearch.com Media Contact Company Name: Grand View Research, Inc. Contact Person: Sherry James, Corporate Sales Specialist - U.S.A. Email: sales@grandviewresearch.com Phone: 1-415-349-0058, Toll Free: 1-888-202-9519 Address:28 2nd Street, Suite 3036 City: San Francisco State: California Country: United States Website: http://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/proximity-displacement-sensors-market Source: ABNewswire Page: 1 Related Keywords:Business, Electronics &amp; Semiconductors, Manufacturing &amp; Industry, Technology, Source:Copyright (c) AB Digital, Inc. All Rights Reserved DMO TEXT LINKS (Click here to place a textlink on this site) This advertisement will close in seconds... Our Privacy Policy --- @ Copyright, 2015 Digital Media Online, All Rights Reserved Webmaster Privacy .
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/f8de2ab8-d843-31d5-a2bf-4c34bb8f9838" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-16T12:07:37Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:09:46.646Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.itbusinessnet.com/articles/viewarticle.jsp?id=4248672&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Ibn-ItBusinessNet-news+%28IT+Business+and+Technology+News%29" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="49" endPos="56" type="product-class" surface="Sensors" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1309" endPos="1339" type="product-class" surface="proximity-displacement sensors" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1543" endPos="1564" type="product-class" surface="Photoelectric sensors" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="2090" endPos="2105" type="product-class" surface="parking sensors" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="3223" endPos="3245" type="product-class" surface="aforementioned sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
