<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>NCV wrote: skeys wrote: NCV wrote: Personally I could not give a dam about equivalence. I know full well how to compare systems I have used M43 right up to 5x4 without problems. It is the arrogance of expression and the “I ‘m so more intelligent than you” attitude that causes lots of us to respond “badly” to these guys. If you could care less, and you are not the DPR member being corrected, why do you respond? Steve Because in the main the gist of these threads is to tell us our favoured system is lacking. mFT is far from lacking. In fact, I consider it the better choice, by far, than FF for the vast majority. More to the point, I think any of the excellent 1 systems out there (RX100, RX10, FZ1000, GX3, GX5, etc.) represent, by far, the best solution for the majority (save those that are best served with cell phones, which is the true majority). But for anyone that thinks there's an advantage of the 40-150 / 2.8 over the 40-150 / 4-5.6, well... The arrogance of these guys is just too much to pass by. Funny you, of all people, should say that. Because I think the distorted way the information is presented leads to confusion and misunderstanding of the basic principles of photography. I think it is just to post correctives. When I asked you : Let's play together. I say that 300 / 4 on mFT is equivalent to 600 / 8 on FF because they have the same [diagonal] angle of view, the same DOF (and diffraction) for the same perspective, framing, display size, viewing distance, and visual acuity, and put the same total amount of light on the sensor for a given scene and exposure time. Do you agree or disagree? If you agree, then I fail to see why we're having this conversation. If you disagree, then I fail to see how you're a qualified engineer. Either way, it looks like I fail. You ducked and deflected. If people did not argue against the simple facts of Equivalence, as you do (I remind you, once again, of your blunder on DOF in Tim's deleted thread), and as the chief editor of DPR noted : Firstly, most of these 'troll threads' that I've seen are started by people who refuse to accept simple scientific facts, and who get aggressive when their faulty reasoning is challenged. It's not trolling to respond (as i did) to threads started to suggest that my writers are wrong about equivalent aperture by pointing to the actual science that proves they've misunderstood. Well, that really tells the whole story. As requested I posted some pictures. You can see some more on my site. I think you, and every one else, would be better served, then, posting pics and helping others out with how to use their equipment than trolling Equivalence threads with self-harming post after self-harming post. But, you are free to do as you like, and I will not complain one way or another.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/c20b09de-9444-33d8-ac4d-f1620eecfff4" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-11T02:20:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:48:54.391Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.dpreview.com/forums/thread/3949433?page=4" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
