<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 11, 2016 C O N T E N T S: Image Courtesy: link: http://www.microsemi.com/applications/industrial/hmi author: microsemi.com description: Human Machine Interface KEY TOPICS ALISO VIEJO, Calif., July 28, 2015 /PRNewswire/ - Microsemi Corporation (Nasdaq: MSCC ),a leading provider of semiconductor solutions differentiated by power, security, reliability andperformance and Mikroprojekt, an IP design house specializing in FPGA IP cores and systems for display, video and graphics applications, today announced the availability of Mikroprojekt's compact and high performance human machine interface (HMI) platform. [1] Through our ecosystem, customers may also access a compact and high performance human machine interface (HMI) platform from Mikroprojekt. [2] Advantech offers a wide range of human machine interface (HMI) products including Automation Panel PCs (TPC and PPC), Industrial Monitors (FPM) and Intelligent Operator Panels (WebOP) which are designed for segmented automation applications to be applied in different industries. [3] WebOP Designer is powerful yet intuitive software to create total solutions for WebOP series Human Machine Interface products. [3] All of the new human machine interface(HMI) product support Advantech iDoor Technology which is a brand-new design concept that utilizes the mini PCIe format, by using standardized modules and interfaces, iDoor Technology gives customers the flexibility to configure the various I/O requirements based on different applications. [3] Human Machine Interface Magelis This website uses cookies to store information on your computer. [4] Plexpack recently teamed up with B&amp;R to create a new human machine interface for Emplex Bag Sealers. [5] Designed for industrial, home appliances, and office equipment employing a human machine interface (HMI), the RZ/G Series extends the capabilities of the successful RZ/A Series MPUs–which supports 2D graphics at up to WXGA resolution–to deliver high-end performance in applications such as image processing, video sensing, and 3-D graphics and multimedia at up to 1080p resolution. [6] NASHVILLE, TN - (Marketwired) - 05/19/15 - INSIGHTS 2015 - Epicor Software Corporation, a global leader in business software solutions for retail, manufacturing, distribution, and services organizations, today announced availability of its next-generation Epicor Mattec manufacturing execution system ( MES ) featuring a new high-performance embedded human machine interface (HMI) to support improved shop floor operator productivity and responsiveness. [7] When it comes to product development in the Internet of Things (IoT), design engineers strive to develop functionalities that enhance the user experience in Human Machine Interfaces (HMI). [8] The system?s unique Human Machine Interface (HMI) can be accessed on the front of the fluid delivery box or remotely via a touch screen tablet. [9] SMART Cortex-A5-based family, adding a 720p resolution hardware video decoder to target Human Machine Interface (HMI), control panel and IoT applications when high performance display capability is required. [10] NASHVILLE, TN –(Marketwired – May 19, 2015) – INSIGHTS 2015 - Epicor Software Corporation, a global leader in business software solutions for retail, manufacturing, distribution, and services organizations, today announced availability of its next-generation Epicor Mattec manufacturing execution system ( MES ) featuring a new high-performance embedded human machine interface (HMI) to support improved shop floor operator productivity and responsiveness. [11] Latest Trends in HMI Software Will Push for Growth This global study covers the global human machine interface (HMI) software and services market. [12] Utilizing open and standard interfaces with the highest degree of features, functionality and flexibility built-in standard, AIS's Compact HMI Systems are optimized to meet an extremely broad range of human machine interface requirements in a multitude of industries and applications. [13] Packaging solutions company, Plexpack Corp., announces new bag sealing models equipped with a high performance Human Machine Interface; their HMI programming now simplifies and monitors all controls. [14] Jayco is an AS9100C certified supplier of high performance Human Machine Interface (HMI) solutions. [15] Plexpack Corporation announced today multiple new Emplex Bag Sealer models with a high performance Human Machine Interface (HMI). [14] As today's industrial control and automation products demand higher performance, richer human machine interfaces (HMI) and assured security on untrusted networks, device manufacturers are moving to new faster processors with integrated acceleration units devoted to 3D graphics, cryptography and industrial communication protocols. [16] Nextion is a Seamless Human Machine Interface (HMI) solution that provides a control and visualisation interface between a human and a process, machine, application or appliance. [17] The global human machine interface market is segmented on the basis of product type, application, and geography. [18] Touchscreens or displays, industrial PCs, interface software, and various other controllers are the main types of human machine interface. [18] High demand for industrial automation coupled with greater focus on efficiency and mobility is a prominent factor that fuels the demand for human machine interface. [18] The significance of human machine interface lies in industrial automation, which aims at managing and instructing large data sets. [18] Robust performance of the manufacturing industry is a key factor that drives the global human machine interface market. [18] One of the areas where improvements can have significant impacts in this pursuit is quite literally staring them in the face; the human machine interface used to control and operate these systems. [19] The prominent areas of application in the human machine interface market are automotive, oil and gas, aerospace, mining and metals, healthcare, pharmaceuticals, food and beverages, packaging, defense, and others. [18] As the name suggests, the interface between an operator and a machine is known as human machine interface. [18] Human machine interface keypads include the electrical switch contacts, support means for the electrical switch contacts, interconnecting circuitry, and often electro-magnetic interference (EMI) or electro-static discharge (ESD) shields. [20] It is anticipated that the global human machine interface market will expand at a 10.4% CAGR during the forecast period. [18] COMPLETE CONTROL OF THE PRODUCTION LINE. YOU CAN RELY ON TE. The HMI serves as the interface between the operating system of an automated production plant and a human oper- ator and as such is a core element in the overall production system. [21] ABSTRACT Highly integrated SoCs using Zynq-7000 All Programmable SoC (AP SoC) technology can be complemented with a highly eff icient, scalable human machine interface (HMI) solution for industrial, scientif ic, and medical applications. [22] The dearth of HMI designs and high cost associated with the installation of HMIs are restricting the market.Touchscreens or displays, industrial PCs, interface software, and various other controllers are the main types of human machine interface. [23] Nematron ( www.nematron.com ) provides state-of-the-art Industrial PC, Monitor, and Human Machine Interface (HMI) products that require high levels of reliability, ruggedness, and longevity to a range of customers in the industrial automation industry. [24] Depending on the industry, this visualization tool is referred to as a user interface (UI) or a human machine interface (HMI). [25] The project team attended a number of workshops addressing high performance human machine interfaces (HMI) and situation awareness. [26] We designed the system to be flexible in coordinating the correction requests for the human machine interface (HMI) as well as the processing. [27] Pepperl+Fuchs leads the industry in human machine interface industrial monitors with VisuNet solutions. [28] Magelis HMI GTU is modular touch screen machine interface that provides superior flexibility and ease of use without compromising performance or openness. [29] Examples of automation are schemes to reduce throughput, trip to minimum firing in furnaces, grade switching, etc. FIGURE 2 Plant operating conditions and corresponding activities of the panel operator 3.4 CENTRALISED HMI The DCS interface shall be the centralised interface for all control and monitoring systems and subsystems, which they include ODS, optimisation, IPS, FGS, tank gauging systems, machine monitoring system, QMIs and CCTV. NOTES: 1. [30] HMI is the main interface between the human operator and the embedded device under control. [22] Many embedded systems need an integrated visual HMI to display real-time information about the processes under PL control, providing high-level interactivity between the human operator and the machine. [22] The panel also features an Allen-Bradley PanelView? Plus 1000 human-machine interface (HMI) for operator access to machine information. [31] INTRODUCTION 1.1 SCOPE This is a new DEP which specifies requirements and gives recommendations for the proper design of the Human-Machine Interface (HMI) of the plant monitoring and control systems to reduce human errors in the operation of the plant. [30] POSSIBLY USEFUL Based on Microsemi's SmartFusion ? 2 system-on-chip (SoC) field programmable gate array (FPGA) devices, the highly-integrated kit provides an easy-to-use platform to develop HMI solutions with touch screen displays for use across a wide range of industrial and building automation, digital signage, vending machine, medical, automotive and appliance applications. [2] Advantech offers operator panels including WebOP-2000T and WebOP-3000T series that come with RISC processors to satisfy the stringent standards required in the automation market, With support for over 450 PLC industrial communication protocols can fulfill the needs of different applications and by bundling WebOP Designer with both models lets the operator panels become a control HMI for flexible system integration. [3] HMIs enable control, management and/or visualization of device processes and can range from simple inputs on a touch display to control panels for highly complex industrial automation systems. [2] HMIs can be found in multiple locations such as portable handheld devices, on machines, centralized control rooms, as well as factory floor machine and process control. [2] The final class of HMI control screens is high performance screens. [32] Mikroprojekt's high performance HMI solution demonstrates the accelerated adoption of SmartFusion2 as we continue to expand Microsemi's collaborations with design houses catering to emerging applications and markets. [1] Based on Microsemi's SmartFusion 2 system-on-chip (SoC) field programmable gate array (FPGA) devices, the highly-integrated kit provides an easy-to-use platform to develop HMI solutions with touch screen displays. [1] The kit offers a compact hardware platform with add-on video input support, IP cores designed for high performance HMI touch screen display and an easy-to-use WYSIWYG GUI editor tool with pre-designed HMI templates. [1] In the world of digital controls, the visual portion of the human-machine interface, or HMI, is typically a configurable, electronic flat panel display. [32] Vijeo XD empowers Magelis HMIs and iPCs to provide a unique user experience. [4] For more information on Microsemi's products and solutions for HMI, visit www.microsemi.com/applications/industrial/hmi. [1] Contact your local Microsemi sales office today to find the right technologies and products for your HMI designs. [2] The design of the Human-Machine Interaction (HMI) plays a critical role in determining the operator's ability to effectively manage the operation, particularly when faced with abnormal situations. [33] Magelis GTU, the high performance modular HMI panel ready for intuitive multi-touch navigation. [4] PAS has developed methodologies for the practical implementation of High Performance HMIs. [33] WebOP Designer 2.0 is a software development tool which involves the use of PLCs and helps create application solutions for labor-saving, improves efficiency of manufacturing and easy control of every machine in the factory. [3] Such solutions can be deployed across a wide range of industrial and building automation, digital signage, vending machine, medical, automotive and appliance applications. [1] Integrated system diagnostics allow users to monitor key components to prevent machine or product damage in case of a system failure. [5] Regular machine-maintenance alerts allow customers to maintain peak performance and machine operability. [5] Our portfolio is engineered to help you control and manage the increasingly complex processes of your machines and systems. [2] Enhancements include an easy-to-use touchscreen interface that simplifies setting, monitoring, and tracking crucial controls. [5] Microsemi's SmartFusion2 SoC FPGAs SmartFusion2 SoC FPGAs integrate inherently reliable flash-based FPGA fabric, a 166 megahertz (MHz) ARM Cortex-M3 processor, advanced security processing accelerators, DSP blocks, SRAM, eNVM and industry-required high performance communication interfaces, all on a single chip. [1] Our Rotary Switch product line offers an assortment of interface components for use on our cases and enclosures. [34] B&amp;R has been a great partner to help us continue our tradition of delivering certain results, says Paul Irvine, Plexpack CEO. They worked closely with us to understand our customers? needs and develop an interface that is easy to use. [5] From digital encoders to 47-step attenuators, you'll find only the highest quality HMI products for your equipment. [34] Mikroprojekt developed a SmartFusion2 SoC FPGA-based HMI kit comprising of hardware, IP and software. [1] PAS provides workshops and consulting services to guide customers through the execution of an HMI enhancement project. [33] As with choosing the best automobile, there are differing opinions as to what constitutes the best style of HMI screen. [32] Human resistance to change has resulted in those same console screens still be used today. [33] It is easy for a screen designer to overlook certain human factor considerations to create a less that optimum screen. [32] The end effect of a high performance screen is to quickly communicate to an operator the status of a process, and if there is problem, to be able to quickly identify and correct it. [32] High performance screens offer simplicity and the ability to quickly determine abnormal situations, but rely on an operator?s firm knowledge of the process flows and connectivity. [32] With the emphasis on simplicity and clarity, the number of high performance screens may be greater than the number of traditional screens needed to show a given process. [32] One monitor can have a high performance  dashboard  of the most important variables, while other monitors simultaneously display schematic and trending screens. [32] Due to their efficacy of communicating past and present states, critical trends are sometimes included in high performance screens. [32] A high performance screen should not be crowded; it should be graphically simple. [32] The presented approach has a general applicability and the obtained results point out that it could be used to operate various assistive systems (e.g., prosthesis vs. wheelchair), or it could be integrated into other control schemes (e.g., myoelectric control, brain-machine interfaces) in order to improve the usability of existing low-bandwidth HMIs. [35] Specifically, the HMI presents the available actions to the user in a cyclical manner through an electrotactile menu interface (EMI). [35] It should also integrate a feedback channel informing the user about the state of the device, thereby closing the control loop. Designing an HMI with these characteristics has been a challenging task, especially in rehabilitation engineering where an assistive system is used by patients with impaired motor and sensory capacities. [35] Here we presented the first prototype to test a novel concept for a simple and transparent general-purpose HMI. The central novelty is a tactile menu system presenting the available options to the user and then waiting for an acknowledgement (selection), instead of relying on the user to generate the control signals. [35] An ideal human-machine interface (HMI) should allow a consistent, intuitive and simple control of a multi-function system with minimal user training. [35] The system then executes the selected function, while the same EMI can also be used to provide feedback about the system?s state to the user, thus closing the control loop. The novelty of this approach is that it greatly simplifies the communication interface on the user side, i.e., he/she needs to be able to provide only a single acknowledgement input. [35] Each RZ/G device includes an 800 megahertz (MHz) DDR3 external memory interface, which provides ample performance margin for applications including image processing of multiple video streams for monitoring systems and video sensing such as face recognition. [6] It features an easy-to-use interface to access onboard diagnostic functions and to monitor and control all system parameters including but not limited to NOx reduction performance and urea concentration levels in real time. [9] The GDC enables on-the-fly graphics processing and offloads the microcontroller CPU allowing it to process other functions such as touch, sensor interface, audio processing and motor control. [8] The proposed concept simplifies the communication interface between the user and the system as well as the signal processing; instead of generating and decoding many signal patterns, only a single acknowledgement command needs to be provided by the user and recognized by the system. [35] Therefore, the proposed approach simplifies the user communication interface (one signal to generate), decoding (one signal to recognize), and allows selecting from a number of options. [35] If the user can produce N discriminable signals (N?1) and the tactile interface presents M states (M?2), the total number of selectable functions becomes N x M for the 1-level menu, and can increase even further using multi-level menu structures. [35] Onose G, Grozea C, Anghelescu A, Daia C, Sinescu CJ, Ciurea AV, et al. (2012) On the feasibility of using motor imagery EEG-based brain-computer interface in chronic tetraplegics for assistive robotic arm control: a clinical test and long-term post-trial follow-up. [35] Mean values (and standard deviation) of the grasp and release performance obtained during experiments with the Menu Interface and the Myocontrol Interface. [35] The S6E2DH series provides high-speed interfaces for connecting to NAND and NOR flash and SDRAM. Spansion?s HyperBus? interface is part of the graphics subsystem allowing very fast image retrieval without blocking code execution. [8] Spansion?s S6E2DH Series with Integrated graphics display controller and S6E2CCxxF and MB9BF568F Series with integrated voice command control offer embedded designers high performance microcontroller based solutions. [8] The new Epicor Mattec MES embedded shop floor HMI reduces training and deployment time, enables manufactures to expand mobile operations, and accommodate the wide variety of devices in use today on the shop floor, while supporting the needs and expectations of today's uber-connected next-generation employee. [7] The new Epicor Mattec MES embedded shop floor HMI improves operator productivity, mobility, and effectiveness on the shop floor with greater flexibility to deploy the system that best meets the needs of manufacturers and their customers. [7] Overall, the presented HMI was characterized with good performance, robustness, naturalness, and low user effort. [35] And also in many other applications, the proposed HMI could be of particular interest for the users with a high-level of disability. [35] In these scenarios, the decoding of user intentions is trivial since only one signal has to be recognized by the HMI, and the specific option is selected by generating the acknowledgement at a proper time (when that option is being presented by the EMI). [35] Contrary to the classic approach, in which the HMI awaits for the user to generate a proper signal pattern and then feedback the result, here we present a novel concept in which the desired function is selected using bidirectional communication between the controller and the user. [35] The proposed HMI is an easy method to increase the number of system functions without concomitantly increasing the number of command signals the user needs to generate. [35] SAFETY AND RELIABILITY WITH TE. As the extent of automation in industrial production grows, so the need for highly functional HMIs that are intuitive and easy to use is also increasing. [21] The importance of HMI systems in the IoT has become increasingly prevalent in industrial, consumer and home applications. [8] The control of grasping in a state-of-the-art active hand prosthesis was chosen as the context for the testing of the proposed HMI. This context was selected since modern myoelectric hand prostheses are capable of implementing several grasp types and therefore represent a relevant example of a multi-function device. [35] Our final goal was not to replace the existing myoelectric control or other conventional HMI systems, but rather to find novel, natural and simple methods that can be used to complement and improve them. [35] They are controlled using a standard, commercially and clinically accepted myoelectric HMI, which could thus be used as the relevant benchmark to compare the novel approach. [35] This implies that if implemented in true real time (embedded system vs. Matlab) and after providing longer training to the subjects, the proposed HMI could be used at a significantly higher pace leading to a substantially faster operation of the system. [35] In HMIs, the user is responsible for generating unique patterns of command signals directly triggering the device functions. [35] In this study, we propose a novel concept for a general-purpose HMI where the controller and the user communicate bidirectionally to select the desired function. [35] This way the user is able to monitor whether the movement intention was decoded properly by the HMI o not. [35] The user generates command signals, while the HMI operates as a decoder, capturing the signals and estimating the user movement intention. [35] The overall result was a simple HMI that was easily comprehended by the subjects (short training) and that could accommodate many commands while still demonstrating a robust performance comparable to that of a conventional EMG driven approach. [35] The favourable results should be regarded as a strong indication that this approach is feasible and might indeed enhance existing control schemes and HMIs if integrated into those frameworks. [35] An effective and user-friendly control of these systems is still an open problem since conventional human-machine interfaces (HMI) cannot easily accommodate the system?s complexity. [35] EVERY CONNECTION COUNTS HMI INNOVATIVE INTERCONNECT SOLUTIONS FOR AUTOMATION SOLUTIONS FOR AUTOMATION /// HMI TE Connectivity (NYSE : TE L) is a $13 billion world leader in connectivity. [21] The new embedded shop floor HMI gives manufacturers the ability to connect, manage and monitor processes and systems via any browser-enabled computing device. [7] State-of-the-art HMIs are based on the functional design of smartphones and tablet PCs. [21] Creating attractive, easy-to-use HMI while being cost competitive, is essential for the successful adoption of a product. [8] The HMI have a general applicability and the current study demonstrated how it could be used for controlling a multi-grasp prosthetic hand in a closed-loop manner. [35] They are all geared to the particular needs of the HMI market. [21] Traditionally, HMIs are designed as unidirectional signal processing chains. [35] We have demonstrated a proof of concept of a novel HMI system (EMI) that can increase the effective number of functions a user can control without concomitantly increasing the number of command signals he/she needs to generate. [35] The automatic control of opening, closing, grasping force with feedback and releasing were also implemented using the novel HMI and its components without relying on any myoelectric control. [35] The results showed that the performance of the novel HMI concept was comparable or, for some outcome measures, better than the classic myoelectric interfaces. [35] The HyperBus interface enables seamless connections with HyperBus memories, including Spansion HyperFlash?, and allows fast flash memory utilization to support the growing demand for memory-intensive graphics. [8] Ganin IP, Shishkin SL, Kaplan AY (2013) A P300-based brain-computer interface with stimuli on moving objects: four-session single-trial and triple-trial tests with a game-like task design. [35] These countermeasures can reflect on the system compactness and time efficiency by limiting the interface size and the pace of option presentation. [35] We also demonstrated how the approach could be used to implement a two-level menu of functions (e.g. Mode 2 of the menu interface), which can be easily extended to multi-level structures of higher complexity without substantially increasing the waiting times. [35] The Otto Bock interface was still used for EMG acquisition. [35] In the current study, only 4 channels have been used to implement the electrotactile menu system and feedback interface. [35] High-speed interfaces including USB 3.0, PCI-Express, and serial ATA are integrated on-chip, allowing easy expansion of functionality without the need for external components. [6] Supporting an exceptional out-of-the-box experience with no software to load, the new interface enables shop floor personnel to effortlessly manage the plant with maximum efficiency and responsiveness. [7] The prosthesis was connected to the host PC using a Bluetooth interface. [35] Discrete Versus Continuous Mapping of Facial Electromyography for Human-Machine Interface Control: Performance and Training Effects. – PubMed – NCBI Warning: The NCBI web site requires JavaScript to function. more. [36] The EMI for grasping and releasing was comparable in performance to the Myoelectric interface, with the exception of the release action where subjects required significantly more attempts (p&lt;0.05, r 0.33) to successfully release an object using the EMI. This is not surprising since synchronizing the elbow extension with the electrocutaneous pattern pacing the release action is more difficult than just activating the extensor muscles to open the hand. [35] When no feedback was used during the Myoelectric interface (G4), the average performance dropped and the variability between subjects was very high. [35] Grasp selection performance between the Menu interface modes (M1G4, M2G4) and the Myoelectric interface modes for 4 grasps (G4, G4A, G4AR). [35] The performance (GA) of EMI was very good for all positions, except for objects placed in the Top Left position, whereas the Myoelectric interface was less robust since the performance was significantly decreased for both top positions. [35] It was shown that the performance and robustness of this novel system are comparable or better, in some aspects, than the classic myoelectric interfaces. [35] In the context of prosthetics, it demonstrates a simple, non-invasive approach to the control of multi-DoF prostheses that is radically different from the usual solutions targeting this problem (i.e., myoelectric interfaces). [35] Found in multiple industries, these so lutions are used in telecom- munication hubs and cabling, computer devices, networking hardware as well as medical instruments, consumer test products and industrial machines. [21] The operation of the prosthetic hand was divided into 4 phases, which were used to develop a state machine that allowed a complete control of the artificial limb ( Fig 3 ). [35] The result is greater shop floor insight through real-time visibility with metrics, machine status, instructions, alerts and notifications to keep plant operators, management, and engineering apprised of all manufacturing operations. [7] The system captures data directly from machines and operators, and delivers real-time production metrics and real-time operations analytics in an easy-to-digest visual manner. [7] State machine controlling the operation of the prosthetic hand. [35] The novel HMI relied on a simple processing, i.e., a rule-based state machine activated by one IMU and electrotactile stimulation. [35] This multifaceted scenario was therefore convenient for exploring the full potential of the novel HMI, allowing its application in different forms (single and two-level menu), modes (menu and feedback), and multiple times during a single execution cycle. [35] Whereas in these BCI systems the subject selects an option indirectly by focusing attention to a specific stimuli to evoke/modulate an involuntary neural response, in the novel HMI the stimuli delivered by the system represents only a cue prompting the subject to perform a voluntary command. [35] The main aim of the present study was to demonstrate the potential of the novel HMI, by illustrating that it can be exploited in different contexts, rather than to develop a general, standalone, ready-to-be-applied control system. [35] The RZ/G series is backed by an ecosystem of Renesas partners that provides system integration services, graphical user interface (GUI) frameworks, middleware, OS support, board design, as well as sales of evaluation and mass-production boards. [37] Buoyed by partners like Cogent Embedded, Timesys, Adeneo Embedded, and others – all leaders in embedded open source development with expertise spanning Linux and Android system integration, middleware, and graphical user interface (GUI) support – customers will be able to confidently tackle their next embedded projects and dramatically compress their typical development cycle. [37] These intellectual property (IP) blocks make it possible to develop highly effective user interfaces (UI) on products ranging from hand-held medical devices to digital signage by incorporating elements such as simple still images, 3-D graphics, plus video content. [37] When using the Myoelectric interface the average time ( T cc ) needed to perform a successful CoCo was approximately 2 s, more precisely, 2.340.66 s in G4, 2.150.7 s in G4A, and 2.260.67 s in G4AR. Importantly, this was longer then the predefined waiting time between the menu options in EMI ( T D 1 s). [35] When using the EMI, the activation time of grasp selection/activation was shorter than when using the myoelectric interface; and the EMI was more robust when grasping objects in different positions. [35] Interestingly, the time needed by the subjects to activate the grasp was significantly lower for the EMI compared to the Myoelectric interface for all options except the first. [35] Only when activating the first option, the myoelectric interface resulted in shorter mean time, but the difference was not statistically significant. [35] For the Myoelectric interface a statistical difference was found between non-neighbouring options (1 vs. 3 and 2 vs. 4). [35] The TTA was used for comparing the speed in selecting functions using Menu and Myoelectric interface. [35] When no feedback and no resetting was used (G4) in the Myoelectric interface, the GSP was lower compared to all the other conditions, although no statistical difference was found mainly due to a large variability in G4. [35] In order to release an object, subjects had significantly more difficulties when using the EMI compared to myoelectric interface. [35] The subjects had more difficulties to lock the grasp with the Myoelectric interface when the object was in the top position (Friedman?s ANOVA results; p &lt; 0.05). [35] As shown by the experimental results, using EMI the subjects were able to achieve a high performance when selecting among eight menu options. [35] Epicor enterprise resource planning (ERP), retail management software, supply chain management (SCM), and human capital management (HCM) enable companies to drive increased efficiency and improve profitability. [7] Some of the automation tasks AIS's PC-based Compact Industrial HMIs excel at include: control, visualization and communications in mechanical engineering, transportation systems or power transmission; acquisition of data, processing and visualization as a data gateway for control and monitoring, machine level applications and more. [13] AIS next generation HMI Touch Panel Series are engineered to meet the increasingly complex processes, demanding visualization and control tasks of machines and automation systems while simplifying operation and programming. [18] AIS's PC-based HMI Operator Touch Panels provide great flexibility with a variety of interface and configuration options. [13] These interface and configuration options offer users tremendous flexibility when integrating AIS's Compact HMI solutions with other networks, systems, equipment and machinery in plants and facilities. [13] Product designers and industrial designers can struggle with specifying backlighting options for custom HMI (Human-Machine Interface) products. [20] Among these, the market for interface software leads the global HMI market at present. [18] Although it has a rugged and robust design, AIS's compact operator touch panels are not only used in harsh, industrial applications requiring heavy duty HMIs, but in light factory, commercial and office application environments as well. [13] The company's HMI solutions are key enabling technologies for the Internet of Things (IoT), Industrial Internet of Things, (IIoT), Machine-to-Machine Communications (M2M) and Industry 4.0 applications. [13] Users and OEMs are deploying more HMI software solutions for a variety of mobile devices, such as tablets and smart phones; performing remote monitoring, and bringing in more data. [12] The HMI software and services market will go through many dynamics during the next few years due to trends, such as emerging technologies of multi-touch touch screens, connecting to more mobile devices, shifting to Windows 10 and Server 2012 operating systems, and demand for better communication and control. [12] The SAMA5D4 is a medium-heavier processor and well suited for IoT, control panels, HMI, and the like, differentiating from other Atmel MCUs by the means of performance and security (not to mention, safety). [10] AIS is fully committed to empowering, improving and delivering turnkey HMI, control, monitoring and display solutions for OEM, ODM and end-user customers. [13] Using flexible and standardized interfaces for embedded computing allows for easy and efficient integration for almost any machine, application or environment. [18] You have the option to select 16-b DDR2 interface, or 32-b if you need better performance, but security is no longer just an option. [10] Besides the graphics and array of switches associated with the HMI, an OEM designer often needs to add some form of backlighting to the user interface. [20] For this article, custom user interface keypads, or simply HMI's, are defined as custom assemblies with arrays of logic-level switches, graphics and other electro-mechanical components used in OEM (Original Equipment Manufacturer) applications. [20] General backlighting provides enough illumination to the user interface graphics so the end user can operate the end application but without being uncomfortable by looking at very bright illumination. [20] Examples of user interface end applications include medical electronics, test equipment, communication electronics, military electronics and process control equipment. [20] The aesthetics of the custom user interface design blends with the visual and industrial design of the end application. [20] If the OEM designer or industrial designer doesn't fully understand the relationship of all the design elements, they need to work with a user interface manufacturer that understands that the user interface assembly's design is more than a collection of parts. [20] OEM designers and user interface manufacturers must understand the interrelationship of the various components in the user interface for a successful design solution. [20] If you design fitness equipment, such as treadmills and exercise machines, you may be more sensitive to connectivity and user interface functions than to security elements even if it?s important to feel safe in respect with counterfeiting. [10] The user interface part of the application appears to be integral to the external visual features and design of the end application rather than simply stuck on the front of the end application. [20] General backlighting of all user interface graphics or at least switch legends and icons so that the end user can operate the end application in very low ambient lighting. [20] Many high performance user interfaces are using molded silicone rubber boots to replace graphic overlays. [20] Interface options include high-speed USB 3.0 and Gigabit Ethernet ports, serial communication with multiple RS-232/422/485 I/O ports, a high endurance SSD and externally accessible non-volatile SD card. [13] The E1000 operator panels offer comprehensive HMI functionality and feature a robust IP66 aluminum construction and multiple communication ports. [38] The global HMI software and services market will continue to grow in the future because the importance of HMI software becomes even more significant as industrial operations worldwide become more complex and automated. [12] The market is extremely competitive and demand is expected to grow as many users recognize the benefits of HMI software. [12] Strategic Issues The challenge in the HMI software and services marketplace is how suppliers can differentiate themselves and continue to offer increasing value propositions to end users and OEMs, especially in a slowing global economy. [12] This creates a vibrant environment for the development of advanced HMI software. [12] Whether for home automation purpose or industrial HMI, you want your system to be safeguarded from hackers, and protect your investment against counterfeiting. [10] ABB Ltd., Atmel Corp., Advantech Co. Ltd., American Industrial Systems Inc., BARTEC Top Holding GmbH, Beijer Electronics Inc., Eaton Corp., General Electric Co., Emerson Electric Corp., Honeywell International Inc., Mitsubishi Electric Corp., Invensys plc, Omron Corp., Siemens AG, Rockwell Automation Inc., and Yokogawa Electric Corp. are the key participants operating in the HMI market across the globe. [18] Any Mitsubishi Electric customer who purchased the E1000 series HMI panels through one of its distributors can now purchase the identical models from Beijer. [38] For years, the E1000 series of HMIs were built by Beijer for Mitsubishi as its primary line of HMI terminals. [38] The dearth of HMI designs and high cost associated with the installation of HMIs are restricting the market. [18] The report also profiles the major companies operational in the global HMI market and provides the competitive landscape and hierarchy present in the market. [18] The user can be the woman on the treadmill, or the various machines connected to the display that SAMA5 MCU pilots. [10] Smart devices are now enabled to display data, fine tune variances on conveyors, commission machines, aid in the diagnosis of maintenance issues and more. [19] Using the high performance Raspberry Pi 2 with Quad Core Cortex-A7 CPU, the CSB502HMI creates a low cost, Human-Machine Interface device. [39] Choosing the backlighting requirement before proceeding with the user interface design and fabrication of assemblies prevents wasted development time and cost. [20] This can cause development delays and additional costs when adding backlighting requirements to user interfaces late in the design process. [20] Design Engineers should be aware of the types of backlighting available and how the backlighting is incorporated before the user interface design begins. [20] Backlighting techniques can be counterintuitive and often at odds with other elements of the user interface design. [20] The user interface is a component assembly supplied to the OEM and is critical to the OEM's end application. [20] If the backlighting technique is an E/L lamp or fiber optic panel, the user's finger pressure on the user interface used to push a switch must flex the E/L or fiber optic panel to close the switch contacts. [20] The edge lighted panel is not being considered in this article because the plastic panel is not flexible and must be mounted behind the user interface keypad. [20] The panel surface is molded or etched with a pattern that redirects the edge light traveling along the plastic panel toward the front of the user interface keypad. [20] Backlighting provides added visual features and enhances the operation of user interfaces to the end user. [20] Figure 5: User Interface with graphic overlay and status LEDs. [20] Experienced user interface manufacturers use a variety of methods to prevent light leakage. [20] Discrete LEDs are small packages with an integrated lens and mounted within or immediately behind the user interface. [20] The open architecture, PC-based control and monitoring system from AIS touts the use of the energy efficient, high performance family of Quad Core Celeron processors from Intel. [13] Although the conductive rubber keypad is popular among designers, the conductive rubber keypad is not appropriate for high performance, long life applications because this keypad cannot be sealed from airborne contamination. [20] Distilling the backlighting option pros and cons with practical decisions about cost and high performance, there are two design approaches that stand above others. [20] Many general elements in HMI design have been packed into controls, users can evoke them directly. [17] All these HMIs involve acquisition systems, which include the amplification, filtering, digitization, recording and processing of the different kinds of signals provided by the wheelchair user. [40] One alternative for people with disabilities is the use of augmentative and alternative communication (AAC) devices within the human-machine interface (HMI) field. [40] The Nextion UART TFT HMI LCD allows you to stop using the GUI library, enabling you to build your user interface in a WYSIWYG editor on your PC, and then easily download and install it on the LCD Nextion. [41] Available in 2.4, and 4.3 models, Nextion is a true analog touchscreen operator interface with programmable function buttons for the most robust applications, using Nextion makes interfacing with your machinery easier than ever. [17] B&amp;R has been a great partner to help us continue our tradition of delivering certain results, says Paul Irvine, Plexpack CEO. They worked closely with us to understand our customers? needs and develop an interface that is easy to use and delivers enhanced features that improve performance and efficiency. [14] The proposed system shown in Figure 1, as with the work developed by and to control a robotic wheelchair, uses myoelectrical eye blinks, iris-tracking and a brain-computer interface to choose letters in a personal digital assistant (PDA). [40] Enhancements include an easy to use touchscreen interface that simplifies setting, monitoring, and tracking crucial controls like heat, seal pressure, and speed as well as new capabilities to set preferences, calibrate processes, manage maintenance, and identify issues. [14] User can drag-and-drop any component in the editor to simplify your interface design. [17] Maker/Developer – Worry about spending time in learning programming the TFT when you start to undertake an interactive interface design? Using Nextion editor, you can drag-and-drop any component in the editor, designing the interface with less programming. [17] In this situation, Nextion editor has mass components such as button, text, progress bar, slider, instrument panel etc. to enrich your interface design. [17] A Close-Up of the PLC interface used on Plexpack's Emplex Bag Sealers Plexpack's bag sealing machines are now equipped with this interface. [14] Getting the job done right at the right price– Nextion is the operator interface solution you?ve been waiting for. [17] This kind of interface decreases the effort of the user when writing the text, delegating the writing effort to the WPS. [40] The PDA provides a graphic interface containing possible letters and actions. [40] A word predictor for inflected languages: system design and user-centric interface. [40] Quickly Adapt and Differentiate – Embrace changing features and interfaces, while reducing time to market, with Lattice FPGAs and CPLDs. [42] The combination of Green Hills Software's functional safety and security expertise and our high performance, heterogeneous processors enables us to deliver market-leading industrial solutions, said Carlos Betancourt, product marketing manager at TI. With INTEGRITY, our Sitara AM57x processor family is an ideal industrial platform offering multiple low-latency industrial network protocols, security engines and integrated DSP and graphics acceleration. [16] The new HMI, developed with B&amp;R, provides fast, repeatable set up, simplifies operation and maintenance, and increases flexibility to manage important data and resources. [14] The new HMI is standard on all Emplex MPS continuous band sealers and and available as an option on select Damark Shrink Wrappers and Bundlers. [14] We believe that your dozen days developing a complex HMI can be done in couple hours by using Nextion. [17] In this work, the robotic wheelchair – developed at the Federal University of Esp'rito Santo (Brazil) – is able to use different HMIs, such as eye tracking, brain signals and sip-and-puff. [40] Preventative maintenance alerts to maintain peak performance and machine operability. [14] Such models are widely used in applications such as automatic speech recognition (ASR) and machine translations (MT). [40] Integrated system diagnostics and background monitoring of key processes and compon ents to prevent machine damage, product loss or system failure. [14] The first and foremost goal of HVHF Sciences is to enable its clients discover and design solutions to maximize opportunities for successful human factors interactions and minimize the likelihood for inefficient interactions, including the elimination of costly and catastrophic errors in a variety of operating conditions ranging from the normal to abnormal to acute emergencies. [43] HVHF Sciences offers training in topics centered around human performance in high stakes situations. [43] Speech-based human and service robot interaction: An application for mexican dysarthric people. [40] Even though real users were not used in the test set, the results show good prospects for the application of the proposed system within the text-based user interface in the robotic wheelchair. [40] This work focuses on the improvement of this aspect in order to achieve a better performance in a text-based user interface located within a robotic wheelchair. [40] Nowadays, text prediction methods – if adequately integrated within user interfaces – can benefit anyone trying to produce text messages or commands. [40] This paper concentrates on improving a text-based human-machine interface integrated into a robotic wheelchair. [40] Overall, the performance of real-life HMI applications depends on the overall SoC architecture, the software architecture, and the number and type of used graphics operations. [22] By changing only application-specif ic SoC parts and re-using large portions of the SoC design–the software code, graphics HMI, and networking–system designers can quickly design the whole line-up of HMI products for different applications as part of a common platform. [22] The provided logicBRICKS software drivers enable software programmers to use the Qt cross-platform application framework in familiar ways, to design HMIs in the same way as with any SoC. The same benchmark tests were run with the Zynq-7000 AP SoC configured to render graphics through the Linux frame buffer using no graphic acceleration, and then again with the logiBITBLT graphics accelerator supported by XylonQPA 2D acceleration plug-in for Qt5.x. [22] Development from scratch of a powerful, extensible PL-based graphics controller/accelerator is a daunting, time-consuming task; thus, a cost-effective, optimized HMI solution is highly advantageous for the Zynq-7000 AP SoC. Pressure to create more differentiated products while shortening development time is driving designers to use off-the-shelf third-party IP cores and software. [22] Using Xilinx Zynq-7000 AP SoCs, this highly scalable integration of hardware, software, and system solutions allows HMI designers to produce a proven HMI solution at an accelerated pace while focusing on their primary mission: to produce optimally differentiated products that support a long marketplace lifetime. [22] The key benefit for systems that require an HMI is the ability to implement differentiating application-specific hardware accelerators in the programmable logic and quickly upgrade it to a full SoC design with a high quality off-the-shelf graphics engine for display control. [22] To create the HMI application running on the displays, use GemStudio, a drag-and-drop application that provides a library of UI widgets and easy importing of custom graphics. [25] A common denominator for these mixed HMI applications is to use web services to communicate with the different HMIs used in four out of the five above options (excluding component display). [25] The provided application-specif ic graphic demos include an industrial HMI example (Figure 3) designed by using the popular Qt application framework for GUI developments and the industrial Qt widgets library, avionics demo, 3D automotive demos, and several others. [22] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (44 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) Related Previous post
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/b3636035-548b-37c0-964d-7fce619f8aee" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-11T23:27:28Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:43:22.166Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/what-is-high-performance-human-machine-interface-hmi/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
