<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Fast Market Research Global <NODE id="28" />MEMs Pressure Sensor<NODE id="48" /> Market 2016-2020 - New Market Study Published Fast Market Research announces the availability of the new TechNavio report, Global MEMs Pressure Sensor Market 2016-2020, on their comprehensive research portal Boston, MA -- ( SBWIRE ) -- 02/10/2016 -- Micro-Electro-Mechanical System (MEMS) pressure sensors provide an interface that can sense, process, and control the external environment of the system on which they are installed. These devices contain tiny electrical and mechanical components on a single chip, and work on the principle of change in resonant frequency to calculate pressure. Technavio's analysts forecast the global MEMS pressure sensors market to grow at a CAGR of 13.82% during the period 2016-2020. Covered in this report The report covers the present scenario and the growth prospects of the global MEMS pressure sensors market for 2016-2020. To calculate the market size, the report considers revenue generated from the sales of MEMS pressure sensors to the following customer segments: Get More Details on this Report and a Full Table of Contents at Global MEMs Pressure Sensor Market 2016-2020 -Automotive -Industrial -Healthcare -Others Technavio's report, Global MEMS Pressure Sensors Market 2016-2020, has been prepared based on an in-depth market analysis with inputs from industry experts. The report covers the market landscape and its growth prospects over the coming years. The report also includes a discussion of the key vendors operating in this market. Key vendors -Bosch -Denso -Sensata Technologies -Freescale Semiconductors Other prominent vendors -Delphi -GE Sensing -Infineon Technologies -Schneider Electric -Texas Instruments Market driver -Increase in vehicle automation -For a full, detailed list, view our report Market challenge -High manufacturing costs -For a full, detailed list, view our report Market trend -Miniaturization of electronic devices -For a full, detailed list, view our report Key questions answered in this report -What will the market size be in 2020 and what will the growth rate be? -What are the key market trends? -What is driving this market? -What are the challenges to market growth? -Who are the key vendors in this market space? -What are the market opportunities and threats faced by the key vendors? -What are the strengths and weaknesses of the key vendors? You can request one free hour of our analyst's time when you purchase this market report. Details are provided within the report. Companies Mentioned in this Report: Bosch, Denso, Sensata Technologies, Freescale Semiconductors, GE Sensing, Delphi, Infineon Technologies, Schneider Electric, Texas Instruments About Fast Market Research Fast Market Research is a leading distributor of market research and business information. Representing the world's top research publishers and analysts, we provide quick and easy access to the best competitive intelligence available. Our unbiased, expert staff is always available to help you find the right research to fit your requirements and your budget. For more information about these or related research reports, please visit our website at http://www.fastmr.com or call us at 1.800.844.8156. Browse all Computer Technology research reports at Fast Market Research You may also be interested in these related reports: - Pressure Sensor Market - Global Forecast to 2020 - Media Relations Contact Bill Thompson Director of Marketing Fast Market Research, Inc. 800-844-8156
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0ac7cb2c-eec1-3d53-b8cf-2ddde6dcf3ac" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-10T18:57:44Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:39:22.291Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.sbwire.com/press-releases/global-mems-pressure-sensor-market-2016-2020-new-661368.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="28" endPos="48" type="product-class" surface="MEMs Pressure Sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
