<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Global Occupancy Sensor Market 2015-2020 - Market is Estimated to Grow to USD 2.78 Billion By 2020 Global Occupancy Sensor Market 2015-2020 - Market is Estimated to Grow to USD 2.78 Billion By 2020 PR Newswire DUBLIN, January 19, 2016 DUBLIN , January 19, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- Research and Markets ( http://www.researchandmarkets.com/research/th68l3/occupancy_sensor ) has announced the addition of the Occupancy Sensor Market by Technology (PIR, Ultrasonic &amp;Dual), Network Connectivity (Wired &amp; Wireless), Coverage Area, Operation (Indoor &amp; Outdoor), Application, Building Type (Residential &amp; Commercial), and Geography - Global Forecast to 2020 report to their offering. (Logo: http://photos.prnewswire.com/prnh/20130307/600769 ) The market is presently witnessing growing demand for <NODE id="786" />occupancy sensors<NODE id="803" /> in commercial buildings and one of the major reasons behind is expected to be the growing importance towards saving energy and proper consumption of the same. With regards to this, advances in technology such as innovation &amp; development of occupancy sensors, motion sensors, and so on are making it easier to save energy and help the environment. For instance, -30% to 50% of electricity in a particular building is utilized for illumination and HVAC (Heating, Ventilation and Air-conditioning) systems. With the help of occupancy sensors, -40% of energy consumption is reduced. The report aims at estimating the market size and future growth potential of the occupancy sensor market across different segments such as technology, network connectivity, coverage area, application, operation, building type, and different region. The base year considered for the study is 2014 and the market size forecast is between 2015 and 2020. Factors such as rise in electricity and power prices, growing government support, and increasing demand for energy-efficient devices on a global basis are expected to play a key role in fueling the growth of the market in the next five years. The research methodology used to estimate and forecast the occupancy sensor market begins with capturing data on key vendor revenues through secondary research. The vendor offerings are also taken into consideration to determine the market segmentation. The bottom-up procedure was employed to arrive at the overall market size of the occupancy sensor market from the revenue of the key players in the market. After arriving at the overall market size, the total market was split into several segments and sub-segments which are then verified through primary research by conducting extensive interviews with key people such as CEOs, VPs, Directors and executives among others. This data triangulation and market breakdown procedures have been employed to complete the overall market engineering process and arrive at the exact statistics for all segments and sub-segments. The breakdown of profiles of primary is depicted in the below figure: Scope of the Report By Technology: - Passive Infrared - Ultrasonic - Dual Technology - Other Technologies (Microwave, IPOS, and IOS) By Network Connectivity: - Wired - Wireless (Wi-Fi, EnOcean, ZigBee, Z-Wave and others) By Coverage Area: - Less than 89 Degree - 90 Degree-179 Degree - 180 Degree-360 Degree By Application: - Lighting Control - HVAC - Security Surveillance By Operation: - Indoor Operation - Outdoor Operation By Building Type: - Residential Buildings (Independent Homes and Apartments) - Commercial Buildings (Office Buildings, Education Buildings, Industrial Buildings, Healthcare Buildings, Retail Buildings, and Hospitality Buildings) Companies Mentioned - Acuity Brands, Inc. - Eaton Corporation Plc - General Electric Company - Honeywell International, Inc. - Hubbell Incorporated - Johnson Controls, Inc. - Koninklijke Philips N.V. - Legrand S.A - Leviton Manufacturing Co., Inc. - Lutron Electronics Co., Inc. - Schneider Electric For more information visit http://www.researchandmarkets.com/research/th68l3/occupancy_sensor About Research and Markets Research and Markets is the world's leading source for international market research reports and market data. We provide you with the latest data on international and regional markets, key industries, the top companies, new products and the latest trends. Media Contact: Laura Wood +353-1-481-1716 press@researchandmarkets.net
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/55c9386f-3a72-3465-b127-d8507bdc3cc2" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-19T18:54:41Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:07:40.613Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.telegraphindia.com/pressrelease/prnw/enuk201601191860_public.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="786" endPos="803" type="product-class" surface="occupancy sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
