<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2014 (14) - MINI Countryman 1.6 One 5dr [Pepper Pack] £13,785 Loading Images... Date Registered: Mar 2014 Mileage: 8,851 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Petrol Price: £13,785 Colour: Black Body Style: Hatchback Vehicle Trim / Variant: One EC Combined (mpg) 47.1 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 54.3 EC Urban (mpg) 38.7  &gt; 47 MPG 12 Insurance Group 98 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 139 CO2 (g/km) £130 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: One Insurance Group 12, ''MINI Service Package Included, Pepper Pack, Bluetooth Telephone Preparation, Automatic Air Conditioning, 16 Alloys, Leather Steering Wheel, Heated Mirrors, Heated Washer Jets, Roof Rails, Interior World Carbon Black, Floor Mats, Extended Storage, Fog Lamps, Park Distance Control, <NODE id="743" />Rain Sensor<NODE id="754" /> Wipers with Auto Headlight Activation, On Board Computer, DAB Digital Radio, White Indicator Lenses Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01302 515998 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating The MINI Countryman is a new entrant to the lucrative crossover market. read more Fun handling Bargain entry level price Stylish looks Excellent residuals Low servicing costs Economical Noisy engines Interior prone to rattles and buzzing Feels a little tinny Rear seats don't fold completely flat Counter-intuitive switchgear and controls Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Bluetooth Connection DAB digital radio Electric door mirrors Folding rear seats Front electric windows Heated door mirrors Height adjustable drivers seat Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Roof rails Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01302 515998 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 2 cupholders in front centre console 3 rear seats 4 lashing points to secure luggage 60/40 split sliding rear seats ABS Adjustable headrests Anti dazzle mirror Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Brake fluid level warning light Brake pad wear indicator warning light CBC - (Cornering brake control) Centre console storage Chrome interior door handles Driver/passenger sunvisors Driver's seat height adjuster DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Electric front + rear windows - anti trap + one touch Electric power steering Electrically adjustable door mirrors Electronic brake force distribution Engine start/stop button Exterior temperature gauge Front seat backrest storage nets Gear knob with chrome ring Gear/selector and handbrake in artificial leather Heated door mirrors/heated windscreen washers Heated rear window with automatic switch off Height/reach adjustable steering column Hill start assist Isofix child seat preparation MINI centre rail Oil level indicator Rear grab handles Rear park distance control Rear wiper Run flat indicator Service interval indicator Side sunvisor for driver Storage compartments in doors Entertainment Auxiliary input socket DAB Digital radio Radio BOOST + single slot CD
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/f8461318-3e4d-3ac9-bb8f-81b638b58b28" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-18T13:24:33Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:09:33.64Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39375935/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="743" endPos="754" type="product-class" surface="Rain Sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
