<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 13, 2016 C O N T E N T S: Image Courtesy: link: https://www.valence.com/battery-breakthrough-in-the-tug-boat-industry/ author: valence.com description: Battery solution in tug boat KEY TOPICS A typical lithium-ion battery consists of two lithium electrodes with a positive and a negative charge, and an electrolyte liquid or gel in the center that allows ions to move back and forth between the two electrodes, sharing their electrons along the way. [1] According to a report from UPI, a new design for a lithium-ion battery with the ability to self-regulate its temperature could soon find its way into your favorite consumer electronics like laptops and hoverboards. [1] The new lithium-ion battery, however, shuts itself down before overheating, and restarts immediately when the temperature cools down. [2] Zhenan Bao, a professor of chemical engineering at Stanford, together with her colleagues have specially designed the improved lithium-ion battery so that explosions and fires will be prevented. [3] New lithium-ion battery shuts down before overheating and restarts as soon as it cools. [4] Virus-Built Wearable Batteries Could Power Military – Two different viruses have been used to create the cathode and anode for a lithium-ion battery. [5] As the university explains, a typical lithium-ion battery consists of two electrodes and a liquid or gel electrolyte that carries charged particles between them. [6] Scientists in the U.S. have designed a reusable lithium-ion battery that will shut down under extreme temperatures and only work again once the device has cooled. [7] The new battery could prevent fires from erupting in an array of lithium-ion battery powered devices. [8] Other teams investigating the same problem have filmed lithium-ion battery explosions in real-time. [7] Scientists at Stanford have designed a lithium-ion battery that doesn't overheat. [9] The lithium-ion battery, developed at Stanford University, shuts off when it gets too hot, and will revive once it?s cooled. [10] Yi Cui, associate professor of materials science and engineering at Stanford University, was successful in developing a lithium ion battery that can issue a signal when it gets too hot, and afterwards promptly shuts down. [11] Key to the new breakthrough is the fact that the battery technology can shut down and then start up again while some existing lithium-ion batteries are able to cut the power if they're about to explode, they're then no longer functional afterwards. [12] Its scientists have developed lithium-ion battery technology that promises much longer-lasting power packs. [9] Scientists in Canada and France have created a micro-supercapacitor with the same energy density of a modern lithium-ion battery that could potentially last forever. [9] An anonymous reader writes: Scientists have designed a lithium-ion battery that self-regulates according to temperature, to prevent itself from overheating. [9] A normal lithium-ion battery comprises of two electrodes and a liquid or gel electrolyte having charged particles between them. [13] They believe it's also more durable, withstanding more than 7,500 cycles without any loss of capacity and surpassing previous aluminium batteries which died after just 100 charge-discharge cycles, while a typical lithium-ion battery lasts about 1,000 cycles. [14] A typical lithium-ion battery consists of two electrodes and a liquid or gel electrolyte that carries charged particles between them. [15] A lithium-ion battery that shuts down before overheating, then restarts immediately when the temperature cools. [16] POSSIBLY USEFUL When the temperature rises, the film expands, and at about 70 degrees Celsius (160 degrees Fahrenheit) the conducting spikes no longer touch each other, breaking the circuit and causing the battery to shut down. [17] The cycle of exchanging electrons between positive and negative ends of a battery can lead to dangerous spikes in temperatures in the intermediary electrolyte material. [1] The battery is a second job for the nickel-embedded polyethylene material. [17] Once the battery shuts down, a runaway thermal reaction is avoided and the battery cools, eventually bringing the nickel spikes back into contact and allowing the electricity flow to resume. [17] We attached the polyethylene film to one of the battery electrodes so that an electric current could flow through it, says lead author Zheng Chen. [1] This new invention could prevent battery fires in smartphones, laptops, and hoverboards. [2] The film, containing sharp nickel nanoparticles coated with graphene, enhances conductivity inside the battery. [1] Compared with previous approaches, our design provides a reliable, fast, reversible strategy that can achieve both high battery performance and improved safety, Cui said in a statement. [17] In a statement, Zhenan Bao, a professor of chemical engineering at Stanford who was a part of the study team, said that while many have tried to find a way to solve the fire problem on lithium-ion batteries, their solution could be the one everyone is looking for. [18] Bao, the Stanford professor, used the same material in a wearable sensor she developed to measure body temperature. [17] Zhenan Bao, a professor of chemical engineering at Stanford University, examines a polyethylene film in a lab at the university. [17] A polyethylene film is tested for its reaction to heat in a lab at Stanford University. [17] A Stanford press release describing the new technology can be found here. [1] Tesla had issues with using lithium-ion batteries in its cars, and Boeing had to scrap some of its 787 Dreamliners after airplanes caught fire from the batteries. [18] People have tried different strategies to solve the problem of accidental fires in lithium-ion batteries, she said. [18] If successful, it could be a tremendous boon to an electronics industry that is growing increasingly reliant on lithium-ion batteries, as safety issues have been the main thing holding back large-scale production. [18] Lithium-ion batteries are powerful and rechargeable, making them an increasingly popular alternative to standard batteries, but their main drawback is how flammable they are, according to a Christian Science Monitor report. [18] We?ve designed the first battery that can be shut down and revived over repeated heating and cooling cycles without compromising performance. [1] When battery heats up above 160 degrees Fahrenheit, the polyethylene film expands like a balloon, separates spiky particles and cause battery to shut down but when it drops down to 160 F, the film shrinks, assembles all the scattered particles and restarts the battery. [4] We attached the polyethylene film to one of the battery electrodes so that an electric current could flow through it, said Zheng Chen, lead author of the study. [4] The new technology could prevent battery fires that have plagued laptops, hoverboards and other electronic devices. [19] The new lithium ion battery is designed after the rash of incidents involving battery-powered devices like laptops, hoverboards and navigation systems. [4] They've developed what they claim is the first lithium ion battery that automatically shuts down before overheating and then restarts itself once it's cooled off sufficiently. [20] The team added that the temperature in which the battery shuts down can be set lower depending on the materials used. [3] The battery shuts itself down as the temperature gets too high and restarts immediately once it cools. [4] Topix › Electric Vehicle › Breakthrough: A new battery that wona. [21] There are 1 comment on the Bay Area Business Woman story from 23 hrs ago, titled Breakthrough: A new battery that wona t overheat and explode. [21] Compared with previous approaches, our design provides a reliable, fast, reversible strategy that can achieve both high battery performance and improved safety, said Yi Cui, co-author of the study. [4] For example, we might want the battery to shut down at 50 C or 100 C. [20] We've designed the first battery that can be shut down and revived over repeated heating and cooling cycles without compromising performance, the professor stated. [3] The latest breakthrough in technology addresses the fire issues in devices today which are caused by overheating batteries. [3] The breakthrough involves using nanotechnology - specifically by developing spiky nickel particles coated in graphene that can then be embedded in a thin plastic film. [20] The problem with those flaming hoverboards (which are really a kind of self-balancing scooter ) comes down to their lithium ion batteries filled with highly flammable material that can overheat and ignite when something goes wrong. [20] Regular lithium ion batteries are made up of two electrodes and electrolyte liquid or gel that transfers electrons from one end to another. [4] People have tried different strategies to solve the problem of accidental fires in lithium-ion batteries, said Zhenan Bao, a professor of chemical engineering at Stanford University. [4] Battery-powered devices with lithium-ion batteries usually catch fire because activities like overcharging, puncturing and shorting generates heat. [3] Lithium-ion batteries in devices like smartphones, navigation systems and even the new hoverboard craze can explode when they overheat. [22] The latest attempt to address the danger through better batteries comes from a team of Stanford chemical engineers. [20] The electrolyte can then explode if the temperature continues to rise until it reaches 150 degrees Celsius, as reported by Stanford News. [3] To address the longstanding problem, Stanford scientists used nanotechnology. [4] Arctan, a solar-powered car built by undergraduate members of the Stanford Solar Car Project, placed sixth in the 2015 Bridgestone World Solar Challenge, a nearly 2,000-mile race across the Australian outback. [19] Stanford engineers have discovered how to make the electrical wiring on top of solar cells nearly invisible to incoming light. [19] Hailed for the discovery of superplastic steel, Sherby was a professor at Stanford for 30 years. [19] Fifteen Stanford graduate students in business, computer science and bioengineering were recently named 2016 Siebel Scholars for outstanding academic performance and leadership in their fields. [19] A recent gathering at Stanford on the emerging science of big data turned the usual gender ratio of science conferences on its head. [19] The new battery, which basically monitors its own temperature in order to determine when to turn itself on and off, harbors the potential to, according to a Stanford news release, prevent battery fires in an array of modern electronic devices from hoverboards to laptops, navigation systems to recliners. [8] Thomas Edison's nickel-iron battery gets 21st-century makeover, could power electric cars – The nickel-iron battery, originally conceived by Edison over a century ago, is back and better than ever thanks to scientists at Stanford. [5] Supercapacitors also have a much higher power density than batteries, and they can provide power far more quickly than existing battery technology. [5] Donald Sadowy's Liquid Batteries – Liquid Metal Battery Corporation, founded by an MIT professor and his students, is commercializing a battery technology for grid-scale energy storage. [5] A Quantum Leap in Battery Design – A digital quantum battery concept proposed by a physicist at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign could provide a dramatic boost in energy storage capacity over lithium ion batteries by several orders of magnitude. [5] Scientists at three Department of Energy national laboratories have discovered how to keep a promising new type of lithium ion battery cathode from developing a crusty coating that degrades its. [23] The exploding lithium ion battery: It has caused fires in laptops at conferences and on planes, in phones worn in pants pockets, in chairs while people are sitting in them and in this season's hot holiday gift, the hoverboard–leading to the boards being banned just about everywhere. [24] The innovation may help to prevent battery fires in specialised lithium-ion technologies. [7] Remember the Japan Airlines plane that caught fire due to a malfunction with its lithium-ion batteries? That, and other fires in items such as hover boards and laptops, have cast a shadow over the battery technology. [6] New battery technology may allow for complete recharging within minutes – New batteries being developed at the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign are said to offer all the advantages of capacitors and batteries, in one unit. [5] Prieto Battery Offers 1000x Power Density – Amy Prieto of Colorado State University is developing a new battery technology that utilizes copper antimonide nanowires, and an ultra thin polymer electrolyte. [5] Lead Acid Battery Reconditioning with Replacement Electrolytes – A group of back yard experimenters are looking a ways to rejuvenate used sulfur lead acid batteries by replacing the electrolyte with pickling alum, as well as magnesium sulfate (epsom salts), and even copper sulfate. [5] SOLAR EAR: Affordable Sun-Powered Hearing Aids – Solar Ear, a Brazilian company, creates low-cost hearing aids that get their juice from solar-powered batteries, seriously cut back on battery waste, while being more affordable than traditional hearing aids. [5] Bradwell's cheap, reliable batteries to store renewable energy – A battery designed by MIT grad student, David Bradwell, has active components that are liquid, which enables it to handle high currents without fracturing, and could eventually cost less than $100 per kilowatt-hour. [5] New Materials Could Double Chevy Volt Battery Capacity – The Chevy Volt is set to become even more appealing as GE announced it is working on a new generation of batteries with double the energy-storage capacity. [5] Once the battery cools to room temperature, the polymer film contracts and the nickel particles are able to conduct electricity again. [7] That causes the particles to spread apart, making the film nonconductive so that electricity can no longer flow through the battery. [8] We attached the polyethylene film to one of the battery electrodes so that an electric current could flow through it To conduct electricity, the spiky particles have to physically touch one another. [8] We attached the polyethylene film to one of the battery electrodes so that an electric current could flow through it, said Chen, lead author of the study. [6] As the nanoparticles in the film, which are spiky graphene-coated nickel particles, require physical contact with one another in order to conduct electricity, they're able to effectively turn the battery off once it's too hot, as the polyethylene film they're embedded in stretches during thermal expansion. [8] When the first capacitor fills, a power management circuit then feeds the electricity into a battery or larger capacitor. [25] Bowling Effect: Two good and one bad battery power a motor while recharging – Back in 2008, David Bowling presented a design he had accomplished but had a hard time repeating. [5] When the battery has cooled down enough, the film retracts and contact between the nanoparticles is reestablished, turning the battery back on. [8] It doesn't permanently shut the battery down, rather, as soon as the battery cools off, the plastic shrinks, the nanoparticles come back in contact with each other, and the battery immediately begins working again. [24] EcoloCap claims its battery technology more than 98% efficient – The Nano Lithium X Battery by EcoloCap offers over 98 percent efficiency and has the world?s highest energy density output per mass. [5] Phinergy's metal-air battery yields 1000-mile EV range – A Israeli company called Phinergy has come up with a metal-air-water battery technology that could enable a vehicle to travel 1000 miles on one charge, with a couple of stops to refill the system with water. [5] As the organic electrolyte is flammable, a battery short can lead to a fire or, as the pressure builds, even an explosion. [7] The mixture is then coated onto a battery electrode, before being placed in the organic electrolyte. [7] Dicken's Magnesium-Water-Copper Battery – Stephen Dickens' H2O Battery/Generator using Mg and Cu Electrodes with Foam Insulator is a lot bigger than an AA, but is cheap and easy to build. [5] Last month there was a news report that, in Hollywood, California, a lithium ion battery burst into flames. [6] Bedini battery can run on mountain dew – John Bedini demonstrated, step-by-step, how even novices can make an ion-transferring crystal power cell that lights up L.E.D.s (light-emitting diodes) bright enough to read by. [5] Sony demos paper-fueled battery – Sony recently showed off a new bio-cell battery that breaks down paper in order to create power. [5] The battery restarts immediately when the temperature cools. [26] Prolonging Battery Life to Make Solar More Plausible – The Earthship lets us begin with a very small system by comparison. [5] Battery Secrets by Peter Lindemann – Learn the real science behind keeping a battery in good shape for a theoretically unlimited number of charge cycles. [5] If you charge and discharge a battery at the same time you destroy it. [5] Chen believes such a safety feature can be incorporated into current battery manufacturing. [7] Although there are internal fail-safes that can shut down an overcharging battery, the process is often irreversible and the cell cannot be used again. [7] Jordan Meshel, 14, had bought a new battery for his radio-controlled car and placed it on his desk to charge in his room. [6] People have tried different strategies to solve the problem of accidental fires in lithium-ion batteries We've designed the first battery that can be shut down and revived over repeated heating and cooling cycles without compromising performance. [8] People have tried different strategies to solve the problem of accidental fires in lithium-ion batteries, said Zhenan Bao, a professor of chemical engineering at Stanford, in a press release. [24] The design is an enhancement of a wearable sensor that monitors human body temperature invented by Zhenan Bao, a professor of chemical engineering at Stanford. [26] Stanford Scientists may have found a way to increase the power of a solar cell by 10% or more. [27] Zheng Chen, the study's lead author and a postdoctoral scholar at Stanford University, explained in a statement that the spiky particles have to physically touch one another in order to conduct electricity, but when the polyethylene stretches during thermal expansion, the particles spread apart, making the film nonconductive so that electricity can no longer flow through the battery. [8] It could prove to be an escalating problem in such an energy-intensive age, according to Zheng Chen, a chemical engineer from Stanford University. [7] Paper-Thin Batteries Provide Bendable Power – New carbon nanotube-based technology could literally allow companies to paint layers of electricity-holding lithium-ion on standard pieces of paper. [5] Then last May, the Insurance Journal reported that at least 18 airlines had banned freight shipments of lithium-ion rechargeable batteries. [6] That sent a lithium-ion scare around the world and last year many airlines refused to carry the batteries as freight, lest they ignite in the hold of an aircraft. [6] The problem is that plenty of manufacturers (think China) have been making lithium ion batteries that were not of the highest standard, a fact that has tarnished the image of the technology. [6] New Lithium-Ion Ultracapacitor Can Charge Tools In Under 60 Seconds – New York-based company Ioxus has developed a new type of lithium ion ultracapacitor that can potentially deliver large amounts of energy in a small amount of time. [5] Lithium-air batteries offer three times the energy density – Lithium-air batteries have the potential of providing energy densities up to three times that of the conventional lithium-ion batteries found in just about every portable consumer electronics device and electric vehicles. [5] Home Batteries to power houses for a week – Panasonic has announced plans to create ‘home batteries.' They are lithium-ion batteries large enough to power a house for a week, making energy sources such as solar and wind power more feasible. [5] This thermal runaway effect limits the voltage window lithium-ion batteries can operate over and their energy storage capacity. [7] The problem: the rechargeable lithium-ion batteries in the foot-rests of the scooters. [6] According to Zhenan Bao, a chemical engineering professor at the university, the new battery she and her colleagues designed is the first battery that can be shut down and revived over repeated heating and cooling cycles without compromising performance. [8] The battery's dead: Scientists invent wafer-thin plastic that can store electricity – British scientists say they have created a plastic that can store and release electricity, revolutionising the way we use phones, drive cars – and even wear clothes. [5] In the decade since its publication, we've witnessed an explosion of breakthroughs in genetic engineering, medical regeneration of the human body, autonomous robotics, computing power, and renewable energy. [26] Breakthrough Solid State Generator – We have finally been given permission to discuss this technology that we consider to be at the very top of our list of emerging clean energy technologies. [5] The Kurzweil Accelerating Intelligence newsletter concisely covers relevant major science and technology breakthroughs (daily or weekly) via e-mail. [26] The Science breakthrough of the year, readers' choice, and the top news from 2015. [23] Solid-State Chip and Water Flashlight Demonstrated – On November 11, 2012, at the Global Breakthrough Energy Movement conference in Holland, Mark Dansie of Infinergy demonstrated a chip that harvests electrons from the ambient. [5] Now a solution is at hand, and this could be a great breakthrough – and another bit of good news for those companies planning to produce lithium or graphite. [6] That causes the particles to spread apart, making the film non-conductive so that electricity can no longer flow through the battery. [28] They then attached the film to one of the battery electrodes so that an electric current could flow through it. [28] For the battery experiment, they coated the spiky nickel particles with graphene and embedded the particles in a thin film of elastic polyethylene. [28] Berkeley Lab battery scientist Nitash Balsara, working with collaborator Joseph DeSimone of the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, came up with a highly conductive hybrid electrolyte, combining the two primary types of solid electrolytes–polymer and glass. [29] The electrolyte is compliant, which means it can readily deform to maintain contact with the electrode as the battery is cycled, and also has unprecedented room temperature conductivity for a solid electrolyte, said Balsara. [29] A new type of battery could finally solve the problem of exploding hoverboards. [30] A novel rechargeable battery developed at MIT could one day play a critical role in the massive expansion of solar generation needed to mitigate climate change by midcentury. [31] It needs something like 1 ton over every square centimeter, so you need a big truck sitting on the battery as it cycles, Balsara said. [29] In conventional lithium electrolytes only 20 to 30 percent of the current is carried by the lithium ion. [29] We don?t necessarily need to match a liquid electrolyte because nearly all of the current in the hybrid electrolyte is carried by the lithium ion. [29] IronNet, for example, says it offers breakthrough, patent-pending technology with complex behavioral modeling, big data analytics and proactive responses. [31] Cambridge scientists hail breakthrough in lithium-air battery development – but say real-life usage is still a decade off. [9] U.K. scientists have created a lithium oxygen battery that could eventually replace lithium ion batteries in electric cars, giving them a much longer range between charges. [9] Ten times more power than lithium ion - but still ten years off: A fluffy carbon electrode has brought scientists at Cambridge University a step closer to producing a workable lithium-air battery, but many technical challenges remain.Today's lithium-ion. [9] Scientists have developed a working laboratory demonstrator of a lithium-oxygen battery which has very high energy density, is more than 90% efficient, and, to date, can be recharged more than 2000 times, showing how several of the problems holding back t. [9] In the quest for smaller, longer-lasting, more powerful batteries, scientists have tried many alternative approaches to battery chemistry. [9] Battery tech is difficult to get right: not only do batteries have to be made at an affordable cost while offering satisfactory levels of performance, they also need to be safe enough to pack into consumer gadgets. [12] That causes the particles to spread apart, making the film nonconductive so that electricity can no longer flow through the battery. [13] Since the nickel pieces are no longer adjoining, the battery stops working, but as it cools, the polyethylene contracts, allowing the particles to touch once again, and to conduct electricity as before. [11] Thanks to a new plastic overlay filled with nickel particles, the new battery shuts itself down when it gets too hot, only continuing to provide power when the levels of heat have dropped to a safe level again. [12] The battery shuts itself off when temperatures get too high, and powers back on once it's sufficiently cooled. [9] Reaching extreme temperatures, the battery is able to shut itself down, only restarting once it ha. [9] Every time, the battery shut down when it became too hot and quickly resumed operated when temperature cooled. [13] Designed to store energy on the electric grid, the high-capacity battery consists of molten metals that naturally separate to form two electrodes in layers on either side of the molten salt electrolyte between them. [32] Newly developed battery having auto-cutoff has high potential to prevent the fires that lead to recalls and bans on battery-powered devices. [13] A kind of battery race is currently in effect to build a better power storage device, including a solar-storage unit for the home marketed by Tesla called the Powerwall. [33] Essentially, the nickel stays within the core of the battery, while other materials encase it in a protective layer, the scientists said. [33] Even by having the top-notch Lithium-ion batteries, most of the smartphones/tablets doesn't give a long battery life as we we. [9] Comments ?A novel rechargeable battery developed at MIT could one day play a critical role in the massive expansion of solar generation needed to mitigate climate change by midcentury. [32] Back in 2013, we talked about a battery that used sodium and wood. [9] Zhenan Bao, a professor of chemical engineering at Stanford, said that efforts have been made to solve the problem of accidental fires in lithium-ion batteries. [13] The gadgets were developed by a team of experts at Stanford University, led by Zhenan Bao, professor of chemical energy, and the achievement was detailed in a study featured in the journal Nature Energy, on Monday, January 11. [11] The SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory at Stanford and the Brookhaven National Laboratory helped look at the material resulting at a nanoscale level, according to the latest study. [33] Such incidents have actually become a relatively frequent occurrence this holiday season, when several hoverboards powered by lithium ion batteries malfunctioned, setting on fire entire homes across the United States. [11] On an annual basis, several hundreds of millions lithium ion batteries are manufactured worldwide, being commonly incorporated in countless portable devices, which require recharging, such as laptops, cellphones, PDAs, cameras etc. [11] As Crabtree explains however, further testing should be conducted so as to determine if the new lithium ion batteries can stay safe even after stopping and restarting several times, or if this process becomes progressively less effective and reliable. [11] Newly invented adaptable lithium ion batteries stop if overheated, and restart soon after they've cooled, thus being much safer than their older versions, which can become highly flammable at times. [11] It's for the first time that scientists have proved so convincingly that lithium-ion batteries can be enhanced in order to eliminate all fire hazards associated with them. [11] While exploding phones are rather rare, lithium-ion batteries have been causing hoverboards to go up in flames, and many models have been pulled from sale. [12] Breakthrough offers a future alternative to lithium-ion batteries. [9] Materials could double the capacity of lithium-ion batteries. [9] That should prevent the battery's electrolyte from ever catching on fire. [12] They have done something different by designing the first battery can shut down and revive in the process involving repeated heating and cooling cycles without any impact on performance. [13] That being said, if you are a little paranoid about exploding batteries, you can start to rest a bit easier because scientists at Stanford have created the first lithium battery that won't explode. [34] It?s a good way to evaluate damage mechanisms in batteries, a way to understand battery materials better, he says. [35] Unfortunately, these techniques are irreversible, so the battery is no longer functional after it overheats, said the study's co-author Cui, an associate professor of materials science and engineering and of photon science. [34] That causes the particles to spread apart, making the film nonconductive so that electricity can no longer flow through the battery. [34] The particles would have to touch in order to conduct electricity, but the polyethylene stretches as the device grows increasingly hotter, spreading out the particles, and stopping electricity from flowing through the battery. [34] When the temperature was below 160 F again, the polyethylene shrank, the spikes came back into contact, and the battery started working (generating electricity) again. [34] The post Operation Begins of First Independent Large-Scale Battery Power Storage System to Balance Northeastern U.S. Electricity Grid appeared first on Solar Thermal Magazine. [36] Operation Begins of First Independent Large-Scale Battery Power Storage System to Balance Northeastern U.S. Electricity Grid (Wed, 13 Jan 2016) Sumitomo Corporation announced they are to commence operation of their innovative battery power storage system, Willey Battery Utility, LLC, that they have been constructing in Hamilton County, Ohio since April. [36] Hongjie Dai, a professor of chemistry at the university hailed it as a breakthrough in battery technology that went further than previous attempts using aluminium. [14] He said: We have developed a rechargeable aluminium battery that may replace existing storage devices, such as alkaline batteries, which are bad for the environment, and lithium-ion batteries, which occasionally burst into flames. [14] They've grown what they explain is a initial lithium ion battery that automatically shuts down before overheating and afterwards restarts itself once it's cooled off sufficiently. [37] We attached the polyethylene film to one of the battery electrodes so that an electric current could flow through it, said lead author Zheng Chen in a press release. [34] We trustworthy a polyethylene film to one of a battery electrodes so that an electric stream could upsurge by it, Zheng Chen, lead author of a investigate on a group's work, pronounced in a release. [37] Unlike a rechargeable battery, which takes in electricity, stores it, and then releases it, this system takes in mechanical energy and puts out electricity. [35] Our rechargeable aluminium battery generates about two volts of electricity. [14] ‘Our new battery won't catch fire, even if you drill through it. [14] It also has an OTC function to reverse charge multiple devices at the same time and the 10000mAg battery only needs 3.5 hours of charging to reach its full capacity. [14] The large battery works like a battery pack most smartphone creators offer and can recharge an iPhone 6S Plus up to three times before running out of juice. [14] While piezoelectric materials are based on a purely physical process, the new system is electrochemical, like a battery or a fuel cell. [35] Brueck explains that the bendy battery works best with normal, human-scale activity, like walking, poking, and bending. [35] The race already underway to improve battery charging technology. [14] Previously, the phenomenon underlying the new device was considered a parasitic effect in the battery community, according to Li, and voltage put into the battery could sometimes induce bending. [35] Oukitel has revealed the K10000, an Android handset with a battery 10 times the size of the iPhone 6S and runs for 10 to 15 days under normal use?. [14] Adjust brightness: Dimming the screen's brightness extends battery life.In addition, turning on Auto-Brightness allows the screen to adjust its brightness based on current lighting conditions. [14] The latest try to residence a risk by improved batteries comes from a group of Stanford chemical engineers. [37] The problem with those fiery hoverboards (which are unequivocally a kind of self-balancing scooter ) comes down to their lithium ion batteries filled with rarely incendiary element that can overheat and light when something goes wrong. [37] By contrast, the new system uses technology similar to that in lithium ion batteries, so it could likely be produced inexpensively at large scale, Li says. [35] It uses two thin sheets of lithium alloys as electrodes, separated by a layer of porous polymer soaked with liquid electrolyte that is efficient at transporting lithium ions between the metal plates. [35] When the sandwich is bent, unequal stresses cause lithium ions to migrate across the electrolyte, producing a compensating electron current that can be harnessed by an external circuit. [35] When bent even a slight amount, the layered composite produces a pressure difference that squeezes lithium ions through the polymer (like the reverse osmosis process used in water desalination). [35] As well as the ‘unprecedented charging times', the team said its prototype is also safer than lithium-ion batteries as it was less prone to catching fire and more environmentally friendly than alkaline models such as AA and AAA. [14] Batteries twice as powerful as those currently available may finally herald the breakthrough of electric cars. [38] The breakthrough involves regulating nanotechnology privately by building spiky nickel particles coated in graphene that can afterwards be embedded in a skinny cosmetic film. [37] Fort Wayne Journal Gazette There's been another breakthrough in the study of the Greenland ice sheet, whose increasing melt rate and growing contribution to global sea-level rise has captured the attention and concern of climate scientists in recent years. [39] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (39 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) Related Related Articles
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/c48be56a-af2b-394f-9297-92298a3194b2" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-14T08:53:54Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:49:51.53Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/stanford-researchers-new-lithium-ion-battery-breakthrough/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
