<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Full Description <NODE id="17" />Acuity Brands, Inc.<NODE id="36" /> (<NODE id="38" />Acuity Brands<NODE id="51" />), incorporated on September 20, 2007, is the <NODE id="97" />parent<NODE id="103" /> company of <NODE id="115" />Acuity Brands Lighting, Inc.<NODE id="143" /> (<NODE id="145" />ABL<NODE id="148" />), and other subsidiaries. Acuity Brands is a provider of lighting solutions for commercial, institutional, industrial, infrastructure, and residential applications throughout North America and select international markets. The Company's lighting solutions include devices, such as luminaires, lighting controls, power supplies, prismatic skylights, light-emitting diode (LED) lamps, and integrated lighting systems for indoor and outdoor applications utilizing a combination of light sources, including daylight, and other devices controlled by software that monitors and manages light levels while optimizing energy consumption (collectively referred to herein as lighting solutions). On March 13, 2013, the Company acquired eldoLED Europe BV. The Company manufactures lighting devices primarily in North America, Europe and Asia. The Company's lighting solutions are marketed under numerous brand names, including Lithonia Lighting, Holophane, Peerless, Mark Architectural Lighting, Hydrel, American Electric Lighting, Gotham, Carandini, RELOC, Antique Street Lamps, Tersen, Winona Lighting, Synergy Lighting Controls, Sensor Switch, Lighting Control &amp; Design, Dark to Light, ROAM, Sunoptics, acculamp, Pathway Connectivity, and Healthcare Lighting. As of August 31, 2014, the Company manufactures products in 14 facilities in North America and two facilities in Europe. Principal customers include electrical distributors, retail home improvement centers, electric utilities, municipalities, lighting showrooms, and energy service companies located in North America and select international markets serving new construction, renovation, and facility maintenance applications. In North America, the Company's lighting solutions are sold primarily by independent sales agents, electrical wholesalers, and factory sales representatives who cover specific geographic areas and market channels. Products are delivered directly or through a network of distribution centers, regional warehouses, and commercial warehouses using both common carriers and a company-owned truck fleet. During the fiscal year ended August 31, 2014 (fiscal 2013), North American sales accounted for approximately 98% of net sales. The Company has one operating segment serving the North American lighting market and select international markets. The Company provides a range of lighting solutions, as well as services used in the applications, such as lighting solutions and services. Lighting solutions and services includes commercial, industrial, infrastructure, residential and services. Lighting solutions are delivered directly from manufacturing facilities or through a network of strategically located distribution centers, regional warehouses, and commercial warehouses in North America using both common carriers and a company-owned truck fleet. For international customers, distribution methods are adapted to meet individual customer or country requirements. Sales of lighting solutions, excluding services, accounted for approximately 99% of total consolidated net sales for Acuity Brands in fiscal 2014. The Company competes with Koninklijke Philips N.V., Eaton Corporation, Hubbell Incorporated, Schneider Electric, and Cree, Inc. » Full Overview of AYI.N
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/a9e946e4-0268-3876-a988-3d3581548127" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-08T02:59:29Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:39:37.37Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/companyProfile?symbol=AYI.N" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="17" endPos="36" type="organization-company" surface="Acuity Brands, Inc." />
<Entity id="1" startPos="38" endPos="51" type="organization-company" surface="Acuity Brands" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="97" endPos="103" type="trigger" surface="parent" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="115" endPos="143" type="organization-company" surface="Acuity Brands Lighting, Inc." />
<Entity id="4" startPos="145" endPos="148" type="organization-company" surface="ABL" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="5" NAME="CompanyRelationship">
<Entity id="0" label="parent" />
<Entity id="2" label="trigger" />
<Entity id="3" label="child" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
