<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>How Engineers Help Architects Posted By: BCNet Staff February 9, 2016 C O N T E N T S: Image Courtesy: link: http://www.bizjournals.com/kansascity/print-edition/2011/11/04/bibb-engineers-architects.html author: bizjournals.com description: Bob Bibb likes to keep himself KEY TOPICS The city boasts world-leading architects, engineers and contractors, giving service companies like DTE the opportunity to help connect a variety of members of the architecture, engineering and construction industry. [1] Demystify New York State's 2015 Energy Conservation Construction Code with Conquer the Code, a training course to help architects and engineers design more energy-efficient buildings. [2] The solution that can help architects and engineers overcome these pain points involves the integration of new technology. [3] Architects who are protective of their vision might feel that structure can get in the way, says Clare Olsen, assistant professor of architecture at Cal Poly San Luis Obispo and proprietor of design firm C.O.CO. Their frustrations come about when the engineers don?t recognize the vision and value of a particular architectural goal. [4] Who?s Getting It Right? Various architects and engineers were interviewed from large firms such as SOM, Gensler, and ARUP for the case studies in Collaborations in Architecture and Engineering. [4] Haines notes that in many cases architects and engineers are unwilling to sacrifice time on a project, due to the observation that more time spent on design can lead to a better end result. [1] For their Berlin Hauptbahnhof (train station) project, SBP?s lead engineer, Hans Schober, said he looked to the architects to stimulate innovation among engineers. [4] Whether a budding engineer or a seasoned professional architect, keep calm and remember the words of Euge-Emmanuel Viollet-le-Duc : The interests of both professions will be saved by their union. (But no one will blame you if you still need to write a Reddit rant for a cathartic release.) [4] The SBP engineers compromised because they were brought along early with the architects? vision, and the architects didn?t feel stunted by the structural limitations. [4] After graduating, an architect might describe his vision, from which a young engineer could isolate 19 different problems. [4] If you go back far enough in time, an engineer and an architect were the same person, Mac Namara says. [4] The challenge I find in dealing with architects and engineers is getting them to appreciate that spending money on the technology should be justified on improving efficiency. [1] Today, words don?t necessarily mean the same thing to an architect as they do an engineer, and they can attribute different meanings to identical words. [4] Considering that the BIM process allows professionals to access more detailed information about buildings at various stages before, during, and after construction, 3D-design software-- Autodesk Revit, for example--can help designers and engineers make sound design decisions early on. [4] The negative stereotypes go like this: Architects have their creative visions in the clouds while structural engineers hold fast to data and science, with no compromise for innovation or beauty. [4] Grassi &amp; Co., one of New York's leading accounting and consulting firms, helps architects, engineers, interior designers, facilities managers, and other architecture and engineering industry professionals overcome financial challenges by providing high-quality, efficient services. [5] The User?s Manual to ANSI/ASHRAE/USGBC/IES Standard 189.1-2014, Standard for the Design of High-Performance, Green Buildings Except Low-Rise Residential Buildings, is intended to help engineers, architects, and contractors understand and comply with the standard and to help code officials and others enforce its requirements. [6] The Premium edition provides an optimized set of tools to help architects, MEP engineers, and structural engineers take advantage of the power of BIM with intelligent 3D modelbased design. [7] Drafters use software to convert the designs of engineers and architects into technical drawings. [8] Using a dedicated, cloud-based construction software solution, architects and engineers can effortlessly communicate with contractors and project managers in real time to seamlessly collaborate on ideas, problems, RFIs, and punch lists so that nothing falls through the cracks and everyone knows exactly what needs to be done to get the job finished on schedule and under budget. [3] With both fresh-eyed students and grizzled veterans agreeing on the need for technological solutions to the problems plaguing the world of architects and engineers, construction companies can look to Procore for the answer. [3] Architects and engineers are typically the first parties to take action when a client decides to begin construction on a new property development. [3] Marine engineers and naval architects design, build, and maintain ships from aircraft carriers to submarines, from sailboats to tankers. [8] Using construction software on a construction project allows every individual involved with a job--from the architects and engineers to the contractors--to provide critical feedback from the initial stages. [3] Integrate More Technology There's a simple way to solve the range of problems currently afflicting architects and engineers. [3] By overcoming these obstacles, architects and engineers have the potential to boost productivity and alleviate miscommunication. [3] Following the architects and the engineers, building services consultants and structural engineers get involved to determine the project's feasibility and what it will take to complete construction. [3] With so many people involved in the process of bringing the architects and engineers' vision to life, it should come as no surprise that mistakes, miscommunications, and adversarial viewpoints create problems during the construction process. [3] Unfortunately too many architects, engineers and contractors peg marketing departments as overhead and not the lead generating tool and revenue driver they can be. [9] Civil engineering technicians help civil engineers to plan, design, and build highways, bridges, utilities, and other infrastructure projects. [8] Industrial engineering technicians help industrial engineers implement designs to use personnel, materials, and machines effectively in factories, stores, healthcare organizations, repair shops, and offices. [8] Mechanical engineering technicians help mechanical engineers design, develop, test, and manufacture mechanical devices, including tools, engines, and machines. [8] Electrical and electronics engineering technicians help engineers design and develop computers, communications equipment, medical monitoring devices, navigational equipment, and other electrical and electronic equipment. [8] The survey will help determine the knowledge and skills required of a licensed architectural engineer with 4 to 6 years of experience to practice in a manner that safeguards the health, safety, and welfare of the public. [10] The operators of Lexington Market is putting out a call for architects and engineers to help with the $26.7 million overhaul of the historic public market on downtown?s west side. [11] The program will also provide an array of risk management resources focused on helping architects and engineers understand and mitigate the exposures they face. [12] You may work 48 weeks a year, slaving away, trying to meet the demands of engineers and architects. [13] Hopefully, I?ve convinced you that it is OK to give gifts to engineers and architects (or other people you work with). [13] This year I want to tackle giving gifts, specifically gifts for engineers and architects. [13] You probably spend more time with engineers and architects than you spend with mom and dad. [13] Here's my list of thoughtful gifts for engineers, architects, etc. You can get them on Amazon. [13] Are they fully licensed architects or engineers? Of course not. [14] Autodesk® Building Design Suite is a comprehensive portfolio of building solutions supporting both BIM- and CAD-based workflows, giving architects, engineers and contractors the ability to design, simulate, visualize and construct better buildings. [7] Customizable coverage for a diverse range of architects, engineers and design firms. [12] Marketing has long been a taboo subject for architects and engineers. [14] As Principal Engineer, you?ll work closely with the CTO, Director, Software Engineering, Team Leads, and Principal Engineers to help define and guide our technology strategy. [15] Some companies have teams of security experts, including engineers, to help protect the overall internal network. [16] Soft skills help security engineers build relationships within an organization. [16] A security engineer usually builds new systems to help protect current networking assets. [16] Anything you can do to make an architect or engineer's life more calming and tranquil will actually help your life. [13] Security engineers are somewhat of a hybrid of network engineers, system engineers and security architects. [16] When it comes to the design of a building, an architect is able to create the idea of a new building and the engineer can help to make sure the structure will be safe, stable, and cost effective. [17] As Belzberg Architects founder Hagy Belzberg points out, architects usually work out a schematic design in response to a client's needs, only later to invite the engineer to help substantiate their idea. [18] Architects have long relied on engineers to help execute formally or functionally complex concepts. [18] Autodesk Architecture, Engineering, and Construction solutions help architects, engineers, builders and owners improve the way they design, build, and manage projects. [19] Engineering Ministries International (EMI) is a non-profit Christian development organization made up of architects, engineers and design professionals who donate their skills to help children and families around the world step out of poverty and into a world of hope. [20] To further advance the adoption of high security smart card-based physical access control systems (PACS), the Smart Card Alliance tool, Guide Specification for Architects and Engineers for Smart Card-based PACS Cards and Readers for Non-government PACS, helps architects, engineers, consultants, integrators, manufacturers and end users incorporate smart card-based PACS cards and readers into architectural and engineering specifications for non-government facilities. [21] As the premier architecture conference for senior engineers, SATURN offers keynotes and sessions on both essential skills and cutting-edge methods for software architects. [22] Every architect or engineer believes their team or firm is the best. [23] In some cases, no error is made, yet you as a professional architect or engineer may be unjustly blamed. [17] The risks that architects and engineers face should not be approached without a proper insurance program in place. [17] If an architect or engineer makes a mistake, it can result in additional costs to others. [17] What Makes an Architect Successful? A proposed model identifies the skills that a successful software architect needs at each phase of a development effort and helps explain common failure patterns. [22] With the overhaul of the Intern Development Program (IDP) launching on June 29, NCARB has developed a calculator tool to help interns pursuing licensure as architects determine how their experience hours will transition from the program?s current 17 areas into the six new experience areas. [24] The candidate will help architect new solutions and flesh out the product ideas that meet high level product management goals. [25] The guide specification is written using industry standard formatting and language (e.g., Construction Specification Institute (CSI) Division 28 - Electronic Safety and Security Section 28 13 Electronic Security System), and is designed for use by architects, consultants, and specifying engineers who are preparing bid specifications for physical access control, building control, and security systems for non-government facilities. [21] When your little one reaches for building blocks over action figures, you know you've got a budding architect or engineer on your hands. [26] Block Games for Budding Architects and Engineers You are using an outdated browser. [26] The architect or engineer preparing the actual smart card specifications should therefore refer to and confirm actual manufacturer?s specifications. [21] The Equitable Distribution Program establishes a pool of architects, landscape architects and engineers available to County departments for professional services on miscellaneous type capital projects. [27] This white paper was developed by the Smart Card Alliance Access Control Council to provide a tool for architects, engineers, consultants, integrators, manufacturers and end users to incorporate smart card-based physical access control cards and readers into specifications for non-government PACS implementations. [21] In accordance with the desires of the clients, landscape architects offer engineers ideas on how to best utilize the space and can help arrange items to maximize the land area the engineer is working with. [28] Accord Architects &amp; Engineers (aa+e) is an architecture and engineering firm located in Myrtle Beach, South Carolina. [29] Accord Architects &amp; Engineers offers over 35 years of experience to their services which include commercial real estate design, residential real estate design, industrial design, federal projects, medical projects, educational design as well as the hospitality industry. [29] As an Architectural or Engineering Project Manager, it is important to stay in close contact with teams at the project site such as designers, contractors, engineers, construction crews, landscape architects and other members in the field. [30] Our team of nearly 40 professionals includes licensed engineers, land surveyors and landscape architects who understand land development and construction. [31] Some may be surprised to discover that landscape architects have a hand in all these features, helping engineers and architects to organize the elements and make them work in the design. [28] CADdetails is the leading provider of manufacturer-specific building product information, delivering to more than 435,000 architects, engineers, contractors, and other design industry professionals throughout North America. [32] FDI is an independent agency that provides insurance to Engineers, Architects and Surveyors throughout the state of Florida. [33] Providing specialized insurance for Engineers, Architects &amp; Surveyors. [33] Architects &amp; Engineers - One-Page and Multi-Page - Site Templates ThemeForest no longer actively supports this version of Internet Explorer. [34] Tony has worked for over a decade specializing in providing insurance for Engineers &amp; Architects. [33] With his continuing growth in Errors &amp; Omission Insurance, Professional Liability Insurance &amp; much more while working at an independent agency that also specializes in insurance for architects &amp; engineers you can be well assured you are dealing with an expert in the industry. [33] Because of his specialization in insurance for Architects &amp; Engineers he is able to provide unique insight, options &amp; pricing. [33] There?s a reason we have two big ears and one mouth: Landscape architects excel in listening to what clients desire and can offer ideas for bringing those unique thoughts to engineers to plug in the details. [28] Weihe Engineers sponsored employee Jamie Shinneman as he ran the Indianapolis Monumental Marathon (26.2 miles) with Team World Vision and Northview Church to help bring clean water to people in Africa. [31] POSSIBLY USEFUL In chapter four of Collaborations in Architecture and Engineering, which examined the Hauptbahnhof, Schober said: Some engineers might be happy if they find one solution that works; our experience is that there are a lot of solutions--not only one economic or efficient optimum solution. [4] In terms of identity, engineers are taught in school to solve problems using their chosen functional specialties, such as structural engineering. [4] Before the station opened in 2006, there was a point during construction when the structural approach came to a crossroads: The architects? design called for a glass wall on one side of the building, but the engineers suggested a structural cable net. [4] Since 1999, DTE has engaged CATIA -based solutions to designers, engineers and building manufacturers. [1] Years of training and supporting its customers in the use and application of this software had taught DTE?s experts that there were ways designers and engineers could reap big benefits. [1] If the engineer is not brought into the process early, she might assume the architect?s familiarity with a concept. [4] Structural engineer Price &amp; Myers, which has used 3D engineering to secure a reputation of engineering geometrically and structurally complex projects and take on more challenging projects. [1] Today, more and more owners are looking to speed along high-quality design, and architects are looking for new solutions to meet that demand. [1] It alleviates some of the traditional challenges associated with having the architect in charge? of all the consultants on the project, Olsen says. [4] Architects are taught to think about the whole picture--to have a vision for a completed structure. [4] The architect may be uncomfortable revealing his lack of technical knowledge. [4] It can help them save time and money by preventing issues later in the process. [4] How were these companies succeeding? To start, a good process can help calm turbulent waters of communication. [4] They also help to plan, design, and build commercial, industrial, residential, and land development projects. [8] Most workers specialize in architectural, civil, electrical, or mechanical drafting and use technical drawings to help design everything from microchips to skyscrapers. [8] Biomedical engineers combine engineering principles with medical and biological sciences to design and create equipment, devices, computer systems, and software used in healthcare. [8] Environmental engineers use the principles of engineering, soil science, biology, and chemistry to develop solutions to environmental problems. [8] Environmental engineering technicians carry out the plans that environmental engineers develop. They test, operate, and, if necessary, modify equipment used to prevent or clean up environmental pollution. [8] Health and safety engineers develop procedures and design systems to prevent people from getting sick or injured and to keep property from being damaged. [8] Materials engineers develop, process, and test materials used to create a wide range of products, from computer chips and aircraft wings to golf clubs and biomedical devices. [8] Chemical engineers apply the principles of chemistry, biology, physics, and math to solve problems that involve the production or use of chemicals, fuel, drugs, food, and many other products. [8] Agricultural engineers attempt to solve agricultural problems concerning power supplies, the efficiency of machinery, the use of structures and facilities, pollution and environmental issues, and the storage and processing of agricultural products. [8] Mining and geological engineers design mines to safely and efficiently remove minerals such as coal and metals for use in manufacturing and utilities. [8] Civil engineers design, build, supervise, operate, and maintain construction projects and systems in the public and private sector, including roads, buildings, airports, tunnels, dams, bridges, and systems for water supply and sewage treatment. [8] Mechanical engineers design, develop, build, and test mechanical and thermal sensors and devices, including tools, engines, and machines. [8] Electrical engineers design, develop, test, and supervise the manufacturing of electrical equipment, such as electric motors, radar and navigation systems, communications systems, and power generation equipment.Electronics engineers design and develop electronic equipment, such as broadcast and communications systems--from portable music players to global positioning systems (GPSs). [8] Petroleum engineers design and develop methods for extracting oil and gas from deposits below the Earth?s surface. [8] NCEES requires a cross section of licensed professional engineers practicing architectural engineering--including those working in industry, consulting, the public sector, and academia--to complete an online survey. [10] Many of these engineers find industrial and medical uses for radioactive materials--for example, in equipment used in medical diagnosis and treatment. [8] Aerospace engineers design primarily aircraft, spacecraft, satellites, and missiles. [8] These engineers discover new directions in computer hardware, which generate rapid advances in computer technology. [8] Architects plan and design houses, factories, office buildings, and other structures. [8] Naval architects are primarily responsible for the ship design, including the form, structure, and stability of hulls. [8] Landscape architects design parks and the outdoor spaces of campuses, recreational facilities, private homes, and other open areas. [8] At Grassi &amp; Co., our team of industry experts takes great pride in developing an understanding of our clients? businesses and, more importantly, leveraging this knowledge to develop strategic, operational, and financial recommendations to help bring A&amp;E firms to the next level of success. [5] Grassi &amp; Co.' s A&amp;E Industry Practice has the capabilities to assist firms in the following areas and help them achieve their short and long-term objectives. [5] These studies help NCEES ensure its licensing exams remain relevant to current professional practice, explained Director of Exam Services Tim Miller, P.E. The value of this PAKS depends on the number of people who participate, so NCEES is eager to get a large response from P.E.s across all areas of architectural engineering. [10] Marketing can help you communicate your company?s unique employee environment. [9] When the nation undergoes build booms, geospatial intelligence helps you design better buildings, parks, and roads. [35] Applicants are also responsible for identify any hardware or software issues that could be a future vulnerability, and work with managers to help change the architecture. [16] They understand the Solution Context and work with the teams, Customers, and Suppliers to help ensure fitness for use in the Customer's environment. [36] You?ll work as part of our agile development teams and collaborate with product owners, ScrumMasters, and other stakeholders to help implement our technology strategy and new product features. [15] Whether you work from a desktop or an enterprise platform, AECOM GIS solutions will help you solve real-world environmental problems. [35] You many need to work with other security specialists to help mitigate damages during current attacks. [16] Aon Affinity is a trade name for Affinity Insurance Services, Inc. Aon Affinity combines the specialized knowledge of affinity program management with the extensive resources of a global company to help clients achieve their goals. [12] We have industry experts to help you learn more about how to solve problems and add value with Esri. [35] These days, most firms understand that the right marketing partnership can reduce RFP churn, help increase business and maximize profits. [14] In the last year, we?ve had 1,140 people join the Help Everybody Army. [13] Learn how MEP engineers design and document building systems with BIM. (3:02 mins.) [7] Points is looking for a Principal Engineer to join our Software Engineering team for a permanent position. [15] Carlson GIS is a highly configurable GIS Swiss Army Knife for surveyors and engineers, with tools for data capture and linking, polygon topology creation and analysis, and more. [35] Some companies still require a degree, but engineers can also get past the degree requirement with relevant certifications and experience. [16] A security engineer understands how to design architecture that protects the company. [16] A security engineer does more building of architecture than monitoring systems. [16] Security engineers are mostly a part of architecture teams, so coding skills are somewhat valued but not a necessity. [16] For security engineers to understand different hardware and software vulnerabilities, they need some experience, so this profession is one that is a goal for many network and system administrators who want to be in the security field. [16] Most security engineers must know how to build security networks including cloud systems. [16] Learn how structural engineers design and analyse structures with BIM. (2:36 mins.) [7] Learn how architects realise the benefits of BIM throughout the design process. (2:50 mins.) [7] The role of an Architect often extends beyond just the software domain to include responsibilities that enable value delivery in a technologically diverse and heterogeneous, multi-domain solution environment, so SAFe takes a fairly expansive view of that role. [36] The role of an Architect is common in software development and has been included in SAFe as one of the critical roles at the program and portfolio levels. [36] This coverage would protect an architect who provides incorrect professional advice or recommendations regarding construction or design requirements to a client. [17] We think you will agree that when it comes time for creating that perfect design for your new home or the amazing new entrance of your existing office building or even the catwalk that spans the foyer of the new model home, it takes more than being an just an architect to do so. [37] However today, there are still some architects and designers, following the same old rudimentary and time consuming conventional methods to create and communicate their architectural designs. [38] Rocky Mountain Group RMG Engineers integrates the engineering services and architectural design into one complete and coordinated set of documents. [37] The skill sets in which we hold to heart here at Rocky Mountain Group RMG Engineers is that architecture needs to be more than just being able to produce a great design. (we are exceptional at great designs and we thought you might want to know now.) [37] Collaborate with engineers or software developers to select appropriate design solutions or ensure the compatibility of system components. [39] Belzberg's own experience collaborating with facade engineers at Arup suggests a different approach--one in which the designers and consultants trade ideas and expertise from the very beginning. [18] Need assistance in the design of a Lighting project or some product options to help with your required energy analysis? Stouch Lighting?s team of Lighting Experts will provide the product options to ensure that your customers' objectives are achieved. [40] With that, Matt gave us a peek into the shoot-from-the-hip style he uses on his site, Help Everybody Everyday, where he offers marketing advice and support to those in the architecture, engineering and construction industries. [23] The SEI helps advance software engineering principles and practices and serves as a national resource in software engineering, computer security, and process improvement. [22] This also helps to lessen the conflicts and time delays that can occur when the architectural and structural elements are designed by different consultants. [37] The building will be a case study in how adaptive facades can help us reappropriate existing buildings so we don't have to knock them down, said Belzberg. [18] The long and short of it is, the best marketing you can do is to help people. [23] During the 60s and early 70s, architects were barred from marketing their services. [23] Registration for SATURN, the premier conference for software architects, is now open. [22] But we want people to come in with case studies of their own that we can work on: Not just questions and answers, but we're hoping that other architects will bring real-life scenarios so that we can brainstorm opportunities. [18] Digital fabrication technology, he explained, allowed Belzberg Architects to craft a new envelope that is highly sculptural and unique, but still performative. [18] AIA Convention is one of the largest and most exciting annual gatherings of architects and design professionals in the U.S. The people, the ideas, the environment, the setting--it all comes together for an unforgettable experience that comes just once a year. [41] Presales engineer responsible for Service Provider Architecture solution planning and design. [42] Join CAF for 2016's Engineering Fest, our celebration of National Engineers Week. [43] The postsales engineer is responsible for solution implementation and operation. [42] Leading AEC firms use Autodesk model-based design and construction solutions, together with integrated building energy analysis tools, to help owners better understand how changes and improvements will affect energy use, payback, emissions, and utility costs throughout the building lifecycle, in addition to providing hard-cost savings during conceptual design and pre-construction. [19] With the Cisco Service Provider Architecture Specialization, you can sell service provider (SP) architecture solutions that help customers reduce operating costs and accelerate revenue growth. [42] Help your customers bring new services to market faster and enhance the end-user experience. [42] Since its introduction of AutoCAD software in 1982, Autodesk continues to develop the broadest portfolio of state-of-the-art software to help customers experience their ideas digitally before they are built. [19] Luckily, a resurgence in simple, classic, quality toys means building games are easier to find and can help your tiny Frank Lloyd Wright shift focus from noisy video games to quiet creativity. [26] Building sets, block games, and new twists on old favorites help to nurture your future I.M. Pei. [26] The group brings together, in an open forum, leading users and technologists from both the public and private sectors and works on activities that are important to the access control community and that will help expand smart card technology adoption in this important market. [21] We're always looking for ways to improve our site, so we want to know why you're here and how we can help you find the information you need. [43] Take advantage of this opportunity to showcase your firm as a thought leader in front of influential architects and designers. [19] Bespoke recruit Architects, Interior Designers and Creative business support staff at all levels. [19] For more than a quarter century, the world's top architects and designers have put their trust in ABC Stone. [19] The AIA Board of Directors voted to award the duo with the Gold Medal for their scholarly writings and built work, which inspired a generation of architects. [41] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (43 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) 1. (26) Architecture and Engineering Occupations : Occupational Outlook Handbook: : U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics Previous post Be the first to comment on How Engineers Help Architects
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/05a9c0ef-4a1d-3983-bffe-c3728f99f4c4" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-09T22:28:11Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:37:27.934Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.bostoncommons.net/how-engineers-help-architects/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
