<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2 litre 0 1 7 0 0 0 Mileage Petrol Aug 2012 Manual Convertible 43 MPG £56 Cost to fill 501 Tank range (miles) 24 Insurance group £180 Road tax 4 Seats Vehicle Trim / Variant: Sport Plus Edition Insurance Group 24, 2 Registered Keepers, A Stunning BMW 118i Sport Plus Convertible Finished in Space Grey Metallic with Full Boston Oyster Leather Trim, Covered 17k Miles with BMW Service History, BMW Service / Maintenance Pack Until 2017, Great Specification with Features 18 Double-Spoke Style 313 Alloy Wheels, Automatic Air Conditioning, Heated Front Seats, BMW Professional Audio with USB Interface, Bluetooth Handsfree Telephone Connectivity, Front and Rear Park Distance Control, Cruise Control, Xenon Headlamps, Rain Sensor, Light Package, Storage Compartment Package, ISOFIX System for Child Seats, Front Armrest, Front Fog Lights, <NODE id="837" />Rain Sensor<NODE id="848" />, Alarm System and Much More, Part Exchange Welcome, Finance Arranged Subject to Status, Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0117 321 5723 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Performance Point Welcome to our showroom of performance and prestige vehicles. We have retail premises based in Winterstoke Road, Bristol where vehicles can be viewed 7 days a week. We can also arrange test drive by appointment. For directions, please click the location button above. Please enjoy browsing our website with the peace of mind that whatever your requirements you can be assured that we have the experience to offer the best quality vehicles at very competitive prices. 0117 321 5723 Email dealer Other cars from this dealer: View all cars at this dealer PARKERS Review Rating If you're after a stylish and small convertible, BMW's 1-Series Convertible fits the bill perfectly.... read more Great to drive, neat styling, wonderful cabin, feels as solid as the Coupe Limited room in the back, fabric roof operation is slow Review provided by: The following features are fitted to this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Alloy wheels Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Leather seat trim Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment fitted to this car... This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0117 321 5723 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle Comfort / Convenience 12V power socket in centre console 3 spoke leather M multi-function steering wheel ABS Air microfilter ASC+T Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic air conditioning + active carbon filter Battery in luggage with jump start facility Black door sill finishers with BMW designation Boston leather upholstery CBC - (Cornering brake control) DSC-Dynamic Stability Control Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric front and rear windows with fingertip open/close + anti-trap all round Electronic brake force distribution Engine start/stop button Front centre armrest with storage compartment Front head restraints Front passenger isofix child seat attachment Front sports seats with electric side bolster adjustment Handbrake and gear lever in sensatec Individual anthracite headlining Isofix rear child seat fastenings Leather gear lever Leather handbrake Lights on warning Load restraint lashing eyes Luggage strap Oil level indicator On board computer On-board diagnosis - OBD Outside temperature display Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear adjustable/removable head restraints Rear seat easy access Rear seat storage trays Run flat tyre indicator Service interval indicator Toolkit located in luggage compartment Tyre puncture warning system Windscreen wipers with adjustable interval Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio with CD player Exterior / Styling 18 double spoke light alloy wheels style 313M Body colour door handles Body coloured bumper strips Body coloured bumpers Brake force display Chrome kidney grille with black vertical slats Electro hydraulic fully automatic soft top Enhanced lighting - 1 Series Convertible Front fog lights/heated windscreen washer jets/heated door mirrors M Aerodynamic pack - 1 series Run flat tyres Twin matt chrome round exhaust pipes Safety / Security 2 rear 3 point inertia reel seatbelts 3 point inertia reel seatbelts on front seats Centre lock switch Crash sensor Driver and passenger airbags Front side airbags Occupancy sensor for passenger seat Pyrotechnically pre-tensioned front seatbelts Remote alarm system/immobiliser Remote central locking Seat belt force limiter Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications... The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. 152 CO2 (g/km) 143 Performance (BHP) 43 MPG £56 Cost to fill 501 Tank range (miles) 24 Insurance group £180 Road tax 4 Seats 2 Doors Petrol Aug 2012 Manual Convertible Grey Emissions CO2 (g/km) 152 Engine and Drive Train Camshaft DOHC Cylinder Layout IN-LINE Cylinders 4 Engine Layout NORTH SOUTH Fuel Delivery MULTI POINT FUEL INJECTION Gears 6 SPEED Transmission MANUAL Fuel Consumption EC Combined (mpg) 43.5 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 52.3 EC Urban (mpg) 33.6 General Insurance Group 1 - 50 Effective January 07 24E Manufacturers Corrosion Perforation Guarantee - Years 6 Manufacturers Paintwork Guarantee - Years 3 NCAP Adult Occupant Protection % NA NCAP Child Occupant Protection % NA NCAP Overall Rating - Effective February 09 NA NCAP Pedestrian Protection % NA Service Interval Frequency - Months 24 Service Interval Mileage 30000 Standard manufacturers warranty - Mileage 999999 Standard manufacturers warranty - Years 3 Performance 0 to 60 mph (secs) False 0 to 62 mph (secs) 9.3 Engine Power - BHP 143 Engine Torque - LBS.FT 140 Engine Torque - NM 190 Top Speed 130 Tyres Wheel Style DOUBLE SPOKE STYLE 313M Wheel Type 18 ALLOY Vehicle Dimensions Height 1411 Height (including roof rails) NA Length 4360 Wheelbase 2660 Width 1748 Width (including mirrors) 1919 Weight and Capacities Fuel Tank Capacity (Litres) 53 Gross Vehicle Weight 1860 Luggage Capacity (Seats Down) NA Luggage Capacity (Seats Up) 305 Max. Loading Weight 440 Max. Roof Load NA Max. Towing Weight - Braked 1200 Max. Towing Weight - Unbraked 670 Minimum Kerbweight 1420 No. of Seats 4 Turning Circle - Kerb to Kerb 10.7 Finance to suit your monthly budget. Adjust finance options Preferred Term Optional Deposit (£) Annual Mileage Finance terms &amp; conditions
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/43ced786-e8ea-3a5c-bbfd-59d0a5322847" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-17T04:07:09Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:00:50.593Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.motors.co.uk/car-38713312/av" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="837" endPos="848" type="product-class" surface="Rain Sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
