<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Westbury Jeep Chrysler Dodge 100 Jericho Turnpike in Jericho, Long Island, NY 11753 Learn More: http://www.westburyjeep.com/new/Chrysler/2015-Chrysler-Town+%26+Country-Long+Island-266ce20a0a0a00de67b738972d7ae545.htm Discerning drivers will appreciate the 2015 Chrysler Town &amp; Country. It features a front-wheel-drive platform, an automatic transmission, and a refined 6 cylinder engine. Top features include front bucket seats, voice activated navigation, automatic dimming door mirrors, power front seats, tilt steering wheel, <NODE id="529" />blind spot sensor<NODE id="546" />, cruise control, and a split folding rear seat. Features such as automatic climate control and leather upholstery prove that economical transportation does not need to be sparsely equipped. Storage solutions are integrated throughout the interior, demonstrating thoughtful attention to detail. Rear passengers enjoy the seat heating functionality, keeping them warm during the winter months. Passengers in the third row enjoy seat back reclining functionality, providing an extra level of comfort and convenience. Premium sound drives 6 speakers, providing you and your passengers a sensational audio experience. Rear LCD monitors provide entertainment that your passengers will appreciate no matter how far the drive. Chrysler also prioritized safety and security by including: head curtain airbags, front SIDE impact airbags, traction control, brake assist, anti-whiplash front head restraints, a security system, and 4 wheel disc brakes with ABS. Electronic stability control ensures solid grip atop the road surface, no matter how challenging the driving conditions. Our team is professional, and we offer a no-pressure environment. They'll work with you to find the right vehicle at a price you can afford. We are here to help you. Tags: new 2015 Chrysler Town &amp; Country Touring-L Van car vehicle automobile Jericho,Long Island NY 11753
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0eb96bf1-feef-3115-b1b9-94ae94ae8666" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-31T20:11:29Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:40:51.37Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0um7IUeoRZ0" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="529" endPos="546" type="product" surface="blind spot sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
