<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>infoTECH News [February 09, 2016] Global Smart Commercial Technologies Market Report - Analysis, Technologies, Trends &amp; Forecasts 2016-2022 - Key Vendors: Google, Intel &amp; Microsoft DUBLIN , Feb. 9, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- Research and Markets ( http://www.researchandmarkets.com/research/42964t/smart_commercial ) has announced the addition of the Smart Commercial Technologies - Technologies, Lighting Lamps (HID, LED, CFL), Components, Applications - Global Market Drivers, Opportunities, Trends, and Forecasts, 2016-2022 report to their offering. The Smart Commercial Lighting market is a multibillion market which started witnessing growth from the beginning of the current decade. The Smart Commercial Lighting market is witnessing growth mainly due to the growing demand for the environment friendly and energy saving solutions from different industry verticals. The smart commercial lighting solutions available today can automatically adjust themselves according to the time of the day (i.e. daylight simulation lighting) while for traditional lighting systems manually settings are need to be done. The smart commercial lighting is gaining popularity as it helps in dealing with the seasonal depressions and reducing elctricity bills such as in hospitals and offices and educational institutes. The wireless technologies and smart network components such as <NODE id="1364" />sensors<NODE id="1371" /> are supporting the growth of this market. These network components help in secure and reliable transfer of data between the connected devices. Few of the smart lighting lamps available today are bluetooth enabled Compact Fluorescent Lights (CFL),Wi-Fi enabled Light-Emitting Diode (LED) and ZigBee enabled lighting systems. This study covers and analyses Smart Commercial market globally. Bringing out the complete key insights of this industry, this reports aims to provide opportunity for players to understand the latest trends, current market scenario, government initiatives, and technologies related to the market. In addition, helps the venture capitalist in understanding the companies better and take informed decisions. Companies Mentioned: Acuity Brands Lighting, Inc. Cisco Systems, Inc. Cyan Technologies Plc. GE Lighting Google Inc. Intel Corporation International Business Machines Corp.(IBM) John Cullen Lighting Koninklijke Philips N.V., Microsoft Corporation Report Structure: 1 Industry Outlook
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1ef01e84-e3cf-369f-8994-283b090f7d9d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-09T21:13:01Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:47:00.047Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://it.tmcnet.com/news/2016/02/09/8314492.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1364" endPos="1371" type="product-class" surface="sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
