<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>- Pd.Adv. Health &amp; Medicine News for Seniors Health News for Seniors Thyroid cancer survivors not as happy with life as other cancer victims Study finds they score way below average on quality of life test Dec. 12, 2015 - Thyroid cancer has one of the highest cancer survival rates, yet, survivors report poor quality of life after diagnosis and treatment compared with patients who are diagnosed with more lethal cancers, according to new research from the University of Chicago Medicine. More... Health News for Seniors Deaths from heart disease declining among rheumatoid arthritis patients Mayo clinic presents arthritis research on rheumatoid, gout and opioid use Nov. 25, 2015 - Rheumatoid arthritis patients, most often senior citizens, are twice as likely as the average person to develop heart disease, but a new study shows that efforts to prevent heart problems and diagnose and treat heart disease early may be paying off. More... Sex Health News for Seniors Seniors taking Viagra may also be lowering their risk of diabetes Erectile dysfunction, diabetes target older men, most frequent users of ED meds with sildenafil Nov. 18, 2015 - Fewer senior men should be developing diabetes now days, if a new study is correct in its finding that sildenafil, a drug used in Viagra and other brand names, improves insulin sensitivity and reduces the risk of diabetes. More... Health News for Seniors Actions to reduce prostate cancer screening may have gone too far PSA screening and rate of prostate cancer have both declined Nov. 17, 2015 - Prostate cancer cases are down and so are prostate-specific antigen (PSA) screenings, according to two new studies that looked at what happened before and after the 2012 U.S. Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF) screening recommendations. Some think we may have gone too far in discouraging screening of older men. More... Health News for Seniors Seniors cut death risk by 27% with aggressive blood pressure management May set new direction of treating hypertension but there is caution Nov. 16, 2015 - How would you like to reduce your risk of death by 27 percent? A new clinical trial indicates it is a possibility for seniors age 50 and older who can lower their systolic blood pressure to below 120 mmHg. Not only did it reduce their death risk, it also cut by 24 percent their risk for heart attack, heart failure or stroke. More... Health News for Seniors Why does cancer strike mostly senior citizens? Why do old tissues decline? Without age-associated inflammation, old mice developed leukemia no faster than young mice Nov. 11, 2015 - The incidence of cancer increases with age. Conventional wisdom blames this on the accumulation of cancer-causing mutations as we grow older. A new study introduces another scenario of how cancer causing mutations take command in senior citizens. More... Health News for Seniors Silent heart attacks have hit about 8 percent of seniors suggests new study Men more likely than women to have myocardial scars: 80% missed in evaluations Nov. 8, 2015 - A study of boomers and seniors with an average age of 68 found eight percent had suffered a heart attack without knowing it and that 80 percent of myocardial scars from these attacks were not recognized in electrocardiography or clinical evaluation. More... Aging &amp; Longevity Another wall falls that kept senior citizens from critical treatments Study rejects biologic age as limiting factor for stem cell transplants Nov. 5, 2015 - More than 40 percent of older patients with acute myeloid leukemia (AML) can remain in long-term cancer remission through a modified, less aggressive approach to donor stem cell transplantation, according to the results of a phase 2 study led by oncologists at The Ohio State University Comprehensive Cancer Center. More... Health News for Seniors Married older adults more likely to survive, thrive after cardiac surgery Known that marrieds survive surgery more often, now we know they do better afterwards, too Oct. 28, 2015 - New research involving 1,500 older adults has found that being married is a predictor of survival and functional recovery after heart surgery. More... Aging &amp; Longevity Death rates for leading causes of death show marked decline in U.S. Declines in all causes combined, heart disease, cancer, stroke, unintentional injuries, and diabetes Oct. 27, 2015 - Three cheers for a new study that finds a dramatic decrease in the U.S. between 1969 and 2013 in the age-standardized death rate and years of potential life lost before age 75 from the most frequent causes of death and all causes. More... Health News for Seniors Doctors should cut back on some medications given seniors, two JAMA studies suggest Too much, too late: Overtreatment for blood pressure and blood sugar can be dangerous for some Oct. 26, 2015 - The medical treatment of senior citizen is often a little more complicated due to the uncertain consequences of old age. The decision on a surgery, a drug dosage or other procedure has to consider the patients age. More... Health News for Seniors Quality of care differs by race for black seniors with prostate cancer Study finds in does not, however, result in worse survival chance; commentator has theory Oct. 22, 2015 – The quality of care differs by race, declares an official with the American Cancer Society in a commentary published in JAMA Oncology. A study in the publication found senior black men on Medicare with localized prostate cancer were more likely to have worst care, higher costs and endure worse postoperative outcomes than white men. Interestingly, this did not translate to worse overall or cancer-specific survival. . Women with more than 11 moles on right arm were more likely to have over 100 on their body. A normal mole, like the one pictured here, is usually an evenly colored brown, tan, or black spot on the skin. It can be either flat or raised, round or oval, says American Cancer Society Health News for Seniors Old age not a factor in success of Melanoma treatment with drug combo Senior citizens, the most likely melanoma patients, see progression-free survival Oct. 14, 2015 - Patients with advanced melanoma skin cancer survive for longer without their disease progressing if they have been treated with a combination of two drugs, nivolumab and ipilimumab, than with either of these drugs alone. New results show that these patients also do better regardless of their age, stage of disease and whether or not they have a cancer-Driving mutation in the BRAF gene. More... Health News for Seniors Patients to find it tougher getting insurance to cover high-priced cholesterol drug, others Express Scripts will control spending by aggressively managing which patients get high-priced drugs By Julie Appleby, Kaiser Health News Oct. 7, 2015 - The nation’s largest pharmacy benefit manager said Tuesday it’s not going to try to bring down costs by forcing the makers of two pricey new cholesterol drugs to compete against each other, as it successfully did this year with expensive hepatitis C treatments. Health News for Seniors Price for women’s health care varies widely: mammogram by $1,000 It pays to shop around for women’s health care: routine services often cost far more in one office than another Oct. 7, 2015 - Thinking about getting a mammogram in the Dallas-Fort Worth area? You might check carefully because the cost can vary from $50 to as much as $1,045. How about an initial routine gynecological exam? Around Phoenix, those prices can range from $72 to $388. Health News for Seniors Baby Boomers may cause telemedicine to explode Financial prospects not clear as program shifts from caring for rural America to baby boomers wanting to age at home Oct. 6, 2015 - Say you’re a rural Midwestern farmer in bed recovering from a major illness at your local hospital. It’s time for nurse’s check in, but there’s no knock on the door. At Mercy Hospital in St. Louis, just over the foot of the bed, a camera whirls around and a monitor lights up to show a smiling face with a headset on. Health News for Seniors Seniors must get flu shot now _ the deadly season is here Elderly should consider the 4 times stronger high dose vaccine Oct. 5, 2015 _ You can assume that a lot of senior citizens are going to die from the flu during this 2015-16 flu season that just opened. History tells us up to 90% of those who die from flu this season will be seniors age 65 or older and well over half who are hospitalized with be in this age group, too. Flu is a very serious threat for the elderly and they should consider the extra protection of the high dose flu shot. Health News for Seniors Early antiviral flu drugs reduce hospital stay, disability risk for senior citizens Antiviral medications also reduces their risk of needing extended care Sept. 18, 2015 - Early treatment of flu-hospitalized people 65 and older with flu antiviral medications cuts the duration of their hospital stay and reduces their risk of needing extended care after discharge, a new CDC study finds. The study is the first to look at the benefits of early antiviral treatment on preventing the need for extended care in community-dwelling flu-hospitalized people 65 and older. Health News for Seniors Age 75 is the new 65 and accepting this in medicine will save lives Updated screening policies could detect more abdominal aortic aneurysms; older male smokers at high risk, maybe women Aug. 20, 2015 – Once again, researchers find older people are dying because of medical policies established years ago, when we did not live so long. The deadly problem this time is the national screening policy for aortic aneurysm. Health News for Seniors Social action needed to maintain gains in reducing deaths from heart disease, stroke American Heart Association cites need to address problems with education, income and racial divide Aug. 4, 2015 — Deaths from heart attacks, strokes and other heart diseases have been declining, but social factors, including race, income, environment and education could reverse that trend according to a first of its kind scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Health News for Seniors Trifecta that dramatically shortens life - diabetes, stroke, heart attack Rate of death: doubles with 1, up 4 times with 2, 8 times with all 3 July 29, 2015 - This is a trifecta you don’t want in any order – diabetes, stroke and heart attack. Your risk of death increases substantially with each additional condition. For example, a 60-year old senior with two of these has a reduced life expectancy of 12 years, says the new research. Senior citizens should consider success of wireless health apps _ life-saving idea Apple leading to promote better health through smartphones By Tucker Sutherland, editor July 28, 2015 - 75,000 people have enrolled in health studies that use specialized iPhone apps - Apple working with hospitals, doctors, and other health care providers like Mayo Clinic to create a bridge between provider and patient for health information Read, see video, links, more... Health News for Seniors Hope for millions of senior citizens facing heart failure found in new research Adding protein vinculin helps fruit flies extend lives 150% June 19, 2015 _ Millions of senior citizens threatened by heart failure, a disease of aging marked by a weak pumping heart, could possibly see their lives significantly extended by the protein vinculin. At least there is the hint of this possibility in new research published this week. More... Health News for Seniors Statins probably do not cause memory loss says giant study Statins have proven very effective at lowering high cholesterol and you should stick with them June 8, 2015 – Previous studies – mostly limited research – have indicated memory lapses resulting after taking statins. Whoa, that may not be the case, says new research involving about a million patients. These researchers suggest you stick with your statins. More... Health News for Seniors Seniors age 75 and older run high risk using newer anticoagulant meds Use caution when considering anticoagulants, say Mayo Clinic researchers June 1, 2015 - If you are over age 75, and taking an anticoagulant, the old standard may be the gold standard, Mayo Clinic researchers in Phoenix and collaborators have determined.For older patients, particularly individuals greater than 75 years of age, the risk of gastrointestinal (GI) bleeding is 3 to 5 times higher when taking newer anticoagulant medications dabigatran or rivaroxaban compared to when using warfarin. More.. Health News for Seniors Loss of muscle in senior citizens remains costly health problem with no clear solution Researchers see possible hope in right combination of exercise, diet to fight sarcopenia May 14, 2015 – Along the way from about age 40 to age 80, about 30 to 50 percent of your muscle mass just goes away. This terrible process is known as saropenia – it is common and clearly linked to frailty and poor health in senior citizens. New research from England suggests the combining exercise with proper diet may offer some hope but existing studies have produced inconsistent results. More... Health News for Seniors Fat around girth increases your risk of developing cancer Latest studies show that young and postmenopausal women are particularly affected by this negative trend toward obesity May 14, 2015 - Cancer is more likely to develop in people who are very overweight (obese), because surplus body fat interferes with various hormone cycles and with glucose and fat metabolism. And, don’t use BMI to measure your danger level – these Austrian researchers say only girth tells the story. More... Health News for Seniors Senior citizens doing quite well at meeting cancer screening goals, CDC reports CDC Healthy People 2020 reports on cancer screening targets for colorectal, breast and cervical cancers May 8, 2015 – Americans are not doing very well at being screened for key cancers, says at new report from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Senior citizens, however, are doing surprisingly well... More Health News for Seniors Seniors do much better than younger adults at affording, taking meds Lots of U.S. adults skip taking prescriptions because they cannot afford them May 8, 2015 - Okay, even most of us senior citizens would assume that when it comes to taking meds regularly, our age bracket would not do as well as younger adults. Wrong! Well at least we do better at not skipping prescriptions because we can't afford them, says a new report from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)... More Health News for Seniors Statins tightly linked to diabetes, disease complications in large study R isk of diabetes with statins has been known, thought this was because people prescribed statins had greater medical risks to begin with May 7, 2015 - For the millions of seniors taking statins at the recommendation of their doctor, it has to be punishing to read week-after-week the new studies that often highlight some new risk. The latest study is a big one - 26,000 members of Tricare... Advertising for Seniors Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Click for Information, Buy Talcum Powder Ovarian Cancer Complete Information &amp; Free Lawsuit Consultation Talcum Powder Lawsuit Center Put Your Message Here Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Click for Information, Buy Put Your Message Here Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Click for Information, Buy Elder Abuse? Medical Malpractice? Experienced Lawyers! Janicek Law Put Your Message Here Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Click for Information, Buy Senior Journal Advertising Health News for Seniors People with a bleeding stroke have best chance in comprehensive stroke center By Tucker Sutherland, editor &amp; publisher Stroke centers have equipment, personnel to deal with most severe strokes, including neurological critical May 6, 2015 - People with hemorrhagic strokes (brain bleeds) are more likely to survive if they are treated at a comprehensive stroke center. If not in a stroke center, their loved ones should move them, says research leader. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Seniors 75 and older may find statins guard against heart attack, stroke …but should they be given to senior citizens not already taking them to protect against cardiovascular events By Michelle Klampe April 21, 2015 – Statins could be a cost-effective tool for preventing heart attacks and other cardiovascular incidents in adults over age 75, but the benefits would need to be weighed against potential side effects, a study being published this week in the Annals of Internal Medicine has found. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Deadly pancreatic cancer cells steered back into normal cells Ability of treated cancer cells to form tumors greatly diminished in test with mice April 20, 2015 - Deadly pancreatic cancer cells were coaxed into reverting back toward normal non-cancerous cells by a protein called E47. The success of this new research provides hope for treatment of this disease that kills 40,000 a year in the U.S. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Breast Cancer to Make Big Jump in U.S. but Some Encouraging Research News Cancer researchers hear fasting may lower risk, combo drug may break breast cancer resistance, more below; increase in women over 70 April 20, 2015 – The bad news about breast cancer is there are expected to be a 50 percent increase in U.S. cases by 2013, compared to 2011, according to research presented at a meeting of the American Association for Cancer Research. But there was also a ton of good news among the many research reports being presented that have found encouragement in the fight against this killer of women – primarily senior women. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Most seniors take a daily aspirin if they need it or not Why do so many older adults gobble down aspirin when it is not recommended by FDA? April 16, 2015 - More than half of older Americans – those age 45 through 75 – take an aspirin every day, even though this use is not recommended by the Food and Drug Administration for most people who have not yet had a heart attack or stroke. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Senior men with history of reflux disease need test for Barrett’s Esophagus New treatment for common digestive condition Barrett's Esophagus also recommended by landmark study April 14, 2015 – Men over 60 with 10-year history of a serious form of reflux disease should be screened for Barrett’s esophagus, which makes them more likely to develop a rare cancer called esophageal adenocarcinoma. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Senior citizens hopeful new therapy can slow age-related macular degeneration Currently no treatment to stop the advance of AMD, leading cause of vision loss in seniors 65 and older April 14, 2015 _ The leading cause of blindness in senior citizens - age-related macular degeneration _ may have met its match. For the first time, there may be a therapy to at least slow the progress of the disease. More Health and Medicine for Seniors Tylenol kills the pain but also keeps you from enjoying it too much ‘Rather than just being a pain reliever, acetaminophen can be seen as an all-purpose emotion reliever’ - popular with many seniorcitizens; used often for arthritis pain by Jeff Grabmeier, Ohio State April 13, 2015 - Researchers studying the commonly used pain reliever acetaminophen found it has a previously unknown side effect: It blunts positive emotions. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Reducing hip fractures in U.S. senior citizens would cost $2 billion Study predicts 357,656 lifetime hip fractures after wrist fracture in all U.S. females age 65 and older By Senior Journal staff April 4, 2018 – Most U.S. senior citizens over age 80 suffer with the steady loss of bone due to osteoporosis, contributing to an estimated 2 million bone fractures each year. A new study finds that routine bisphosphonate drug treatment of women over 65 who sustain a distal radius (wrist) fracture - one of the most common fractures associated with osteoporosis - could significantly reduce the risk for additional fractures... More... Health Alert for Seniors Older people threatened by new diarrhea superbug resistant to preventive drug Young children, gay men are most common victims of this diarrhea; threat may increase amount adults due to this bugs resistance to preventive drug for adults April 2, 2015 _ A new variety of a bug that already causes about half-a-million cases of diarrhea each year in the U.S. is proving resistant to drugs usually prescribed to protect adults. More Health and Medicine for Seniors Senior citizens with back pain often get quick x-ray or MRI that may be a waste Early imaging of those age 65-plus does not seem to improve the outcome March 18, 2015 – When you, or another other senior citizen, goes to the doctor complaining of back pain, it is not uncommon for the physician to recommend an x-ray or an MRI to get a better look at the spine. The doctor would be following an accepted procedure for an early imaging in hopes of a quick solution. A new study, however, finds seniors getting the early image have no better success than older adults who did not. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Intense stress and depression almost doubles death risk for heart patients Short-term risk of death or heart attack increased 48% for older heart patient in the high stress-high depressive group March 14, 2015 - Few seniors are not aware that stress and depression are a bad mix, yet, they very often link together – you are stressed or depressed, which tends to cause the one you don’t already have to raise its ugly head. The startling news is, however, that older people coping with these two afflictions plus a heart problem are likely to see a really big increase in their risk of a heart attack or death. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors in other media Seniors sleeping over 8 hours linked to greater risk of stroke March 6, 2015 - Older people who sleep for more than eight hours increase stroke risk ... this risk doubles for older people who persistently sleep longer than average ...four times that of people sleeping normal hours… Eureka Alerts Health and Medicine for Seniors Boomers, other seniors drive record spending for drugs Drugs for hepatitis C, compounded medications push prices higher March 10, 2015 – The money spent on drugs in the U.S. increased at a faster rate in 2014 – 13.1 percent – than in any year for the last decade. The culprits, according a report by Express Scripts, were new high priced medicines for hepatitis C and the ' exploitation of loopholes for compounded medications.' Most hepatitis C patients are senior citizens. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Going vegetarian offers way for seniors to lower risk of colorectal cancer Senior citizens making great progress against this deadly cancer due to more having colonoscopies March 9, 2015 - A good way for seniors to avoid colorectal cancer – the number two cancer killer in the U.S. among cancers – is to eat a vegetarian diet, says a study of Seventh - day Adventist published online by JAMA Internal Medicine. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Less sex, less desire in senior men leads to testosterone decline - not vice versa Decline in testosterone was 'strikingly small,' less than 10%; declines in estrogen also associated with declines in sexual activity March 8, 2015 – For male senior citizens age 70 and older, decreased sexual activity and desire may be the cause, not an effect, of low testosterone level, according to research presented yesterday at the Endocrine Society meeting in San Diego. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors H igher heart disease risk for men due to high testosterone, low estrogen Sex hormones testosterone nor estrogen caused changes in bad, cholesterol, blood pressure, or body weight in this study March 8, 2015 - Why men have more heart disease than premenopausal women has been a puzzle, but a new study shows that the sex hormones testosterone and estrogen alter cardiovascular risk factors in a way that raises a man's risk of heart disease. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Obesity is an expensive disease, especially for aging senior citizens Obese 70-year-olds may live as long as healthy weight 70-year-olds but will spend $39,000 more on health care By Sarah Varney , Kaiser Health News March 2, 2015 - Bayou La Batre, Alabama, calls itself the seafood capital of Alabama. Residents here depend on fishing and shrimping for their livelihood, and when they sit down to eat, they like most things fried. It’s here that former U.S. Surgeon General Dr. Regina Benjamin has been trying to reverse the nation’s obesity epidemic one patient at a time. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Statin drug not clearing cholesterol? Blocked arteries could be to blame Patients whose bad cholesterol levels don’t respond may have more artery blockages than those whose cholesterol levels drop Feb. 28, 2015 — If your 'bad' cholesterol level stays the same or increases after you take statin drugs, you may have more blocked arteries than people whose levels drop, according to research in the American Heart Association journal Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis and Vascular Biology. Advertising for Seniors Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Click for Information, Buy Talcum Powder Ovarian Cancer Complete Information &amp; Free Lawsuit Consultation Talcum Powder Lawsuit Center Put Your Message Here Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Click for Information, Buy Put Your Message Here Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Click for Information, Buy Elder Abuse? Medical Malpractice? Experienced Lawyers! Janicek Law Put Your Message Here Only Daily News Site for Senior Citizens Click for Information, Buy Senior Journal Advertising Health and Medicine from Other Media Physicians performing breast exams may miss masses deep in breast New sensor technology finds many doctors may not be pressing hard enough Feb. 23, 2015 - Many physicians who tested their breast-examination skills on a new type of pressure-sensing breast model failed to detect masses deep in the breast because they were not pressing hard enough, a study has found. EurekaAlert Health and Medicine for Seniors Type 2 Diabetes patients should exercise after dinner Study is particularly helpful for health care providers who have patients who exercise every day but are not seeing benefits Feb. 18, 2015 – Individuals with Type 2 diabetes have heightened amounts of sugars and fats in their blood, which increases their risks for cardiovascular diseases such as strokes and heart attacks. Exercise is a popular prescription for those suffering from the symptoms of Type 2 diabetes, but most research has focused the benefits of different exercise methods. A news study, however, decided to look at the difference in benefits based on the time of the exercise. Doing it after dinner is best, they say. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Human stem cells restore cognitive function after chemotherapy damage First solid evidence that transplantation of human neural stem cells can reverse chemo induced damage of healthy tissue in the brain Feb. 16, 2015 - Human nerve system stem cell treatments are showing promise for reversing learning and memory deficits after chemotherapy, according to UC Irvine researchers. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Seniors surviving heart failure have 20 percent risk of death for a year Yale study looked at 3 million Medicare patients who survived hospitalization for heart failure and pneumonia By Karen N. Peart Feb. 6, 2015 – Senior citizens – age 65 and older – who survive hospitalization for heart failure have a 20 percent chance of going back into the hospital or death in the month after being discharged. New research, however, has found these risks remain high for up to a year, although they can be addressed with targeted care. But problems with blood clots may be more common in older women, study suggests Feb. 2, 2015 - Older women don't have an increased overall risk of complications from breast reconstruction after mastectomy, reports the February issue of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, official journal of the American Society of Plastic Surgeons. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Living alone a deadly risk after stroke, especially for older men People living alone are less likely to take medicine, wait longer to see doctor, live less healthy lives Jan. 20, 2015 – A study of adults in western Sweden, who had experienced a stroke before the age of 70, found those who live alone are the most likely to die within 12 years but men have a considerably greater risk of dying prematurely than women or men who live with a partner. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Senior women happy with life less likely to suffer osteoporosis Study focused on the possible effects of depression and other factors on bone health Jan. 13, 2015 - Women aged 60-70 who are satisfied with their lives have a higher bone density and they suffer less frequently from osteoporosis than their unsatisfied peers, according to a recent study completed at the University of Eastern Finland. The study focused on the possible effects of depression and other factors on bone health. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Thromboembolism is Target of New Campaign by Alliance for Aging Research Educational effort supplies brochures, video, online quiz to help spread word on dangers of deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism Jan. 13, 2015 – The nonprofit Alliance for Aging Research has launched a new campaign to raise awareness about venous thromboembolism (VTE), the third most common cardiovascular illness, and its associated conditions deep vein thrombosis (DVT) and pulmonary embolism (PE). VTE affects more than 600,000 Americans, mostly senior citizens. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Most optimistic older adults have the healthiest hearts People up through age 84 with most positive attitudes twice as likely to have best cardiovascular health Jan. 9, 2015 - Older people with a positive, upbeat attitude also have significantly better cardiovascular health. And, as the positive attitude scores climbed, so did the health scores in this study that included seniors up to age 85. Those with most optimism were twice is likely to enjoy a healthy heart. More... Senior Health News – Other Media Senior citizens disagree with younger Americans on sharing of medical information Poll for NPR finds majority of adults not concerned with privacy Jan. 9, 2015 – Most Americans do not seem to be worried about what happens to the information in their medical records. Well, that is really mostly American under age 65. Senior citizens, on the other hand, do not want to share the information. Sixty-one percent of adults younger than 35 were fine with the idea, but only 43% of people 65 and older agreed. NPR’s Blog Shots Health and Medicine for Seniors Most cancers are just bad luck, others from bad genes, environment Best way to eradicate these cancers will be through early detection, when they are still curable by surgery Jan. 4, 2015 – Two thirds of cancers in adults are just bad luck and the rest are due to inherited genes and environmental factors, according to scientists from the Johns Hopkins Kimmel Cancer Center. They created a statistical model that measures the proportion of cancer incidence, across many tissue types, caused mainly by random mutations that occur when stem cells divide. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Senior’s ability to balance on one leg may detect brain health, stroke risk One-leg standing test is easy way to determine early signs of being at risk for a stroke and cognitive impairment By Tucker Sutherland, editor, SeniorJournal.com Dec. 19, 2014 – You know how they warn you on TV when they are about to show something gruesome. We need to use that same type of warning on this report. It is about a new study that finds senior citizens - average age of 67 - that have trouble balancing on one leg for at least 20 seconds may have increased risk of small blood vessel damage in the brain - stroke - and reduced cognitive function. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Seniors keeping teeth longer than ever, tips for keeping it up Simple, routine dental care matters for senior citizens to save teeth and live healthier Dec. 18, 2014 - Today, approximately 75 percent of senior citizens over age 65 have kept some or all of their teeth - a record -thanks to better preventive measures like community water fluoridation and daily brushing with fluoride toothpaste, according to the American Dental Association (ADA). The group offers some additional tips for keeping this dental progress going. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Tiny sensors may soon monitor seniors' medicines from the inside Managing medication conflicts and confusions more pressing as 10,000 baby boomers turn sixty-five every day, and 90 percent suffer at least one chronic illness. By Some over-the-counter meds can have negative impact on hypertension Dec. 10, 2014 – It is the season for colds and flu. Most of us seniors do not hesitate to seek quick relief from an over-the-counter (OTC) medication. Not so fast, says the American Heart Association, most senior citizens also have hypertension. Some medications taken over the counter can have a negative impact on blood pressure. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Bad signs on horizon although flu season off to slow start Early check of dominant viruses indicate a severe season, less protection from vaccine, but better than nothing for seniors Dec. 9, 2014 – The good news about the 2014-15 flu season is that so far influenza activity is slow. This, however, is swamped by the potential bad news – it is looking like this could develop into a rough season with a high death rate and this season’s flu vaccine may not been the best match to beat back the viruses that are showing up. Still, senior citizens should get a flu shot! You will fair better than without it. More... Nutrition, Vitamins &amp; Supplements for Seniors Vitamin claims for treating age-related macular degeneration challenged Research shows that of 11 popular supplements analyzed all have misleading claims Dec. 9, 2014 - Americans spend billions of dollars each year on nutritional supplements. And, for senior citizens with aging eyes, purchasing eye vitamins that claim to help protect vision is an attractive proposition. Unfortunately, a new study finds these claims for most products from the top-selling brands don't match the scientific evidence, especially for treating the leading cause of blindness among older adults, age-related macular degeneration (AMD) More... Health News _ Other Media Obesity may shorten life expectancy up to eight years Dec. 8, 2014 - Tis the season to indulge. However, restraint may be best, according to a new study. The researchers examined the relationship between body weight and life expectancy. Their findings show that overweight and obese individuals have the potential to decrease life expectancy by up to eight years. Science Daily Health News _ Other Media Who Needs Knee Replacement? ...video by NIH SeniorHealth Health News _ Other Media Genetic errors linked to aging underlie leukemia that develops after cancer treatment Dec. 8, 2014 - New research at Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis challenges the view that cancer treatment in itself is a direct cause of a fatal form of leukemia that can develop several years after a patient receives chemotherapy or radiation therapy.EurekaAlert Health News _ Other Media Most elderly women with early stage breast cancer may miss most effective treatment Dec. 8, 2014 - A new analysis finds that while clinical trial data support omitting radiation treatments in elderly women with early stage breast cancer, nearly two-thirds of these women continue to receive it. The findings are published early online in Cancer, a peer-reviewed journal of the American Cancer Society. EurekaAlert Health and Medicine for Seniors Common prostate cancer treatment associated with decreased survival in older men Evidence growing that androgen deprivation therapy may lead to earlier death Dec. 4, 2014 - A common prostate cancer therapy - androgen deprivation therapy (ADT) - should not be used in men whose cancer has not spread beyond the prostate, says a study led by researchers at Henry Ford Hospital. The findings are particularly important for men with longer life expectancies because the therapy exposes them to more adverse side effects, it is associated with increased risk of death and it deprives men of the opportunity for a cure by other methods. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Dance helps people with Parkinson’s, maybe healthy senior citizens, too Ballroom dancing could help people with Parkinson’s improve their balance and mobility, and maybe do the same for other seniors By Tucker Sutherland, editor, SeniorJournal.com Dec. 4, 2014 – Researchers at the University of Southhampton, UK, recently announced that participants in their study who had Parkinson’s and took part in ballroom dance lessons improved their balance, confidence and posture. They are not the first to discover that dancing can make life better and safer for Parkinson’s patients, who are also almost exclusively senior citizens. Maybe seniors without PD should also consider how this exercise reduced falls in the PD group. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Improving patient safety saves 50,000 lives, 1.3 million from harm, $12 billion in cost Hospital-acquired conditions decline by 17 percent over a three-year period Dec. 3, 2014 - A report released by the Department of Health and Human Services yesterday shows an estimated 50,000 fewer patients died in hospitals and approximately $12 billion in health care costs were saved as a result of a reduction in hospital-acquired conditions from 2010 to 2013. This progress toward a safer health care system occurred during a period of concerted attention by hospitals throughout the country to reduce adverse events. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Mobility is most common disability for American senior citizens High disability rates for seniors in Southern counties, especially central Appalachia and Mississippi Delta Dec. 2, 2014 - Nearly 40 percent of people age 65 and older had at least one disability, according to a U.S. Census Bureau report that covered the period 2008 to 2012. Of those 15.7 million people, two-thirds of them say they had difficulty in walking or climbing. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors All Senior Citizens Under 76 Should Consider Statins to Reduce Cardiovascular Risks All men and most women 66 to 75 qualify for statins in new study – 97 percent of all November 24, 2014 - Nearly all individuals in their late 60s and early 70s - including 100 percent of men - now qualify for, and should consider, starting a statin medication to reduce their risk of cardiovascular disease, under the recently released cholesterol guidelines from the American College of Cardiology (ACC) and the American Heart Association (AHA). More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Pain Suffered by Aging Adults is Topic for New Publication One thing that does not increase your pain - this magazine is free By Tucker Sutherland, editor, SeniorJournal.com Nov. 19, 2014 – I have to admit I did not see this coming – a whole publication dedicated to pains suffered by senior citizens. But, when I stop and think about, I realize it is a major topic of conversation among many of my senior friends. This subject choice was made the editors of a new publication series named 'From Policy to Practice' from The Gerontological Society of America (GSA). Oh, and did I mention it’s free? More... Health and Medicine for Seniors More Heart Attack Victims Saved with Faster Response of Coordinated Effort Collaboration between paramedics and hospitals in treating heart attack patients resulted in shorter emergency department wait times that result in better survival. Nov. 19, 2014 – Virtually all senior citizens know that when a heart attack strikes, the faster the victim receives medical attention, the better the chances the patient will survive. A report released today about a coordinated emergency response system proves faster care can save thousands of lives and that it is possible to speed up the rescue effort. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Senior Heart Patients Feeling Hopeless Find Relief with Home Exercise Patients likely thinking more positively about the future, more capable of making positive changes for a healthy lifestyle Nov.18, 2014 — Home exercise can ease feelings of hopelessness in older people – average age of 66 - with coronary heart disease , according to a study presented at the American Heart Association’s Scientific Sessions 2014. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Erectile Dysfunction More Likely in Men with Early Vascular Disease ‘Erectile function can be a window into men’s cardiovascular and overall health’ Nov. 18, 2014 — Men who have asymptomatic subclinical vascular disease are more likely to develop erectile dysfunction than men who don’t have early stage vascular disease, according to research presented at the American Heart Association’s Scientific Sessions 2014. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Stent Patients Suffer Fewer Heart Attacks if Anti-Clotting Meds Extended Benefits extended if taken for more than standard 12 months - patients average age 62 Nov. 17, 2014 - Patients - average age 62 - who took two anti-clotting medications beyond the standard 12 months after stent placement were significantly less likely to develop blood clots within their stents or to have a heart attack than those whose treatment followed the 12-month protocol, according to late-breaking clinical trial research presented at the American Heart Association’s Scientific Sessions 2014. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Seniors May Dash Hopes for Broader Use of Internet for Health Information Few seniors use internet for health information, especially the large number with low health literacy Nov. 12, 2014 - Providing health information on the internet may not be the 'cure all' that it is hoped to be, at least for senior citizens. A new study shows few Americans 65 or older use the internet to find health information and many seniors have low health literacy. Among those with poor knowledge about health, less than ten percent use the internet to seek health information. The new concern is that greater reliance on digital health information will just leave many seniors further behind. More... Medicare &amp; Medicaid News Medicare Lung Cancer Screening a Lifesaver for Seniors, Say Radiologists CT lung cancer screening recommended for adults 55-80 with 30 pack a year smoking history, currently smoke or have quit within 15 years Nov. 11, 2014 - New Medicare computed tomography (CT) lung cancer screening coverage provides high-risk seniors with access to care that can save more lives than any cancer screening test in history, says a news release from the American College of Radiology. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Older Women Lead Millions in Not Getting Screened for Cervical Cancer Most new cervical cancer cases occur among women who have never or rarely been screened, says CDC - women over 65 may not need Pap test Nov. 6, 2014 - Despite evidence that cervical cancer screening saves lives, about eight million women ages 21 to 65 years have not been screened for cervical cancer in the past five years, with the older women the worst offenders, according to a new Retinal-scan analysis can predict which AMD patients may go blind Nov. 5, 2014 - A new way to forecast which patients with age-related macular degeneration are likely to suffer from the most debilitating form of the disease has been found by Stanford University School of Medicine scientists. AMD is the leading cause of blindness and central vision loss among senior citizens older than 65. More... Medicare &amp; Medicaid News Physicians, Others in Health Care Want Patients to Take More Responsibility for Their Care ‘…actions - or inaction - of patients should be considered in programs designed to improve care and patient outcomes’ By Tucker Sutherland, editor &amp; publisher, SeniorJournal.com Nov. 3, 2014 –An interesting twist has just been made in the national effort to improve healthcare – the doctors want the patients to step up and share some the responsibility. Keep in mind that when we talk about patients, we are primarily talking about senior citizens. And, the health care world is not just composed to health care providers and patients. The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services is the big kid on the block. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Seniors with Heart Problems Need to Worry About NOT Getting Flu Shot Those with cardiovascular problems probably most in need of a flu shot By Tucker Sutherland, editor, SeniorJournal.com Oct. 31, 2014 – When you have heart problems, as so many senior citizens do, it is natural to become concerned about things you put in your body – like vaccine to prevent flu. In this case, don’t worry, the Centers for Disease Control says what you should be worried about is catching the flu – that does increase the risk of a heart attack. There are even studies that say the flu shot may offer protection against heart attacks. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Prostate Cancer, Kidney Disease Detected on Spot by Innovative Device Study looked at prostate cancer and kidney disease, same method could be a diagnostic tool for other diseases Oct. 28, 2014 - When you flush the toilet, you may be discarding microscopic warning signs about your health. But a cunningly simple new device can stop that vital information from 'going to waste.' It can detect markers of kidney disease and prostate cancer in a few minutes. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Many Elderly Found with Puzzling Mutations Linked to Leukemia, Lymphoma Researchers find no connection with blood cancer that seldom strikes senior citizens Oct. 22, 2014 – A surprisingly large percentage – 5 percent – of senior citizens over age 70 have been found to have genetic mutations linked to leukemia and lymphoma in their blood cells. The vast majority won't get blood cancer, however, as the incidence of these cancers is less than 0.1 percent among the elderly, according to the researchers at Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Flu Vaccine May Hold Key to Preventing Heart Disease with a Shot A new study in Vaccine explains how flu vaccines prevent heart attacks Oct. 21, 2014 – One of the reasons senior citizens should not hesitate to get a flu shot every year is the added protection it provides against heart attack. Those who get vaccinated are 50 percent less likely to suffer a heart attack in a year. The potency of this protection has motivated researchers to learn more about what is causing it and how to create a vaccine just to prevent heart disease. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Fake ‘Good’ Cholesterol Wins Fight to Reduce Plaque Buildup Points toward new method for preventing plaque buildup in the arteries that can cause heart attacks and strokes Oct. 10, 2014 - Scientists at The Scripps Research Institute (TSRI) have created a synthetic molecule that mimics 'good' cholesterol and have shown it can reduce plaque buildup in the arteries of animal models. The molecule, taken orally, improved cholesterol in just two weeks. More... Caregiver &amp; Elder Care News Heart Valve Disease Hits One of Ten Elderly Women Warns Educational Campaign Alliance for Aging Research says it hits men and women but women tend to have worse prognosis Oct. 10, 2014 - A new campaign has been launched aimed at educating about heart valve disease in women, a condition that causes damage to one or more of the heart’s four valves and can lead to loss of independence, disability and death. It affects one in 10 women age 75 and over and one in 50 of all adult women, says the Alliance for Aging Research. Oct. 8, 2014 - Reports of insomnia are common among the elderly, but a new study finds that sleep problems may stem from the quality of rest and other health concerns more than the overall amount of sleep that patients get. Medicare &amp; Medicaid News Physical Therapy Before Hip, Knee Replacements May Save Medicare Mega-Millions Also good news for senior citizens, who undergo most knee, hip replacements, to endure less stress following surgery By Tucker Sutherland, editor, SeniorJournal.com Oct. 7, 2014 – New research released today finds that postoperative care and costs could be reduced by about 30% for patients having total hip (THR) or total knee (TKR) replacement surgery, if physical therapy is administered before joint replacement surgery. It is good news for senior citizens, who have the majority of these procedures, and it makes sense considering the increasing abilities of seniors to tolerate physical exercise at increasing age levels. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Cancer Grows at Night, Maybe That’s When to Attack, New Study Says Weizmann Institute scientists find that a hormone that keeps us alert also suppresses the spread of cancer Oct. 6, 2015 - They emerge at night, while we sleep unaware, growing and spreading out as quickly as they can. And they are deadly. In a surprise finding that was recently published in Nature Communications, Weizmann Institute of Science researchers showed that nighttime is the right time for cancer to grow and spread in the body. Their findings suggest that administering certain treatments in time with the body’s day-night cycle could boost their efficiency. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Key to Beating Diabetes May Be in Medicine for Treating Tapeworms Rutgers study seeks to find a safe, practical way to diminish fat content in the liver; niclosamide may be it Oct. 5, 2014 - New research from Rutgers shows promising evidence that a modified form of a different drug, niclosamide – now used to eliminate intestinal parasites – may hold the key to battling the disease at its source. Type 2 diabetes affects an estimated 28 million Americans and almost one out of four seniors 60 and over, according to the American Diabetes Association, but medications now available only treat symptoms, not the root cause of the disease. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Blood Test Reveals Genetic Risk of Atrial Fibrillation and Stroke About half of the people with AFib are seniors age 75 or older Oct. 3, 2014 – Atrial fibrillation, which causes an irregular heartbeat, can lead to a number of health risks, including heart disease and stroke. Developing AFib increases markedly with older age, with about half of those with the condition are senior citizens over age 75. The American Heart Association points out people are more likely to get the condition if a family member has it. New research, however, has discovered how to identify with a simple blood test those who are genetically predisposed to develop atrial fibrillation and possibly a stroke. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Old Lungs Look New Again - Ibuprofen Reduces Inflammation in Elderly Finding might someday support use of ibuprofen as adjunct therapy for senior citizens with tuberculosis By Emily Caldwell Oct. 2, 2014 - New research shows that the lungs become more inflammatory from cell damage with age and that ibuprofen can lower that inflammation. Researchers have found that immune cells from old mouse lungs fought tuberculosis bacteria as effectively as cells from young mice after lung inflammation was reduced by ibuprofen. Sept. 28, 2014 - Scientists have discovered a sign of the early development of pancreatic cancer – an upsurge in certain amino acids that occurs before the disease is diagnosed and symptoms appear. Health and Medicine for Seniors Many Senior Women Receive Unnecessary Pap Tests Surprised that so many women over age 65 reported recent Pap test; unnecessary tests can result in stress for the patient, increased costs, and inefficient use of time By Stephanie Stephens, HBNS Contributing Writer Oct. 1, 2014 - As many as half to two-thirds of women who have undergone hysterectomies or are older than 65 years in the United States report receiving Pap tests for cervical cancer. This prevalence is surprising in light of the 2003 U.S. Preventive Services Taskforce guidelines recommending that women discontinue Pap testing if they have received a total hysterectomy without a history of cervical cancer and if they are over age 65 years with ongoing and recent normal Pap test results. Health and Medicine for Seniors Heart Attacks in Older Men May Drop 80% with Modest Diet, Lifestyle Changes Study of over 20,000 men age 45 to 79 published in Journal of the American College of Cardiology Sept. 28, 2014 – If you are a male senior citizens this study should get your attention. It concludes that 80 percent - four out of five - of heart attacks (myocardial infarctions) in men may be preventable with a relatively easy combination low-risk behavior in diet and lifestyle. Seniors are 90% of Flu Deaths; Just 65% Get Free Medicare Vaccinations Actions those senior citizens 65 and older need to take this flu season with links to lots of information - CDC says get shot by October Sept. 28, 2014 – There is a reason that senior citizens are the focus of attention when flu season approaches - 90 percent of seasonal flu-related deaths and between 50 and 60 percent of seasonal flu-related hospitalizations in the U.S. occur in people 65 years and older, according to government estimates. Knowing these numbers and that Medicare provides free flu shots, it should be easy to convince seniors to get vaccinated. Health and Medicine for Seniors Vicodin, Other Pain Killers with Hydrocodone Will Be Harder to Get Patients generally must present a written prescription, doctors will no longer be able to call in a prescription By Michelle Andrews, Kaiser Health News Sept. 26, 2014 - Patients who use drugs containing hydrocodone as a pain reliever or cough suppressant are going to have to jump through more hoops to get them starting next month. The Drug Enforcement Administration is reclassifying so-called 'hydrocodone combination products' from Schedule III to Schedule II under the Controlled Substances Act, which will more tightly restrict access. Health and Medicine for Seniors Glimmer of Hope in Battle Against Pancreatic Cancer Salk scientists find that a vitamin D-derivative makes tumors vulnerable to chemotherapy. See video Sept. 25, 2014 - A synthetic derivative of vitamin D was found by Salk Institute researchers to collapse the barrier of cells shielding pancreatic tumors, making this seemingly impenetrable cancer much more susceptible to therapeutic drugs. Health and Medicine for Seniors New Skin-Like Device Warns of Cardiovascular, Skin Health Problems Ease of use, small size may appeal to many senior citizens, frequent victims of cardiovascular problems; monitors blood flow rate By Megan Fellman Sept. 25, 2014 - A new wearable medical device can quickly alert a person if they are having cardiovascular trouble or if it’s simply time to put on some skin moisturizer, reports a Northwestern University and University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign study supported by the National Science Foundation. Health and Medicine for Seniors Most Breast Cancer Patients Who Removed Healthy Breast Would Do It Again Women who decided against reconstructive surgery were most likely to say they would choose to have both breasts removed again in Mayo Clinic study Sept. 24, 2014 - More women with cancer in one breast are opting to have both breasts removed to reduce their risk of future cancer. New research shows that in the long term, most have no regrets. Mayo Clinic surveyed hundreds of women with breast cancer who had double mastectomies between 1960 and 1993 and found that nearly all would make the same choice again. The findings are published in the journal Annals of Surgical Oncology Health and Medicine for Seniors Diabetes Appears to be Leveling Off in U.S. Prevalence continues to increase for some subgroups, like young adults; incidence rate up for Hispanic, black adults Sept. 23, 2014 – The incidence and prevalence of diabetes, which doubled in the U.S. from 1990-2008 appears to have leveled off between 2008 and 2012, according to a new study in JAMA. Prevalence continued to increase at a significantly greater rate for young adults aged 20 to 44 years compared to older Americans. The incidence rate continued to increase in Hispanic and non-Hispanic black adults. Other Media Reports Research Points to Daily Aspirin for Cancer Prevention September 17, 2014 - Research published in Annals of Oncology shows that taking aspirin in daily low doses – often just one pill a day - can significantly reduce the risk of developing stomach and bowel cancers, as well as cancer of the esophagus. Combination of Medications More Effective for Older Patients with COPD – Video September 17, 2014 - Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, or COPD, is the third leading cause of death worldwide. Medications are the mainstay of COPD management. A new study examined two different regimens and how these medications might impact older people JAMA Network Video Health &amp; Medicine for Senior Citizens No Time To See The Doctor? Try A Virtual Visit Online Doctors available through LiveHealth Online designed for business travelers and busy parents; allows patients who get sick on weekend to avoid going to emergency room, too By Anna Gorman, Kaiser Health Blog, Capsules September 17, 2014 - Patients looking for convenient medical appointments can now see UCLA Health System doctors using their cell phones, computers or tablets. Health and Medicine for Seniors New Statin Strategy from Lipid Association Challenges Others Expert panel urges individualized, cholesterol-targeted approach to heart disease and stroke By Tucker Sutherland, editor Sept. 15, 2014 – If you thought all the controversy about statin use – a daily pill for millions of senior citizens - has been settled, you better think again. An expert panel coordinated by the National Lipid Association has created its own outline for how to best treat people at risk for cardiovascular disease and it seems to challenge several previous recommendations, including guidelines by the American Heart Association and the American College of Cardiology. Other Media Report Stroke Risk Decline Primarily Among Seniors, Drop in Deaths in Younger Group Sept. 15, 2014 - Although previous studies have shown a steady decline in stroke risk and death, a new study says the decline in stroke risk was concentrated mainly in the over 65 set – senior citizens - with little progress in reducing the risk of strokes among young people. In contrast, the drop in stroke related deaths was primarily found among those under age 65, with mortality rates holding firm in older people. Health and Medicine for Seniors Diabetes Patients Have Heart Risk Other Than Cholesterol or Atherosclerosis 'It looks like diabetes may be slowly killing heart muscle in ways we had not thought of before.' Sept. 10, 2014 – Diabetes patients are at increased risk of heart failure and cardiac death unrelated to the common culprits of cholesterol and atherosclerosis, says a new study. People with diabetes who appear otherwise healthy may have a six-fold higher risk of developing heart failure regardless of their cholesterol levels, according to this research from Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health. Health and Medicine for Seniors Diabetes Patients Cope with Positive Outlook, Social Support Almost one out of every four senior citizens age 60 and over has diabetes, more than half of all U.S. adults with diabetes are seniors By Jennifer Abbasi Getting Old is Challenge Enough! Editor's Note: Getting old is challenge enough but almost one in four senior citizens in the U.S. also has to cope with the challenges of Type 2 diabetes. Learn more about diabetes below - insert in news report. Sept.9, 2014 - A positive outlook and support from people around them help patients with diabetes cope with psychosocial challenges of the disease, according to an international study that included researchers from Penn State College of Medicine . A better understanding of the emotional, psychological and social challenges people with diabetes face could improve health outcomes. Alzheimer's, Dementia &amp; Mental Health Do Not Upset Grandpa or Grandma Before Surgery, It Can Hinder Recovery Family conflicts, other non-physical worries before colon cancer surgery raise patients’ complication risk; reducing stress speeds recovery Sept. 2, 2014 - How well patients recover from cancer surgery may be influenced by more than their medical conditions and the operations themselves. Family conflicts and other non-medical problems may raise their risk of surgical complications, a Mayo Clinic study has found. Addressing such quality-of-life issues before an operation may reduce patients’ stress, speed their recoveries and save health care dollars, the research suggests. More chronic conditions means more health care services, negative outcomes, unnecessary hospitalizations, adverse drug reactions, declining functional status, and mortality Aug. 21, 2014 - Three new research awards — totaling $19.4 million over five years — will address the growing proportion of the U.S. population that has multiple chronic medical conditions. Estimates are that almost 75 percent of senior citizens over age 65 and 1 in 15 children suffer from two or more chronic medical conditions — such as diabetes mellitus, chronic kidney disease, hypertension, and chronic pain. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Deaths from Heart Disease and Stroke Have Plunged in Last Decade Drop in Hospitalizations Heart Attack -38.0% Unstable Angina -83.8% Heart Failure -30.5% Ischemic Stroke -33.6% Rates declined more for these conditions than for any others; improved lifestyle, quality of care and prevention strategies contributed to the decrease. Aug. 20, 2014 - U.S. hospitalizations and deaths from heart disease and stroke dropped significantly in the last decade, according to new research in the American Heart Association journal Circulation. More... Medicare &amp; Medicaid FDA Approves First Non-Invasive DNA Screening Test for Colorectal Cancer Collaboration with Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services contributed to proposed Medicare coverage for Cologuard Cologuard vs Fecal Immunochemical Test (FIT) Cologuard detected 92% of colorectal cancers, 42% of advanced adenomas. FIT screening detected 74% of cancers, 24% of advanced adenomas. Aug. 19, 2014 - The U.S. Food and Drug Administration on August 11 approved Cologuard, the first stool-based colorectal screening test that detects the presence of red blood cells and DNA mutations that may indicate the presence of certain kinds of abnormal growths that may be cancers such as colon cancer or precursors to cancer. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Too Many Senior Citizens Get Cancer Screening Says JAMA Study Researchers examined rates of prostate, breast, cervical and colorectal cancer screening in patients 65 or older Aug. 18, 2014 – A large number of senior citizens with limited life expectancy continue to receive routine screenings for prostate, breast, cervical and colorectal cancer, according to the authors of a study in JAMA Internal Medicine. And, they add, the procedures are unlikely to benefit them. More... Senior Citizen Alerts Most Seniors Not Aware of High Dose Flu Shot for Elderly Provided by Medicare Flu vaccine, including high dose version, is provided at no cost to seniors covered by Medicare - vaccine finder on page Aug. 17, 2014 – A stronger flu vaccine was created just for senior citizens. The high dose vaccine contains four times the antigens as the regular flu vaccine and is intended to create a stronger immune response for seniors, who are at greater risk of developing severe flu-related illnesses. The problem is that the majority of seniors are not aware of its importance. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Diabetes Risk Rapidly Increasing in U.S., Almost Half Adults Likely Victims Lifetime risk for Hispanics, black women probably more than 50 percent Aug. 13, 2014 – More than half of Hispanics and black women, and just less than half of all adults in the U.S. are projected to develop type 2 diabetes in their lifetime, according to projections from a new study in The Lancet Diabetes &amp; Endocrinology. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors Cognitive Problems in Senior Citizens Found as Risk for Stroke, Death Declining memory and cognitive ability may increase the risk of stroke, death in seniors over age 65 Aug. 12, 2014 – Most senior citizens are well aware that poor cardiovascular health, including a stroke, is an important risk factor for developing cognitive impairment. New research, however, says the opposite is also true for senior citizens age 65 and older: cognitive impairment is a risk factor for having a stroke. More... Medicare &amp; Medicaid News Obese Senior Citizens More Likely to Survive Deadly Sepsis Infection Study suggest that excess weight may cause the body to respond differently to critical illness Aug. 6, 2014 – It is not often we see good health news for fat senior citizens. The University of Michigan Health System claims, however, that obese senior citizens in Medicare were more likely to survive life-threatening sepsis infection than other patients. More... Health and Medicine for Seniors
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/ca852985-d1c6-37a0-b4e8-32a1089b2eb1" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-09T03:34:40Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:52:07.285Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.seniorjournal.com/NEWS/Eldercare/../../NEWS/Medicare/../../Health.htm" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
