<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2010 (60) - BMW 5 Series 520d SE 4dr £15,031 Loading Images... Date Registered: Oct 2010 Mileage: 59,634 miles Transmission: Manual Fuel: Diesel Price: £15,031 Colour: Grey Body Style: Saloon Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE EC Combined (mpg) 57.6 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 65.7 EC Urban (mpg) 47.9  &gt; 57 MPG 32 Insurance Group 184 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 129 CO2 (g/km) £110 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: SE Black Dakota Leather, Satellite Navigation, Bluetooth Telephone Preparation, 18 Alloys, Media Pack BMW Business, Auto Start-Stop, Brake Energy Regeneration, Sport Steering Wheel, Run Flat Tyres, Reversing Assist Camera, Auto Dim Interior Mirror, Heated Front Seats, Park Distance Control, USB Interface, BMW Assist Online Portal, Sun Protection Glass, Auto Drive Away Locking System, Remote Central Alarm Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 0113 333 9614 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating BMW is renowned for building cars that are great to drive but sometimes at the expense of comfort. read more High-class luxury car feel Superbly refined and quiet Outstanding handling Generous passenger room Forgiving ride Amazingly frugal 520d version Steering lacks some of the feel you'd expect from a BMW Review provided by: The following features are fitted on this car... ABS Alarm Audio remote control Bluetooth Connection Cruise control Electric door mirrors Front electric windows Front fog lights Heated door mirrors Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Traction control Trip computer Equipment This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 0113 333 9614 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle. Comfort / Convenience 12V power point front 12V socket in rear centre console ABS/EBD Aluminium brake calipers Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Body coloured door mirrors CBC - (Cornering brake control) Check control system Cruise control with brake function DSC+ Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric + heated aspheric door mirrors Electric front and rear windows with fingertip open/close + anti-trap all round Electromechanical parking brake Fogging sensor for front windscreen Front centre armrest Front cupholder Front/rear Parking distance control Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated windscreen washer jets Hill start assist iDrive Controller and Display with 7 monitor Illuminated glovebox with lock Isofix rear child seat preparation Luggage compartment release button in drivers A pillar Luggage compartment with electric unlocking via key remote control Multi-function controls for steering wheel On board computer Outside temperature display Personal Profile <NODE id="3118" />Rain sensor<NODE id="3129" /> with auto light activation system Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear centre armrest with 2 cupholders + storage Rear headrests Securing rings in luggage compartment Service interval indicator Speed limiter Tyre puncture warning system Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio/CD/MP3
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/6c32737b-fc4a-314b-a2ec-6419009474e2" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-10T22:43:04Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:16:06.409Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-40105768/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="3118" endPos="3129" type="product-class" surface="Rain sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
