<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Tatsuhiro Miyagi, Shigeru Tanaka, Izumi Hide, Toshihiko Shirafuji, Norio Sakai x Published: January 22, 2016 DOI: 10.1371/journal.pone.0147466 Figures Abstract G-protein-coupled receptor (GPR) 3 is a member of the GPR family that constitutively activates adenylate cyclase. We have reported that the expression of GPR3 in cerebellar granular neurons (CGNs) contributes to neurite outgrowth and modulates neuronal proliferation and survival. To further identify its role, we have analyzed the precise distribution and local functions of GPR3 in neurons. The fluorescently tagged GPR3 protein was distributed in the plasma membrane, the Golgi body, and the endosomes. In addition, we have revealed that the plasma membrane expression of GPR3 functionally up-regulated the levels of PKA, as measured by a PKA FRET indicator. Next, we asked if the PKA activity was modulated by the expression of GPR3 in CGNs. PKA activity was highly modulated at the neurite tips compared to the soma. In addition, the PKA activity at the neurite tips was up-regulated when GPR3 was transfected into the cells. However, local PKA activity was decreased when endogenous GPR3 was suppressed by a GPR3 siRNA. Finally, we determined the local dynamics of GPR3 in CGNs using time-lapse analysis. Surprisingly, the fluorescent GPR3 puncta were transported along the neurite in both directions over time. In addition, the anterograde movements of the GPR3 puncta in the neurite were significantly inhibited by actin or microtubule polymerization inhibitors and were also disturbed by the Myosin II inhibitor blebbistatin. Moreover, the PKA activity at the tips of the neurites was decreased when blebbistatin was administered. These results suggested that GPR3 was transported along the neurite and contributed to the local activation of PKA in CGN development. The local dynamics of GPR3 in CGNs may affect local neuronal functions, including neuronal differentiation and maturation. Citation: Miyagi T, Tanaka S, Hide I, Shirafuji T, Sakai N (2016) The Subcellular Dynamics of the Gs-Linked Receptor GPR3 Contribute to the Local Activation of PKA in Cerebellar Granular Neurons. PLoS ONE 11(1): e0147466. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0147466 Editor: Alexander G. Obukhov, Indiana University School of Medicine, UNITED STATES Received: August 11, 2015; Accepted: January 3, 2016; Published: January 22, 2016 Copyright: © 2016 Miyagi et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License , which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited. Data Availability: All relevant data are within the paper and its Supporting Information files. Funding: This work was supported by JSPS KAKENHI Grant Number 15K09317, the Ministry of Education, Science, Sports and Culture Grant-in-Aid for Scientific Research (to S.T.), and by grants from the Mitsubishi Pharma Research Foundation (to S.T.) and the Takeda Science Foundation (to S.T.). This work was also supported in part by the Japanese Smoking Research Foundation (to N.S. &amp; S.T.). The funders had no role in study design, data collection and analysis, decision to publish, or preparation of the manuscript. Competing interests: The authors have declared that no competing interests exist. In the present study, we analyzed the distribution of GPR3 in rodent mouse brain. We further analyzed the distribution of GPR3 in CGNs by transfecting fluorescently tagged GPR3 expression vectors. Time-lapse analysis of these cells revealed that the GPR3 florescent puncta moved along the neurite. The local dynamics of GPR3 were significantly correlated with local PKA activation at the neurite tips in CGNs. Our current studies suggested that GPR3 may contribute to the local activation of PKA in CGN development. Materials and Methods Animals C57BL/6 mice and Wistar rats were obtained from SLC (Shizuoka, Japan). GPR3-knockout mice (GPR3-/-; LacZ+/+ mice) were generated from cryopreserved embryos, which were obtained from MMRRC (Bar Harbor, ME) and resuscitated at the Institute of Laboratory Animal Science, Hiroshima University under the license of Deltagen, as previously described (San Mateo, CA) [ 4 ]. All experiments were approved by the Animal Care and Use Committee of Hiroshima University (approval number A13-155). Materials Dulbecco’s modified Eagle medium (DMEM), Ham's F12 Medium, Neurobasal A medium, B27 supplement, GlutaMAX, fetal bovine serum, Alexa Fluor secondary antibodies, LysoTracker, MitoTracker, Alexa Fluor 633-conjugated WGA, CellMask, and Hoechst33342 were obtained from Life Technologies (Carlsbad, CA). The penicillin/streptomycin solution and polyethyleneimine were from Nakalai Tesque (Kyoto, Japan). The HaloTag vectors and HaloTag ligands were from Promega (Madison, WI). The anti-KDEL antibody was from Enzo Life Sciences (Farmingdale, NY). The anti-Rab5 and anti-Rab7 antibodies were from Cell Signaling Technology (Danvers, MA). The G Silencer siRNA against rat GPR3 ( 5’-CCUACUACUGAGAGACAACtt-3’ / 5’-GUUGUGUCUGAGUAGUAGGtg-3’ ) and the negative control #1 siRNA were purchased from Ambion, Inc. (Austin, TX). The glass-bottomed culture dishes (35-mm diameter) were from MatTek (Ashland, MA) and the 8-well chamber slides were from AGC Techno Glass (Shizuoka, Japan). All other reagents or chemicals were from Sigma-Aldrich (St. Louis, MO), unless otherwise indicated. Plasmid Constructs The full-length mouse GPR3 cDNA was amplified by PCR and inserted in frame into the HaloTag expression vector, which was designated as pGPR3-HT. In the same way, a PCR fragment of mouse GPR3 was inserted in frame with monomeric GFP into a FLAG-tagged expression vector, which was designated as pGPR3-mAGFL. pYFP-mem was from Life Technologies. The expression vector for the FRET-based PKA sensor AKAR3-EV [ 26 ] was kindly provided Michiyuki Matsuda (Kyoto University). X-gal staining After anaesthetizing the GPR3 heterozygote knockout mice, the animals were transcardially perfused with an ice-cold 4% paraformaldehyde-PBS solution. The brains were then removed and post-fixed in 4% paraformaldehyde-PBS for eight hours. Coronal or sagittal sections were cut using a vibratome (Dosaka EM, Kyoto, Japan). The sections were then immersed in 0.05% glutaraldehyde (EM grade) for 10 min for additional fixation, followed by two washes with phosphate-buffered saline. The sections were immersed in an X-gal staining solution (1 mM MgCl2, 3 mM potassium ferricyanide, 3 mM potassium ferrocyanide, and 1 mg/ml X-gal in phosphate buffer) for one hour at 37°C. The X-gal reaction was terminated by washing in PBS(-) followed by 4% paraformaldehyde. The images were captured on a BZ-9000 microscope (Keyence, Tokyo, Japan) using the tiling scan mode, and then reconstructed to a single image with built-in image joining software. Cell culture, CGN isolation, and transfection The SH-SY5Y human neuroblastoma cell line was obtained from ATCC (American Tissue Culture Collection, Manassas, VA). SH-SY5Y cells were grown in DMEM/F-12 (1:1) media supplemented with 10% fetal bovine serum and 1% penicillin-streptomycin. The CGNs were isolated from Wistar rats or C57BL/6 mice, as detailed in elsewhere [ 3 ]. Briefly, the entire cerebellum was removed from postnatal day 7 (P7) pups and dissociated using the Worthington Papain Dissociation System (Worthington Biochemical, Lakewood, NJ). The dissociated cells were then separated using two-step Percoll gradient (35%/ 60%) centrifugation. After centrifugation at 2,000 ×g for 10 min, the granule neuron-enriched fraction was collected from between the 35% and 60% Percoll layers. The isolated neurons were washed once with PBS and suspended in DMEM medium supplemented with 10% fetal bovine serum and plated at 5x105/cm2 onto 0.03% polyethyleneimine-coated glass bottom dishes and 8-well chamber slides. Four hours after cell plating, the culture media was replaced with CGN culture medium: Neurobasal A media supplemented with 2% B27 supplement, 200 μM of GlutaMAX and 1% penicillin-streptomycin. Using this protocol, 95–99% of the cultured cells were neurons. All cells were cultured in a humidified atmosphere containing 5% CO2 at 37°C. For the imaging experiments, the fluorescently tagged GPR3 expression vectors were transfected into the CGNs or cell lines using a NEPA21 Super Electroporator (Napa Gene, Chiba, Japan) according to the manufacturer’s protocols. Briefly, 5x106 cells were counted using a TC20 automated cell counter (BioRad, Hercules, CA) and re-suspended in 100 μl of serum free Neurobasal A medium, mixed with 50 μg of plasmid DNA or 1.5 μg of siRNA, and transferred into a cuvette (2 mm GAP) (Napa Gene). The electroporation for the CGNs and SH-SY5Y cells was performed using the following conditions: for the poring pulse—175 V, 2.5 msec pulse length, 50 msec pulse interval, 4 pulses, and a 10% decay rate; and for the transfer pulse—20 V, 50 msec pulse length, 50 msec pulse interval, 5 pulses, and a 40% decay rate. After electroporation, the cells were immediately rescued with 600 μl of DMEM medium containing 10% FBS and plated onto the glass bottomed dishes at a density of 5x105 cells/ well. Four hours after plating, the culture medium was replaced with fresh CGN culture medium. Using this protocol, at least 80% of cells were viable on the following day (data not shown). Analyses of GPR3 localization and time-lapse imaging To analyze the localization of GPR3, the CGNs were transfected with pGPR3-HT or pGPR3-mAGFL plasmids as described above. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the cells were fixed with 4% paraformaldehyde. To determine the co-localization of GPR3 with the endoplasmic reticulum and endosomes, GPR3-transfected CGNs were immunostained with anti-KDEL (1:100), anti-Rab5 (1:100), and anti-Rab7 antibodies (1:100), respectively, followed by Alexa Fluor-conjugated goat anti-mouse and anti-rabbit IgG antibodies (1:400), respectively. To analyze the localization of GPR3 in the Golgi bodies, pGPR3-mAGFL-transfected CGNs were also labeled with WGA633, a Golgi body marker, for 30 min before fixation. To analyze the plasma membrane localization of GPR3, the CGNs were co-transfected with pGPR3-HT and pYFP-mem, a marker for the plasma membrane. To further confirm the plasma membrane localization of GPR3, pGPR3-mAGFL-transfected CGNs were also labeled with CellMask, another plasma membrane marker, for 30 min before fixation. The labeled cells were counterstained with Hoechst 33342. The co-localization of the fluorescently tagged GPR3 with the organelle markers was evaluated using a Zeiss LSM510 META confocal microscope (Carl Zeiss, Oberkochen, Germany). The fluorescent intensity was analyzed by 'line-profiling' using MetaMorph software. Briefly, to detect the PKA activities in the plasma membrane and cellular organelles, a line was drawn across the cell body that avoided the nucleus, and then a list of intensity values was obtained. To detect the PKA activities in the neurites or neurite tips, the line was drawn across the neurites or growth cones at the neurite tips, respectively. To capture the time-lapse images, the neurons were transfected with pGPR3-HT or pGPR3-mAGFL plasmids. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the cells were imaged with a BZ-9000 fluorescent microscope (Keyence, Tokyo, Japan). The microscope was equipped with a CO2 incubation chamber (Tokai Hit, Shizuoka, Japan), and the cultured cells were maintained in a humidified atmosphere containing 5% CO2 at 37°C while the images were captured. PKA FRET analysis For the PKA FRET analysis, the neurons were co-transfected with AKAR3-EV and a GPR3 expression plasmid. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the cells were imaged with a BZ-9000 fluorescent microscope equipped with an oil immersion 60x Nikon Plan Apo VC objective lens with a numerical aperture of 1.4 using 2 x 2 binning on built-in cooled CCD camera with a 2.5x digital zoom. While capturing the images, the culture dishes were kept in a humidified atmosphere containing 5% CO2 at 37°C. CFP and FRET images were obtained with two sets of filter cubes; one with the 438/24 nm excitation filter, 458nm dichroic mirror, and the 483/32nm emission filter for CFP channel, and the second one with the 438/24 nm excitation filter, 458nm dichroic mirror, and the 542/27nm emission filter for FRET channel (Semrock, Lake Forest, IL). Samples were exposed 83ms for both CFP and FRET with a 20% transmittance with a natural density filter in the excitation light passed through diffusion filter from the 120W Hg arc lamp source. To obtain the FRET level of PKA in the fully activated condition, the FRET/CFP images were also captured after administering dbcAMP (final conc. 1 mM) into the culture medium with a bath application. After each measurement, FRET and CFP fluorescent values were corrected for bleedthrough ( S2B and S2C Fig ) and background as described [ 27 , 28 ]. The corrected FRET/CFP ratio images were analyzed by the MetaMorph software (Universal Imaging, West Chester, PA). To analyze the distribution of PKA activity in a single cell, the CGNs were transfected with AKAR3-EV/pGPR3-HT or AKAR3-EV/mock vectors. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the CGNs were stained with CellMask (plasma membrane), ER tracker (ER), WGA633 (Golgi body), LysoTracker (lysosome), and MitoTracker (mitochondria), respectively. The FRET/CFP ratios in the images were visualized and analyzed by the MetaMorph software. Data analysis The data are expressed as the means ± SEM. The statistical analyses were performed using one-way ANOVA followed by Fisher's PLSD test, unless otherwise indicated. A value of p &lt; 0.05 was considered significant. Results The distributions and subcellular localizations of GPR3 in mouse brain Fig 1. The subcellular distribution of fluorescently tagged GPR3 in CGNs. (A) We employed a GPR3-HT expression vector to analyze the localization of GPR3. After transfecting the GPR3-HT vector into the CGNs, the cells were labeled with the TMR HaloTag ligand at forty-eight hours after transfection. A representative image was shown. (B) To evaluate the localization of GPR3 at the plasma membrane, the CGNs were co-transfected with the GPR3-HT and YFP-mem expression vectors, followed by TMR HaloTag ligand labeling. YFP-mem fluorescence was shown in the green pseudo-color to easily visualize the co-localization. (C-F) To evaluate the localization of GPR3 in the endoplasmic reticulum, Golgi body, and endosomes, the GPR3-mAGFL expression vector was transfected into the CGNs. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the cells were immunostained with various organelle markers: anti-KDEL antibody (endoplasmic reticulum), WGA633 (Golgi body), anti-Rab5 antibody (early endosome), and anti-Rab7 antibody (late endosome). Co-localization of GPR3 with the organelle markers was evaluated by confocal microscopy using built-in Z-stack analysis software. Scale bar = 10 μm. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0147466.g001 Subcellular analyses of GPR3-mediated PKA activity in CGNs Fig 2. The GPR3-mediated modulation of PKA activity was analyzed with a PKA FRET indicator. (A-C) HEK293 cells were co-transfected with the AKAR3-EV and GPR3 expression plasmids. AKAR3-EV and the mock vector were co-transfected as a control. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the CFP and FRET images were captured using a fluorescent microscope. Some of the AKAR3-EV/mock vector co-transfected cells were treated with 1 mM dbcAMP 15 min before the images were captured. The FRET/CFP ratios in the images were analyzed by the MetaMorph software. (A) Representative images of cells transfected with either the mock vector (top) or the GPR3 vector (bottom) are shown. (B) The YFP/CFP ratio in each group were analyzed identically in each dish (n = 8). The values are expressed as the percentage of the FRET/CFP ratio in the GPR3-transfected or dbcAMP-treated cells compared to the mock-transfected cells, i.e., the percentage of the control vector-transfected cells. The means ± SEM were calculated for each condition. The asterisk (*) represents p &lt; 0.001 compared to the cells transfected with the mock vector. (C) The FRET/CFP ratio in the cytoplasm and plasma membrane were evaluated in a single GPR3-transfected cell. The asterisk (*) represents p &lt; 0.001 compared to the values for the cytoplasm. (D-E) The PKA activity in GPR3-expressing CGNs was evaluated by AKAR3-EV. CGNs were co-transfected with mock/AKAR3-EV or pGPR3-HT/AKAR3-EV expression plasmids. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the CGNs were stained with organelle-specific markers for the plasma membrane, ER, Golgi body, lysosome, and mitochondria. (D) Representative images of CGNs stained with CellMask (plasma membrane), ER tracker (ER), WGA633 (Golgi body), LysoTracker (lysosome), and MitoTracker (mitochondria) were shown (middle raw). The CFP/YFP ratios in the images were visualized and analyzed by the MetaMorph software (right raw). (E) The FRET/CFP ratios were compared in each organelle of the mock/AKAR3-EV- or pGPR3-HT/AKAR3-EV-transfected CGNs. The FRET/CFP ratios were significantly increased in the plasma membrane of the GPR3-HT-expressing CGNs compared to the mock-transfected CGNs. The data represent the means ± SEM for each condition (n = 6). The asterisk (*) represents p &lt; 0.05. (F) The PKA activity in the plasma membrane around soma was analyzed in CGNs transfected with control siRNA+Mock, GPR3 siRNA+Mock, and GPR3 siRNA+ pGPR3-HT, respectively. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the FRET/CFP images were taken. The FRET/CFP ratio in each group were analyzed identically. The data represent the means ± SEM for each condition (n = 10). The asterisk (*) represents p &lt; 0.05 and the double asterisk (**) represents p &lt; 0.005. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0147466.g002 The PKA activity was highly modulated at the tips of neurite by GPR3 expression in CGNs We further evaluated whether the local PKA activity at the neurite tips was modulated by the expression of GPR3. CGNs were co-transfected with a GPR3 expression vector and AKAR3-EV, and FRET/CFP images were taken 48 hours after transfection. After the images were captured, the cells were treated with 1 mM dbcAMP for 15 min, and another set of FRET/CFP images were captured in the same cell to evaluate the fully activated PKA. The FRET/CFP ratios are expressed as the percentage of the maximum level stimulated by 1 mM dbcAMP in each cell. The FRET/CFP ratio in the plasma membranes of the neurite tips was significantly increased in GPR3-transfected CGNs compared to the mock vector-transfected CGNs ( Fig 3C and 3D ). However, the increased PKA activity at the neurite tips was significantly decreased when endogenous GPR3 expression was down-regulated by the GPR3 siRNA. The down-regulation of PKA by the GPR3 siRNA was rescued by co-transfection of GPR3 siRNA and an siRNA-resistant GPR3 expression vector. We performed similar experiments using the SH-SY5Y neuroblastoma cell line. Real-time PCR analysis revealed that GPR3 was endogenously expressed in the SH-SY5Y cells, but GPR6 and GPR12 were expressed at very low levels in these cells ( S3A Fig ). The increased PKA activity at the neurite tips was also observed when GPR3 was up-regulated in these cells ( S3C Fig ). The PKA activity at the neurite tips was significantly reduced in the GPR3 siRNA-transfected cells compared to the control siRNA-transfected cells ( S3D Fig ). In addition, the GPR3 siRNA-mediated reduction of the PKA activity in the neurites was rescued when the siRNA-resistant GPR3 expression vector was co-transfected with GPR3 siRNA. All of these results indicated that GPR3 expression is associated with local PKA activity at the neurite tips in neuronal cells. Analyses of local GPR3 dynamics in CGNs Next, we asked whether the transportation of the GPR3 puncta in neurite is associated with the local expression of GPR3. To address this, we transfected the fluorescently tagged GPR3 expression vector and evaluated the fluorescent intensity of GPR3 at the neurite tips with or without the actin or tubulin inhibitors. When Latrunculin B or Nocodazole was administered to these cells, the fluorescent intensity of GPR3 in the plasma membrane at the neurite tips was remarkably decreased compared to the control ( Fig 4D and 4E ). Furthermore, administration of Blebbistatin also decreased the fluorescent intensity of GPR3 at the neurite tips. However, the fluorescent intensity of GPR3 was not changed when Monastrol was administered. Thus, these results indicated that the GPR3 puncta are preferentially transported toward at the neurite tips through actin- and tubulin-dependent mechanisms. GPR3 transport in neurites was associated with local elevation of PKA activity at the neurite tips Finally, we asked whether the movements of GPR3 in neurites affect the local PKA activity. To address this, GPR3- and AKAR3-EV-expressing CGNs were treated with the myosin II inhibitor. Administration of Blebbistatin (50 μM) significantly decreased the levels of PKA at the neurite tips, whereas addition of Monastrol did not change the PKA levels ( Fig 5A and 5B ). These results implicated that the GPR3 puncta were transported to the plasma membrane at the neurite tips in myosin II-dependent manner, thereby contributing to the local activation of PKA at the neurite tips. Fig 5. The PKA activity at the neurite tips was modulated by the local transport of GPR3 in CGNs. (A-B) Forty-five hours after transfection, GPR3-HT was labeled with the TMR HaloTag ligand for 15 min. After three sequential washes in PBS, the cells were incubated with Blebbistatin or Monastrol for another 2 hours. As a control, a 1:1000 dilution of DMSO was added to the culture medium. After capturing the CFP and FRET images, 1 mM dbcAMP was applied to the bath and additional CFP and FRET images were captured. (A) The representative FRET/CFP images from control, Blebbistatin-treated (5 μM, 50 μM), and Monastrol-treated (0.2 mM, 2 mM) CGNs at the neurite tips were shown. (B) The FRET/CFP ratio in each inhibitor-treated group were analyzed identically. The FRET/CFP ratios are expressed as the percentage of the maximum level stimulated by 1 mM dbcAMP in each cell. The data represent the means ± SEM for each condition (n = 8). The asterisk (*) represents p &lt; 0.005. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0147466.g005 In the current study, we found that the expression of GPR3 in developing CGNs correlated with local PKA activation at the neurite tips in a myosin II-dependent manner. In the development of cultured hippocampal neurons, several minor processes are elaborated from the cell body, and one of the minor processes extends rapidly to form the axon [ 42 , 43 ]. Similar polarization is observed in the development of CGNs [ 44 ]. Recent studies suggested that several internal cues (i.e., Rac1, MARK2 kinase, SAD kinase, and CAM Kinase) and external cues (i.e., neurotrophins, Wnts, IGF-1, TGF-β, and TAG-1) affect axon formation [ 45 ]. Among them, SAD kinase is phosphorylated by LKB1, which is phosphorylated by PKA [ 46 , 47 ]. Thus, the downstream pathway of cAMP is suggested to be a key regulator of neuronal polarization [ 48 ]. The expression of GPR3 in CGNs is increased during neuronal differentiation and maintained thereafter [ 5 ]. In the current study, we found that GPR3 was transported to and accumulated at increased levels at the neurite tips and thus contributed to local PKA activation at the neurite tips in CGN development. Together, these results suggested that the GPR3-mediated local PKA activation may play a role in axon formation during neuronal development. Supporting Information S1 Fig. The distribution of GPR3 promoter activity in the mouse central nervous system. A GPR3-/-; LacZ +/+ mouse was employed to determine the distribution of GPR3 in the developing postnatal cerebellum, where the E. coli LacZ gene was substituted into the GPR3 locus. Coronal or sagittal sections of the central nervous system were cut with a vibratome at 100 μm thickness. The GPR3 promoter activity was evaluated by β-galactosidase expression in the slices using X-gal staining (detailed in the Materials and methods ). The dark green staining in each section represented the locations where the GPR3 promoter was activated. A: anterior from the bregma; P: posterior from the bregma. Scale bar = 0.5 mm. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0147466.s001 (TIF) S2 Fig. The acceptor photo bleaching experiments for AKAR3-EV and the bleedthrough corrections. (A) We performed acceptor photo bleaching experiments to confirm that the FRET phenomena of AKAR3-EV has really occurred in our system. CGNs were transfected with AKAR3EV expression vector. Forty eight hours after transfection, 1mM dbcAMP was administrated in the medium and incubated for 15 min. FRET and CFP images were taken every one min. and acceptor photo bleaching was performed by exposing YFP excitation light for one min without using a natural density filter nor diffusion filter. After bleaching, FRET and CFP images were also taken every one min. (B-C) To address CFP bleedthrough into YFP channel, CFP only expressing vector was transfected in CGNs. CFP transfected cells were then excited by 438nm CFP excitation light and fluorescence was recorded in the CFP and YFP emission channel. YFP channel intensity per CFP channel intensity was calculated and found out 0.23 in our system (Coefficient α). To address YFP excitation by CFP excitation light, YFP only expressing vector was transfected in CGNs. YFP transfected cells were then excited by CFP or YFP excitation light and fluorescence was recorded in the YFP emission channel. YFP channel intensity excited by CFP emission per FRET channel intensity excited by YFP emission was calculated and found out 0.01 in our system (Coefficient β). We then calculated corrected FRET values according to the following equation by MetaMorph software. [CorrFRET] = [RawFRET] − β*[Acceptor] − α*[Donor]. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0147466.s002 (TIF) S3 Fig. The PKA activity at the neurite tips was modulated by the expression of GPR3 in SH-SY5Y cells. (A) We evaluated the intrinsic expression of GPR3 in SH-SY5Y cells under normal culture conditions. The total RNA was extracted from SH-SY5Y cells in normal culture conditions. The RNA samples were subjected to quantitative RT-PCR analysis using primers specific to human GPR3, GPR6, and GPR12. All quantitative data were adjusted using the levels of the GAPDH mRNA as internal control. Real-time PCR analysis revealed that GPR3 was endogenously expressed in SH-SY5Y cells, but GPR6 and GPR12 were expressed at very low levels in these cells. (B) The SH-SY5Y cells were transfected with a control siRNA or GPR3 siRNA. Twenty-four hours post-transfection, the levels of the GPR3 mRNA was examined by real-time PCR. The endogenous expression of GPR3 was reduced to ~10–15% by the transfection of the GPR3 siRNA. (C) SH-SY5Y cells were co-transfected with AKAR3-EV and a GPR3 expression plasmid. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the FRET/CFP images were captured using a fluorescent microscope. After capturing the images, some cells were treated with 1 mM dbcAMP for 15 min and additional FRET/CFP images were captured to evaluate the fully activated PKA. The FRET/CFP ratio in each group were analyzed identically in each dish, as previously described. The FRET/CFP ratios are expressed as the percentage of the maximum level stimulated by 1 mM dbcAMP in each cell. The data represent the means ± SEM for each condition (n = 8). The asterisk (*) represents p &lt; 0.0001. (D) SH-SY5Y cells were co-transfected with AKAR3-EV and the GPR3 siRNA. Forty-eight hours after transfection, the FRET/CFP images were captured using a fluorescent microscope. For the rescue experiments, a GPR3-expressing plasmid was also co-transfected with the GPR3 siRNA. The FRET value in each condition was evaluated as described above. The data represent the means ± SEM for each condition (n = 6). The asterisk (*) represents p &lt; 0.005. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0147466.s003 (TIF) S1 Movie. Fluorescence time-lapse movie of a single GPR3-HT-expressing CGN. Representative movie of the GPR3-HT transfected CGNs was shown. The time counter in the upper left corner represents minutes after initiation of recording. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0147466.s004 (AVI)
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/2c9879e4-6f1b-30c8-a06e-a2743395ceca" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-23T05:12:10Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:52:06.423Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0147466" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
