<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Rather than write an essay, I'll keep it short. Some background: I tried the consumer version of <NODE id="97" />Oculus<NODE id="103" /> Rift<NODE id="108" /> sans controllers for 8 minutes with the <NODE id="149" />xbox<NODE id="153" /> controller on EVE and chronos as well as DK2 on the Omni, and the DK2 last year. For the <NODE id="243" />HTC<NODE id="246" /> <NODE id="247" />Vive<NODE id="251" /> I got the 20 minute demo this year with controllers, the bike demo (an exercise bike made by a third-party used to control your movements with leaning for directions and buttons on the ends of the handlebars for input) and Elite Dangerous for a while. According to one person who's tried the Oculus controllers, they have some bugs with movement detection which caused him to clip through the train in Bullet Train. I'm speculating that it could also be the interference caused by the massive amounts of devices from the show floor in addition to bugs. EVE Valkyrie's control scheme is very intuitive and looking around in the cockpit and leading your target was a lot of fun Chronos (not the Zelda copy :P) for Oculus was interesting, but the Oculus didn't necessarily add anything compelling to the game experience aside from the visuals. Most likely great for people suffering from motion sickness due to fixed perspective camera HTC Vive's controllers have some difficulty tracking in heavy sunlight (which happened because the demo tent was outside the convention center, I turned toward the back of the tent and it was instantly better). Makes sense because it's an infrared laser, and the laser projectors remind me of self-driving car sensors. Also it means that you can't really be sitting next to your buddy when they're playing the Vive because you don't want to be occluding the lasers. The controllers communicate to the HMD via bluetooth. The Vive controllers are VERY accurate. I tried estimating how accurate by drawing very tight spirals in three dimensions on the Vive demo and if I had to guess they're about within 3mm of tracking accuracy. The Chaperone system is really useful, with the grid showing you the bounds of an area you predetermine. Also being a able to see through the virtual world with the embedded camera system was great. Dumb name though. Looks like HTC's people were happy to see Oculus show it's cards on pricing and to gauge the public's reaction. It looks like there isn't a planned HTC lite edition that is bundled without the controllers, since they want everyone on the same experience. However they are shipping with more hardware: 2x base stations, the headset and controllers. The base stations are reported to be cheap though. I think they said the motors inside are similar if not the same as dvd drive spinner motors. Fidelity on both systems are roughly the same, with IPD adjusters on both and quality roughly the same as well. Refresh rate was high and a no noticeable lag on both. Both were also equally comfy in the limited time I had. The Omni's shoes are SUPER SLICK. Walking up the stairs to the platform was a bit perilous but thankfully there were handrails to prevent me from face planting and some kind of black carpet on the ground to help with traction. The machines the HTC Vive were running off of had Titan X's. The Elite Dangerous rig was a laptop with a 980m CES 2015's Oculus Demo was probably the best way to introduce people to VR. I honestly wish they had last year's standing demo on this year's consumer ready unit rather than playing xbox controlled games in a chair. Nothing quite beat the war-torn street with bullets whizzing by and seeing a car explode and flip above you. Comparison between DK2 and CV1: CV1 seems like it has lower latency, and the optics/screen were improved. I didn't get the pixel screen-mesh effect this year. Also the headset seems lighter overall. Did not like the bike demo HTC Vive + 3rd party bike. It consisted of a stationary bike with buttons on the handlebars, and I had to lean with my shoulders to turn left and right. The leaning was not that responsive. I had to lean REALLY far to turn, almost uncomfortably so. Still, I'm sure some gyms are going to the touting this this year. Also the demos graphics weren't that great. All base stations for the HTC Vive were on mounting poles looking down towards the player, in diagonally opposite locations about 6 feet high off the ground. 360 degree cameras were everywhere as well, probably to capitalize on the VR stuff and youtube VR. That's it for now. I'll add more if I can remember anything else.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/08236393-2e0d-3e37-9022-bf35487bdee7" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-11T01:21:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:38:24.162Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.reddit.com/r/oculus/comments/40e4bq/i_got_to_try_both_the_latest_oculus_rift_and_htc/?limit=500#40e4bq" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="97" endPos="103" type="organization-company" surface="Oculus" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="97" endPos="108" type="product" surface="Oculus Rift" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="149" endPos="153" type="product" surface="xbox" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="243" endPos="246" type="organization-company" surface="HTC" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="247" endPos="251" type="product" surface="Vive" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="5" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="6" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
