<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>White Papers 1-20 of 51 &lt; first | prev | next | last &gt; Tips for Using Multi-Function Safety Relays in Automation Industries One or more multi-function safety relays can often be used to replace many basic single-function safety relays, simplifying installations and saving money. AutomationDirect 07/28/2014 Benefits of AutomationDirect Group Motor Protection Rather than explaining the full NEC standard, the paper provides an easy-to-understand overview of Article 430 of the NEC motor branch circuit requirements for short circuit and ground fault protection, as well as motor overload protection. This White Paper provides detailed information to distinguish between overcurrent and overload protection, as well as when it is more beneficial to provide protection for individual motors over group motors. AutomationDirect 07/09/2014 Cut Costs, Boost Machine Flexibility with Distributed Servo Systems In this latest installment of the Control Design Essentials series, learn how you can cut costs and build more flexible machines with distributed servo systems. Control Design Staff 04/16/2014 How OEMs Can Improve the Energy Efficiency of Machines But while many OEMs are conscious of the growing pressure and demands coming from the market, they are reluctant to make changes due to the perception that new technologies will make their machines more expensive to sell. Schneider Electric 03/27/2014 Market Intelligence Report: Motion, Drives and Motors February 2014 MIR Identifies Usage and Application Trends Among Machine Builders ControlDesign.com 01/31/2014 Top 10 Tips: Specifying VFDs This white paper offers some expert tips to consider. AutomationDirect 01/14/2014 Pneumatics &amp; Hydraulics In this Market Intelligence Report, you will find detailed survey results with key findings summarized. ControlDesign.com 08/27/2013 Integrated Architecture Scales to Fit Your 'Right-Sized' Control System Learn how a single, scalable system can help machine and equipment builders reduce cost and complexity, and provide a more competitive offering around the globe. <NODE id="2071" />Rockwell Automation<NODE id="2090" /> 05/21/2013 <NODE id="2102" />Feedback Sensors<NODE id="2118" /> Keep Servo Motors on Target Fundamentally a servo system can perform no more accurately than the accuracy of the feedback device controlling it. In addition, errors in speed or position can be introduced into the system by the less than perfect mechanisms that transfer the motor power to the load. Environmental factors like electrical noise or temperature  may also introduce positioning errors. Sometimes the errors are acceptable. More frequently, however, they are not. After all, servo motors can be expensive, and the expectation is that they will be the most reliable and accurate of all positioning devices. When it comes to high-performance servo applications, feedback devices fall into several different categories. In this white paper, learn how each offers unique advantages and disadvantages, both electrical and mechanical, which make one better suited for a particular application than another. Gene Matthews, product manager for Kollmorgen 02/19/2013 Motion, Drives and Motors: Usage and Application Trends An electronic survey of our readers was conducted in February 2013 in order to identify usage and application trends of motion, drives and motors among the industrial machine builders that comprise our readership. ControlDesign.com 02/05/2013
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/4db193ff-edd2-3592-bbaf-f86f5b734c74" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-06T12:47:54Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:04:37.237Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.controldesign.com/whitepapers/?categoryid=10&amp;start=0" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="2071" endPos="2090" type="organization-company" surface="Rockwell Automation" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="2102" endPos="2118" type="product-class" surface="Feedback Sensors" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="2" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
