<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Please Try again! expand This Robot Changes Color Like a Chameleon Jamie Condliffe | Gawker Media Feb 5, 2016, 02.19 PM IST Imagine a world where robots creep up on you: Electric motors just a gentle whir, hard shells changing color to blend in with their surroundings. Well, there's no need to imagine-it's happened. Researchers form the Guoping Wang of Wuhan University in China have created a robot that changes color with its surroundings, much like a chameleon. It uses a series of plasmonic displays to achieve the feat. These displays are glass sheets with a series of holes in them that measure just 50 nanometers in diameter. The team added a gold coating, creating small domes of the precious metal where each hole lies, and then a smear of electrolyte gel with added silver ions was layered on top. Varying a local electric field causes some silver ions to adhere to the gold surface, the result being a change in color. Add a <NODE id="938" />sensor<NODE id="944" /> to the robot to detect the color of the surroundings, and the electric field can be tuned so the robot changes color with its local environment. The research is published in ACS Nano . The robot's color changing abilities are modest right now: it can only manage red, green or blue. But in theory if it can create the RGB palette, it can turn any color it damn well pleases. That'll be the next version, then. [ ACS Nano via New Scientist ] Next StoryAugmented Reality Climbing Looks Like So Much Damn Fun Also on Gizmodo 7 Robots That You May See In The Zoo Of Future prev next of 7 7 Robots That You May See In The Zoo Of Future It’s A Robot Chameleon This 3D printed robot emulates a real chameleon skin-color changing abilities. Created by researchers at China’s, this robot showcases its camouflage technology. Researchers believe that this technology could one day allow military vehicles or body armor to blend perfectly into the background. (Image: ACS Nano via New Scientist) ​Here Comes An Energy-efficient Kangaroo Robot With the BionicKangaroo , Festo has technologically reproduced the unique way a kangaroo moves. Like its natural model, it can recover the energy when jumping, store it and efficiently use it for the next jump. The German engineering-driven company hopes that this creation will help demonstrate how energy from movement can be recovered more effectively. (Image: Festo) Meet The Daler Inspired by shape of a vampire bat known as Desmodus rotundus, the DALER (Deployable Air-Land Exploration Robot) comes with the wings that have been actuated using a foldable skeleton mechanism covered with a soft fabric such that they can be used both as wings as well as legs. This robot, which has been designed at the Laboratory of Intelligent Systems, comes with a primary motive of carrying out exploration, search-and-rescue, or surveillance applications. (Image: YouTube) Pleurobot: A New Salamander-inspired Robot Scientists at Switzerland’s École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne have come up with a new salamander-inspired robot that can swim and crawl. Known as Pleurobot , this robot will help researchers understand exactly how nervous system coordinates movement in vertebrates. (Image: YouTube) Say ‘Hi’ To RoboBee With an aim to open up a wide range of discoveries and practical innovations, researchers at Harvard’s School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS) have developed an insect-sized robot known as the RoboBee , which is capable of both flying and swimming. The researchers stated that it can be used for pollinating a field of crops, in various search and rescue operations, hazardous environment exploration, military surveillance, high resolution weather and climate mapping as well as traffic monitoring. (Image: robotinsider.com) The World’s First Robotic Elephant That Educates Kids Children have a natural empathy for animals. And when they learn about animal suffering, many kids want to do their part to help stop it. So schoolchildren across the country are getting the opportunity to interact with a recently freed 'elephant,' thanks to PETA’s new walking, talking 6.5-foot-tall robot named Ellie , which is voiced by actor Priyanka Chopra, star of ABC’s new hit show Quantico. (Image: PETA) LS3: This Robot Is Inspired By A Mule Boston Dynamics, a US-headquartered engineering and robotics design company, has invented a robot named ‘LS3’ that follows its leader using computer vision, so it does not need a dedicated driver. It is also capable of travelling to designated locations using terrain sensing and GPS. This robot has been design with an aim to assist soldiers in the field by carrying substantial equipment loads on patrol, with built-in gas engines and voice control. (Image: Boston Dynamics)
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/2d6788ed-fd88-3fce-a7d7-c88ae0b44087" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-10T01:30:37Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:52:25.379Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.gizmodo.in/science/This-Robot-Changes-Color-Like-a-Chameleon/articleshow/50865231.cms" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="938" endPos="944" type="product-class" surface="sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
