<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Monday, January 18, 2016 Zebra Technologies Introduces Smart Refrigeration IoT Solution Reference Design for Retailers Automatic solution powered by Zatar and Atmel low-power wireless mesh technologies, eliminates the cost of manual, inaccurate monitoring of refrigeration units By PR Newswire NEW YORK , Jan. 18, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- Zebra Technologies Corporation (NASDAQ: ZBRA),a global leader in solutions and services that provide real-time visibility into organizations' assets, people and transactions and Atmel Corporation, a leader in microcontroller (MCU) and touch technology solutions, today announced it is demonstrating a smart refrigeration Internet of Things (IoT) reference design at NRF 2016 being held on Jan. 17-20, 2016 , at the Jacob K. Javits Convention Center in New York City . In addition to the latest in low-power silicon and cloud services, this demonstration at booth #1603 will show how products designed with the ARM mbed IoT Device Platform bring improved security and energy efficiency. Consumer demand for fresher, safer food and medication is driving retailers to invest in automatic, non-invasive temperature monitoring of refrigeration units. According to the CDC, 48 million Americans get sick each year from foodborne diseases. Compliance is increasingly necessary with the adoption of the Food Safety Modernization Act. Zebra's Zatar , the first ARM mbed enabled IoT Cloud Service, offers seamless, out-of-the-box connectivity with any device for both reference designs and commercial-scale solutions. Zebra is working together with silicon partners like Atmel to bring state-of-the-art, IoT reference designs that Fortune 1000 companies can pilot immediately and deploy in-scale to address specific industry pain points like temperature monitoring of perishable goods. KEY FACTS The Smart Refrigeration IoT Solution Reference Design provides an easy-to-deploy, cloud-based temperature monitoring solution using wireless sensors, mesh networking technologies and the Zatar IoT Cloud Service. This solution utilizes inexpensive sensors together with Atmel | SMART 802.15.4 solutions and mesh communications with Zatar. The collaboration between Zatar and Atmel will allow retailers, manufacturers and logistics companies to quickly deploy automatic, commercial-class temperature monitoring in their stores and facilities from trusted vendors. The first ARM mbed-enabled IoT Cloud Service, Zatar is an open, industry-standard-based platform designed to manage large-scale, commercial deployments and reduce the time-to-market for connected products. SUPPORTING QUOTES Pierre Roux , director, Wireless Microcontrollers, Atmel Corporation Managing the quality and inventory of perishable goodsa significant way to reduce costshas been one of the biggest challenges in the retail industry for decades. The new smart refrigeration reference design developed by Zebra Technologies is managed through a secure wireless connection to the end point, allowing retailers to easily add real-time temperature monitoring. We are excited to team with Zebra to bring this new design to market and to propel the retail industry into the age of the IoT. Thomas Kurian , senior director, New Growth Platforms, ZebraTechnologies Managing and recording the temperature of fast-moving, perishable goods is increasingly necessary for a superior, safer customer experience. Bringing together Atmel's low-power, mesh technologies with Zatar, our IoT Cloud Service, helps retailers eliminate the cost and inaccuracy of manual recordings and meet compliance requirements. SUPPORTING RESOURCES Website: Zebra Technologies Facebook: Zebra Technologies Twitter: @ZebraTechnology About Zebra Technologies Zebra (NASDAQ: ZBRA) makes businesses as smart and connected as the world we live in. Zebra tracking and visibility solutions transform the physical to digital, creating the data streams enterprises needto simplify operations, know more about their businesses, and empower their mobile workforces. For more information, visit http://www.zebra.com?tactic_type=ZBR&amp;tactic_detail=PR_NA . Media Contact: Therese Van Ryne Zebra Technologies Phone: +1- 847-370-2317 therese.vanryne@zebra.com Industry Analyst Contact: Caitlin DeRango Zebra Technologies Phone: +1-847-793-5896 cderango@zebra.com Zebra Technologies, Zebra and the Zebra logo are trademarks or registered trademarks of Zebra Technologies Corporation and are used under license. Third-party trademarks mentioned are the property of their respective owners.2016 Zebra Technologies Corporation. All rights reserved. Logo - http://photos.prnewswire.com/prnh/20140731/132232 To view the original version on PR Newswire, visit: http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/zebra-technologies-introduces-smart-refrigeration-iot-solution-reference-design-for-retailers-300205266.html SOURCE Zebra Technologies Corporation Copyright 2014 PR Newswire. All Rights Reserved
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/bb4fa30d-c76d-3b43-991f-482fbcdd944d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-18T16:44:22Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:46:21.809Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.videobasedtutorials.com/articles/viewarticle.jsp?type=businesstech&amp;id=4250369" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
