<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Small, Flexible Candlestick Sensor Measures Air Temperature and Velocity <NODE id="73" />Advanced Thermal Solutions, Inc.<NODE id="105" /> (<NODE id="107" />ATS<NODE id="110" />) now <NODE id="116" />provides<NODE id="124" /> the base-and-stem <NODE id="143" />Candlestick sensor<NODE id="161" /> for simultaneously measuring air temperature and velocity when characterizing thermal conditions inside electronic systems. The Candlestick sensor is narrow and low profile, in heights of 9, 12 and 20mm. These features minimize the disturbance of airborne heat flow in the test domain for more precise measurements. The use of a single sensor to measure both temperature and velocity eliminates errors that can occur when airflow is non-isothermal. <NODE id="611" />Multiple Candlestick sensors<NODE id="639" /> can be used to thoroughly map an entire system's thermal and airflow conditions. The sensors' robust nature allows for continuous repositioning and reading. Their all plastic design prevents electronic shorting. Candlestick sensors are calibrated for low (natural convection) and high velocity flows. They are capable of temperature measurements ranging from -20° to +120°C, ±1°C. Velocity measurements range from 0 to 50m/s (0 to 10,000ft/min), ±2%, depending on the particular model of <NODE id="1128" />sensor<NODE id="1134" />. The base diameter for all Candlestick sensor models is 9.5mm. The stem diameter is 0.5mm and bead diameter is 1.1mm. Double-sided adhesive is available for long term mounting. Wire lengths are available up to 30 meters. More information on Candlestick sensors is available on the Advanced Thermal Solutions website, Qats.com or by calling 1-781-769-2800. Topics covered in this article sensors
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1be0212f-d4e9-3429-8a8e-c24e4489ea24" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-11T04:33:01Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:45:50.491Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://embedded-computing.com/news/small-measures-air-temperature-velocity/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="73" endPos="105" type="organization-company" surface="Advanced Thermal Solutions, Inc." />
<Entity id="1" startPos="107" endPos="110" type="organization-company" surface="ATS" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="116" endPos="124" type="trigger" surface="provides" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="143" endPos="161" type="product" surface="Candlestick sensor" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="611" endPos="639" type="product-class" surface="Multiple Candlestick sensors" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="1128" endPos="1134" type="product-class" surface="sensor" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="6" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="0" label="company" />
<Entity id="2" label="trigger" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
