<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>2012 (12) - BMW X5 xDrive30d M Sport Auto FULL LEATHER &amp; BLUETOOTH 5-Door £21,500 Loading Images... Date Registered: Jun 2012 Mileage: 83,247 miles Transmission: Automatic Fuel: Diesel Price: £21,500 Colour: Black Body Style: 4 X 4 Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport EC Combined (mpg) 38.2 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 42.2 EC Urban (mpg) 32.5  &gt; 38 MPG 43 Insurance Group 245 Performance (BHP) 5 Seats 195 CO2 (g/km) £265 Road Tax History Checked Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport Bluetooth, Full Leather, Paddle Shift, Downhill Desent, Rain-Sensing Wipers, Headlamp Jetwash, Sun Protection Glass, Front Centre Armrest, Multi-function Steering Wheel, M Sport Bodykit, M Sport Alloys, Sports Seats, Air Conditioning, Climate Control, Rear Wash/wipe, Front Fog Lamps, Push Button Start, Metallic Paintwork, I Drive System, Auto Lighting, Memory Seats, Electric Seats, Auxiliary In, Child Locks, CD Player, Isofix, ABS, Air Bag, Alarm, Radio, Side Air Bags, Immobiliser, Remote Alarm, Traction Control, Central Locking, Remote Central Locking, Trip Computer, Stability Control, Adjustable Steering Column, Automatic Electric Windows, Head Restraints, Power Steering, Electric Mirrors, Stereo, Colour Coded Body, Height Adjustable Seat, Rear Headrests, 19'' Alloys, 12V socket in luggage compartment, 3 rear 3 point seatbelts, 6.5'' colour display screen, 60/40 split folding rear seat, ADB - Automatic Differential Brake, Anthracite Velour floor mats, Anti-lock brake system, Automatic Stability Control (ASC), Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices, BMW professional twin tuner radio with single CD player and MP3 CD playback facility, Body colour bumpers, Body colour door handles, Body colour electric adjust heated aspherical door mirrors, Boot lashing points, Brake force display, CBC - (Cornering brake control), Child locks on rear doors, Clear indicator lenses, Crash Sensor - activates hazard/interior lighting + unlocks doors, Double kidney grille with chrome surround and titanium slats., For more photos, enhanced specification, vehicle documents and the HPI certificate visit our web site or pick up the phone - Centre open 'till late. Compare over a 1,000 cars side by side all in one place. All cars + £196.39 admin Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01634 624419 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. Review Rating The BMW X5 can claim to have begun the trend towards large 4x4s that were meant for road use rather than frequent forays into the wilderness. Upmarket image, robust build quality, comfortable and hushed on the move, seven seat option Limited off road, cramped third row of seats, firm ride Review provided by:
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/96720630-4e2a-3e7e-bee6-077745f06aa8" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-14T15:06:26Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:32:13.236Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.carmony.co.uk/car-39856387/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
