<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Roper Industries, Inc. (ROP) Price Target Cut to $201.00 by Analysts at RBC Capital Posted by Taylor Nule on Feb 2nd, 2016 // No Comments Roper Industries, Inc. (NYSE:ROP) had its price objective cut by RBC Capital from $214.00 to $201.00 in a report issued on Tuesday morning, StockTargetPrices.com reports. They currently have an outperform rating on the stock. Roper Industries ( NYSE:ROP ) opened at 163.73 on Tuesday. The firm has a 50 day moving average of $178.59 and a 200 day moving average of $174.06. Roper Industries has a 1-year low of $150.91 and a 1-year high of $195.93. The firm has a market cap of $16.50 billion and a P/E ratio of 24.66. Roper Industries (NYSE:ROP) last announced its quarterly earnings results on Monday, February 1st. The company reported $2.05 earnings per share (EPS) for the quarter, beating the consensus estimate of $1.87 by $0.18. The business earned $943.60 million during the quarter, compared to analysts' expectations of $960.61 million. During the same period last year, the company earned $1.85 EPS. On average, equities research analysts expect that Roper Industries will post $6.73 EPS for the current year. The firm also recently disclosed a quarterly dividend, which was paid on Friday, January 22nd. Stockholders of record on Friday, January 8th were given a $0.30 dividend. This represents a $1.20 annualized dividend and a dividend yield of 0.73%. This is a positive change from Roper Industries's previous quarterly dividend of $0.17. The ex-dividend date was Wednesday, January 6th. Several other brokerages also recently issued reports on ROP. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. upped their price target on shares of Roper Industries from $157.00 to $163.00 and gave the company an underweight rating in a report on Tuesday, October 27th. Stifel Nicolaus assumed coverage on shares of Roper Industries in a research note on Wednesday, November 25th. They set a buy rating and a $215.00 price objective on the stock. Gabelli assumed coverage on shares of Roper Industries in a research note on Wednesday, October 7th. They set a buy rating and a $205.00 price objective on the stock. Barclays upped their price objective on shares of Roper Industries from $172.00 to $180.00 and gave the company an overweight rating in a research note on Tuesday, October 27th. Finally, Zacks Investment Research downgraded shares of Roper Industries from a buy rating to a hold rating in a research note on Tuesday, October 6th. One analyst has rated the stock with a sell rating, three have given a hold rating and five have issued a buy rating to the company's stock. The company currently has an average rating of Hold and an average price target of $193.38. In other news, VP Paul J. Soni sold 12,000 shares of the stock in a transaction on Thursday, November 19th. The shares were sold at an average price of $190.41, for a total value of $2,284,920.00. Following the completion of the sale, the vice president now owns 47,212 shares of the company's stock, valued at $8,989,636.92. The transaction was disclosed in a document filed with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, which is available through this hyperlink . Also, Director Robert D. Johnson sold 500 shares of the stock in a transaction on Friday, December 11th. The stock was sold at an average price of $183.76, for a total transaction of $91,880.00. Following the completion of the sale, the director now directly owns 8,500 shares of the company's stock, valued at approximately $1,561,960. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . Other large investors have added to or reduced their stakes in the company. Janus Capital Management raised its stake in Roper Industries by 16.7% in the third quarter. Janus Capital Management now owns 1,100,487 shares of the company's stock valued at $172,447,000 after buying an additional 157,624 shares during the last quarter. Frontier Capital Management Co. LLC raised its stake in Roper Industries by 1.2% in the fourth quarter. Frontier Capital Management Co. LLC now owns 394,106 shares of the company's stock worth $74,797,000 after buying an additional 4,544 shares during the last quarter. Global Thematic Partners LLC purchased a new stake in Roper Industries during the fourth quarter worth $56,731,000. Chevy Chase Trust Holdings raised its stake in Roper Industries by 2.4% in the fourth quarter. Chevy Chase Trust Holdings now owns 250,071 shares of the company's stock worth $47,461,000 after buying an additional 5,827 shares during the last quarter. Finally, Nationwide Fund Advisors raised its stake in Roper Industries by 2.8% in the fourth quarter. Nationwide Fund Advisors now owns 217,612 shares of the company's stock worth $41,301,000 after buying an additional 6,020 shares during the last quarter. Roper Technologies, Inc. ( NYSE:ROP ), formerly Roper Industries, Inc., is a diversified technology company. The Company operates in four segments, including Medical and Scientific Imaging segment, which offers products and software in medical applications and digital imaging products; RF Technology segment, which provides radio frequency identification (RFID) communication technology and software solutions; Industrial Technology segment, which produces fluid handling pumps, materials analysis equipment and consumables, leak testing equipment, flow measurement and metering equipment and water meter and automatic meter reading products and systems, and Energy Systems and Controls segment, which produces control systems, fluid properties testing equipment, industrial valves and controls, <NODE id="5566" />vibration sensors<NODE id="5583" /> and controls, and non-destructive inspection and measurement products and solutions. This story was originally published by Corvus Business Newswire (http://corvuswire.com) and is the sole property of Corvus Business Newswire. If you are reading this article on another website, that means this article was illegally copied and re-published to this website in violation of U.S. and International copyright law. You can view the original version of this story at http://corvuswire.com/2016/02/02/roper-industries-inc-rop-price-target-cut-to-201-00-by-analysts-at-rbc-capital/796578/ Receive News &amp; Ratings for Roper Industries Inc. Daily - Enter your email address below to receive a concise daily summary of the latest news and analysts' ratings for Roper Industries Inc. and related companies with MarketBeat.com's FREE daily email newsletter . « Previous Cambiar Investors LLC Has $81,069,000 Position in Agilent Technologies Inc (A) Advertisement
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/3e318e30-1a72-3c70-8aa0-c35997053e7f" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-02T16:19:41Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:58:45.77Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://corvuswire.com/2016/02/02/roper-industries-inc-rop-price-target-cut-to-201-00-by-analysts-at-rbc-capital/796578/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="5566" endPos="5583" type="product-class" surface="vibration sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
