<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Stifel Nicolaus Cuts Sensata Technologies Holding (ST) Price Target to $50.00 Posted by Shayan Afkhami on Jan 15th, 2016 // No Comments Sensata Technologies Holding (NYSE:ST) had its price target decreased by Stifel Nicolaus from $54.00 to $50.00 in a report issued on Monday, Market Beat.com reports. Stifel Nicolaus currently has a buy rating on the stock. Sensata Technologies Holding ( NYSE:ST ) traded down 4.777% during midday trading on Monday, hitting $34.985. 1,086,898 shares of the stock were exchanged. The company's 50 day moving average is $43.82 and its 200 day moving average is $46.18. Sensata Technologies Holding has a 1-year low of $34.97 and a 1-year high of $55.53. The company has a market capitalization of $5.95 billion and a P/E ratio of 30.159. Sensata Technologies Holding (NYSE:ST) last issued its quarterly earnings results on Tuesday, October 27th. The company reported $0.72 earnings per share for the quarter, topping the Zacks' consensus estimate of $0.71 by $0.01. During the same period last year, the firm posted $0.63 earnings per share. The company earned $727.40 million during the quarter, compared to analysts' expectations of $736.41 million. Sensata Technologies Holding's quarterly revenue was up 26.0% compared to the same quarter last year. Analysts predict that Sensata Technologies Holding will post $2.74 earnings per share for the current fiscal year. In other Sensata Technologies Holding news, SVP Martin J. Carter sold 66,000 shares of the company's stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, November 17th. The stock was sold at an average price of $43.87, for a total value of $2,895,420.00. Following the completion of the sale, the senior vice president now owns 38,080 shares of the company's stock, valued at $1,670,569.60. The sale was disclosed in a legal filing with the SEC, which can be accessed through this link . Also, VP Geert Braaksma sold 54,874 shares of the company's stock in a transaction that occurred on Tuesday, November 3rd. The stock was sold at an average price of $49.29, for a total value of $2,704,739.46. Following the completion of the sale, the vice president now directly owns 5,505 shares of the company's stock, valued at approximately $271,341.45. The disclosure for this sale can be found here . Other hedge funds have recently modified their holdings of the company. Independent Portfolio Consultants raised its stake in shares of Sensata Technologies Holding by 7.2% in the fourth quarter. Independent Portfolio Consultants now owns 2,965 shares of the company's stock valued at $137,000 after buying an additional 200 shares in the last quarter. Stock Yards Bank &amp; Trust Company purchased a new stake in shares of Sensata Technologies Holding during the fourth quarter valued at about $350,000. KBC Group raised its stake in shares of Sensata Technologies Holding by 248.8% in the third quarter. KBC Group now owns 33,821 shares of the company's stock valued at $1,499,000 after buying an additional 24,124 shares in the last quarter. Three Peaks Capital Management raised its stake in shares of Sensata Technologies Holding by 19.4% in the fourth quarter. Three Peaks Capital Management now owns 219,381 shares of the company's stock valued at $10,105,000 after buying an additional 35,719 shares in the last quarter. Finally, Eagle Asset Management raised its stake in shares of Sensata Technologies Holding by 99.5% in the third quarter. Eagle Asset Management now owns 966,484 shares of the company's stock valued at $42,852,000 after buying an additional 481,991 shares in the last quarter. Several other equities research analysts also recently commented on ST. RBC Capital reaffirmed a sector perform rating on shares of Sensata Technologies Holding in a report on Monday, October 5th. Zacks Investment Research downgraded shares of Sensata Technologies Holding from a hold rating to a sell rating in a report on Monday, October 5th. Citigroup Inc. downgraded shares of Sensata Technologies Holding from a buy rating to a neutral rating in a report on Wednesday, October 7th. JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co. initiated coverage on shares of Sensata Technologies Holding in a report on Thursday, October 15th. They set an overweight rating and a $62.00 price objective on the stock. Finally, SunTrust downgraded shares of Sensata Technologies Holding from a buy rating to a neutral rating and dropped their price objective for the company from $55.00 to $50.00 in a report on Friday, November 13th. Six investment analysts have rated the stock with a hold rating and six have issued a buy rating to the company. The company has an average rating of Buy and an average price target of $56.75. Sensata Technologies Holding N.V. is a global industrial technology company. The Company is engaged in the development, manufacture and sale of sensors and controls. The Company's operating segments include Sensors segment and Controls segment. The Company produce sensors and controls for applications such as thermal circuit breakers in aircraft, pressure sensors in automotive systems, and bimetal current and temperature control devices in electric motors. The Company's sensors are customized devices that translate a physical phenomenon, such as force or position, into electronic signals that microprocessors or computer-based control systems can act upon. Its controls are customized devices embedded within systems to protect them from heat or current. The Company's products include low-, medium- and high-pressure sensors, temperature sensors, speed sensors, position sensors, force sensors, motor protectors, and thermal and magnetic-hydraulic circuit breakers and switches. document.write(‘ ‘); Receive News &amp; Ratings for Sensata Technologies Holding Daily - Enter your email address below to receive a concise daily summary of the latest news and analysts' ratings for Sensata Technologies Holding and related companies with MarketBeat.com's FREE daily email newsletter . Advertisement
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/da74e96c-451d-3799-a580-d7fddd5d35f6" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-16T09:44:24Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:58:10.983Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.mideasttime.com/stifel-nicolaus-cuts-sensata-technologies-holding-st-price-target-to-50-00/659954/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
