<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>3 litre 0 2 9 0 0 0 Mileage Diesel Oct 2012 Automatic Saloon 57 MPG £62 Cost to fill 714 Tank range (miles) 38 Insurance group £110 Road tax 5 Seats Vehicle Trim / Variant: M Sport Insurance Group 38, Alpine White with Black Dakota Leather, Cost New £40,485! , Full BMW Service History,,FACTORY OPTIONAL EXTRA'S FITTED:- BMW Professional Media package - Professional satellite navigation, Bluetooth telephone prep with telematics, Voice control system, Bluetooth audio streaming, 19 M Double spoke alloy wheels, Sun protection glass, Brushed aluminium interior trim, Front armrest with sliding adjustment, High gloss interior trim, Front seat heating, DAB digital radio &amp; Interior comfort package. STANDARD M-SPORT FEATURES:- Park distance control front &amp; rear, <NODE id="762" />Rain sensor<NODE id="773" /> + automatic driving lights control, Cruise control with brake function, M sports leather steering wheel, Drive Performance Control, Sports function on gearbox with steering wheel mounted gearshift paddles, On board computer, BMW professional radio/CD/MP3, Auto dimming rear view mirror, Dual zone automatic air conditioning, Isofix system on outer rear seats, Interior lights pack - 3 Series Saloon, Hill start assist, Remote control alarm, M-Sport bodystyling kit + much more! **This Stunning example and rare 330d benefits from - Full BMW Service History having been serviced @ 15k miles &amp; @ 28k miles, 1 Yrs MOT, on x4 nearly new matching tyres, Full Detailed Valet, Nationwide Executive Warranty, HPI Gold Check Clear, Full Leather Book Pack &amp; 2 Keys** Exact specification may vary from the details on this page. Please contact the seller via our email dealer form or on 01506 551610 to reconfirm any details before purchasing. See terms &amp; conditions for further info. 01506 551610 Email dealer Other cars from this dealer: View all cars at this dealer PARKERS Review Rating This is the sixth generation of the BMW 3 Series.... read more Class-leading handling Sizeable boot Economical engines Manual seats are difficult to adjust Servicing costs can be high Review provided by: The following features are fitted to this car... ABS Air conditioning Alarm Audio remote control Electric door mirrors Front electric windows Front fog lights Immobiliser Isofix child seat anchor points PAS Passenger airbag Radio/CD Rear electric windows Remote central locking Reverse parking aid Service indicator Side airbags Sports seats Traction control Trip computer Equipment fitted to this car... This equipment listed below is a standard description and may differ from the exact detail for the vehicle displayed. If you require further clarification call us on 01506 551610 and we will only be too pleased to discuss in greater detail or answer questions you may have regarding this vehicle Comfort / Convenience 12V sockets in front centre console and passenger footwell 2 speed adjustable intermittent wipers with wash/wipe function 2 x folding cupholders in instrument panel above glovebox 3 rear seat head restraints 4 foldable grab handles - rear with clothes hook 4 lashing points to secure luggage ABS Auto dimming rear view mirror Automatic Stability Control (ASC) Body colour electric adjustable door mirrors Brake pad wear indicator warning light CBC - (Cornering brake control) Check control system Digital clock Door/boot open warning light Drive Performance Control DSC+ Dual zone automatic air conditioning Dynamic brake control Dynamic Traction Control - DTC Electric front and rear windows with one touch/convenient open/close function Electronic differential lock Folding front centre armrest + storage Front and rear door armrests Front door storage bins with bottle holder Front sports seats with electric side bolster adjustment Front/rear park distance control Green tinted heat insulating glass Heated rear window with automatic switch off Heated windscreen washer jets Height adjustable front headrests Hill start assist Individual anthracite headlining Isofix system on outer rear seats Leather gear knob Leather gear selector lever handle Leather handbrake grip Lights on warning Lockable glovebox Multi-function controls for steering wheel Oil temperature gauge On board computer On board diagnostics Operation warning of all exterior lights Outside temperature display Push button starter Rain sensor + automatic driving lights control Reach + rake adjustable steering column Rear centre armrest Rear storage compartment in multifunction centre console with sliding cover Run flat tyre indicator Service interval indicator Servotronic PAS Sports function on gearbox with steering wheel mounted gearshift paddles Storage compartment in rear doors Toolkit located in luggage compartment Entertainment Auxiliary point for auxiliary devices BMW professional radio/CD/MP3 CD Changer preparation Exterior / Styling Automatic headlight beam throw control Body colour bumpers Body colour door handles Body colour roof mouldings Brake force display Chrome exhaust tailpipe Clear indicator lenses Daytime running lights Door sill finishers Dynamic brake lights Front fog lights Front ornamental grille with chrome plated kidney bars and chrome bezel 'Guide me home' headlamps High gloss shadow line Interior lights pack - 3 Series Saloon Low rolling resistance tyres Run-flat tyres Shark fin roof aerial Safety / Security 3 point inertia reel seatbelts + pre-tensioners on outer rear seats Automatic drive away locking facility Central locking fuel filler cap Centre lock switch Crash sensor Driver and passenger airbags Electronic immobiliser Front and rear head airbags Front passenger airbag deactivation Front seat side impact airbags Front seatbelt pretensioners + load limiters Key integrated remote control central locking Rear child proof door locks Remote control alarm Seatbelt warning Three 3 point rear seatbelts Twin horns Warning triangle and first aid kit Technical Specifications... The technical specifications detailed below may differ from the exact specifications for the vehicle displayed. 129 CO2 (g/km) 258 Performance (BHP) 57 MPG £62 Cost to fill 714 Tank range (miles) 38 Insurance group £110 Road tax 5 Seats 4 Doors Diesel Oct 2012 Automatic Saloon White Emissions CO2 (g/km) 129 Engine and Drive Train Camshaft DOHC Cylinder Layout IN-LINE Cylinders 6 Engine Layout NORTH SOUTH Fuel Delivery COMMON RAIL Gears 8 SPEED Transmission SEMI-AUTO Fuel Consumption EC Combined (mpg) 57.6 EC Extra Urban (mpg) 65.7 EC Urban (mpg) 47.1 General Insurance Group 1 - 50 Effective January 07 38D Manufacturers Corrosion Perforation Guarantee - Years 6 Manufacturers Paintwork Guarantee - Years 3 NCAP Adult Occupant Protection % 95 NCAP Child Occupant Protection % 84 NCAP Overall Rating - Effective February 09 5 NCAP Pedestrian Protection % 78 Service Interval Frequency - Months 24 Service Interval Mileage 36000 Standard manufacturers warranty - Mileage 999999 Standard manufacturers warranty - Years 3 Performance 0 to 60 mph (secs) False 0 to 62 mph (secs) 5.6 Engine Power - BHP 258 Engine Torque - LBS.FT 413 Engine Torque - NM 560 Top Speed 155 Tyres Wheel Style MULTISPOKE STYLE Wheel Type 18 ALLOY Vehicle Dimensions Height 1429 Height (including roof rails) NA Length 4624 Wheelbase 2810 Width 1811 Width (including mirrors) 2031 Weight and Capacities Fuel Tank Capacity (Litres) 57 Gross Vehicle Weight 2090 Luggage Capacity (Seats Down) NA Luggage Capacity (Seats Up) 480 Max. Loading Weight 550 Max. Roof Load 75 Max. Towing Weight - Braked 1800 Max. Towing Weight - Unbraked 745 Minimum Kerbweight 1540 No. of Seats 5 Turning Circle - Kerb to Kerb 11.3 Telephone numbers starting with 08XX will cost you 7p per minute plus your phone company's access charge. Calls to other telephone numbers will only cost your phone company's access charge Motors.co.uk is authorised and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority. Full details upon request.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1d50ea60-3a8e-3c47-96f2-11445d518e18" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-27T23:38:37Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:46:23.778Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.motors.co.uk/car-39614335/11/sp" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="762" endPos="773" type="product-class" surface="Rain sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
