<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>This is a good, How To Video. Where Ben Heck, tries to fix a 1970's Atari Video Music Effects System. It was made, to produce Efx on your TV. From the Audio input, coming from a Music - Stereo System. Check out the related videos and the rest of the Ben Heck Show, on Elemen14.com, http://www.element14.com/community/docs/DOC-43657/l/the-ben-heck-show-archived-episodes?ICID=benheck-episodes-videodoc... Don  Ben Heck's Atari Video Music Teardown &lt;br&gt; Video link... https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=INnpnJvDXDg The Ben Heck Show Published on Jan 15, 2016 In this episode Ben takes a stab at repairing an old piece of 70's technology, The Atari Video Music. Learn more about design challenges and join the element14 community at http://bit.ly/1Q92xDl Up next Phantom V4.1 high-speed camera teardown tesla500 6,915 views 37:21 Teardown of next-generation LED filament lamp. bigclivedotcom 44,918 views 17:25 Ben Heck's Hour of Code in 50 Minutes The Ben Heck Show 47,375 views 50:41 Ben Heck's Workshop Hacks The Ben Heck Show 123,503 views 19:26 Chinese 200A TIG welder teardown xjet 32,463 views 25:45 Ben Heck's ZX Spectrum Mod Part 1 The Ben Heck Show 139,451 views 22:34 Ben Heck's pi-top Assembly Demo The Ben Heck Show 48,802 views 15:43 Teardown: Duracell CEF23 Battery Charger/USB Powerbank Julian Ilett 6,839 views 18:22 Ben Heck's Holiday Present Protection System The Ben Heck Show 32,686 views 21:11 Ben Heck's DIY Novena Laptop Part 2 The Ben Heck Show 54,558 views 19:32 Ricer Honda Turbo Build : Teardown Continues Braden Carlson 4,339 views 24:43 Ben Heck's Auto Tracking Camera Part 1 The Ben Heck Show 100,829 views 18:16 Ben Heck's Xbox One Portable Part 1 The Ben Heck Show 311,713 views 21:21 PS4 1215 Teardown Tips &amp; Tricks TronicsFix 703 views 15:25 Ben Heck's Single-Handed Pinball Mod The Ben Heck Show 81,994 views 27:59 Ben Heck's Restored Atari Landfill Cartrige Benjamin Heckendorn 5,009 views 1:11 Ben Heck's Raspberry Pi Shop Cam The Ben Heck Show 135,915 views 24:24 How To Make An Illuminated Ping Pong Ball Lamp! Mist8k 106,835 views 4:33 Ben Heck's Dreamcast Portable Part 3 The Ben Heck Show 131,251 views 22:26 Ben Heck Teaches Alyson How to Solder The Ben Heck Show 98,261 views 23:37 Ben Heck's Hacking the Zombie Apocalypse The Ben Heck Show 67,917 views 24:13 Ben Heck's Star Wars Christmas Special The Ben Heck Show 51,069 views 26:34 Ben Heck's Animatronic Puppet Head Part 1 The Ben Heck Show 62,644 views 20:12 Playing with junk 18 - SUN M5000 $100'000 server teardown chrigel1234 984 views 47:35 Ben Heck's Xbox One Portable Part 3 The Ben Heck Show 325,237 views 22:03 Introduction to Interfaces The Ben Heck Show 107,877 views 16:35 Ben Heck's Xbox One Portable Part 2 The Ben Heck Show 214,036 views 22:04 DIY Automated Motion: Motorized Camera Dolly Part 2 The Ben Heck Show 73,954 views 15:46 The Screen Savers: Portable Atari 2600 scorpshockey 17,751 views 6:43 Ben Heck's Controller Mods Tutorial The Ben Heck Show 80,287 views 25:48 Ben Heckendorn's Wii Laptop Pakman20 79,098 views 1:17 Ben Heck's DIY Novena Laptop Part 1 The Ben Heck Show 72,976 views 25:32 Ben Heck's Arcade Joystick Accessibility Mod The Ben Heck Show 54,764 views 24:22 The Ben Heck Show - That 70's Xbox The Ben Heck Show 202,786 views 23:00 GoTenna Teardown Adafruit Industries 2,897 views 6:42 The Ben Heck Show - Ruggedized PlayStation 3 The Ben Heck Show 302,019 views 17:55 Ben Heck's NEStari didntyouhear 48,525 views 0:19 Blue Monday on Atari C-240 nickelindimer 7,460 views 7:27 Conan O'Brien Plays Atari 2600 Classics: Clueless Gamer | Conan on TBS Team Coco 2,521,957 views 7:38 Atari Video Music Demonstration World One Video 26,396 views Element14 108-0302-001 | Emerson Connectivity/Johnson 108-0302-001 | Banana Plug 15A Solderless Red | Newark element14 1PK-302N-F (EURO) - DURATOOL - TOOL KIT, LARGE ELECTRONICS, EURO | Newark 22-8815 - DURATOOL - ELECTRONIC TOOL KIT | Newark 25ET - BUSSMANN BY EATON SEMICONDUCTOR FUSE | Newark element14 430BOOST-SHARP96 TEXAS INSTRUMENTS Daughter Boards / Modules | 11X5261 | Newark element14 5-5530843-0 - TE CONNECTIVITY / AMP - CONNECTOR, CARD EDGE, RCPT, 20POS | Farnell element14 72-8429-03 - DURATOOL - BENCH TOP BUNDLE | Newark 72-8429-04 - TENMA - POCKET DMM BUNDLE | Newark 8429-1011-2 - DURATOOL (FORMERLY FROM SPC) - BASIC MAINTENANCE ASSORTMENT KIT | Newark 955 - ADAFRUIT INDUSTRIES - STARTER PACK, RASPBERRY PI | Newark Actions | element14 Actions | element14 Activity | element14 Activity | element14 A Day In The Life As An Engineer's Wife - YouTube Agilent 34461A Digital Multimeter - element14 Agilent 34461A Digital Multimeter - element14 Agilent 34461A Digital Multimeter - element14 Agilent MSOX2024A with a Development Kit - element14 Agilent U1273AX Handheld Digital Multimeter - element14 Agilent U1273AX Handheld Digital Multimeter - element14 Alejandro Moreno alejandro moreno's Profile | element14 AM-510 - AMPROBE INSTRUMENTS - MULTIMETER, DIGITAL, AUTO/MANUAL | Newark AM-520 - AMPROBE INSTRUMENTS - MULTIMETER, DIGITAL, HVAC, AUTO | Newark AN375-Using MCF5329EVB NAND Flash to Host uClinux Root File System - element14 ANALOG PARTS KIT - DIGILENT - KIT, ANALOG ACTIVE/PASSIVE COMPONENTS | Newark element14 US Analog / Power / Sensor / Wireless / Lighting Development Kits | Newark Anaren AIR CC2530 BoosterPack Kit - element14 Application - element14 Arduino: Christmas Gift Ideas part 1 - Arduino Kit | element14 Arduino Due - element14 Arduino Due - element14 Arduino Due - element14 Arduino Esplora - element14 Arduino Esplora Wireless Controller - YouTube a simple printf function | element14 a simple printf function | element14 Assortments &amp; Kits | Newark | Results AT91SAM9G45-EVK - element14 Atmel SAMA5D34-EK Evaluation Kit - element14 Atmel SAMA5D4 Xplained Ultra | element14 Automation Ace | Newark element14 Automotive Fuses Product List | Newark element14 Auto Ranging | Newark | Results Axial Fans | Diagonal Fan | Air Blowers | Industrial Fans | Newark | Results ▶ Batteryless Carbon Monoxide Detector - YouTube Beaglebone Black - element14 ▶ BeagleBone Black VS Raspberry Pi! - YouTube Bench Top Power Supplies | Newark | Results Ben Heck Uses Google's Arduino-Based ADK to Mod Baby Car Seat Motion Simulator in element14's The Ben Heck Show - element14 Ben Heck vs. Hak5 Case Mod SHOWDOWN! - YouTube Blog Management: Don Bishop's Blog - element14 Blog Management: Don Bishop's Blog - element14 Blog Management: Don Bishop's Blog: Import - element14 brijesh patel's Profile Profile - element14 - Made a nice comment on my MSP-EXP430FR5739 Review Building a six-channel floppy drive synth from start to finish Bundle Bonus Promo-NEWARK.indd - panduit_bundle_bonus_promo_july_oct_2014.pdf Can I connect and old TV with S-Video and/or th... | element14 Can I connect a pcb card edge connector to a ra... | element14 Cartridge Fuses | Newark element14 Catalog | Newark.com Catalog | Newark element14 Change Update Status here... Your Homepage Preview - element14 Cheapest PCB makers, low volume | element14 Cheapest PCB makers, low volume - element14 chipKIT™ Pi - element14 chipKIT™ Pi - element14 Community: 3D Printing 101 | element14 Community: About the Knode - element14 Community: About the Knode - element14 Community: About the Knode - element14 Community: Atmel SAMA5D3 Xplained | element14 Community: CadSoft EAGLE | element14 Community: Cypress PSoC Kits | element14 Community: Cypress PSoC Kits - element14 Community: Design Center, Development &amp; Eva... | element14 Community: Design Center | element14 Community: Design Center | element14
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/06c29d52-852c-3daa-a735-db40cdd59b5a" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-18T01:33:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:37:52.737Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://donsdeals.blogspot.com/2016/01/ben-hecks-atari-video-music-teardown.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
