<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Here's how partial proof testing aids automation Proof testing level instruments Endress+Hauser 02/11/2015 Protecting Our Water – Keep Chemicals in the Tank Leaking or overfilled tanks containing chemicals, fuel oil, sewage or hazardous materials can cause environmental problems, contaminate drinking water and cost a company millions of dollars in fines and lawsuits. This white paper discusses instrumentation and controls that can monitor the contents of a vessel and provide an alarm in the event of a leak or overfill event. Bill Sholette, Ricardo Chavez, Endress+Hauser 04/03/2014 Guided Wave Radar vs. Differential Pressure Transmitters for Liquid Level Measurement Differential pressure transmitters were first implemented in the 1950s but are still one of the most commonly used technologies for measuring liquid level in process industries. In many areas of the industrial level measurement market - including chemical, petrochemical, refining, and electric power generation—differential pressure transmitters have captured the vast majority of level applications; and still represent the largest worldwide sales volume of process level measurement equipment. Their popularity and installed base is so prevalent because DP transmitters are versatile, cost-effective, and due to their long history, plant personnel are familiar with their operation. Magnetrol 04/27/2010 Information on pH measurement The pH value is the most frequently used process variable in analysis. The pH value is of outstanding importance in water and environmental analysis and in almost all sectors of industry. Whether the cheese in a dairy is of the right quality, the water in a drinking water supply causes corrosion damage, or the precipitation in a treatment plant for waste water from an electroplating process occurs at the optimal point, all depend on such parameters as the pH value. Dr. Jürgen Schleicher, JUMO 10/30/2008 Information on the Amperometric Measurement of free Chlorine, Chlorine Dioxide and Ozone in Water For reasons of hygiene, drinking water, or any other water that people come into direct or indirect contact with, often has to be treated with compounds that destroy any micro-organisms contained in it. Chlorine, chlorine compounds or ozone are very often used as disinfectants. In this sensitive area, a high level of safety for the consumer is an absolute requirement, and for this reason, systems are used for fully automatic monitoring, control and recording of the disinfectant concentration. Amperometric sensors provide the best means of monitoring the disinfectant concentration. This technical publication will present the electrochemical fundamentals and the application technology of such sensors in an easily understood form, for the interested reader. Dr. Jürgen Schleicher, JUMO 10/30/2008
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/ed4688a7-7d83-3cee-b4b9-6ef6d5c720fb" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-08T02:43:39Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:05:22.143Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.controlglobal.com/whitepapers/?categoryid=11&amp;start=0" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
