<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>News Patent Application Titled <NODE id="31" />Sem Scanner Sensing Apparatus<NODE id="60" />, System and Methodology for Early Detection of Ulcers Published Online (USPTO 20150366499) Electronics Newsweekly | Thursday, 07 January 2016 21:05 (EST) By a News Reporter-Staff News Editor at Electronics Newsweekly -- According to news reporting originating from Washington, D.C., by VerticalNews journalists, a patent application by the inventors Sarrafzadeh, Majid (Anaheim Hills, CA); Kaiser, William (Los Angeles, CA); Mehrnia, Alireza (Los Angeles, CA); Bates-Jensen, Barbara M. (Pasadena, CA); Wang, Frank (Cupertino, CA); Flesch, Michael (Beverly Hills, CA); Boystak, Joseph (Marina Del Rey, CA); Lam, Yeung (Sherman Oaks, CA), filed on August 17, 2015, was made available online on December 31, 2015. The assignee for this patent application is Bruin Biometrics, Llc. Reporters obtained the following quote from the background information supplied by the inventors: This invention pertains generally to monitoring skin pressure ulcers and more particularly to skin ulcer monitoring via measurement of Sub-epidermal Moisture (SEM). Patients' skin integrity has long been an issue of concern for nurses and in nursing homes. Maintenance of skin integrity has been identified by the American Nurses Association as an important indicator of quality nursing care. Meanwhile, pressure ulcers remain a major health problem particularly for hospitalized older adults. When age is considered along with other risk factors, the incidence of pressure ulcers is significantly increased. Overall incidence of pressure ulcers for hospitalized patients ranges from 2.7% to 29.5%, and rates of greater than 50% have been reported for patients in intensive care settings. In a multicenter cohort retrospective study of 1,803 older adults discharged from acute care hospitals with selected diagnoses, 13.2% (i.e., 164 patients) demonstrated an incidence of stage I ulcers. Of those 164 patients, 38 (16%) had ulcers that progressed to a more advanced stage. Pressure ulcers additionally have been associated with an increased risk of death one year after hospital discharge. The estimated cost of treating pressure ulcers ranges from $5,000 to $40,000 for each ulcer, depending on severity. Therefore, there is an urgent need to develop a preventive solution to measure moisture content of the skin as a mean to detect early symptoms of ulcer development. In addition to obtaining background information on this patent application, VerticalNews editors also obtained the inventors' summary information for this patent application: An aspect of the present invention is a smart compact capacitive sensing conforming handheld apparatus configured to measure Sub-epidermal Moisture (SEM) as a mean to detect and monitor the development of pressure ulcers. The device incorporates an array of electrodes which are excited to measure and scan SEM in a programmable and multiplexed manner by a battery-less RF-powered chip. The scanning operation is initiated by an interrogator which excites a coil embedded in the apparatus and provides the needed energy burst to support the scanning/reading operation. Each embedded electrode measures the equivalent sub-epidermal capacitance corresponding and representing the moisture content of the target surface. An aspect of this invention is the in situ sensing and monitoring of skin or wound or ulcer development status using a wireless, biocompatible RF powered capacitive sensing system referred to as smart SEM imager. The present invention enables the realization of smart preventive measures by enabling early detection of ulcer formation or inflammatory pressure which would otherwise have not been detected for an extended period with increased risk of infection and higher stage ulcer development. In one beneficial embodiment, the handheld capacitive sensing imager apparatus incorporates pressure sensing components in conjunction with the sensing electrodes to monitor the level of applied pressure on each electrode in order to guarantee precise wound or skin electrical capacitance measurements to characterize moisture content. In summary, such embodiment would enable new capabilities including but not limited to: 1) measurement capabilities such as SEM imaging and SEM depth imaging determined by electrode geometry and dielectrics, and 2) signal processing and pattern recognition having automatic and assured registration exploiting pressure imaging and automatic assurance of usage exploiting software systems providing usage tracking. One major implication of this sensor-enhanced paradigm is the ability to better manage each individual patient resulting in a timelier and more efficient practice in hospitals and even nursing homes. This is applicable to patients with a history of chronic wounds, diabetic foot ulcers, pressure ulcers or post-operative wounds. In addition, alterations in signal content may be integrated with the activity level of the patient, the position of patient's body and standardized assessments of symptoms. By maintaining the data collected in these patients in a signal database, pattern classification, search, and pattern matching algorithms can be developed to better map symptoms with alterations in skin characteristics and ulcer development. This approach is not limited to the specific condition of ulcer or wound, but may have broad application in all forms of wound management and even skin diseases or treatments. One aspect is apparatus for sensing sub-epidermal moisture (SEM) from a location external to a patient's skin. The apparatus includes a bipolar RF sensor embedded on a flexible substrate, and a conformal pressure pad disposed adjacent and underneath the substrate, wherein the conformal pressure pad is configured to support the flexible substrate while allowing the flexible substrate to conform to a non-planar sensing surface of the patient's skin. The apparatus further includes interface electronics coupled to the sensor; wherein the interface electronics are configured to control emission and reception of RF energy to interrogate the patient's skin. Another aspect is a method for monitoring the formation of pressure ulcers at a target location of a patient's skin. The method includes the steps of positioning a flexible substrate adjacent the target location of the patient's skin; the flexible substrate comprising one or more bipolar RF sensors; conforming the flexible substrate to the patient's skin at the target location; exciting the one or more bipolar RF sensor to emit RF energy into the patient's skin; and measuring the capacitance of the skin at the target location as an indicator of the Sub-Epidermal Moisture (SEM) at the target location. Further aspects of the invention will be brought out in the following portions of the specification, wherein the detailed description is for the purpose of fully disclosing preferred embodiments of the invention without placing limitations thereon. BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING(S) The invention will be more fully understood by reference to the following drawings which are for illustrative purposes only: FIG. 1 illustrates an assembled perspective component view of the SEM Scanner of the present invention. FIG. 2 illustrates a perspective view of a Kapton-based conforming sensing substrate assembly of the present invention. FIG. 3 shows a top view of an exemplary concentric sensing electrode in accordance with the present invention. FIG. 4 illustrates a side view of a flex stack-up for the Kapton-based conforming sensing substrate shown in FIG. 2. FIG. 5 illustrates a side view of an alternative flex stack-up for a Kapton-based conforming sensing substrate. FIG. 6 shows a top view of two-electrode sensing Kapton-based flex sensor substrates for three alternative types of capacitive sensing concentric electrodes. FIG. 7 illustrates an exploded perspective component view of the SEM scanner of FIG. 1. FIG. 8 illustrates a schematic side view of the SEM scanner of FIG. 1. FIG. 9 illustrates a schematic side view of the SEM scanner of FIG. 8 in contact with subject skin. FIG. 10 illustrates a perspective view of an assembled SEM scanner with an alternative array of sensors in accordance with the present invention. FIG. 11 is a plot of normalized responses of the tested electrodes of the present invention. FIG. 12 is a graph of measured equivalent capacitance for dry volar arm for three different concentric sensor electrodes. FIG. 13 is a plot of time dependent fractional change in capacitance relative to dry skin for three different concentric sensor electrodes (after 30 minutes of applying lotion). FIG. 14 is a plot of time dependent fractional change in capacitance relative to dry skin for three different concentric sensor electrodes (after 15 minutes of applying lotion). FIG. 15 is a plot of fractional change vs. time. FIG. 16 shows a SEM scanner electrode system and electrode layering providing proper shielding from interference. FIG. 17 shows an SEM scanner mechanical compliance for electrodes developed to enable probing of bony prominence. FIG. 18 is an overview of the wound registration method according to an embodiment of the description. FIG. 19 illustrates pressure and moisture measurements obtained according to an embodiment of the description. FIG. 20 illustrates sample measurements over two different days. For more information, see this patent application: Sarrafzadeh, Majid; Kaiser, William; Mehrnia, Alireza; Bates-Jensen, Barbara M.; Wang, Frank; Flesch, Michael; Boystak, Joseph; Lam, Yeung. Sem Scanner Sensing Apparatus, System and Methodology for Early Detection of Ulcers. Filed August 17, 2015 and posted December 31, 2015. Patent URL: http://appft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO2&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsearch-adv.html&amp;r=7392&amp;p=148&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;d=PG01&amp;S1=20151224.PD.&amp;OS=PD/20151224&amp;RS=PD/20151224 Keywords for this news article include: Ulcers, Hospital, Electronics, Bruin Biometrics Llc. Our reports deliver fact-based news of research and discoveries from around the world. Copyright 2016, NewsRx LLC DISCLOSURE: The views and opinions expressed in this article are those of the authors, and do not represent the views of equities.com . Readers should not consider statements made by the author as formal recommendations and should consult their financial advisor before making any investment decisions. To read our full disclosure, please go to: http://www.equities.com/disclaimer You have to be logged in to leave a comment.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/4795080e-299e-36ea-8a9f-688bf6ec4a5d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-08T09:07:26Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:02:17.909Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="https://www.equities.com/news/patent-application-titled-sem-scanner-sensing-apparatus-system-and-methodology-for-early-detection-of-ulcers-published-online-uspto-20150366499" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="31" endPos="60" type="product" surface="Sem Scanner Sensing Apparatus" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
