<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Product News: Test &amp; Measuring Instruments, <NODE id="44" />Sensors<NODE id="51" />, Monitors &amp; Transducers, HVAC Topics Test &amp; Measuring Instruments, Sensors, Monitors &amp; Transducers, HVAC Inclination and Tilt Sensors prevent heavy equipment from tipping. Press Release Summary: January 29, 2016 - As IP67-rated inclinometers with integrated RS-232 interface and flying lead cable, MTLT series operates from single 9_32 V supply and utilize <NODE id="409" />MEMS sensors<NODE id="421" />, over temperature calibration, and SmartSensing™ technology. Programmable tilt alarms, also included, can be used to lock out controls or trigger alarm or warning light. Respectively, models MTLT105S and MTLT110S are designed for applications needing &lt;0.5° and &lt;1.0° accuracy over full operating temperature range. Original Press Release MEMSIC INC Announces New MTLT Family of Inclination and Tilt Sensors Press release date: January 26, 2016 MEMS Sensors and SmartSensing™ Technology Help Prevent Heavy Equipment from Falling Over Andover, Massachusetts _ <NODE id="980" />MEMSIC Inc.<NODE id="991" />, a leading sensing solutions provider, today announced the launch of a new product family, the <NODE id="1087" />MTLT<NODE id="1091" /> series of Inclination and <NODE id="1118" />Tilt Sensors<NODE id="1130" />. Samples of the first three family members in MTLT series, the MTLT110S-R, MTLT105S-R and MTLT105D-R are currently available for evaluation. The MTLT family of tilt sensors are appropriate for a wide range of static and dynamic applications in construction and industrial markets such as boom tilt monitoring, bucket loader roll back protection, PV/CSP solar tracking systems and others. All three products are IP67 rated inclinometers with an integrated RS-232 interface and flying lead cable operating from a 9 V to 32 V single supply. The MTLT105S and MTLT110S are designed for applications needing &lt; 0.5 degree and &lt; 1.0 degree accuracy, respectfully, over the full operating temperature range. Vibration and vehicle motion have caused problems for inclinometers for years, forcing customers to either sacrifice response time by heavily filtering the output of a static inclinometer or buy more expensive IMU solutions with more capability than they need, said James Fennelly, MEMSIC Product Marketing Manager. The MTLT105D gives customers a new cost effective choice that does not sacrifice response time. The MTLT sensors also include programmable tilt alarms for tilt safety applications. The alarm can be programmed to be triggered to activate when the tilt exceeds a specified threshold. The tilt alarm can also be used to lock out controls or trigger an alarm or warning light. It is an all-in-one tilt safety solution eliminating the need for an external microprocessor to interpret tilt angles. The MTLT family achieves the best price and performance by utilizing Micro Electro-Mechanical System (MEMS) sensors, extensive over temperature calibration, and MEMSIC's SmartSensing™ technology that was recently developed and deployed in MEMSIC's industry leading Inertial Measurement Units (IMU) and Attitude Heading Reference Systems (AHRS) products. SmartSensing™ technology provides users with unmatched sensor fusion and performance in critical motion sensing applications. Each unit is fully calibrated over temperature providing confidence in safety applications. MTLT samples are available to qualified customers for evaluation. Designers can evaluate and log data using MEMSIC's NavView Software, available for download from www.memsic.com/tilt-sensors . Datasheets are available by contacting MEMSIC at Info@Memsic.com . More about MEMSIC MEMSIC Inc., headquartered in Andover, Massachusetts, provides advanced semiconductor sensors and multi-sensor system solutions based on micro-electromechanical systems (MEMS) technology and sophisticated integration technologies in both the IC level and module level. MEMSIC's unique and proprietary approach combines leading-edge sensor technologies, such as magnetic sensors, accelerometers, flow sensors and current sensors with mixed-signal processing circuitry to produce reliable, high quality, cost-effective solutions for the mobile phone, automotive, consumer, industrial, medical and general aviation markets. FOR MORE INFORMATION MEMSIC Inc. One Tech Drive Suite 325 Andover, MA 0180 Tel: 978-738-0900 Fax: 978-738-0156 Email: info@memsic.com www.memsic.com/Tilt-Sensors Mark Shapiro SRS Tech PR - Media Relations for the Connected World mshapiro@srs-techpr.com + 1 619 249 7742 Twitter - @SRSTechPR http://www.linkedin.com/in/markrshapiro/ LinkedIN articles https://www.linkedin.com/today/author/475028 Google Plus - https://plus.google.com/+MarkShapiroSRSTech
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/5baa4eb0-c275-39b4-a9fe-0e17cf0c10b7" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-30T05:04:44Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:09:53.493Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://news.thomasnet.com/fullstory/inclination-and-tilt-sensors-prevent-heavy-equipment-from-tipping-20053427" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="44" endPos="51" type="product-class" surface="Sensors" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="409" endPos="421" type="product-class" surface="MEMS sensors" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="980" endPos="991" type="organization-company" surface="MEMSIC Inc." />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1087" endPos="1091" type="product-class" surface="MTLT" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1118" endPos="1130" type="product-class" surface="Tilt Sensors" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="5" NAME="CompanyProvidesProduct">
<Entity id="3" label="product" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
