<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>| ScienceDaily: Latest Science News | | Negotiation tip: Gain sympathy and gain the advantage In rainforests, battle for sunlight shapes forest structure Lead exposure linked to ADHD in kids with genetic mutation Increased legal liabilities limit prescribed fire use for brush control Detecting when, why deadly blood clots form Blocking melanoma's escape: Avatars break theraping resistance in relapsed cancers Snappy Sleep Stager system identifies gene related to shorter sleep Dam projects on world's largest rivers threaten fish species, rural livelihoods The Anthropocene: Hard evidence for a human-driven Earth Cellular 'switch' helps brain distinguish safety from danger, new study finds Deep ties between diverse tropical rainforests revealed Pathogens found in Ice Man's stomach New iron transporter essential for Leishmania parasite virulence is potential drug target Genetic variation linked to respiratory disease Coffee flour offers a potentially healthier way of enjoying java Superiority of chromoendoscopy in dysplasia detection in patients with colitis, landmark study shows New touchless device makes earlier detection of heart problems possible Small changes in DNA can affect nicotine consumption Single-chip laser delivers powerful result A 'printing press' for nanoparticles Portable NIST kit can recover traces of chemical evidence By the dozen: NASA's James Webb Space Telescope mirrors Random mutation, protein changes, tied to start of multicellular life Possible strategy against stroke discovered Slow stem cell division may cause small brains Tweak in gene expression may have helped humans walk upright In Arctic winter, marine creatures migrate by the light of the moon Neanderthal genes gave modern humans an immunity boost, allergies New NDV-H5NX avian influenza vaccine has potential for mass vaccination of poultry Orthopedic surgery simulation Genetic traffic signal orchestrates early embryonic development New role of protein kinases in embryo development and cancer Improving musical synchronization with mathematical modeling Three new chigger mite species discovered on rodents in Thailand Bug eyes: Tiny 3D glasses confirm insect 3D vision Epigenetic regulation of metastatic breast cancer progression may guide prognosis, future therapy Gun, fire, motor vehicle safety practices linked to parents' depressive symptoms Overcoming hurdles to climate change adaptation in the Arctic Most distant massive galaxy cluster identified New antithrombotic guideline update for treatment of VTE disease New work makes lightweight, strong metal Light exposure and kids' weight: Is there a link? Were Panamanian islanders dolphin hunters? A carbon sink that can't be filled Researchers gauge quantum properties of nanotubes, essential for next-gen electronics Smokers diagnosed with pneumonia found to have higher risk of lung cancer One in four kids sexually harassed by friends online Religious beliefs don't always lead to violence Trees employ similar strategies to outcompete their neighbors New approach to diagnosing low back pain, revealed by clinical study Cancer death rate continues steady drop Corals respond to changing ocean conditions by altering regulation of the DNA message Polymers render concrete fire-resistant What the mouse eye tells the mouse brain Molecular mechanism responsible for a neurodegenerative disease discovered Love hertz Eat less and be happy: Is it possible? Veterans, civilian patients at risk of ICU-related PTSD up to a year post discharge Researchers ride new sound wave to health discovery Your symptoms? Evolution's way of telling you to stay home | Negotiation tip: Gain sympathy and gain the advantage Posted: 07 Jan 2016 03:50 PM PST Is sympathy considered a sign of weakness or is there a place for sympathy in negotiations? Research suggests that when one party conveys information with emotional reasons behind it, the other party is more likely to develop sympathy, be more willing to compromise, and find creative solutions. | | In rainforests, battle for sunlight shapes forest structure Posted: 07 Jan 2016 03:50 PM PST Competition for sunlight among rainforest trees leads to the remarkably consistent pattern of tree sizes seen in tropical forests around the globe, researchers have found. The finding help refine models of how rainforests absorb carbon dioxide and hold back rising global temperatures. | | Lead exposure linked to ADHD in kids with genetic mutation Posted: 07 Jan 2016 03:49 PM PST Exposure to small amounts of lead may contribute to ADHD symptoms in children who have a particular gene mutation, according to new research. The scientists do not purport that lead is the only cause of ADHD symptoms, nor does the research indicate that lead exposure will guarantee an ADHD diagnosis; rather, the study demonstrates that environmental pollutants, such as lead, do play a role in the explanation of ADHD. | | Increased legal liabilities limit prescribed fire use for brush control Posted: 07 Jan 2016 03:49 PM PST Private landowners and managers tend to shy away from the use of prescribed fire for maintaining rangeland and forest ecosystems in spite of the known benefits due to the potential liability factor, according to a study. This is a concern, reports a new article, as fire has historically played an important role in achieving land management objectives, and eliminating its use could have detrimental effects. | | Detecting when, why deadly blood clots form Posted: 07 Jan 2016 03:49 PM PST A better assay for testing blood's clotting tendency, also known as hemostasis, has been devised. Researchers say it could one day prove lifesaving in a variety of clinical situations in which a patient's health is jeopardized by abnormal blood coagulation and platelet function. | | Blocking melanoma's escape: Avatars break theraping resistance in relapsed cancers Posted: 07 Jan 2016 03:49 PM PST By utilizing a revolutionary method that allows mice to serve as 'avatars' for patients, scientists have shown that a previously ineffective targeted drug for melanoma may actually be quite potent in halting the progression of disease in certain patients. | | Snappy Sleep Stager system identifies gene related to shorter sleep Posted: 07 Jan 2016 03:49 PM PST Sleep genetics research has been advanced by developing a new method for monitoring mouse sleep cycles. The Snappy Sleep Stager is a non-invasive, automated sleep cycle monitoring system based on mouse respiration, or breathing. By combining it with a new system for developing nearly perfect knock-out mice, they have identified a new short-sleeper gene, Nr3a. | | Dam projects on world's largest rivers threaten fish species, rural livelihoods Posted: 07 Jan 2016 12:17 PM PST Advocates of huge hydroelectric dam projects on the Amazon, Congo, and Mekong river basins often overestimate economic benefits and underestimate far-reaching effects on biodiversity, according to a new article. | | The Anthropocene: Hard evidence for a human-driven Earth Posted: 07 Jan 2016 12:17 PM PST Evidence for a new geological epoch which marks the impact of human activity on the Earth is now overwhelming, according to a recent paper by an international group of geoscientists. | | Cellular 'switch' helps brain distinguish safety from danger, new study finds Posted: 07 Jan 2016 12:17 PM PST Researchers have identified a cellular circuit that helps the mouse brain to remember which environments are safe, and which are harmful. Their study also reveals what can happen when that circuitry is disrupted -- and may offer new insight into the treatment of conditions such as posttraumatic stress, panic and anxiety disorders. | | Deep ties between diverse tropical rainforests revealed Posted: 07 Jan 2016 12:17 PM PST Researchers report striking new findings about the structure of tropical rainforests and how the trees in them interact with one another. Their study suggests important new recommendations for how scientists study and model tropical rainforests. | | Pathogens found in Ice Man's stomach Posted: 07 Jan 2016 12:17 PM PST Scientists are continually unearthing new facts about Homo sapiens from the mummified remains of Otzi, the Copper Age man, who was discovered in a glacier in 1991. Researchers have now succeeded in demonstrating the presence of Helicobacter pylori in Otzi's stomach contents, a bacterium found in half of all humans today. | | New iron transporter essential for Leishmania parasite virulence is potential drug target Posted: 07 Jan 2016 12:17 PM PST Leishmaniasis is a serious parasitic disease that affects 12 million people worldwide. Like for many neglected tropical diseases that disproportionately affect poor populations, existing drugs have serious side-effects and face increasing parasite resistance. A study identifies a new drug target, and supports the conclusion that iron-dependent signals generated in the mitochondria are essential for the development of parasite stages that cause disease in humans. | | Genetic variation linked to respiratory disease Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:06 AM PST Genetic mutations in a protein associated with asthma can affect a person's susceptibility to a variety of lung diseases -- and could lead to new treatments -- researchers have discovered. | | Coffee flour offers a potentially healthier way of enjoying java Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:06 AM PST Scientists are developing the flour milled from a new invention -- parbaked coffee beans -- both as a food ingredient and a nutritional supplement. | | Superiority of chromoendoscopy in dysplasia detection in patients with colitis, landmark study shows Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:06 AM PST Chromoendoscopy is superior to random biopsy or white-light colonoscopy in detecting dysplasia in patients with inflammatory bowel diseases (IBD), according to a long-term surveillance study. | | New touchless device makes earlier detection of heart problems possible Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:05 AM PST A revolutionary system for monitoring vital signs has been created that could lead to improved detection and prevention of some cardiovascular issues, as well as greater independence for older adults. | | Small changes in DNA can affect nicotine consumption Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:05 AM PST Nicotine is an addictive substance and genetic factors are known to play a role in smoking behaviors. Recently, a team of researchers determined how small differences in a particular region of the mouse genome can alter nicotine consumption. | | Single-chip laser delivers powerful result Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:05 AM PST Researchers have made a breakthrough in mid-infrared semiconductor laser technology that combines tunable wavelength emission with high-output power on a single chip. | | A 'printing press' for nanoparticles Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:05 AM PST Gold nanoparticles have unusual properties, which scientists are seeking to put to use in a range of technologies. Some of the most interesting properties emerge when nanoparticles are brought close together. But a major challenge has been finding ways to assemble these bits of gold while controlling the three-dimensional shape of their arrangement. In a new article, researchers outline a new technique. | | Portable NIST kit can recover traces of chemical evidence Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:04 AM PST A chemist at the National Institute of Standards and Technology has developed a portable version of his method for recovering trace chemicals such as environmental pollutants and forensic evidence including secret graves and arson fire debris. | | By the dozen: NASA's James Webb Space Telescope mirrors Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:04 AM PST One dozen flight mirrors are now installed on NASA's James Webb Space Telescope, out of the eighteen mirror segments that make up the primary mirror. The assembly of the primary mirror is an important milestone for the Webb telescope, but is just one component of this huge and complex observatory. | | Random mutation, protein changes, tied to start of multicellular life Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:04 AM PST All it took was one mutation more than 600 million years ago. With that random act, a new protein function was born that helped our single-celled ancestor transition into an organized multicellular organism, suggests new research. | | Possible strategy against stroke discovered Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:04 AM PST Scientists have identified the oxygen sensor PHD1 as a potential target for the treatment of brain infarction (ischemic stroke). Despite (minor) improvements in stroke treatment, stroke remains the fourth leading cause of death and the most common reason of severe disability. The impact of stroke is overwhelming for the patient, family and society -- representing one of the largest unmet medical needs. | | Slow stem cell division may cause small brains Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:04 AM PST Researchers have figured out how a developmental disease called microcephaly produces a much smaller brain than normal: Some brain stem cells are simply too slow as they proceed through the neuron production process. The findings provide not only a new mechanistic explanation for microcephaly, but could also enhance understanding of autism or other neurodevelopmental disorders thought to arise from disruptions in the proper balance of neurons in the brain. | | Tweak in gene expression may have helped humans walk upright Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:04 AM PST Researchers have identified a change in gene expression between humans and primates that may have helped give us this edge when it comes to walking upright. And they did it by studying a tiny fish called the threespine stickleback that has evolved radically different skeletal structures to match environments around the world. | | In Arctic winter, marine creatures migrate by the light of the moon Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:04 AM PST A few months ago, researchers reported the surprising discovery that marine creatures living in one Arctic fjord keep busy through the permanently dark and frigid winter months. Now, a report extends this activity to the whole of the Arctic. They also find that, in the absence of any sunlight, it's the moon that drives the vertical migrations of tiny marine animals. | | Neanderthal genes gave modern humans an immunity boost, allergies Posted: 07 Jan 2016 11:04 AM PST When modern humans met Neanderthals in Europe and the two species began interbreeding many thousands of years ago, the exchange left humans with gene variations that have increased the ability of those who carry them to ward off infection. This inheritance from Neanderthals may have also left some people more prone to allergies. | | New NDV-H5NX avian influenza vaccine has potential for mass vaccination of poultry Posted: 07 Jan 2016 10:10 AM PST In the course of three months, researchers were able to develop and test a new vaccine that protects chickens and other poultry from multiple strains of avian influenza found in the U.S., including H5N1, H5N2 and H5N8. | | Orthopedic surgery simulation Posted: 07 Jan 2016 10:00 AM PST A unique training simulator for orthopedic open surgery (knee reconstruction with total joint replacement) has been developed by researchers. | | Genetic traffic signal orchestrates early embryonic development Posted: 07 Jan 2016 10:00 AM PST A DNA-binding protein called Foxd3 acts like a genetic traffic signal, holding that ball of undifferentiated cells in a state of readiness for its great transformation in the third week of development, new research by stem cell biologists has revealed. | | New role of protein kinases in embryo development and cancer Posted: 07 Jan 2016 09:41 AM PST A group of protein kinases have been found to play an important role in embryo development and may even be a potential cancer drug target, a research team demonstrates. | | Improving musical synchronization with mathematical modeling Posted: 07 Jan 2016 09:40 AM PST Researchers propose a stochastic differential equation model that simulates how musical performers in a large ensemble sustain tempo and phase while responding to a conductor, other musicians, and additional distractions modeled as 'noise.' | | Three new chigger mite species discovered on rodents in Thailand Posted: 07 Jan 2016 09:39 AM PST Three new species of chigger mites have been discovered on rodents in Thailand, report scientists. The new species were discovered as part of a broad sampling effort across 11 provinces in Thailand, and they were found on rodents. With the addition of these three species, there are now 99 known species of chiggers in Thailand. | | Bug eyes: Tiny 3D glasses confirm insect 3D vision Posted: 07 Jan 2016 09:39 AM PST Miniature glasses have proved that mantises use 3-D vision, providing a new model to improve visual perception in robots. 3D vision in mantises was originally shown in the 1980s but this work used prisms and occluders which meant that only a very limited set of images could be shown. The new research team has developed 3D glasses suitable for insects which means they can show the insects any images they want, opening up new avenues of research. | | Epigenetic regulation of metastatic breast cancer progression may guide prognosis, future therapy Posted: 07 Jan 2016 09:39 AM PST A gene that plays a role in the development of breast cancer to metastatic disease has been identified which may help to predict disease progression and serve as a target for the development of future breast cancer therapies. | | Gun, fire, motor vehicle safety practices linked to parents' depressive symptoms Posted: 07 Jan 2016 09:39 AM PST A new study links parental depression to increased safety risks for their children. The results suggest that mothers with moderate or severe depressive symptoms were two percentage points less likely to report that their child always sat in the back seat of the car and three percentage points less likely to have at least one working smoke detector in the home. | | Overcoming hurdles to climate change adaptation in the Arctic Posted: 07 Jan 2016 09:39 AM PST Outdated land management practices, a dearth of local decision-making bodies with real powers, a lack of long-term planning, along with long-standing educational and financial disempowerment and marginalization are among the hurdles the prevent Arctic communities from adapting to climate change, says a research team. | | Most distant massive galaxy cluster identified Posted: 07 Jan 2016 09:39 AM PST Astronomers have detected a massive, sprawling, churning galaxy cluster that formed only 3.8 billion years after the Big Bang. Located 10 billion light years from Earth and potentially comprising thousands of individual galaxies, the megastructure is about 250 trillion times more massive than the sun, or 1,000 times more massive than the Milky Way galaxy. | | New antithrombotic guideline update for treatment of VTE disease Posted: 07 Jan 2016 09:38 AM PST Each year, there are approximately 10 million cases of venous thromboembolism (VTE) worldwide. VTE, the formation of blood clots in the vein, is a dangerous and potentially deadly medical condition and is a leading cause of death and disability worldwide. In this latest evidence-based guideline, experts provide 53 updated recommendations for appropriate treatment of patients with VTE. | | New work makes lightweight, strong metal Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:52 AM PST A lightweight but very strong structural metal has been created that could improve energy efficiency in aerospace, automobile, defense, mobile electronics and biomedical applications. | | Light exposure and kids' weight: Is there a link? Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:48 AM PST Light exposure plays a role in the weight of preschool children, a world-first study reveals. The researchers studied children aged three to five, from six childcare centers, measuring the children's sleep, activity and light exposure for a two week period, along with height and weight to calculate their BMI, then followed up 12-months later. | | Were Panamanian islanders dolphin hunters? Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:48 AM PST Dolphins played an important part in the diet of inhabitants of Panama's Pedro Gonzalez Island 6000 years ago. But did they hunt dolphins from dugout canoes, or use another technique to capture them? | | A carbon sink that can't be filled Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:48 AM PST As global temperatures rise, the organic matter in forests appears to break down more quickly, which is accelerating the release of carbon into the atmosphere, according to new research. | | Researchers gauge quantum properties of nanotubes, essential for next-gen electronics Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:48 AM PST Researchers have discovered an important method for measuring the properties of nanotube materials using a microwave probe. | | Smokers diagnosed with pneumonia found to have higher risk of lung cancer Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:48 AM PST Screening heavy smokers admitted to the hospital with community-acquired pneumonia could facilitate the early diagnosis of lung cancer and thereby reduce the incidence of mortality, a new report suggests. | | One in four kids sexually harassed by friends online Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:48 AM PST It's not just strangers who target children online. Kids' own friends are sexually harassing them over the Internet, finds new research. Girls, and kids with low self-control, were more likely to be sexually harassed online. But the biggest surprise was the finding that 24 percent of study participants were sexually harassed over the Internet. | | Religious beliefs don't always lead to violence Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:48 AM PST From the Christian Crusades to the Paris attacks, countless conflicts and acts of violence have been claimed to be the result of differing religious beliefs. These faith-based opinions are thought to motivate aggressive behavior because of how they encourage group loyalty or spin ideologies that devalue the lives of non-believers. However, new research reveals the opposite: religious beliefs might instead promote interfaith cooperation. | | Trees employ similar strategies to outcompete their neighbors Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:48 AM PST Trees worldwide compete in some of the same ways, making simpler models of forest response to climate change possible, say researchers. The study demonstrated how 'personal' traits such as wood density and leaf morphology influence a tree species' ability to compete. | | New approach to diagnosing low back pain, revealed by clinical study Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:48 AM PST A new, personalized approach to diagnosing low back pain has been discovered by researchers. Low back pain is the second most common cause of physician visits in the US and contributes to an estimated $100 billion in US costs per year, making it clear that it causes a significant burden on both the healthcare system and the economy. For physicians trying to diagnose low back pain, they are looking at many potential causes and unpredictable responses to treatment. | | Cancer death rate continues steady drop Posted: 07 Jan 2016 07:47 AM PST Steady reductions in smoking combined with advances in cancer prevention, early detection, and treatment have resulted in a 23 percent drop in the cancer death rate since its peak in 1991. | | Corals respond to changing ocean conditions by altering regulation of the DNA message Posted: 07 Jan 2016 06:50 AM PST Some corals may cope with climate change by changing markings on their DNA to modify what the DNA produces. | | Polymers render concrete fire-resistant Posted: 07 Jan 2016 06:47 AM PST Self-compacting high-performance concrete has till now suffered from one weakness: when exposed to fire it flakes and splits, which reduces its loadbearing capacity. Scientists in Switzerland have now developed a method of manufacturing fire-resistant self-compacting high-performance concrete which maintains its mechanical integrity under these conditions. | | What the mouse eye tells the mouse brain Posted: 07 Jan 2016 06:47 AM PST Researchers have shown that image processing in the eye is more extensive than previously thought. They investigated the channels that transmit information from the eye to the brain. In the course of this investigation, they not only identified numerous new cell types: they also found that the retina seems to possess some 40 different channels into the brain, twice as many as previously assumed. | | Molecular mechanism responsible for a neurodegenerative disease discovered Posted: 07 Jan 2016 06:47 AM PST A mechanism that is responsible for the degeneration of Purkinje cells in the cerebellum in a neurodegenerative disease called Spinocerebellar ataxia type 1 has been discovered by researchers. The results of this study open up new avenues for the future treatment of cerebellum associated degenerative disorders. | | Love hertz Posted: 07 Jan 2016 06:44 AM PST Sex sells when it comes to luring male mosquitoes, a new study has found. Researchers set out to make a cheap and effective audio lure for scientists collecting male Aedes aegypti mosquitoes -- the species that carries dengue and yellow fever. They found a tone of precisely 484 Hertz, the frequency of a female Aedes aegypti's wings, brought 95 percent of male mosquitoes to the trap. | | Eat less and be happy: Is it possible? Posted: 07 Jan 2016 06:44 AM PST Small, uncertain incentives stimulate the same reward center of the brain as food, new brain-imaging research reveals. In a new article, the authors offer food for thought on why we overeat and how we can be just as happy not doing it. | | Veterans, civilian patients at risk of ICU-related PTSD up to a year post discharge Posted: 07 Jan 2016 06:44 AM PST One in ten patients is at risk of having new post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) related to their ICU experience up to a year post-discharge. This was the finding from a multicenter, prospective cohort research study of veterans and civilians. | | Researchers ride new sound wave to health discovery Posted: 07 Jan 2016 06:41 AM PST Acoustics experts have created a new class of sound wave -- the first in more than half a century -- in a breakthrough they hope could lead to a revolution in stem cell therapy. | | Your symptoms? Evolution's way of telling you to stay home Posted: 07 Jan 2016 06:41 AM PST Our selfish genes are behind the aches and fever, suggests new research. In the paper, the scientists go through a list of common symptoms, and each seems to support the hypothesis that feeling sick is an evolutionary adaptation. Appetite loss, for example, hinders the disease from spreading by communal food or water resources. Fatigue and weakness can lessen the mobility of the infected individual, reducing the radius of possible infection. Along with the symptoms, the sick individual can become depressed and lose interest in social and sexual contact, again limiting opportunities to transmit pathogens. | | You are subscribed to email updates from Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily. To stop receiving these emails, you may unsubscribe now. | Email delivery powered by Google | | Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States |
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/be362a46-8c43-36b4-9be3-d77c2c2c02e2" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-08T11:15:00Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:47:27.174Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://cashgainer.blogspot.com/2016/01/sciencedaily-latest-science-news_8.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
