<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Chapter Twenty-Eight Instruments of Destruction, Part 2 Date: October 15th, 1860 Location: the Yellow Sea Time: 9:30 AM Over the previous eighteen hours, the remnants of the once proud Anglo French fleet were hunted down and destroyed by the Nautilus. In the end, not one single ship escaped; those that ran aground in the shallows were destroyed with torpedoes through the sternposts. For these ships, Captain Collins exercised her discretion and allowed the crews to safely abandon ship before they were blown up. Out in the deeps of the Yellow Sea, there were no survivors. Among the last vessels to be blown into oblivion were HMS Calcutta and the ships in the fleet's command squadron. Despite dozens upon dozens of furious broadsides, all that was accomplished was the expenditure of tons of round shot and thousands of barrels of powder (plus the creation of a massive amount of powder smoke). The very last ship to be sunk was HMS Calcutta herself. The ship's guns fell silent as the last barrels of powder were expended; as nothing further could be done, Admiral Seymour, Captain Phipps and the ship's officers stood on the ship's quarterdeck awaiting their inevitable destruction. Forward on the gun deck, some of the crew begin to sing. The melody is quickly picked up HMS Calcutta's officers and begins to echo across the surface of the Yellow Sea. ‘Men of Harlech stop your dreaming, Can't you see their spearpoints gleaming? See their warriors' pennants streaming, to this battlefield. Men of Harlech stand ye steady, It cannot be ever said ye for the battle were not ready Stand and never yield…' Just before the second line of the song completes, Captain Phipps turns to Admiral Seymour and says Sir, I just wanted to say that it has been an honor serving under your command. I have never known a finer officer than you. Admiral Seymour replies Captain, if there were to be any survivors of this calamity, I would see to it that your gallant conduct would be brought to the attention of the First Sea Lord. Captain Phipps exhales sharply and says Thank you, sir. The two officers exchange formal salutes, then reach out to shake hands one last time. The handshake is undone, because at that exact moment, the last torpedo from the Nautilus finds its target and detonates under the keel amidships; just ten feet from the ship's hull. The explosion breaks HMS Calcutta's back and blows the ship to pieces. Broken timbers from the hull and jagged splinters of every size are sent flying hundreds of yards in all directions. The ship's masts are snapped off like matchsticks, while the sheer force of the explosion dismounts every piece on both gun decks. Being the heaviest pieces of machinery on the ship, the engines survive the massive explosion largely intact and quickly sink to the bottom of the sea. They are joined by the ship's gun barrels, her anchors and various other pieces of metalwork both large and small. The most significant items are the pay chests for the British component of the combined fleet. These were stored in the paymaster's office and are strongly built of riveted sheet iron; the chests hold a total of one million gold sovereigns. Of even greater value that the fleet payroll are the chests containing the indemnity paid by the Chinese Imperial Government. These were aboard HMS Splendid and other principal warships, and were intended for transport back to England. Along with the indemnity, there were the riches confiscated from the nearby Chinese cities of Beitang and Dagu. As soon as the mangled wreck of HMS Calcutta slips below the waves, Captain Collins looks to her communications officer and says Sparks, send to Smith Actual aboard the Wasp. Say that all ships in the Anglo French Fleet have been dealt with. Aye, Ma'am. Location: Aboard the Wasp Time: 9:45 AM The message from the Nautilus is received by Captain Steadman and instantly given to Mr. Smith. He gets on the fleet wide communications channel and says Attention all hands, this is Smith Actual. It's time to go feet dry; stand by for further instructions from your team leaders and section chiefs. To Captain Steadman, he says Roger, get the UCAVs up and over the beach where we'll be landing. The LCACs will put the warframes ashore first so they can establish a beachhead. Then, the trucks will come next. Lastly, two of the Ghost Eagles are to fly on ahead to scout out the best route for the road march. Understood, boss. Below, the Wasp's cavernous hangar deck is buzzing with activity. The warframe pilots and maintenance crews have completed their PMCS, and all weapons have been fully loaded. On the well deck, those personnel assigned to the trucks have rallied on the vehicles after drawing supplies and ammunition. The first wave to go ashore will consist of four warframes and two trucks in each LCAC, while the second wave will bring the rest of the trucks. Each truck is crewed by a driver, assistant driver and two people in the cargo bed. Every one of these are wearing combat suits and macrovisor helmets. The standard sidearm is a 9 mm electrothermal machine pistol, and every man or woman in the strike team carries either a CP 150 5.7 mm SMG or a pulse rifle. Before the warframes board the LCACs, GySgt Faulkner and May Day confer with the other pilots and give them their instructions. She says Alright boys &amp; girls, when we hit the beach, First Section will be with me on the left flank and Second Section will be with May Day on the right. We'll set up a security perimeter and keep watch while the rest of the trucks come ashore. When everybody has rallied together, then we'll move out. Any questions? May Day speaks up and says Joanne, what are our rules of engagement? They're very simple. Mr. Smith says that anyone in British or French uniform is to be fired on. If they surrender, that's all well and good. However, if any enemy personnel try to take advantage of this, all bets are off. As far as Chinese civilians are concerned, they are not to be engaged unless absolutely necessary; warning shots only. Lethal force is not to be used against the Chinese except as a last resort. Is that understood? May Day and the others nod their heads, then GySgt Faulkner grins with satisfaction as she says Alright, people. Strap in and move out. Each pilot goes to his or her machine and is strapped in by the crew. Shortly thereafter, all twenty four machines are slowly stomping across the hangar deck; the footsteps of their machines echo loudly across the cavernous space like those of a titan of classical antiquity. With somewhat irreverent humor, one of the pilots calls out the words of an old nursery rhyme: Fee, Fi, Fo, Fum. I smell the blood of an Englishman. Be he alive or be he dead, I'll grind his bones to make me bread. The humor in these few words is infectious, and soon, all of the warframe pilots are laughing out loud; GySgt Faulkner shakes her head back and forth, chuckles and silently quotes a few lines of Shakespeare's ‘Henry V' to herself In peace, there's nothing that so becomes a man as modest stillness and humility. But, when the blast of war blows in our ears, then imitate the action of the tiger; stiffen the sinews, summon up the blood and disguise fair nature with hard favored rage. The warframes board the LCACs, and then the boarding ramp on the aft end of the wasp is lowered down. The LCAC pilots spin up their engines and swivel their ducted fans around to back their machines out of the well deck. Outside the ship, the calm, placid surface of the Yellow Sea belies the violence which has so recently taken place. The LCACs advance towards the shore from where the Wasp is holding its position (a distance of five miles) at a speed of 30 knots. The objective is a smooth stretch of beach a mile west southwest of the city of Dagu. The UCAV helicopters are already hovering over the landing beach, while the two Ghost Eagles have flown over land to scout the route of advance and also to locate the British French expeditionary force. For those Chinese peasants, government functionaries and soldiers still in the area, what they see and hear now only adds fear to the humiliation they suffered very recently at the hands of the British and French. One man in particular (Ge Li, bannerman in service to General Zeng Guofan) looks up when he hears strange fluttering noises coming from the sky and loud roaring noises coming from the sea . What Ge Li sees and hears freezes his feet to the ground as certainly as if they had been rooted there. His mind is squeezed by unrelenting fear as Ge Li sees giant flying machines come swooping down over the beach from out of the sky. To make matters worse, these machines are garishly painted and playing strange, unearthly music of a kind that he has never heard before. He gestures frantically to his friends and calls out loudly FEILONG…FEILONG!! Ge Li and his friends have their backs turned to the beach and so, are taken by surprise when the LCACs come roaring up like ships about to run aground. For them, this is the last straw. They take to their heels and run towards the woods as fast as their fete can carry them. Some of the more superstitious call out DILONG…DILONG!! while others call on the Heavenly Emperor or the Dragon Kings of the Four Seas to protect them against evil. Out on the water, the six LCACs reassemble themselves into two lines of three machines each. The first line slows down and comes on shore, slowing down even more as the three LCACs climb the slope of the beach. While the LCAC crews keep their ducted fans howling, the forward ramps are dropped and twelve warframes come out. Six of them (commanded by GySgt Faulkner) take up positions on the left, while the second group of six (commanded by May Day) arrange themselves on the right. When the warframes are in position, Faulkner scans the countryside and sees that there are no hostiles present. Accordingly, she gives the signal for the trucks to come off and come into line. As soon as the first three LCACs have unloaded their trucks and warframes, they withdraw so that the next three can come on shore and do likewise. While this is going on, the first three LCACs return to the Wasp so that more trucks can be loaded. Aboard one of these trucks, Alexander Randall has been detailed by Mr. Smith to serve as an assistant driver. This is his first combat assignment, and he is determined to live up to Mr. Smith's expectations. Alexander is a veteran of the United States Marine Corps, and is no stranger to amphibious operations. He climbs into the cab of his assigned truck and waits for the signal to move the vehicle towards the well deck. This isn't long in coming, as the first three LCACs are coming back aboard ship. Once again, the LCAC crews keep their engines and fans turning as each vehicle takes four trucks aboard. In less than ten minutes, the trucks are loaded and secured. The three LCACs back out of the well deck and head towards the shore, passing the second three on the way back to the Wasp. Time: 10:30 AM All of the warframes and trucks are now on the beach, assembled and ready to move out. The warframes are on the flanks and the trucks are in the middle (in six groups of four trucks each). Air cover is provided by the four UCAV helicopters flying overhead. Joanne Faulkner is the senior member of Mr. Smith's staff on hand, and so she gives the order to Head ‘em up, Move ‘em out!! The route chosen for the march is the very same one that the troops of the Anglo French expeditionary force are travelling on, a branch line of the Imperial Highway system established by Emperor Shi Huangdi. This particular stretch of road is wide and flat, measuring 20 Bu is width. It is paved with stone and trenched on both sides to drain any water that might accumulate. On both sides of the road, the land is open and relatively flat, with small hills and stands of trees here and there. For ease of maneuverability, Mr. Smith's trucks are driving on the road while the warframes travel offroad next to the highway. Each group of four trucks is escorted by two warframes on either side, with a distance of twenty yards between each group. Back aboard the Wasp, Mr. Smith is in the CIC observing the progress of his surface elements when he is apprised of the exact location of the Anglo French task force by a member of the Ghost Eagle operating team. He immediately calls GySgt Faulkner and says Gunny, this is Smith Actual. I have traffic for you. Faulkner to Smith Actual, proceed. Be advised that the enemy expeditionary force is fifty miles from your location. It comprises three regiments of infantry with artillery support; it is also escorted by a column of cavalry. Received and understood. What are your instructions? Advance to contact but do not engage until I arrive. I'll send the UCAVs on ahead to block their line of march. Copy that, Smith Actual. Faulkner out. Mr. Smith leaves the Wasp's CIC and goes up to the flight deck, where the other members of his strike force are assembling. Of the two hundred men and women in the strike force, 108 are already on the road (the 12 warsuit pilots and 96 personnel on the trucks). The remaining 92 will be inserted by helicopter once the Old Summer Palace has been secured. The remaining air assets aboard Wasp consist of three CH 47 Chinook and three UH 60 Blackhawk helicopters. The CH 47s were purchased ‘sub rosa' by one of Mr. Smith's agents, who traveled back to Viet Nam in 1977, two years after the war ended. The UH 60s were acquired in much the same manner, this time from the Iraqi army in 2008. He seeks out the Wasp's director of flight operations and says Tony, spin up one of the Blackhawks. I'm going to go make the British and French troops an offer they can't refuse. Mr. Kauffman grins and replies Boss, are you figuring to have them wake up next to the horse's head? Mr. Smith laughs out loud at the movie reference and says Something like that, Tony. If they stand down, they get to keep breathing. If not, they die. Look at it this way, in a contest of black powder versus high explosive, who do you think is going to win every time? Right, boss. When do you want to leave? Have the crew do their pre flight checks and be ready to go in one hour. One hour it is, boss. Who’s Who and What’s What Date: October 15th, 1860 Location: On the road to Peiking Time: 11:00 AM Below on the Wasp’s hangar deck, Mr. Smith is supervising the loading of the rest of his strike team and their equipment aboard the transport helicopters, He pauses for a moment to consider whether or not to give the French and British troops fair warning about what is going to happen and also to give them a chance to surrender. He decides not to, then takes out a small radio from his pocket and says “Flight Ops, this is Smith Actual, I have decided not to give the French and British troops a chance to surrender. Instead, I and the troops are going to wait until the Summer Palace is secure before taking off to join the others on site.” “Understood, Boss. Flight Ops out.” Being supported by batteries of artillery and columns of cavalry, the 3,500 troops under the command of Colonel Charles Philby have made excellent progress on their march to the Summer Palace of Emperor Xianfeng; the column is more than halfway t their objective when Colonel Philby’s second in command rides up, salutes and says “I say, sir. The march is going as well as expected, is it not?” “It is indeed, Lt Colonel York. My only regret thus far is that we’ve not had the opportunity to give the Chinese a goodly taste of shot &amp; shell. I think, however, that this will change once we reach the Summer Palace and bring down the vengeance of Her Majesty the Queen. Whatever happens, the Chinese will certainly deserve all of it and more for their vile treachery towards the diplomatic party headed by Messers Loch &amp; Parke.” Colonel Philby exercises his command discretion and orders a halt so that the men and can rest and refresh themselves. Just then, Lt. Colonel York point to the sky forward of the column’s line and shouts with evident alarm and no small amount of fear in his voice “By the venerable St, George, what in the name of god are those things?” Colonel Philby looks to see where his 2nd in command is pointing, and beholds four strange flying machines. The noises that these machines make as they move through the air are quite unlike anything else that he has ever heard.” Colonel Philby stands tall in his saddle and says “Lt. Colonel York, I like not the looks of those machines; I think perhaps that they have some fell purpose. Stand the men to and have them fall into ranks. Bring up the artillery, crank the barrels up as high as they’ll go and deploy the cavalry on the flanks.” Lt. Colonel York hesitates somewhat, then Colonel Philby shouts out angrily “Snap out of it, man and pull yourself together. You’re a soldier of Her Majesty the Queen, not some wet behind the ears subaltern yearning for the comforts of hearth and home.” Back aboard the Wasp, the UCAV operators are watching live video feeds from their UAH 64. They note with interest how the Anglo French column has halted and is now coming into line. This information is given to Captain Steadman, and he in turn communicates it to Mr. Smith. Captain Steadman says “What are your orders, boss?” “Tell the operators to have their UAH 64’s set up for an attack run on the forward elements of the column. Begin with thermobarics and follow up with white phosphorus and cluster munitions. Then, they are to strafe the British and French troops. The idea is not to kill them all, but instead to keep them from advancing or scattering to the flanks. GySgt Faulkner, May Day and the rest of the warframe pilots will be on scene in five minutes; the UCAVs can drop the hammer then.” “Yes sir, Mr. Smith.”. Mr. Smith turns his attention back to supervising the loading of the rest of his strike force on the transport helicopters. In the UCAV operations room, the necessary instructions are transmitted to the AH 64s. The machines throttle themselves up to full power and move to attack the targets on the ground. Colonel Philby and Lt. Colonel York are still issuing orders for the better deployment of their troops when the four mysterious flying machines come screaming towards them like the Banshees from Irish myth and legend. Above and in front of the enemy column, the computer brains aboard the UAH 64s disengage the safeties on their weapons and prepare to fire. Each machine carefully selects a portion of the enemy formation and ranges it with an infrared targeting laser in the chin turret. Aside from a full load of ammunition for the guns, each UAH 64 is armed with a pair of 19 shot 70 mm rocket pods (loaded with WP rockets), eight AGMs with 50 lb thermobaric MAC warheads, a pair of cluster munitions dispensers and two chemical spray tanks on the tips of their external stores support systems. First to be deployed are the AGMs; these weapons are volley fired in pairs, with their aiming points chosen so as to affect as wide an area as possible. The first to die are Colonel Philby and his entire command staff; an AGM impacts directly in their midst, and everyone within twenty yards is killed instantaneously by a combination of blast pressure and hot burning gases. This scene is repeated dozens of times as the AGMs rake the formation unmercifully. Even with such unmitigated destruction raining down upon their heads, the surviving British and French officers begin to rally their troops. Bayonets are fixed, muskets are loaded and pieces of field artillery are charged with powder and shell. The artillery crews crank the barrels of their pieces as high as they can go and the infantry prepares to fire. GySgt Faulkner, May Day and the rest of the warframe crews are watching from a distance of two hundred yards. Faulkner turns to her partner and says “Bring your ‘frames on line to the right and I’ll do the same on the left. As soon as the UAH 64s open fire with their rocket pods, we’ll join the party with our .50 caliber gatlings and 25 mm autocannons.” “Copy that, Gunny.” May Day has her warframe detachment come into line, and GySgt Faulkner does the same with hers. Several hundred yards ahead, the UAH 64s come around for another attack run. This time, the UCAVs ripple off 70 mm WP rockets as fast as they can be fired. The rockets strike among the scattered remnants of the British and French infantry and explode, sending burning hot pieces of white phosphorus and warhead casing in all directions. Those not immediately killed by the blasts are severely burned by particles of WP that are forced into their bodies. Battered, bloody and with great gaping holes torn in their once proud formations, the British and French troops raise their muskets to their shoulders and open fire. Very soon, the clouds of smoke from fires on the ground and from burning white phosphorus and joined by thick, off white clouds of blackpowder smoke. Elsewhere, artillery crews attach lanyards to friction primers in the vents of their pieces and give them a quick pull. Instantly, the crack and thunder of artillery fire joins with the chaos and disorder already in play on the battlefield. GySgt Faulkner sees this, calls to her partner May Day and says “those redcoats’ asses are grass and we’re the lawnmowers. OPEN FIRE!!!” Twelve .50 caliber caseless electrothermal gatlings are brought to bear on the targets, then each warframe pilot pulls the trigger. The weapons erupt with a loud ripping, tearing noise as they are swept back and forth in great, wide arcs. Everywhere, the huge bullets strike home. The bodies of men and horses alike are literally blown apart by the incredible hydrostatic pressure. Above the battlefield, the UAH 64s trigger their cluster munitions dispensers and sew yet more seeds of death on the ground. When the CMDs are empty, the UAH 64s begin to cross back and forth over the ground, firing their 20 mm autocannons and .30 caliber gatlings as they go. Ten minutes later, it is all over; of the once proud Anglo French expeditionary force, not a single man or horse remains alive. GySgt Faulkner gets on the general comm. channel and says “Cease fire and safe all weapons.” She radios back to Mr. Smith aboard the Wasp and says “Smith actual, this is Faulkner. I have traffic for you.” “Gunny, this is Smith Actual. Go ahead.” “Smith Actual, the combined Anglo French column has been totally wiped out; there are no survivors.” Mr. Smith replies “Good work, Gunny. You and the others are to proceed to target and set up a security perimeter. Apprise me upon arrival; and I’ll join you shortly.” “Smith Actual, received and understood. Faulkner out.” The warframes and trucks detour around the battlefield and take up their line of march towards the Summer Palace. One hour later, they arrive at the palace. GySgt Faulkner uses the hand on her warframe to tear the gates off the hinges, then the trucks and other ‘frames follow her inside the palace grounds. She sends a message back to Mr. Smith that the Summer Palace is in her possession. He replies “Copy that, Gunny. Have everyone in your column mask up and turn on their NBC systems. I’m going to have the palace and surrounding countryside gassed so that everyone there will fall unconscious and not interfere with our ‘withdrawls’. I and the rest of the crew will be there in 30 minutes.” “Copy that, Smith Actual, Faulkner out.” The Summer Palace was constructed as a residence for the Emperors of China starting in 1707. As such, it is surrounded by wide, flat open fields where crops are grown and livestock raised. The palace is currently unguarded, with the garrison having been withdrawn to join the imperial army in its fight against the barbarian English and French invaders. Presently, there are only some palace servants and minor court functionaries residing there. Some of these people gaze fearfully out of the windows at the new strangers and wonder what ill portents they bring. These thoughts don’t last long as Mr. Smith’s UAH 64s begin to fly over the palace and the surrounding lands in a ‘grid square’ pattern. Each of the UCAV’s computer brains triggers the electronic valves on their twin external spray tanks. If anyone were close enough, they would only hear a slight hissing noise (as of a kettle boiling on a stove). The gas is odorless, colorless and tasteless; it takes effect within thirty seconds. Wherever anyone or any animal is within a one mile radius, they lose consciousness and fall to the ground. The gas is non persistent, but the physiological effects will last for the next three days. “Smith Actual, this is GySgt Faulkner. Be advised that the residents of the palace and the people in the surrounding countryside have been neutralized with knockout gas. The palace has been secured and we are awaiting your arrival.” Mr. Smith replies “Understood, Gunny. I and the rest of the crew are on the way. Smith Actual out.” One hour later, Mr. Smith and the rest of his troops arrive on transport helicopters. He debarks the aircraft and comes up to GySgt Faulkner and May Day. Mr. Smith take sin the scene for a few moments and says “Alright, ladies. Let’s get to work. The twenty four trucks are parked by the Summer Palace’s front door with their cargo beds open and the loading ramps in place. Mr. Smith, GySgt Faulkner anfd May Day get out of their warframes and enter the palace along with the full complement of men from the strike force, he says “May Day, take a dozen men and go to the palace strong room. Strip it of the very last coin and ingot and bring it all here. Gunny, I’ll have you and fifty others go to where the Imperial collections of jade and timepieces are stored; bring everything here.” The two women exchange glances of eminent satisfaction, then GySgt Faulkner replies “Right boss man.” While Mr. Smith’s badboys and badgirls set to work, he walks through the palace alone. There are certain pieces in the Imperial collections that he personally wants to attend to. Among these are the ‘Bell of Zhou’, the ‘Carved Olive Stone Boat’, the ‘Jadeite Cabbage’, the ‘Meat Shaped Stone’, the ‘Cauldron of the Duke of Mao’ and the bronze heads of the twelve zodiac statues from the Summer Palace’s ‘Haiyantang’ water clock fountain. Elsewhere, Mr. Smith’s people begin to remove the jades, ceramics, lacquerware and carvings from their display cases and rack. These are carefully placed into their storage boxes and brought out onto the palace’s front terrace, where they are subsequently loaded onto the trucks for transport back to the beachhead and subsequently aboard the SS Arcadia. The Summer Palace’s collections are so vast that it will take at least twelve round trips to get everything aboard ship. Due to the distance from the Palace to the beachhead (100+ miles) and the time needed to offload the LCACs to SS Arcadia, only one trip per day can be accomplished. The 24 trucks are loaded and ready to go with the first shipment by 4:00 PM; these are sent back to the beachhead with armed personnel aboard. In the meantime, Mr. Smith, GySgt Faulkner, May Day and the warframe crews will stay behind along with the rest of the strike group in order to secure the palace. From elsewhere in the palace, May Day and her crew have succeeded in locating the strongroom; the door is forced open, and the glittering sight inside nearly takes their breath away. Everywhere they can see, there are bags of gold and silver coins in piles the height of a tall man plus neatly stacked bars of gold and silver bullion, chests of jewelry and caskets of unset gemstones. May Day radios back to Mr. Smith and says “Boss, we’ve hit the jackpot. I located the palace strongroom, and the contents are simply unbelieveable.” Mr. Smith instantly replies “Good job, May Day. What is your location?” “Boss, the crew and I are on the south southeast side of the palace, 150 yards from your position.” “Copy that, May Day. I and some of the boys are on the way. In the meantime, start doing a count, I’d like to see an estimate of what’s there.” “Understood, Boss man. May Day out.” “Very soon, Mr. Smith, GySgt Faulkner and a dozen others are on their way to the strong room. When they get there, they see the heavy, bronze strapped doors thrown wide open and enter room immediately. Though Mr. Smith is well used to being around vast quantities of precious metals, even he is impressed by what he sees. GySgt Faulkner’s eyes blaze with pleasure as she interjects and says “I LIKE IT!!” Mr. Smith grins widely and says “May Day, what do you and the boys have for a count thus far?” “Boss, the count was much less involved than I thought at first. As you can see, the bars of gold and silver are all of the exact same size. Furthermore, each bar is stamped with an inscription which mentions its weight and purity. We’re looking at two hundred tons of gold bullion and eight hundred tons of silver bullion. There are also 25,000 bags of coins, each of which weighs just about 60 lbs. Lastly, there are some 300 chests of jewelry and 900 caskets of unset gems.” Mr. Smith claps his hands in enthusiasm and says “those are the kinds of numbers I like to hear, May Day. The gold and silver from the ships we sank out in the Yellow sea gets divided among the crews of the Nautilus, the Wasp, SS Glomar Explorer and SS Arcadia. They’re also going to get 25% of everything that’s in here. The remainder will be stored at Niihau Station for later transport to the Alpha Site.” “Thanks, boss. I’m sure the crew is going to appreciate that. I’ve got a suggestion, Mr. Smith. In order to save time and effort, why don’t you have the trucks drive up outside of this building? This way, we don’t have to bust our asses by carrying this stuff all the way across the palace compound to the front gate.” “That’s an excellent suggestion, Madam. In the meantime, I want you to get your warframe and to come back here with five of your crew to stay and guard the stash. I, Faulkner and the others are returning to the front to set up base camp. I have already sent the trucks back to the beachhead with the first load, They should be back here tomorrow morning.” “Understood, boss man.” When Mr. Smith and the others return the Palace’s front entrance, May Day straps herself back into her warsuit; her other five men equip themselves then follow her back to the treasure vault. After May Day leaves, Mr. Smith says “Gunny starting at 7:00 PM local time, I want a detail of a dozen men on watch at all times. One hour shifts, and the duty is to be staggered so that no one has more than one shift per night, or has the same shift twice in a row. Other than that, I leave the arrangement of the duty schedule to your own discretion.” “Understood, boss. You can count on me.” Time: 5:00 PM For reasons of security and operational control, Mr. Smith keeps all of his people (except for those at the treasure vault) in the same area. The men and women set out their cots &amp; sleeping bags, then prepare meals using their combat rations and chemical based heat packs. After the meals are done, some of Mr. Smith’s people set out surveillance equipment so that advance warning will be given if hostiles are approaching. Lastly, four Automated Sentry weapons platforms are set out and activated. Two platforms are by the front gate and two are set up in the courtyard in front of the palace’s main entrance; the fields of fire are arranged so as to be mutually support each other as necessary. Mr. Smith sits back on his cot against the wall, extracts a Cohiba Grande from his cigar case and lights up. He takes a couple of slow puffs and says to everyone else “Smoke ‘em if you got’em, people.” GySgt Faulkner sits on her bunk just across the hallway form where Mr. Smith is and says “Boss, this operation we’re on is the most complicated and richest one we have ever attempted. Not even your plan to pillage your way through the Stock Market in October comes close. I assume that you had a reason for not killing the Chinese here in the palace and in the surrounding countryside.” “Quite right, Gunny. I didn’t have them killed for the simple reason that they did nothing to deserve being killed. Right now, the servants and court officials here in the palace are lying unconscious where they fell; so are the peasants in the countryside near the palace. They will wake up the day after tomorrow with nothing more than a slight headache. We’re still going to be here when they do; I don’t want any unnecessary complications, so I want all of the residents of the palace collected and deposited somewhere safe outside the walls tomorrow.” “Right, boss. How about the bodies of the French and British troops that we offed earlier today, are you going to do anything about them?” “Nope. After all, the crows have to eat too, you know. If the British and French hadn’t previously been such a bunch of assholes to the Chinese, the situation would certainly be different.” Just then, a flash of inspiration strikes Mr. Smith. He thinks for a few moments and says “Gunny, I just had a idea on how to help the Chinese address the problem of their technological inferiority on the battlefield.” “What’s that, boss?” “Tomorrow, I want you to get back into your warframe and pick one of the other ‘frames to come along with you. You will head back to the battlefield and secure it; my idea is to collect and secure all of the weapons and artillery formerly possessed by the English and French troops.” GySgt Faulkner replies “That’s a tall order, Jim; two of us won’t be able to get it done in any reasonable amount of time.” “Precisely, Gunny. That’s why I’m going to send thirty people by helicopter from the crew here at the palace to join you. Right now, there’s a Ghost Eagle on station orbiting above the battlefield to let us know if anyone starts to approach; the most recent scan shows that the supply train attached to the Anglo French column is still there; both unguarded and un harmed. I’ll want you and the others to rally the wagons together in a laager; bring the artillery and their caissons inside the enclosure and stack the salvaged muskets and other weapons next to the artillery.” “What comes after that, Jim?” “Why nothing at all, Gunny. The local Chinese government authorities will come along to see what happened sooner or later; they aren’t stupid, so they’ll take the materiel in hand and use it as they see fit. There’s one last thing; after you and your people get the wagons together, un harness the horses and just let them all go. I’m sure the local Chinese peasants and farmers will come up with a use for them.” “Sounds like a plan, boss.” Making Withdrawls Date: October 16th, 1860 Location: the Old Summer Palace, Peking Time: 7:00 AM Mr. Smith and the rest of his people rouse themselves from their sleeping bags, eat a quick breakfast and continue with the business of the day. All throughout the palace, Mr. Smith’s men and women commence to removing items of value and packing them in their cases and crates. At 7:30 AM, GySgt Faulkner comes to Mr. Smith and says “Boss, Mr. Fletcher and I are ready to go.” “Alright, Gunny. Get to the battlefield as quickly as possible. I’ll dispatch those thirty men by transport helicopter as soon as you leave.” Faulkner replies “Copy that, boss” and heads off to join Mr. Fletcher (who is already strapped into his warframe). Shortly thereafter, the trucks begin to arrive back at the palace. Mr. Scaramanga hops out of the lead truck and says “Good morning, boss.” “Good morning, Mr. Fletcher. I trust that the first delivery went as well as could be expected.” “It did, boss man. We only saw a few groups of Chinese on the way, and they didn’t give us any trouble. In fact, they scattered as soon as they saw us; they probably thought that we were demons of some sort. As soon as we got to the beachhead, we offloaded the swag, rested for a while then turned around and came back. Captain Steadman and Captain Teach had work parties assigned to the beach from their deck divisions; it took less than an hour to get everything onto the LCACs.” “Excellent news, Mr. Fletcher. Now, to the business at hand. Get everybody off the trucks and have them join the crews going through the palace.” “Right, boss.” The rest of the day proceeds without incident, moving even smoother now that the unconscious bodies of the palace’s residents have been removed and carried somewhere safe outside the walls. The contents of one room in particular catches Mr. Smith’s attention, and so he decides to attend to it personally. This room houses Emperor Xianfeng’s collection of clocks and timepieces. As he removes each item from its display, he notices that the vast majority are from famous European clock &amp; watchmakers like Vacheron Constantin, Jaeger Le Coultre, Patek Phillipe, Breguet, Beaucourt, Thwaites &amp; Reed, Joseph Johnson and many others. Mr. Smith pauses momentarily to admire the craftsmanship of several pieces before packing them away into one of two large chests he found in a nearby alcove. The rest of the work takes less than a half hour. By that time, both chests are full. Mr. Smith personally carries one chest to the front door of the palace and sends back four of his men to get the other one. By 3:00 PM, the trucks have been fully loaded and are back out on the road once again. GySgt Faulkner and Mr. Fletcher return from their mission to the battlefield and report back to Mr. Smith. “Boss, I, Mr. Fletcher and the others rallied the wagons, unhitched the horses and gathered up the weapons just as you said. There was quite a bit of material; I’m sure the Chinese government will be quite pleased with the present you left for them.” “Excellent, Gunny. Did you get a count of what you recovered from the battlefield?” Faulkner replies “we did, boss. There were 2,000 Pattern 1853 Enfield rifle muskets and 1,500 French Model 1842 rifled muskets with bayonets and full sets of leather gear. For artillery, there were two batteries of Armstrong 12 pdr rifled breechloaders and three batteries of 12 pdr smoothbores. Just as you instructed, we placed the artillery in the middle of the wagon enclosure, then stacked all of the weapons neatly around the guns. Just as you said, the supply train was full to overflowing with rations, ammunition, powder and shot.” “Good work. Why don’t you and Mr. Fletcher get something to eat and rest up for a while? I and the others will continue stripping the palace.” “Sounds good, boss.” A Certain Complication Date: January 17th, 1929 Location: the Farm, Monee Township, Illinois Time: 9:00 AM Otis Needleman is Mr. Smith’s Operations &amp; Intelligence Chief. As such, it is his task to monitor all of the Organization and see to it that all functions proceed smoothly. At exactly 9:00 AM, Otis receives a call on his personal communicator from Pete Kruger at the Alpha Site in Xenia, Ohio. He fishes the device out of his pocket, activates it and says “Needleman here, what do you have, Pete?” “Mr. Needleman, the Early Warning Section just sent me an alert. Apparently, there has been a temporal event in another timeline; one that Mr. Smith has neither created or been to.” Otis replies “Thanks for the heads up, Pete. What are the specifics?” “Mr. Needleman, the boss set up the Early Warning Section to detect incursions into this timeline by others with access to time travel technology. Mr. Smith’s original idea was to prevent Dr. Martin McFly, Jennifer Parker or anyone else from Timeline: Alpha from coming after him here. The details are that, at 8:45 AM local time, sensors detected a massive, non specific release of chronal energy; this energy was not directed towards us. It seems that someone else in another timeline is trying the brute force approach to time travel.” “Thank you, Pete. Now that Mr. Smith is engaged in carrying out Operation: Summer Palace, I have full authority over all of the Organization’s assets in his absence. Note the temporal coordinates of the event and log them into the computers for further reference. You’ll also dispatch a time probe UAV to study the new timeline and report back. We have no indication of how advanced the technology is in this new timeline, so let’s err on the side of caution and arm the probe’s self destruct mechanism.” “Understood, Mr. Needleman; will advise. Kruger out.” As soon as the transmission ends, Pete Kruger has his staff prepare a time probe UAV for launch. Next to the warsuits and stealthsuits, time probe UAVs represent Mr. Smith’s most advanced technology. Mr. Smith’s UAVs come in different shapes and sizes, according to their missions. Those intended for temporal surveillance measure just six feet long overall and are three feet wide. They move by means of four electrically powered and completely silent ducted fans; lift is provided by gravitic repulsion. The signature suppression systems are superior to those used in the stealthsuits. One of a time probe UAV’s primary missions is to gather all manner of photographic and electronic intelligence. As such, the probe is capable of wirelessly tapping into all forms of electronic communication and data storage (no matter how good the encryption might be). The recovery of a time probe UAV by forces outside the Organization would be a severe blow to security; therefore all time probes are equipped with a nuclear isomer self destruct mechanism. This device is loaded with five grams of pure Hafnium 178. When triggered, this five grams of material would release the same amount of energy as that from 3,300 lbs of TNT; the energy would be in the form of X rays and gamma rays. The probe is brought to the transit room and the computers aboard are loaded with the coordinates of the new timeline. Pete Kruger orders everyone out of the room and back to Traffic Control. He says “stand by to engage the probe’s time drive on my mark: three….two….one….MARK!!”. The temporal displacement effect quickly forms around the body of the probe and it quickly fades from view. Hello There Date: April 10th, 1986/2015 Location: 50,000’ AGL over New York City; New Timeline, designation NTL 00008 Time: 2300 hours The time probe UAV materializes in the dead of night, nearly 9.5 miles over the City of New York. The probe’s computer brain quickly establishes the precise date and commences with its survey mission. If the computer were sentient, it would not with evident satisfaction how easy it was to bypass communications encryption in this timeline. One of the computer’s subroutines dedicates a part of the sensor array to the task of environmental analysis. It is soon determined that several nuclear weapons have been recently detonated above ground; the locations of the detonations are noted, and the precise yields of the weapons involved are found by analysis of the fission by products. Next, the probe infiltrates the communications networks and databases of the U.S Government along with those belonging to private corporations all over the world. Information is gathered on the general state of technology, with special emphasis on the military. This information is compressed and stored in the probe’s memory for later transmission back to the Alpha Site. Big Trouble in Little China Date: October 18th, 1860 Location: outside the city of Siping, northern reaches of Liaoning Province Time: 12:00 PM The old principle which says ‘Good news travels fast, and bad news travels even faster’ has never been more true than today. British General Sir James Hope Grant, French General Charles Cousin Montauban and their troops are in their camp outside the city of Siping having recently engaged and dispersed several units of the Green Standard Army under the command of Zeng Guofan. Shortly before noontime, an orderly comes barging into the command tent almost out of breath. He exclaims “General Grant, sir, I have an urgent message for you from Captain Jennings at the Port of Dalian!!” Unused to such an interruption, General Grant snaps out “Steady up and catch your breath, Man.” When the orderly is able to speak clearly, he says “Sir, a dispatch rider from Dalian just came in bearing news of the fleet.” The pained expression on the orderly’s face causes General Grant to sit up and take immediate notice. He says “I am waiting to hear what you have to say, Leftenant.” “Very good, sir. The rider said that Captain Jennings had sent out a packet boat to carry your most recent messages to Admiral Sir Michael Seymour aboard HMS Calcutta. The boat put to sea and, instead of finding ships on patrol or at anchor, all that he saw was mangled wreckage and floating bodies as far as they eye could see. I have here a document with the specifics.” “WHAT?? Give that document to me right now!” The folded dispatch is handed over; General Grant opens it, reads it and exclaims “Oh, My God. The entire fleet...it’s...it’s gone.” His face assumes a ghastly pallor, as if he had seen a ghost come out of the ground right in front of him. General Grant recovers his composure and says “Orderly, was there anything else?” “Sir, the dispatch rider said that Captain Jennings had entrusted him to convey that the packet boat went further afield to see if her commanding officer could find out the source of the disaster. Nothing definitive was found, except more wreckage and bodies. He did, however spot three strange ships off in the distance towards the city of Dagu. Not wishing to endanger his command unnecessarily, the leftenant commanding ordered his vessel to put about and return to port. As soon as the boat returned, the circumstances of the disaster were conveyed to Captain Jennings. He, in turn, composed the message which you now hold.” “Very well, Leftenant. Run over to General Cousin Montauban’s tent as fast as you can go. Ask that the General and his staff come over here immediately.” The orderly braces to attention, snaps off a parade ground salute and replies “Yes, Sir!!” Next, General Grant calls for one of his subalterns and says “Leftenant, go to my bugler and have him sound ‘officers call’ immediately. On the way out, go to the officer of the day and tell him that I want all of my staff here in five minutes.” “Yes, sir.” The subaltern turns on his heels and runs out of the tent as fast as he can go. A few minutes later, the members of General Grant’s staff come filing in with their own looks of concern writ large on their faces. He says “Gentlemen, please take your seats. There has been a great disaster which struck our fleet out on the waters of the Yellow Sea. I called you all here to give you the details thereof.” One of General Grant’s cavalry officers speaks up and says “What happened, sir?” “Captain North, the fleet is gone. Every ship in both the British and French divisions thereof has been lost with all hands. A packet boat had gone out to HMS Calcutta to carry message to Admiral Seymour and found nothing but mangled wreckage and floating bodies. Captain Jennings in the city of Dalian immediately sent out a dispatch rider to let me know what happened#SYMBOL \f Symbol188” Overhead, the bugled notes of ‘Officers Call’ echo throughout the camp. Very shortly thereafter, General Cousin Montauban and his top officers come into General Grant’s tent. He says “What is the meaning of this, sir?” “Ahh, General Montauban; so good of you to join us.” General Grant proceeds to give him full details of the disaster, whereupon Montauban responds by cursing and saying “Merde Alors, the entire fleet#SYMBOL \f Symbol188gone. What could possibly have happened to cause such a calamity??” “I do not know, sir. However, this has changed the strategic outlook entirely, I believe that we should cease offensive operations against the Chinese immediately and pull all of our troops back into camp, saving only those on picket duty. We should also pull back to Dagu and encamp there. Without all those ships, we have no means of resupply of long distance transport.” “Oui, Monsieur General Grant. That is a wise precaution.” “Indeed, sir. Once we get back to Dagu, we can commandeer whatever civilian shipping is available and head back to Shanghai. Whatever else our feelings are about this disaster, we must see that our respective governments are informed.” “Oui, Monsieur General. Though I would much rather stand and fight, we know not who or what is responsible for this disaster. With your kind permission, I will return to my own command tent and order my troops back to camp.” The two general officers shake hands and salutes; then., General Montauban and his staff officers leave General Grant’s tent. After they leave, General Grant turns to his staff and says “Gentlemen, the officers of this command are assembled in their company areas. I want you all to go out among them and give them a brief appreciation of the disaster. Say also that they are to withdraw their troops back to camp and await further orders. Lastly, I want the number of pickets on the perimeter doubled at the very least. By the blessed St. George, I’ll not let whoever or whatever is responsible for this debacle to come at us without a fight.” General Grant’s officers nod their understanding, then hurry to carry out his orders. Elsewhere in China on the border between the provinces of Heibei and Shandong, Zeng Guofan and Prince Gong of the First Rank are meeting to discuss operational strategy against further depredations by the British and French Barbarians. Just then, a bannerman comes up in great haste; he kneels, kowtows and waits for permission to speak. Zeng Guofan gives the man permission to stand and bids him to speak. He says “Oh, noble Prince of the First Rank and General Zeng, I bring word of a disaster which the Heavenly Emperor and the Dragon Kings of the Four Seas have seen to visit upon the armies and ships of the Foreign Devils.” Prince Gong raises an eyebrow in curiosity and replies “Say on, fellow.” “Yes, your highness. But three days ago, the foreign devil ships which plague our shores were destroyed by dragons which came up from the sea and out of the sky. This news came from the officers commanding those elements of the Green Standard and Eight Banners army which remain in the provinces of Shandong and Liaoning.” Prince Gong claps his hands in enthusiasm and exclaims loudly “If what this man says is true, the Heavenly Emperor has blessed us. Everywhere, the armies of the foreign devils press us unceasingly. All that we have been able to do is to slow them down, and that not well at all. General Zeng, you will send your best and most reliable men to discover what happened and report back here to me. If this man speaks the truth, he will be richly rewarded; then, we will take the offensive against the foreign devils. If he speaks not the truth, he will be set to the Board of Punishments where they will show him the error of lying to a Prince of the Blood.” “Yes, Your Highness. It will be as you say.” Location: outside the City of Siping Time: 2:00 PM News of the disaster at sea has been fully communicated throughout the camp of the Anglo French expeditionary force. Everywhere, from the highest to the lowest ranks, the news is greeted with shock and horror. The British and French command staffs spend the rest of the day in pulling their outlying troops back to camp and setting up a defense against a possible ground attack. Little do they already know that the hammer has already struck massive and fatal blows. Back at the Old Summer Palace, the business of ‘salvaging’ its contents proceeds apace. All hands are involved, except for those on the perimeter security detail. In between carrying crates and boxes out to the trucks and loading them up, Mr. Smith takes the time to walk around the palace complex and see how his people are doing; one of the people he encounters is Alexander Randall. Alexander encounters Mr. Smith just as he is coming out of a storage room with a packing crate full of delicate porcelains in his arms. He says “Good afternoon, boss.” Mr. Smith replies “Hello, Alex. How are you liking your first trip into the past?” “It’s pretty slick, boss man. I will say one thing, however; the temporal displacement effect takes quite some time getting used to.” “That’s quite understandable, Alex. After all, this is only your second time jump. There will be others and before too long, you’ll get used to them.” “Thanks, boss. Being back here in the year 1860 presents some opportunities, I think. The biggest one I can think of is what is going on in the United States right now. The national conventions for the six political parties involved have already been held, and now their candidates for President and Vice President are campaigning all over the country. Given that the key factors in the outbreak of the Civil War are already in play, do you intend to intervene?” “Not directly, Alex. Our activities here in China have already muddied the water considerably. The British and French are going to be too busy replacing their lost ships to interfere on the side of the Confederacy; British shipyards certainly won’t be building any commerce raiders for the Confederate Navy, and Crappy Nappy the Third certainly won’t be invading Mexico in December, 1861.” “Boss, what about the Civil War itself? Are you going to do anything to stop it?” “Alex, the war is inevitable; there’s nothing I can do to stop it. The Northern and Southern states are too set in their ways to listen to the voice of reason. In this timeline, however, the Civil War won’t last as long as it did in the world we came from. When the war does begin, I’ll pay a visit to President Lincoln and persuade him to order the adoption of certain weapons, namely the Sharps Model 1859 2 band rifle for the infantry and the Spencer Model 1860 Carbine for the cavalry. Brigadier General James Ripley was the U.S Army’s Chief of Ordnance at the time, and will most certainly oppose this; I’ll take him out of the picture by arranging an ‘accident’.” Down Under The Sea Date: October 20th, 1860 Location: the waters of the Yellow Sea, off the coast of Qingdao Time: 1:00 PM While the LCAC crews are engaged in transporting the treasure of the Summer Palace out to SS Arcadia, Captain Roberts and the crew of the SS Glomar Explorer proceed to the location of where HMS Calcutta (flagship of the British portion of the Anglo French fleet) was sunk. The objective is to recover the treasure aboard her; namely the fleet's pay chests (which hold the sum of one million pounds sterling in gold), the indemnity extracted from the Chinese Imperial Government for payment to the governments of England and France (320,000 bars of silver weighing 50 taels each) and the gold taken from various Chinese cities during General Sir James Hope Grant's operations (40,000 bars of gold weighing 50 taels each). As soon as SS Glomar Explorer arrives on site, she drops anchor and her crew deploys remotely operated vehicles and manned submersibles to begin recovering the treasure. By consulting Mr. Smith's historical database, the ROV operators and submersible crews are able to study HMS Calcutta's plans and determine exactly where on the ship that the treasures were stored. With this information in hand, the ROVs and manned submersibles descend to the wreck site and begin cutting away those portions of the ship's hull surrounding the forward hold and the office of the ship's paymaster; this is no archaeological expedition, where the remains of the ship have to be treated with great care. Instead, it is a brute force attack using plasmacutters and shaped charge explosives; designed to accomplish as much as possible in the shortest period of time. The first part of the wreck to be serviced is the paymaster's office, which is located in the stern directly below the captain's cabin. When HMS Calcutta was still afloat, this part of the stern would have been above water and was therefore not as strongly built as the rest of the hull. The pilots of the submersibles use their machines' robotic arms to first clear away tangled rigging and broken timbers; plasmacutters are used on the rest (except for the heaviest timbers, which are cut by the use of small shaped charges. Two hours later, the interior of HMS Calcutta's stern is exposed and the pay chests are located by using multiscanners. In total, there are 65 locked iron chests each containing 50 lbs weight in gold sovereigns. In order to pay the crews of the British ships, the paymaster would have taken the gold and converted it into silver at local ports of call. The submersibles are withdrawn a short distance away, then the two ROVs (which are smaller than the submersibles) are sent into the wreck to begin taking out the chests. Each ROV can accommodate 500 lbs in its external cargo basket; due to the size and bulk of the iron pay chests, only five can be carried in the basket at any one time. As soon as the first ROV is loaded, it is brought back up to the surface to offload its precious cargo. At the same time, the second ROV is being loaded down below. Given the time needed for the ROVs to rise to the surface, offload and come back down to the shipwreck, only four trips per hour can be accomplished. Seven hours later, the last of the pay chests has been secured aboard SS Glomar Explorer; then, Captain Roberts' attention turns to HMS Calcutta's forward hold, where the bulk gold and silver bullion are stored. This part of the ship was the most strongly built (next to the powder magazine); here, the planking and framing are nearly two feet thick. The main timbers are blasted apart with larger explosive charges, while the other, smaller timbers are severed with the submersibles' plasmacutters. Due to the structural strength of the hold, most of the chests of gold and silver stored here have escaped damage; only a few have been broken open from the force of the explosions which sank the ship. The chests are only marginally less secure than the ones containing the fleet payroll, being constructed of thick, oaken boards strapped with riveted iron bands. Each chest contains 50 bars of either gold or silver bullion, for a total weight (including the bullion) of 250 lbs. There are a total of 7,200 chests so, to speed up recovery of this part of the treasure, the manned submersibles are pressed into service. By working in concert, the ROVs and manned submersibles are able to raise a total of 168 chests per hour. The crew of SS Glomar Explorer works around the clock, and the last of the treasure comes aboard two days later. Captain Roberts gets on the ship's radio and says Smith Actual, this is Captain Roberts. I have traffic for you. Teach, Smith Actual here; proceed. Boss, I'm pleased to tell you that my boys and girls have finished stripping the wreck of HMS Calcutta. We're standing by for further orders. Excellent work, Teach; my compliments to all hands. What's the take? Boss, we've got 665 tons of silver, 83 tons of gold and one million gold sovereigns. On the other end of the comm. channel, Mr. Smith whistles his appreciation and says That's quite a haul, Teach. You and the rest of my badboys and badgirls are going to get a very nice payday out of this one. In other matters, I want you to come back here and rally with the rest of us. It will be three days until the Summer Palace has been stripped of all its valuables; we've got all the hard stuff aboard SS Arcadia; now, it's the books and paintings. These are very light compared to the chests of gold, silver, gems and jewelry from the palace's strongroom, but very bulky. Understood, boss. We'll raise anchor and meet you and the rest of the squadron soonest. Roberts out. Back at the Summer Palace, Mr. Smith pauses in the midst of loading one of the trucks and switches on the cross time channel of his personal communicator. The signal goes directly through to the office of Li Chang, President of the People's Republic of China. Accounting for the relative differences in time, Mr. Smith says in fluent Mandarin Good afternoon, Mr. President, this is Mr. James Smith. President Chang replies Ahh good afternoon, Mr. Smith. It is so good to hear from you again. Thank you, Mr. President. I am pleased to be able to tell you that my recovery efforts are proceeding apace, and that they will be complete in just three days. I would like to know where and when you want the materiel from the Summer Palace to be delivered; please bear in mind that it will be coming by ship. So, any of your port cities will be suitable. Ahh, so Mr. Smith. This news gladdens my mind. For too long, my country has been denied of our rightful cultural patrimony by those long gone bastard Englishmen. Dare I ask how you managed to accomplish such a great feat? Mr. Smith chuckles politely over his communicator and says Mr. President, a wise man once said ‘Ask me no questions and I'll tell you no lies.' As for my compensation, I ask that the specified sum of money be ready for immediate wire transfer to my account in the First Commerce Bank in Lubumbashi; the raw materials I requested will be loaded aboard one of my ships after the Summer Palace materiel has been handed over. That will be eminently satisfactory, Mr. Smith. Given the historical significance of the Port of Beitang in both of those cursed ‘Opium Wars', I believe that it would be a matter of historical justice if you were to make your delivery there. My Defense Minister will want to know what vessels you are bringing. Mr. Smith replies Certainly, Mr. President. I will be coming in my personal watercraft along with two other ships. The SS Arcadia will be transporting the Summer Palace materiel, and the SS Glomar Explorer will come along to take delivery of the refined metals. Very good, Mr. Smith. I will convey that information to the Defense Minister. As for your arrival, please be in the waters off the Port of Beitang no later than two weeks from today. Of course, Mr. President. I'm nothing if not punctual. May I ask if you and your ministers will be on hand? Most certainly, Mr. Smith. Thank you, Mr. President. Mr. Smith ends the transmission and turns his attention back to helping to load the trucks. Homeward Bound Date: October 23rd, 1860 Location: Bohai Bay, three miles off the port city of Beitang Time: 9:00 AM At long last, and after truly herculean amounts of effort being expended, the last of the treasures from the Old Summer Palace have been loaded aboard SS Arcadia. Mr. Smith's team leaders and section chiefs have informed their people of his plans to share the treasure recovered from the wreck of HMS Calcutta, which news causes much rejoicing. In particular, Alexander Randall seeks out Mr. Smith to express his thanks. On the Wasp's hangar deck, Mr. Smith sees Alexander approach and says well Alex, what did you think of your first major field assignment? Boss, this job was the cat's own ass. Are they all this easy? Not at all. Some previous assignments have been extremely dangerous to all those involved. There was one instance where I sent five of my guys to Germany in 1945 to steal certain valuable property back from the Waffen SS. There was an entire company at the target, and my guys had all they could do to accomplish the mission. The crew got away with it, but in so doing, one man took a 20 mm cannon shell to the chest and almost died from his injuries. I realize that, boss man. Isn't it the name of the game, so to speak? I'd also like to thank you in advance for my split of the take. Desiree is going to be beside herself when she sees it. Of course, Mr. Randall. The bullion and coins will be yours to use as you see fit; if you wish, I'll have them converted to cash. If you decide to keep the gold, I'll tell you that President Roosevelt will be issuing his Executive Order #6102 on April 5th, 1933. This order forbade people in the United States from owning gold; the exceptions were very limited. Spending gold in any form after that date will raise more questions than I think you want to answer. I understand, boss. If it's all the same to you, I'd like to have the silver put in secure storage and the gold converted to cash. Certainly, Alex. The split will be made once we get back to Niihau Station. Now, if you'll please excuse me, there is a meeting of the senior staff that I must attend. Mr. Smith heads across the hangar deck and ascends the stairs until he reaches the ship's main conference room. In attendance are GySgt Faulkner, May Day and the commanding officers of the Wasp, the Nautilus, SS Glomar Explorer and SS Arcadia. Mr. Smith takes his seat at the head of the table and says Ladies and gentlemen, it goes without saying that Operation: Summer Palace has been a complete success. My compliments to you all for having accomplished your jobs with such skill. Before we head back to Niihau Station, I thought you'd all like to hear the total take. From the wreck of HMS Calcutta, there are 16,000,000 taels weight of silver, 2,000,000 tales weight in gold, plus an additional one million pounds sterling value in gold sovereigns. From the Summer Palace's treasure vault, there is 800 tons of silver bullion, 200 tons of gold bullion, 800 tons of silver bullion, plus 600 tons of silver coins, 150 tons of gold coins, 300 chests of jewelry and 900 caskets of unset gems. The others seated at the conference table break out in spontaneous cheers which go on unabated for a few seconds. When everyone finally quiets down, Mr. Smith goes on to say People, the contents of the Palace treasure vault are going into storage at the Alpha Site. To thank you all for a job well done, everything from HMS Calcutta will be divided among you. As there are 1,000 individuals in our august fellowship, this means that each and every person will be getting 16,000 taels of silver, 2,000 taels of gold and one thousand pounds sterling value in gold sovereigns; just to let you all know, a tael is a standard unit of Chinese weight equal to 1 1/3 ounces. This means that 16,000 taels of silver converts to 21,280 ounces and the 2,000 taels of gold converts to 2,660 ounces. The gold sovereigns from HMS Calcutta's pay chests each contain 0.235420 ounces of gold; 1,000 of these coins contains just over 235 ounces of gold; quite a tidy little sum, if I do say so myself. Captain Collins from the Nautilus speaks up and says Boss, what's the plan for now? We'll be setting course for Niihau Station at our best possible speed. When we get to a point 50 nautical miles away from the island, we'll come to a halt and make the time jump back to 1929. After that, you and your crew will stand down for maintenance and re supply. SS Glomar Explorer will offload the treasure she carries and stand by to accompany SS Arcadia when she goes to deliver the materiel from the Summer Palace to the Chinese government in 2090. I will go on ahead to the Beta Site in Rhode Island and will meet both ships at the rendezvous point with the Chinese. Once the goods have been transferred and payment has been received, we'll all go back home for some much needed rest. How does that sound? The members of Mr. Smith's staff express their enthusiasm in various ways; he gives them a few moments and then says To your stations, if you please. Let's get under way.
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/fce34bfe-aaaf-39a2-be8f-c6d22bfb6d94" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-16T13:05:34Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:11:16.829Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://otherhistory.proboards.com/thread/194/crime-time-story-thread#http://otherhistory.proboards.com/post/3637/thread" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
