<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Jollbot Though it doesn't have grasshopper legs, the Jollbot can jump like one. The spherical Jollbot, the brainchild of Rhodri Armour from the University of Bath, can roll across rugged terrain and leap over small obstacles that block its path, thanks to its springy and light skeleton. The robot relies on motors winding up and tightening springs to release and launch itself off the ground--to a height of nearly 2 feet. The Jollbot's maneuverability and durability could make it an interesting rover design for other planets, Armour says. This robot was built through printer-like rapid prototyping, in which parts are built by printing layers of plastic on top of each other to produce a 3D object. Advertisement - Continue Reading Below RoboSwift Inspired by the common swift, a bird that spends almost its entire life in flight, the RoboSwift is a highly maneuverable bird-shaped micro-aircraft. A push-rod mechanism allows the pilot to make on-the-fly adjustments to the sweep of the robot's wings; similar to the way a swift will tuck its wings when hunting insects. Although the robot is not an ornithopter (its wings do not flap), its geometric design gives it a birdlike appearance that makes the bot a hard-to-recognize spy-in-the-sky. Dr. David Lentink, who led the developing team at Wageningen University in the Netherlands, is currently studying birds in wind tunnels at Harvard and working on getting funding to integrate a GPS system and additional cameras so that the RoboSwift can soar autonomously. Robofish Researchers at the University of Washington have successfully built three robotic fish that can communicate with one another while swimming under water. The Robofish, much like its biological counterparts, relies on fins to generate motion. Approximately the size of a 10-pound salmon, the Robofish could help track drifting underwater targets, such as patches of pollution and hard-to-monitor fish. Robotic Fly Modeling a robot after a common housefly, which is about 8 mm long and lives for less than a month, is no easy task. After nearly a decade of work, however, researchers at Harvard's Microbiotics Laboratory have successfully developed a micro-robot that functions like a fly. The fly weighs 60 milligrams and has a 3-centimeter wingspan, making it an ideal machine for navigating mounds of rubble during rescue operations or for gaining access to seemingly impenetrable locations for reconnaissance work--if developers can figure out how to incorporate onboard sensors, flight controls and batteries into such a small machine. AirJelly and AquaJelly The German-based company Festo has developed two robots inspired by the undulating movements of jellyfish. The mammoth, remote-control AirJelly relies on a helium-filled ballonet to stay afloat and is powered by only two lithium-ion-polymer batteries. Festo says that the development of the AirJelly is a step toward lighter-than-air aviation. The smaller, autonomous AquaJelly is equipped with 11 infrared-light-emitting diodes, allowing it to communicate with other AquaJelly robots and a charging station from up to 80 centimeters away. What do you think? More From New Technology
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/aeb22290-d5cc-3b95-9925-f480785f8c07" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T07:40:42Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:41:25.088Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.popularmechanics.com/technology/robots/a2900/4308043/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
