<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Partners / Media Executive Sponsors Associate Sponsors Exhibitors Overview We are delighted to present the 2nd annual DPharm Europe: Disruptive Innovations to Advance Clinical Trials event.DPharm Europe takes on more global examples of disruptive ideas, examples of applying digital technologies and examples of collaborations to advance clinical trials. We are delighted to announce that Sue Collier, Head of Medical Operations for the Salford Lung Study, GSK and Christian Gossens, PhD, MBA, Global Head Early Development Workflows, pRED Informatics, Roche Pharmaceutical Research and Early Development (pRED) will co-chair the 2016 event. The co-chairs together with the speaking faculty will address: How can we drive innovation in clinical trials into everyday patient care – what are the lessons and the potential benefits to everyday clinical practice? How can we use digital innovation to enable more HCPs and patients to get involved in research on an everyday basis _ embed research as part of normal routine clinical care? What can we in the healthcare business learn from technical innovation in other areas of life – smart phones, interactive web-based systems, Facebook, Twitter etc? 2015 Keynote Discussion with Magnus Essand, Uppsala University, Alexander Masters, iCancer and Craig Lipset, Pfizer. DPharm Europe has an exciting line up of speakers doing amazing things in how we can better develop therapeutics for the benefit of the patient. We have patients inventing apps and technologies disrupting industry. We have industry disrupting how we create enabled products for product appropriateness. We have government disrupting every obstacle to reach and engage patients and caregivers directly. We have examples of new economic models to drive cures as well as insights into the future of mobile computing, wearables, sensors and so much more. St Pancras Renaissance Hotel, London, England. In the spirit of biomedical research investments to make the St Pancras / Kings Cross area of London the center for R&amp;D innovation, we are pleased to announce that DPharm Europe will be held at the St Pancras Renaissance Hotel in London, UK. Event History It was a daunting task to develop the first industry forum on thinking radically different about the way we perform clinical trials, but the result was this conference. The event was first launched in Philadelphia in September 2011 with 125 disruptive thinkers and change makers eager to discuss current solutions in clinical development, propose innovative changes, and commit to testing and sharing the results in order to transform drug development and the industry. Dr Jeff Kasher, Founder of Patients Can't Wait speaking at the 2015 event. The first DPharm event addressed virtual clinical trial models, adaptive design thinking, the role of EHRs in clinical data, open source, telemedicine, and self-reported patient data among many other ideas. By the time the 2nd annual DPharm program took place, the concept of applying disruptive thinking to clinical development had taken root, with many attendees bearing titles with clinical innovation in them. Fast forward to current day, we are looking at how new innovations will attract and retain more people in clinical trials, bring down development timelines and figure what data is really useful. Carol Maguire, UCSF engages in Q&amp;A with the presenter. With support from MedCity, the British Consulate and NIHR Clinical Research Network, we look forward to bringing more global examples of disrupting clinical trials and to collaborating on an even broader scale between industry and others. Not all innovation is disruptive. However, as a global community, we can continue to drive down the cost of drug development and provide better access to clinical trials through innovation, while greatly enhancing the patient experience. We look forward to greeting you at the St Pancras Renaissance hotel in London on February 9-10, 2016. Sincerely, Valerie Bowling Executive Director DPharm Europe Meredith Sands Executive Director, Business Development DPharm Europe Jessica Rothenberg Marketing Director DPharm Europe Elizabeth Bard Business Development Manager DPharm Europe Bridget L. Murphy Meeting Planner DPharm Europe
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/75f9fad8-7229-3840-a5d7-bd0bd90fc205" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-17T04:21:35Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:19:51.29Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://pharmalicensing.com/index.php?adclick=578" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
