<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Brain Transplantation into an Artificial Body Related Content: Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 6, 2016 Image Courtesy: link: http://motherboard.vice.com/read/a-qa-with-the-first-human-head-transplant-surgeon author: motherboard.vice.com description: ?Screengrab: ?TEDx See up to 10 related YouTube videos at end. KEY TOPICS It is a procedure distinct from head transplantation, which involves transferring the entire head to a new body, as opposed to the brain only. [1] Another similar literary theme, though different from either procedure described above, is the transplanting of a human brain into an artificial, usually robotic, body. [1] In 1970, Robert White performed the first successful brain transplantation from one rhesus monkey into the body of another. [2] The main challenge is making the brain function with artificial body parts, however there are prosthetic and bionic body parts available to amputees today, that are controlled solely by thought. [3] BOCANEGRA: The biological brain will essentially connect to artificial body parts that can be controlled by responses to brain waves. [3] Unlike biological hearts, artificial ones can pump blood throughout the body and oxygen to the brain when the rest of the body breaks down. [4] Caplan said he thinks it's much more likely that scientists will one day be able to replace the body of a person who has serious injuries with an artificial body, such as an exoskeleton. [5] HEAVEN/GEMINI is the first public facing project that has detailed the process that could make brain transplantation a reality. [2] Brain transplantation is essentially the transplantation of consciousness and memory, which is proven rudimentary and unnecessary with the development of Phoenix Biogenic?s proprietary techniques. [2] It is the progressive thinking that envisions whole brain transplantation that helps further the neuroscience industry. [2] While no further experiments have been publicized the four decades since White?s brain transplantation, the complexity of technology in the neurological realm has progressed. [2] Literal brain transplantation of an older man's brain into an attractive female body. [6] This data will be coded into multiple sensor technologies, which will be built into an artificial body with the brain of a deceased human. [7] The artificial body functions will be controlled with your thoughts by measuring brain waves. [7] When the technology is fully developed we'll implant the brain into an artificial body, Bocanegra explained to Popular Science. [7] Sure, we've worked out how to use brain waves to control things like artificial limbs, robots, and even other people's arms, but getting an isolated brain to think and control a body independently is a whole other story. [7] The mind may be transferred in various ways: via computer, some kind of psi power, the ability of an alien, physical brain transplantation, or by some other means an author has imagined. [6] Death is the one thing that's guaranteed in today's uncertain word, but now a new start-up called Humai thinks it might be able to get rid of that inconvenient problem for us too, by promising to transfer people's consciousness into a new, artificial body. [7] This is a procedure distinct from head transplantation, which involves transferring the entire head to a new body, as opposed to the brain only. [8] The first step might be to try this with spinal cord repair – brain transplantation would be the next step. [9] What you are about to observe is the reprograming of our body functions using QUANTUM COMPUTERS – (AI) Artificial Intelligence to override our brains and control us. [10] We take your original living brain and transplant it into a completely artificial machine body. [11] POSSIBLY USEFUL Putting aside the considerable technical issues involved in removing a living person?s head, grafting it to a dead body, reviving the reconstructed person and retraining their brain to use thousands of unfamiliar spinal cord nerves, the ethics are problematic. [12] Canavero believes that the spinal cord nerves that would allow the recipient?s brain to talk to the donor?s body can be fused together using a substance called polyethylene glycol. [12] According to the procedure Canavero outlined this month, doctors would first cool the patient?s head and the donor?s body so their cells do not die during the operation. [12] In 1970, Robert White led a team at Case Western Reserve University in Cleveland, U.S., that tried to transplant the head of one monkey on to the body of another. [12] The Italian doctor, who recently published a broad outline of how the surgery could be performed, told New Scientist magazine that he wanted to use body transplants to prolong the lives of people affected by terminal diseases. [12] He has claimed for years that medical science has advanced to the point that a full body transplant is plausible, but the proposal has caused raised eyebrows, horror and profound disbelief in other surgeons. [12] Despite Canavero?s enthusiasm, many surgeons and neuroscientists believe massive technical hurdles push full body transplants into the distant future. [12] The surgeons stopped short of a full spinal cord transfer, so the monkey could not move its body. [12] When they come round, Canavero believes they would be able to speak and feel their face, though he predicts they would need a year of physiotherapy before they could move the body. [12] The idea of body transplants – or head transplants, depending on the perspective – has been tried before. [12] The history of transplantation is full of cases where people hated their new appendages and had them removed. [12] The first step of Canavero's proposed procedure would be to sever the spinal cords of both a recipient (who has a diseased body but an otherwise healthy head and brain) and a donor (who would likely be a brain-dead person, with an otherwise healthy body). [5] I predict this will be more challenging than Dr. Canavero makes it out to be because scientists do not yet have an accurate method to distinguish stem cells from other cells recovered from the blood or bone marrow, which will cause the donor's body stem cells to attack the head and brain. [13] The challenges would include keeping his brain alive during the transfer, piecing together the severed spinal cords and getting them to communicate, and keeping the body from rejecting the head, to name a few. [13] In order for the preserved head to be able to communicate with and control its new body, the spinal cord and the brain must be seamlessly connected, or fused. [14] A brain transplant or whole-body transplant is a procedure in which the brain of one organism is transplanted into the body of another. [1] Most likely the brain transplant will give the body and the person that body belongs to new brain. [15] Starting with a presupposition that transplanting the head with a brain would automatically transplant the whole person with its mind, personality and consciousness, Canavero brings forth a mechanistic framework of the human person. [16] Imagine the parents of the brain dead body donor – racked by sorrow and despair for their loss – who are told that, once the new being will start reproducing, his or her offspring will actually be their (the donor's parents) descendants! Life out of death. [16] For the procedure to be practical, the age of the donated body must be sufficient: an adult brain cannot fit into a skull that has not reached its full growth, which occurs at age 9-12 years. [1] While the ultimate goal of transplanting is transfer of the brain to a new body optimized for it by genetics, proteomics, and/or other medical procedures, in uploading the brain itself moves nowhere and may even be physically destroyed or discarded; the goal is rather to duplicate the information patterns contained within the brain. [1] Robert White of Cleveland Metropolitan General Hospital transplanted the brains of six dogs into the necks of other dogs, to show that the brains could be kept alive in another body. [13] I myself created a supernumerary phantom arm in the course of motor cortex stimulation for chronic pain, by altering brain plasticity! In the field of IVR, the rubber hand illusion shows that a rubber arm can be incorporated into what feels as if it is part of the body, the shrinking waist illusion can give the strong sensation of the waist radically reducing (or expanding) in size, and the Pinocchio illusion that the nose has grown very long. [16] It houses not just your brain but your eyes, ears, nose, mouth, and skin, as well as two separate gland systems: the pituitary, which controls the hormones that circulate throughout the body, and the salivary, which are responsible for producing saliva. [14] In one episode of Star Trek, Spock's Brain is stolen and installed in a large computer-like structure; and in  I, Mudd  Uhura is offered immortality in an android body. [1] To date, they can transplant almost every major organ of the body, like the heart, liver, lungs, kidneys, pancreas, and intestine, but not the head. [17] A Russian man named Valery Spiridonov, who suffers from a muscle wasting disease, will appear on stage with Dr. Canavero as he details his plan to transplant Spiridonov's head onto the body of a healthy donor as soon as 2017. [18] The difference that I noticed between Dr. Whites and Dr. Canavero's procedures is; Dr. White appears to have transferred both blood and the head to the recipients body, while Dr. Canavero drain's the blood from the head first. [13] No attempt was made to join the spinal cord of the transplanted head onto the host body, so the monkey was paralysed from the neck down and required artificial assistance in order to breathe. [19] In a 1970s experiment that would never be allowed today, neurosurgeon Robert White transplanted the head of a monkey onto the body of a donor monkey. [14] Robert White transplants the entire head of a rhesus monkey onto another monkey's body. [13] In 1970, Robert White and his team transplanted the head of a monkey on to the body of another monkey. [17] A team led by Robert White at Case Western Reserve University School of Medicine in Cleveland, Ohio, transplanted the head of one monkey onto the body of another. [18] Or Doctor Robert White, who transplanted the head of one monkey on to the body of another in 1970 (the same warning applies). [19] What of the Identity issue? I don't think transplanting a head to another body will not create an identity crisis? This will amount to a whole new territory for human race. [13] In case you haven?t heard, a doctor in Italy has announced plans to transplant a guy's head onto a new body two years from now. [13] Tired of hearing head transplant Its technically a body transplant. [13] Is it OK to use an entire body to save one person, when the organs could save many? Will we pay for it? Would you, if you could save your husband or wife?s head? (Answer that one carefully.) [13] The idea behind the operation is that it could theoretically extend the life of a person whose body is gravely damaged or diseased by putting his or her head onto the body of a deceased donor. [5] The head in question is that of Valery Spiridonov, a 30-year-old Russian computer programmer who stepped forward in April as a volunteer; the body would come from a brain-dead donor. [13] For the first surgery, the plan is this: Take two people (one with a living head but a disabled body, the other braindead but with a healthy body), chop their heads off at the exact same time, place the healthy head on the healthy body, glue them together with a substance called Poly-ethylene glycol, and wait. [20] He calls it a Gemini spinal cord fusion protocol, which will be used to perform a Cephalosomatic anastomosis, the surgical transference of a healthy head on a surgically beheaded body under deep hypothermic conditions, he ?explained in a paper published in February. [20] The surgeon said he plans to achieve this feat by joining the spinal cords of the severed head and new body. [5] In the 1930s and 40s, some experimental surgeons have used this material, which is a type of plastic, to fuse the spinal cords of dogs, but these experiments typically involved attaching a foreign head to the complete body of a dog (artificially giving it two heads), not replacing one dog's head with that of another. [14] Working swiftly, the surgeons would have to reattach the head of the person they want to keep alive to the circulatory system of the donor's body while both bodies are under total cardiac arrest. [14] You'd have to use one hell of a lot of drugs and immunosuppressants to stop the body rejecting the head, even if the surgery does go well. [13] You have an otherwise perfectly healthy head on a body that no longer functions. [19] No, you're not going to be able to have your head stitched onto another person's body any time soon. [14] In any transplant, the donor organ (the one that's been taken from a donor's body) has to be kept alive until it can be placed into the recipient's body. [14] As with any transplant, one of the main issues facing patients is that of their own body: If the immune system flags the foreign organ (or organs, in this case) as foreign, it can unleash a full-scale attack. [14] Therefore, the person will encounter huge difficulties to incorporate the new body in its already existing body schema and body image that would have strong implications on human identity. [16] Lestat demands that the procedure be used on him to allow him to be human once again, but soon finds that he has made an error and is forced to recapture James in his vampiric form so he can take his body back. [1] Shelley's Victor Frankenstein created the Monster by sewing together body parts from human corpses. [17] Despite his vision, modern cognitive science shows that our cognition is an embodied cognition, in which the body is a real part in the formation of human self. [16] They want to decorporalize humans, which, I don?t oppose that, but I want to stay in a body. [20] The AVATAR initiative is confident that they can transplant a brain inside a cyborg within 10 years: It is called the plasticity principle that together with the relativistic brain hypothesis will allow humans to transcend biology within our lifetime. [16] Dr. Canavero has named his human head transplant project HEAVEN. A person who is possibly suffering from an incurable and debilitating medical condition but has a healthy and functioning head and brain will be the recipient. [17] In 1998, a team of surgeons from the University of Pittsburgh Medical Center attempted to transplant a group of brain cells to Alma Cerasini, who had suffered a severe stroke that caused the loss of mobility in her right limbs as well as limited speech. [1] Scientists in Japan graft infant rats? heads onto the thighs of adults, to test cooling the brain to prevent brain damage with oxygen loss. [13] The brain is not the mind or being of a person it is just an organ. [15] Unlike single organ transplants, a head transplant is a composite tissue allotransplantation (CTA) consisting of skin, muscle, tendons, bone, cartilage, fat, nerves, and blood vessels – and of course the brain. [16] As your brain matures, genetic engineering will help fight the aging process, while advancements in nanotechnology will offer extensive tissue repair and regeneration, including the repair of individual brain cells, one molecule at a time. [15] A study using a monkey as a subject shows that it is possible to directly use commands from the brain, bypass the spinal cord and enable hand function. [1] Misalignment – which is inevitable – will be offset by rewiring in the cord upstream and in the brain (as occurs in spinal cord injury cases that recover function). [16] Injecting stem cells or olfactory ensheathing cells – self-regenerating cells that connect the lining of the nose to the brain – into the spinal cord, or creating a bridge over the spinal gap using stomach membranes have shown promise in helping people walk again after spinal injury. [18] We want to transplant your brain into an elegantly designed bionic body called Humai. [15] The whole-body transplant is just one of several means of putting a consciousness into a new body that have been explored by both scientists and writers. [1] As mentioned, failure of the first-hand transplant followed poor integration of the transplanted hand into the patient's own body image. [16] Canavero said he has dreamed of doing a head transplant since he was 15, when he read a newspaper article about Dr. Robert White, an American surgeon who transplanted the head of one monkey onto another monkey's body in 1970. [5] Once I attach a new body, I fully expect the head and body to adapt to each other, he said. [5] My gut feeling (sic) is that the body will reject it's new head on the grounds of ethics, independence and on principle! Character incompatibility may also play a roll. [13] There were jokes about Ted Williams? head, currently frozen in Arizona and awaiting a new body. [13] The major obstacle to HEAVEN is the possibility of immune rejection of the head by the new body. [16] The recent renewed effort toward achievement of the arguably most ambitious medical enterprise ever – reconnecting a head to a body – has sparked a global controversy of biblical proportion, reaching tones bordering on fanaticism – not to mention slander. [16] A person who has been declared brain-dead but still has a healthy body will be the donor. [17] The goal is to eventually allow you to grow a clone body of yourself that you can then use to keep yourself physically young forever, by getting recurring head transplants onto donor bodies grown from your own genetic material (how you?ll keep your brain–and face–young during all of this is an unanswered question). [20] The fact that the gonads belong to the body donor is actually a facilitator for the whole enterprise. [16] That?s not long, but by keeping the donor body?s brainstem, the body is able to continue to control its own heartbeat and breathing. [13] Even memories of the role the former body played in the creation of the subjects identity would encounter possible conflict with a new donor given body, because the identity would reflect itself in the corporeality that does not exist anymore. [16] Theoretically, a person with advanced organ failure could be given a new and functional body while keeping their own personality and memories. [1] Even from the crippled recipient's body, some organs might be salvageable to help other lives. [16] As soon as an organ gets removed from a body, it begins to die. [14] Several people have volunteered to get a new body, according to Canavero. [18] What would we make of it if someone did go there? It might well be impossible to deliver what the public might expect: a person who walks around perfectly normal except for their mismatched body. [13] In a sense, this allows him to return to life after the Battle of Endor, as well as other events where his current body dies. [1] You, me, well, hopefully me, will be able to get a new body. [20] There is a line of thought (sic) that the gut plays a large part in determinig the body functions and indeed, reactions. [13] It's the heaviest and one of the most complex parts of the body. [14] To bring fresh ends of the divided spinal cord together, we resected enough vertebral body and thus shortened the spine. [16] Both decapitations would be done under hypothermic conditions (i.e., with the body temperatures lowered), in order to preserve the tissue during the time when it is not connected to a circulatory system, he said. [5] This Light is as present about us as is the air we breathe, yet, unlike the air that sustains life in the body, must come down - be drawn down by desire and effort - from above, heaven. [15] Do you want to transplant human heads onto artificial bodies? Is that where this is heading in say, 100 years? ? There?s a mistake there. [20] Can a neurosurgeon replace the brain with an artificial one? The answer is clearly no. [13] Since there is no movement of the brain(s), however, this is not quite the same as a whole-body transplant. [1] In 1982 Dr. Dorothy T. Krieger, chief of endocrinology at Mount Sinai Medical Center in New York City, achieved success with a partial brain transplant in mice. [1] Brain transplants and similar concepts have been explored in various forms of fiction. [1] Historically, brain transplants have not been feasible and were widely regarded as improbable if not impossible. [1] The brain is an immunologically privileged organ, so rejection would not be a problem. (When other organs are transplanted, aggressive rejection can occur; this is a major difficulty with kidney and liver transplants.) [1] There is what we are going to do with clones, and then there are others who will have transplanted their brains into cyborgs. [20] A similar procedure often found in science fiction is the transfer of one consciousness to another without moving the brain. [1] Such a long coma is a potential problem as well, University of California, Davis professor of neurosurgery Harry Goldsmith told Popular Science, because medically induced comas often result in infection, blood clots, and reduced brain activity. [14] The resulting loss of fresh blood and oxygen pushes the brain into a coma, soon followed by death. [14] Brain surgeons are typically assumed to be highly intelligent and educated; this one is an idiot. [13] A vascular surgeon of the brain, yes, but he knows nothing. [20] My problem with the cyborg thing is simple: How can you imagine spending 100-200 years, a brain inside a machine, doing what? I propose, it may sound crazy, but there?s a way to enhance your brain to have hyper hedonistic features. [20] Like what you read? Give to Brain Blogger sponsored by GNIF with a tax-deductible donation. [17] Just the other day there was an article in The Seattle Times that a new type of flexible brain implant could enable the paralyzed to walk again. [15] BRAIN ABSCESS IT8 SUBOIGAL PATHOLOGY AND OPERATIVE TEOHNIO BY WELLS P. EAGL. from those encountered in the treatment of non-suppurative lesions of the brain. [1] Classic Literature Collection World Public Library.org Title: BRAIN ABSCESS Author: WELLS P. EAGLETON Language: English Subject: Fiction. piece. [1] Finally the day has come when the brains of brilliant men can be kept alive in the bodies of dumb people. [13] In a paper published in Surgical Neurology International, he has outlined his technique: first, both the transplant head and the donor body would need to be cooled in order to slow cell death. [19] In an editorial in Surgical Neurology International, Canavero proposes cooling the head and donor body to limit cell damage from oxygen loss, and fusing the spinal cord with a process called GEMINI, which uses PEG and electrical stimulation, which has been shown in other studies to promote spinal cord repair. [13] Dr. Canavero's strategy involves cooling Spiridonov's head and the donor body to extend the time their cells can survive without oxygen, the New Scientist article states, citing the scientific journal Surgical Neurology International. [18] Spiridonov's head is then moved onto the donor body and the two ends of the spinal cord – which resemble two densely packed bundles of spaghetti – are fused together. [18] This procedure encounters some social and ethical problems facing organ donations: on one hand because of uncertainty of the procedure, the donor body with it's organs would be wracking the organs that could be useful to someone else that needs a heart or liver that could save his/her life. [16] It is infinitely more complex than the human heart which can be replaced with an artificial pump. [13] We have robotic prostheses, humanoid robots, artificial human skin, and a range of nanotechnology applications used in medicine and the military that are quickly redefining life and nature itself. [15] Canavero S. HEAVEN: The head anastomosis venture Project outline for the first human head transplantation with spinal linkage (GEMINI) Surg Neurol Int. 2013; 4 :S335-42. [16] The challenge in human head transplantation is to minimize the scar area when severing the spinal cords. [17] No head transplantation experiment in monkeys or humans has been attempted since. [17] There is also no doubt that the possibility of successful human head transplantation will create serious concerns in many quarters. [17] Dr. Sergio Canavero is scheduled to deliver the keynote lecture on the subject on Friday at the American Academy of Neurological and Orthopaedic Surgeons in Annapolis, Md., in a speech, titled, Head Transplantation: The Future Is Now. [18] The removal of the head and the transplantation was carried out simultaneously. [17] Tabakow P, Raisman G, Fortuna W, Czyz M, Huber J, Li D, et al. Functional regeneration of supraspinal connections in a patient with transected spinal cord following transplantation of bulbar olfactory ensheathing cells with peripheral nerve bridging. [16] Suturing a transplant of fascia lata into the dural defect makes an excellent cerebral. y, the immediate death of cerebral tissue from trauma, associated with the transplantation of micro-organisms in unprepared cerebral tissue, furnishes. t in position. [1] Chronic rejection has been observed for hand transplants, but not for facial transplantation. [16] The human brain is far too complex in its architecture and chemistry to facilitate transplantation. [13] Nothing stated above is not already a success in the laboratory, or being worked on extensively under multi-billion dollar government projects like the U.S. BRAIN Initiative, or the European Human Brain Project. [15] People are already working on interfacing human brains and machines. [13] He would then fuse the recipient head and donor body together, essentially giving the head a new body to control and inhabit. [5] In any event, it will be the donor body that rejects the head, not the other way around. [16] Each individual tissue possesses a different degree of antigenicity: The skin, being the most antigenic organ in the human body, elicits a strong immune response when recognized as foreign tissue. [16] Your Humai will use a brain-computer interface to communicate with the sensory organs and limbs of your bionic body. [15] Since that time, experimentation with head transplants has been minimal, but Dr Canavero believes that our knowledge of surgery techniques and how the human body works has caught up. [19] Dr. Canavero believes that inducing hypothermia during the transplantation procedure and using sharp severing instruments and specialized healing agents will help him overcome many of the challenges inherent in the procedure. [17] We read with interest and some perplexity the article by the Italian surgeon, Sergio Canavero, on the subject of head transplantation commonly known as HEAVEN surgery shorthand for its more full name, 'head anastomosis venture' and GEMINI spinal cord fusion (SCF) procedure. [16] To follow the latest on Canavero's proposal, I?ll be at the American Academy of Neurological and Orthopedic Surgeons meeting in Annapolis this June when he gives a keynote address on head transplantation. [13] Before head transplantation moves into trials in people, all of these problems have to be addressed in animal trials. [14] Advances in artificial organs (e.g., artificial heart) will also help allay similar misgivings. [16] Artificial intelligence will be integrated into synthetic organs, so they can operate independently. [15] Similar in many ways to this is the idea of mind uploading, promoted by Marvin Minsky and others with a mechanistic view of natural intelligence and an optimistic outlook regarding artificial intelligence. [1] There are a lot of outrageous claims being made within the halls of neuroscience and artificial intelligence. [15] That's all without even taking into account the ethical considerations: in order to have the best chance of success, the donor body has to be still technically living. [19] Incredibly, doctors rebooted Williams? heart - but for three days, he was in an induced coma, his body packed in ice to minimize brain damage. [4] Elderly billionaire Johann Sebastian Bach Smith is being kept alive through medical support and decides to have his brain transplanted into a new body. [21] Planarians are simple flatworms with the extraordinary ability to regenerate lost body parts, even being able to regrow their brain and nervous system. [2] We now know that it is possible to shed the physical body and brain while being able to keep consciousness, we also now know that the body is central to our true existence. [2] Once there, her body starts to reject her (Smith's) transplanted brain. [21] If successful, the brain recipient would wake up in a new body and after physiotherapy be able to function as normal. [2] Risks? ? uh ? insanity caused by a whole new set of chemicals rushing into your brain from a stranger?s body ? and, well, catastrophic biological failure, AKA - death. [22] The science for transplanting a brain to any body is close but still has a few challenges. [3] Insisting that HEAVEN will work, Dr Canavero says that both the donor – somebody who is brain-dead but whose body remains healthy – and Spiridonov would have their heads cut off from their spinal cords at exactly the same time. [23] Dr. Canavero pointed out a near similar case when another surgeon, Dr. Robert White effectively transplanted a monkey's head onto another monkey's body at the Case Western Reserve University School of Medicine in 1970. [23] A team led by Robert White at Case Western Reserve University School of Medicine in Cleveland, Ohio, transplanted the head of one monkey onto the body of another. [22] The big question we have here at The Big Science Blog (spoken through an echo chamber by a baritone) is whether the procedure should be called a head transplant or a body transplant. [22] We discuss scientists? effort to create bioartificial hearts using stem cells, full body transplants, and bioengineers? quest to develop a continuous flow device, which are small, implantable turbine-like pumps that send blood through the body at a steady stream, much like a hose or faucet. [4] De La Cruz needed a new heart, but her small body and high level of antibodies made her an unlikely transplant candidate. [4] How can you say it?s irreversible, when the circulatory function is restored in a different body? We tend to overlook that because we want to transplant these organs, says Truog. [24] Sometimes the patient?s body rejects the transplant - a painful process where the immune system attacks and kills the foreign organ. [4] The Jarvik?s design was simple: two man-made ventricles, connected to an external air pump, expand and contract the artificial organ, propelling blood throughout the body - much like Williams? artificial heart today. [4] Living with an artificial heart has its downsides: Williams is constantly accompanied by a caretaker, typically his wife, in case the device malfunctions; he is forever connected to a battery or plugged into a power outlet; the large doses of blood thinners he takes make his body run cold; and he can?t submerge himself in water. [4] They didn?t attempt to join the spinal cords, though, so the monkey couldn?t move its body, but it was able to breathe with artificial assistance. [22] As technology grows ever complex there will be an eventual necessity for political candidates to be knowledgeable enough to present their opinion on concepts like artificial intelligence, technological body modification, virtual economies, genetic manipulation and life extension. [2] The patient, with his new body, will be put into a coma for four weeks for the head and body to heal. [23] The donor heart first has to be methodically extracted from a very recently deceased body, transported hundreds, sometimes thousands of miles on ice, and installed in an entirely foreign vessel. [4] Doctors say it may extend the time a heart can last outside the body and is letting them recover hearts from donors who haven?t been eligible before. [24] Taking a living heart from one person?s body and putting it into another person is a high-risk procedure with ample room for error. [4] A donated heart beats outside the body while being supplied with blood and oxygen. [24] The proposal was harrowing: his chest cavity would be cracked, critical arteries severed, and the heart he?d lived with for 53 years pulled out of his body. [4] In the fundamental human ideal of self-preservation we have attempted and been able to slow and delay the death of the body, but we have yet to stop it. [2] If we can build this bionic body that connects to the brain soon enough, you can essentially move out of your biological body so you don't have to deal with the consequence of the natural human biological process; aging, disease, sickness etc. [3] He said that if his company can preserve the brain before its human body dies, and then transplant it into a bionic body, then it can achieve a point where no one has to die at all. [25] We want to physically transplant the brain to a thought-controlled bionic body. [3] Wait, there's more: the Humai will also use genetic engineering to fight the aging process as the brain itself (the only part of you still human) matures, including the use of nanotechnology that offers extensive tissue repair and regeneration one molecule at a time. [26] Jake has a massive rupture of a large blood vessel in his brain and dies but his personality is saved and joins Smith and Eunice in Joanne's head. [21] He has a mechanical heart that, while burdensome, keeps blood pumping to his organs and oxygen to his brain. [4] People can be brain dead, or they die because the heart and blood flow stop. The latter is what they now call circulatory death. [24] Following cessation of circulation, his team has waited five minutes, then quickly clamped off the blood supply to the brain and restarted the donor?s heart without removing it. [24] This way the team effectively turns a circulatory death into a brain dead beating heart donor. [24] After several weeks of training scientists decapitated the flatworms, the bodies were then isolated and left to allow the head, brain and nervous system to regrow. [2] She ends up brain dead, supposedly, and his brain ends up being implanted into her (first transplant of this kind). [21] The brain may also be compared to a computer; the consciousness would serve as the software and neural biological systems would serve as the hardware. [2] We have already recreated the brain, a perfect computer unto itself, through completely biological and not digital means. [2] I don't know the answer to the question, but science is learning that our brains aren't the only part of our nervous system that contains the mind whatever that actually might be. [21] On a snowy day in March of 1982, after multiple organs failed, Clark experienced brain death. [4] Brain regrowth, memory retention and cell regeneration are the key takeaways from the experiment, these things provide a great deal of insight and may open up further studies in a more complex species. [2] I?ve had patients where the liver and kidney failed, the skin turned yellow and died, and the only thing working normally was the brain, Arabia says. [4] Oxford University?s whole brain emulation roadmap is an accurate and fairly simple look into how we may achieve WBE, as well as the benefits and complications that come with it. [2] Think of the brain as giving commands and sending signals that tell your bionic body what to do and how to move. [3] I think our mission can be widely misunderstood by some, but really all we?re doing is transplanting the brain to a bionic body. [3] Founder Josh Bocanegra isn't as keen on creating brain popsicles though as he is on his preferred methodology: transplanting a live person?s brain into a bionic body as it would achieve a point where no one has to die at all. [26] I guess they write that because body transplant is too non-specific. [22] Her operation, though, didn?t go as smoothly as Williams?: De La Cruz?s body rejected the new organ and she went into kidney failure. [4] A technology to keep organs alive outside the body is saving lives. [24] Smith omits to place any restriction on the sex of the donor, so when his beautiful young female secretary, Eunice Branca, is murdered, her body is used. [21] This doesn?t only take from your body, it takes from your mind, spirit, and soul. [4] His liver was congested, fluid reappeared in his lungs, and his heart?s right and left ventricles were practically destroyed, making it hard for blood to circulate throughout his body. [4] He advertises an offer of a million dollars for the donation of a body from a brain-dead patient. [21] While consciousness transference has become an amazing development, it comes at the expense of the individual?s original body. [2] These can be cooled down inside the body, then stopped, removed, and shipped at near 4 C. Cold temperatures cut the tissue?s metabolic rate by about 90 percent, creating time to reach the recipient. [24] Developments that fully allow us to prevent the deterioration, disease and death of the body would be culmination of life extension technology. [2] Key to the planarian?s regenerative capabilities are the abundance of adult pluripotent stem cells, which have the ability to become any cell in their body. [2] Valery Spiridonov, a terminally ill Russian who has a rare medical condition called Werdnig-Hoffman disease, has volunteered to undergo a procedure dubbed HEAVEN and be the first patient to have his head transplanted onto another healthy human body. [23] We?re not 100% sure what year exactly we will begin human trials, but what we do know is we?d be running multiple animal trials before the first human brain transplant into a bionic body. [3] Humai, Inc. is developing technology that will allow human brains to be transplanted into a bionic body. [26] We plan to implement these breakthroughs as we work towards performing the first surgical procedure of restoring and implanting a human brain to a new bionic body. [25] This was the first step, opening up a new area of scientific discovery concentrated on creating a map of the human brain and its connections. [2] As a species we are doing ourselves a disservice by replicating consciousness digitally when we have available the perfect computer, the human brain, and the technology to transfer consciousness. [2] Whole brain emulation, or WBE, is modeling the function of the human brain perfectly through digital methods. [2] Seung believes that a complete map of the human brain would help us capture human memory, skill and emotion as well as determine why certain mental disorders exist. [2] An entrepreneur says his new artificial intelligence company will be able to resurrect the dead by 2045 by preserving human brains before their owners die. [25] Artificial intelligence will be integrated into the organs so they can be operated independently, with sensor technology allowing the user to feel the essence of the human experience. [26] It has a simple design: a pair of fist-sized artificial ventricles that attach to the atria, the heart?s blood collection chambers; the aorta, the body?s largest artery; and the pulmonary artery, which connects the heart and lungs. [4] While the device was impractical as a permanent replacement for the heart, a young heart surgeon from Arizona named Jack Copeland saw the potential to use artificial hearts as a bridge to transplant. [4] Patients like De La Cruz, who are out of options, often end up at Cedars-Sinai; the plush medical center adjacent to Beverly Hills performs more total artificial heart transplants than anywhere else in the country. [4] Now, the company is preparing to leap forward: pending FDA approval, it plans to offer its total artificial heart - the same model De La Cruz and Williams have - as a permanent implant for patients in the U.S. If approved, the device will become available to a wider set of patients, including those not eligible for biological transplants. [4] Soon thereafter, the CardioWest device became the first and only FDA-approved artificial heart for a bridge to transplant. [4] Almost two-thirds of SynCardia total artificial heart recipients can get out of bed and walk two weeks after surgery, and the majority survive long enough to get a transplant. [4] Williams? best shot at survival was to have his heart almost completely removed and replaced with a total artificial heart - a synthetic machine that stands in for a living, beating organ. [4] At 1:30 the following morning, Williams had his artificial heart removed, was placed on a heart-lung bypass machine, and had a stranger?s biological organ installed in him. [4] Williams would be among a handful of patients who receive artificial hearts every year. [4] Living with an artificial heart is also hard on patients, and once the surgery begins, it?s irreversible. [4] Fewer than 2,000 patients have received an entirely artificial heart in the device's three decades of existence, and most patients haven?t used the machines for long. [4] I?m just in shock still: I can?t believe I don?t have the artificial heart; I can?t believe there?s no noise; I can?t believe I don?t have to take the blood thinners, he said a few weeks after the operation. [4] In 1988, after nearly a quarter of a billion dollars, the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute pulled funding from the Artificial Heart Program. [4] The proposal intrigued Congress, which funneled hundreds of thousands of dollars into the newly created Artificial Heart Program at the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute. [4] If it stopped beating 30 years into the future, he might have a permanent and non-intrusive artificial heart. [4] His artificial heart, which beat nearly 13 million times over 112 days, was shut down. [4] In the 1960s, scientists promised to develop a total artificial heart by the end of the decade, to cure end-stage biventricular heart failure. [4] Of the 81 people in the trial, 17 died after the artificial heart was installed. [4] A Russian suffering from Werdnig-Hoffman disorder, an incurable disease causing muscle atrophy, has volunteered for and been accepted to have his head removed from his troubled body and patched onto a donor body. [22] Can a copy of our consciousness really be considered a person? Can living within a computer or mechanical facsimile be considered living? At Phoenix Biogenic we argue that living is truly constituted by the sense of self within the human body. [2] Because of this radical experiment, the surgeon is now being branded as a real-life Victor Frankenstein, the fictional scientist who assembled different parts of the human body to recreate dastardly creatures. [23] The company claims that the Humai (the name of the bionic body as well as that of the company) will use a brain-computer interface to communicate with the sensory organs and limbs within the bionic body. [26] Similar to organ transplantation, rejection is a real risk. [2] There?s no doubt life is not the same with, but the human body can adjust to incredible things. [4] Many scientists studying the prospect of immortality are looking for ways to prevent physical decay of the body, but a lot of futurists now believe that the key to extending human life is in the brain. [27] Unable to repair his body, his brain was transplanted into a robotic body. [28] Brain Drain considered himself a failure but the Master of the World saw great potential and recruited Brain Drain to be a member of his new Omega Flight, where he contained a robotic body. [28] AI technologies used for brain mapping and mind uploading fragment the person?s consciousness energy, which is supposed to be directed by the spiritual bodies, and is inherent in the organic design of the original human DNA. Each copy of the original consciousness content that is synthetically AI generated, such as a clone, interconnects into the larger artificial intelligence networks that are generated by alien machinery. [27] If we froze and recovered a brain, the brain would still need sleep, but if we?re talking about the ability to implement human consciousness into unknown biological substrate, like a computer through cryogenics or another method then, presumably sleep might not be necessary. [27] Enhance human capabilities Can we become competitive? Upload information to our brains like we do to computers, via advances in genetic engineering? Unlikely. [27] Googling for futuristic factoids, I happened upon many articles about mind uploading, brain computer interfaces, and cybernetic pedagogies that may one day allow lazy humans to download knowledge and skill sets into their brains. [27] In this episode, he speaks to us about why uploading human identity in a computer substrate might be possible in the coming decades, and the type of progress we?re making today in the areas of computing and mapping the brain. [27] The lead story in this post is about mice being made smarter by having human cells implanted into their brains. [27] In the longer term, the innovation could even be used to make a human bionic brain, by co-injecting mesh electronics with cells into host systems for unique engineering and biomedical applications,? the study said. [27] These cells took over, to the point where almost all the glial cells in the mouse's brain were human in origin and they had a measurable effect. [27] Science is closer to achieving brain cloning over mind transfer from human to human. [27] Now with control over his destiny, Brain Drain enrolled in the Empire State University with a disguise to his his evident unusual features and appear to be a normal human. [28] Presumably, your wiring diagram in combination with the dynamics of activity that define you would find it to be a bumpy ride into a new electronic brain, perhaps more so than a revived, once-vitrified human. [27] This mesh of electrodes can unfold once in position and has so far been used to monitor brain activity in mice suggesting it may be capable of similar feats in humans one day. [27] Unlike relatively simple tissues such as bones and skin, to give a heart, the donor must be declared brain dead and the family must consent. [29] Shortly after, Brain Drain's head casing was trapped under a mountain of snow in Switzerland through unknown means. [28] Brain Drain was later shot in the head with an armor piercing bullet by Dominic Fortune, but was not arrested because ICON technically didn't exist. [28] The procedure is expected to last up to 36 hours, and it will require Spiridonov?s head be cooled as well as the donor?s body to extend the period during which the cells can survive without oxygen, CEN reported. [30] If you're hung up on the complexity of the human mind and can't get over just how something so complex can be transferred into another body or machine or alien being. [6] Many scientists believe that the human brain and mind define who we are, based solely on their information pattern, while the body or hardware that information is implemented upon is secondary or interchangeable. [27] Stephen Hawking voiced his belief in the possibility of one day copying the human brain to a computer to retain a digital version of it after the body dies. [27] V. WORKING OF NATURAL BRAIN A. Getting to know more about Human Brain The brain essentially serves as the body?s information processing centre. [27] @Gadgeteer honestly i'd want a genetically modified/improved clone of my own body. that's assuming they will learn how to grow a clone body without the head, for ethical reasons. [31] At Troupe?s tenth birthday celebration, while he skated with his friends, chatted up his family, and scarfed pizza, the heart of another child pumped blood into his lungs, through his body, and back again. [29] To carry out the transplant, a state of hypothermia is first induced in both the head to be transplanted and the donor body, to help the cells stay alive without oxygen. Surgeons would then cut into the neck tissue of both bodies and connect the blood vessels with tubes. [31] Surely the ability to transplant an identity from one body to another or from a body to a machine will have an impact on the nature of identity. [6] If you find the idea that the mind is quantifiable upsetting–transferring a person's mind to a computer or through a computer into another body means the mind must first be quantified, and that can be an upsetting thought. [6] The transference of a mind into another body, a computer, a mechanical object, or an alien body is a popular theme in Science Fiction. [6] The spinal cords, however, were not connected to each other, leaving the monkey unable to control its body. [31] Like, do you really want to give up your body and live as a spaceship? Do you want to live as an AI with the possibility of being hacked or edited? Surely this is an idea-rich sub-genre full of questions fit for exploration. [6] We?re using artificial intelligence and nanotechnology to store data of conversational styles, behavioral patterns, thought processes and information about how your body functions from the inside-out. [7] An artificial heart is a prosthetic device that is implanted into the body to replace the original biological heart. [32] Here are just a few body parts that can be grown in the lab. [33] Although it's a nice idea, for now Y (still) OLO, and that life ends when your body does. [7] There can be no such thing as a head transplant – it's a body transplant. [31] Transplanting a human head onto a donor body may sound like the stuff of science fiction comics, but not to Italian doctor Sergio Canavero. [31] The severed head would then be placed on the donor body and the two spinal cords encouraged to fuse together with a sealant called polyethylene glycol, which Canavero notes in his paper, has the power to literally fuse together severed axons or seal injured leaky neurons. [31] Dr Goertzel believes that in the future we could use whole brain emulation or mind uploading to store our minds, memories and personality into a computer device. [27] As the brain ages we'll use nanotechnology to repair and improve cells. [7] The possibility of uploading the inner workings of your brain to a computer and living immortally in an avatar might just be a few decades away. [27] With the help of her friend Nancy Whitehead and their knowledge in computer science, Squirrel Girl repaired Brain Drain, removing the old processors that didn't let him change his ways. [28] Brain Drain made two behind-the-scenes appearances in Giant-Size Invaders #1 and Invaders #1, but his first actual appearance wasn't until Invaders #2. [28] Brain Drain was a Nazi scientist during World War II who helped create Master Man. [28] In 2013, scientists from the Institute of Molecular Biotechnology in Vienna, Austria announced they had successfully created a miniature brain in the lab. [33] When a story deals with minds, brains, and identities to the extent that this sub-genre does, characterization is pretty important. [6] The cerebral organoid didn?t look exactly like a real brain, but it had active neurons and had much the same organizational structure. [33] Basically, what these scientists want to do is to incrementally move the human mind into more disembodied andno better way to say itfuturistic vehicles: first a humanoid robot controlled entirely by a human brain via brain-machine interface, then a conscious human brain transplanted into a humanoid robot, then consciousness uploaded to a computer, and finally a hologram that contains a full conscious human mind. [27] It is possible by using a super computer, with a huge amount of storage capacity, processing power and an interface between the human brain and artificial one. [27] The goal of mind uploading is to recreate whole brain emulation, which has the ability to transfer the data from a human brain to a computational device, such as a digital, analog, quantum-based or software-based artificial neural network. [27] Scientists have become adept at harnessing human and animal cells to grow artificial versions of complex tissues, including entire limbs. [33] Feb. 25, 2008 – A method to create an artificial heart using the extracellular matrix of an actual heart that has been stripped of all cells may hold promise for its use in transplant surgery. [32] The obvious benefit of a functional artificial heart would be to lower the need for heart transplants, because the demand for donor hearts greatly exceeds supply. [32] Mar. 27, 2014 – The largest single-center study of patients implanted with a total artificial heart finds the device may help patients in severe heart failure survive until they can receive a heart transplant. [32] July 1, 2015 – A 44-year-old woman has received a successful heart transplant, thanks to an experimental Total Artificial Heart designed for smaller patients. [32] Jan. 12, 2015 – Wearable technology allows 24-year-old with a total artificial heart to wait at home for a heart transplant. [32] Well, that is, we put our faith in the Australian startup Humai that wants to download people's consciousness and transfer them into artificial bodies to give them eternal life. [7] Complex scaffolds for many types of artificial tissues, including the kidney, the liver, and blood vessels, can be created using this approach. [29] Cloning the individual's brain and nervous system is the only hope today's scientists have to understand the human brain and develop advanced artificial intelligence and synthetic telepathy, allowing people to communicate by thought, not speech. [27] The artificial intelligence we will eventually create may not need sleep, he said, and the sort of brains that human brains may become as we incorporate deeply invasive computerized prosthetics may eventually not need sleep. [27] I definitely expect important advances in computer hardware and software over the next 30 years, including steady advances in AI. 1 quadrillion human brains in 2045? Even if the compute capacity exists, we won't have anything like the equivalent of 1 quadrillion HBEs. [27] We would need powerful computers, and a complete map of the brain?s connections, as well as the activity that runs on top. These conditions are many years away but could one day be fulfilled, making it possible to produce a full simulation of a human brain. [27] He predicts that in approximately 2023only 8 years into the future$1000 will buy 20 petaflops of computer powerroughly equivalent to one human brain. [27] If Moore's Law the doubling of transistors per square inch on integrated circuits every year, coined by Intel co-founder Gordon Moore continues, the computers of 2030 will have as much power as the human brain, believes. [27] A new computer prototype called a memcomputer works by mimicking the human brain, and could one day perform notoriously complex tasks like breaking codes, scientists say. [27] Cognitive computers function more like the human brain, making them capable of tasks that are very difficult for regular computing machines. [27] The computer needed to hold a human brain and simulate its functions might be either engineered or potentially grown. [27] Whenever I write a post about why you can't just plug a human brain or a map of it into a future computer and expect to get a working mind as a result, two criticisms inevitably get sent to both my inbox and via social media. [27] As Harmon explained in her story, a human brain is so complex that we estimate that mapping one mind would take up half of all the digital storage capacity on Earth and that's just the structure, not even the living action happening inside that structure. [27] Mind transfer between human brains is definitely not something to look out for in the near future. [27] Once we can reverse engineer the human brain, at the end of one's active life, his/her memories and most part of his/her consciousness can be uploaded to the cloud. [27] Could we grow such a platform? What better repository for human consciousness could there be than a human brain maybe even one cloned from your own brain? It?s possible to grow brain tissues called cerebral organoids from stem cells, producing cerebral cortical structures with mature cortical neuron subtypes. [27] The human brain is still a great unknown mystery to experts, and we do not posses a lot of knowledge about consciousness either. [27] Earlier this year, Dr. Thomas Insel, at the time the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health, explained to Tech Insider that we're trying to map the human brain now, but that's just a beginning. [27] By 2045 it will be over 1 QUADRILLION human brain equivalents every year. [27] Let's assume that the computing power of the human brain has remained a fixed number of calculations per second for the last ~200 years. [27] Connectome is a word that did not exist a few years ago and was coined to describe the complete set of all neural connections in the human brain. [27] While it's reasonable to contend that the complexity inherent in the human brain is entirely the result of mundane physics, and therefore can be reproduced in principle, singularitarians tend to assume that the emulation of human intelligence not being impossible means having the ability to in the near future. [27] Possible? If intelligence is based on human brain models, then it might be a real possibility. [27] For instance one idea is to actually grow a silicon brain which models human brains and then develop an AI by effectively teaching a new brain the way we teach a newborn; instead of starting with a final AI we simply help the brain develop intelligence. [27] The human brain is a complex network just like any other, and therefore one must understand all of its connections in order to get an idea of how it functions. [27] In memcomputers the processor and memory are combined, like they are in a human brain. [27] You calculated that in 2035, computers would add 8 million human brain equivalents. [27] To say the outcome is predictable is something of an understatement, for as soon as we hear Cotton mention downloading the human brain into a computer, we feel, rather jarringly, as though we've been here before. [27] The second points to a computer simulation, such as the recent successful attempt to recreate a second of human brain activity, and say it's proof that all we need is just a little more computing oomph before we can create a digital replica of the human brain. [27] Keywords: Neurons, Sensory System, Supercomputers, RTNeuron, Neuroscience, Microscopy, Brain Modeling I. INTRODUCTION The Blue Brain System is an attempt to reverse engineer the human brain and recreate it at the cellular level inside a computer simulation. [27] Currently, no computer (or network of computers) is powerful enough to simulate a human brain. [27] This is currently separate from the Blue Brain Project but it will become part of the Human Brain Project if the latter is chosen for EU funding in late 2012. [27] Let's assume for a second that computing power will match human brain power at some point in time. [27] It may very well be possible to preserve a brain well enough to define this set of connections uniquely for a human brain in our own lifetimes. [27] Caption: The wiring diagram of a human brain, measured in a healthy individual, where the movement of water molecules is measured by diffuse tensor magnetic resonance imaging, revealing the connections. [27] Next, it be created a life support system for the human brain, which connects to the Avatar A, turning into Avatar B. [27] Using stem cells, they grew a model of a developing brain that was about the size of an embryonic human brain at nine weeks old. [33] If I'm going to have my head transplanted, I wouldn't want another human body. [31] It subsequently died after the donor body rejected the head. [31] Right now, only a human body can grow a complex human organ. [29] I like the human body, i like eating food, and all the other pleasant things that come with being made of wetware. [31] A military pilot's mind is transferred into a spaceship, at the expense of his human body. [6] A cardiac pump is only suitable for use not longer than a few hours, while for the artificial heart the current record is 17 months. [32] Brain transplant is a procedure in which the brain of one organism is transplanted into the body of another. [8] If a heart can be successfully transplanted from one body to the next, surely this answers the argument that the brain rules the heart. [34] If those connections are frozen intact, the hope is that future scientists would be able to read them from a frozen brain and recreate that person from those connections - either implanted into a synthetic, or lab-grown, brain and body, or potentially into a computer. [35] When we investigate what the identity conditions for persons are, we'll be relying on some thought-experiments in which we have to make assumptions about whether a certain body or brain has remained one and the same thing over time. [36] Over the next two weeks, the patient is cooled to about -320 degrees Fahrenheit, and the cryopreserved brain and/or body is stored under liquid nitrogen for long term care. [35] The body has to learn that it is being steered by a different brain. [9] Recent scientific studies suggest that consciousness emerges from the brain and the body acting together. [34] It then communicates instructions to the cranial brain and the rest of the body, by using its own hormonal system, its own integration into the body?s nervous system, neuron broadcasts, and electromagnetic fluctuation signals. [34] It is assumed that the brain rules the body, and defines your personality and who you are. [34] The premise of this belief is that the brain is special, and different in composition to the rest of the body. [34] You may think organ transplants are common procedures – but Sergio Canavero's plans to give a head a new body will be a world first, if it happens. [9] After cooling the donor?s body and the recipient?s head, neck tissue is dissected, blood vessels are linked with tubes, and the spinal cords are cleanly severed, New Scientist explains. [37] With the new head on the body, the ends of the spinal cords are fused together using a chemical that prompts fat in cell membranes to connect. [37] Canavero suggests doing that with a compound called polyethylene glycol, which has been shown to promote nerve growth in the spinal cord and could be used as a sort of glue between the body and the head. [38] While the monkey lived and breathed for eight days, the spinal cord from the head and body were not fused, so it could not move. [38] In 1970, a neurological surgery professor at Case Western Medical School named Robert White successfully transplanted the head of a rhesus monkey onto the body of another one, whose head had been removed at exactly the same time. [38] White, now deceased, was at Case Western Reserve University School of Medicine in Cleveland, Ohio, when he transplanted the head of one monkey onto the body of another. [39] Alongside the patient in the same surgical room, the donor would have his or her head decapitated, and the remaining body would then need to be fused to the recipient?s head. [38] Canavero said he?d devised a way to fuse a severed head, presumably from someone with a life-threatening illness, onto a body donated by a brain-dead patient. [38] Earlier this year, an Italian surgeon announced that he?ll be attempting the world?s first human head transplant, that despite the hurdles, a human head may actually be attached onto another person?s body in two years. [37] In 1999, White wrote that, What has always been the stuff of science fiction - the Frankenstein legend, in which an entire human being is constructed by sewing various body parts together - will become a clinical reality early in the 21st century. [38] Skin Transplant is a surgical procedure that involves removing skin from one part of your body (the donor site) and moving it, or transplanting it, to a different part. [8] Tissue transplants means for reconstructive surgeons to repair parts of the body, restoring appearance and in many cases function and feeling. [8] This transplant may be done if part of your body has lost its protective covering of skin due to injury or illness. [8] Canavero's plans involve cooling the severed head and decapitated body so that the cells can remain without oxygen for as long as possible. [9] He says head to body surgeries will be useful for saving people with cancer-ravaged bodies, or for those locked in by tetraplegla. [39] Italian doctor Sergio Canavero plans to put one man's head onto another man's body. [9] Even if the head and body were successfully fused, the newly attached body wouldn?t work. [38] His team didn't even try to join the spinal cords; the monkey was able to breathe with artificial assistance but couldn't move its body. [39] Creating the Avatar C through developing an artificial brain and understanding the nature of human consciousness, says the Dalai Lama, could be attainable, and would be a great benefit to future development of science. [40] Tl;dr: In my opinion the only way to truly extend your singular life is to create artificial bodies and do a complete brain transplant, as far as I am concerned your original consciousness can only survive as long as your original brain can last without contracting a disease (Alzheimer's) or deteriorating into nothing. [41] The third step, named Avatar C, is developing an artificial brain in which to transfer one's individual consciousness with the goal of achieving cybernetic immortality. [40] Canavero proposes cooling the brain down so that, when the head is decapitated, blood flow would slow down enough to extend the amount of time it can survive without oxygen. A brain cooled down to hypothermic temperatures - roughly 12 to 15 degrees Celsius - can survive without oxygen for up to an hour instead of as little as four minutes. [38] The vagus nerve, at the base of the brain, controls bodily functions like heart rate, blood pressure, digestion, and more. [38] Whilst the operational possibility of a brain transplant remains only theoretical, we have been conducting heart transplants since 1967. [34] Retinal transplant is a transplantation of photoreceptors survive but also that they connect to nerve cells in order to be able to transmit signals to the brain. [8] Even the 2008 face transplant was a huge feat, and that was probably about 1/1000th the difficulty of hooking up the brain and the spinal cord. [38] This BSD theory proposes that human consciousness (left brain) is mortal, and up on death is cast into limbo trapped within its own memories which it can no longer add to. [34] In the last few years, scientists now begin to show an interest about consciousness, as well as brain specialists, neuroscientists, who also begin to show interest about consciousness or mind. [40] In his TED talk, Canavero showed a photo of Rob Summers (first epidural stim patient); in his most recent publication, Canavero cites the 2014 Angeli-Edgerton-Harkema paper from Brain about Summers and the other three completely injured guys who regained voluntary movement in the first epidural stimulation studies that showed that the spinal cord doesn't need full cortical connection. [39] OK. I got drawn in, read the literature and watched both a fascinating 2009 documentary about Robert White, the brain surgeon who pioneered monkey head transplants in 1970, and a TED talk from Canavero from last fall, in Limassol, Cyprus. (Note: skip to minute 31:45). [39] This being that our forebears realized that the heart kept residual memories when the brain didn't. [34] When the heart senses negative emotional feelings, its rhythmic electromagnetic pulses become incoherent which in turn affects the brains neurological states restricting the brains neural and cognitive capacity and inducing a negative mental state and attitude. [34] It was also found that one person?s brain waves can synchronize to another person?s heart. [34] The hearts neural infrastructure and complex circuitry allows it to operate independently of the brain in order to feel and sense, and remember and learn. [34] Our brains will always concede to orders from the heart, whereas the heart can choose to ignore warning signals and instructions from the brain. [34] Most surprisingly of all, in recent studies the heart brain has demonstrated certain dominance over the cranial brain. [34] There is a problem with this whole premise of swapping conscious awareness at brain component level, and the major problem is with the heart. [34] It uses these to process feelings and sensory information, and then sends issues instructions to the cranial brain via the vagus nerve running through the spinal column. [34] Over time, it can forge a new nervous bridge to the vagus nerve running through the spinal column connecting to the brain, but will communicate through other ways in the meantime. [34] Bodies and brains, like other material objects, are gradually losing molecules and having those molecules replaced, as time goes by. [36] Adjoining the two ends of the spinal cord - which is a giant bundle of nerves stretching from the brain to the spine and branching out to all parts of our bodies - is probably impossible. [38] Even if the brain and spinal cord didn?t fuse, that wouldn?t necessarily be a deal breaker. [38] There?s no way he?s going to hook up somebody?s brain to someone?s spinal cord and have them be functional, Dr. Chad Gordon, professor of plastic and reconstructive surgery and neurological surgery at Johns Hopkins University, told BuzzFeed News. [38] The basic concept is the replacement of degenerated cells by the implantation of new cells that repopulate damaged brain areas to restore local neuronal circuitries and neurotransmission, and thereby, brain function. [8] Cells taken from a foot and placed into the brain have been witnessed to change into neurons. [34] These cells were assumed to be found only within the cranial brain and the nervous system. [34] These neuropeptides are a way for the brain to communicate to other bodily organs and for the organs to relay information back. [34] When a person is happy, the heart?s rhythmic patterns are coherent, and the neural information being relayed to the brain facilitates mental clarity and decision making, and increased creativity. [34] Experts, including Winfried Denk, a brain mapping expert at the Max Planck Institute of Neurobiology in Germany, who Harmon quoted in her story, think the ability to revive someone who has undergone cryopreservation is at least 40 years away. [35] There are also interesting questions about what makes bodies and brains preserve their identity over time. [36] This keeps the brain healthy during the cryopreservation process. [35] Perhaps that part of our consciousness cannot dwell in the cellular memory of heart or other body parts. [34] The heart uses this magnetic field as a carrier wave and synchronizing signal for the whole body. [34] It is possible to monitor the heart from any position around the body. [34] There is a growing body of evidence which now suggests that the heart plays a particularly significant role in the process. [34] In medical experiments conducted on different animals, it has been found that when limited cells are transplanted from one part of the body to another, they adopt and take on the structure and purpose of the indigenous cells which now surround them. [34] Another option, says Dr. Christoph Hncke, who has successfully transplanted arms, is using machines which continually circulate oxygenated blood through the detached parts of the body. [9] The donor would have to be a brain-dead, living patient who had previously promised their body to science. [38] There is another use for the heart?s potent magnetic field which can extend several feet away from the body; and this is for interactions between people and other living things. [34] By 2045, Canavero predicts the dematerialization of body: . humanity, for the first time in its history, will make a fully managed evolutionary transition and eventually become a new species. [39] Now Canavero is claiming that thanks to new medical tools that can help fuse together the bundles of nerves in the spinal cord in the neck and body, we may have finally reached that point. [38] Is it actually possible to fuse two spinal cords and stop the recipient?s body from rejecting the new head? Last century attempts with dogs and monkeys resulted in animals who survived for a few days, though a more recent mouse head transplant showed that it was basically possible. [37] In laboratory conditions, body organs have literally been grown from single stem cells. [34] Stem cells have the remarkable potential to develop into many different cell types in the body during early life and growth. [34] The problem is, when the body dies, cells immediately start releasing toxic substances and decomposing. [35] The high levels of anti-rejection meds will poison the body, and who knows if the recipients will fully gain the function of their new parts. [37] Perhaps that part of the conscious awareness is distinctively separate from the body and may leave the body upon death. [34] Several people have already volunteered to get a new body, he says. [39] Cellular memory might be possible because of neuropeptides which exist in all the tissues of the body. [34] A head transplant is an operation which involves the grafting of one organism's head onto the body of another. [8] New Scientist summarizes: The recipient's head is then moved onto the donor body and the two ends of the spinal cord – which resemble two densely packed bundles of spaghetti – are fused together. [39] In a paper published this month describing this hypothetical procedure, Canavero describes attaching the head to the donor body. [38] Arm transplantation is the transfer of the arm from a deceased human donor to a patient with amputation of one or both arms, is an experimental reconstructive procedure that has the potential to significantly improve the lives of upper extremity amputees. [8] Penis transplantation is a transplant procedure surgically in which a penis is transplanted to a patient. [8] Surgeons and transplant teams are at the forefront of pediatric organ transplantation and work to ensure optimal treatment before, during and after transplant. [8] Organ transplantation is becoming the optimal therapy strategy for end stage renal, liver heart and lung diseases. [8] Organ donation takes healthy organs and tissues from one person for transplantation into another. [8] Islet transplantation, cells are taken from a donor pancreas and transferred into another person. [8] It can be surmounted, photoreceptor transplantation may in time open the way to saving sight, either by inhibiting further degeneration or even by restoring some sight by having transplanted photoreceptor cells communicate with surviving retinal nerve cells. [8] He coined the term donor dominance to explain the basic principle of hair transplantation which says that transplanted hair continues to display the same characteristics of the hair from where it was taken. [8] Facial hair transplantation is a commonly performed surgical procedure designed to transplant scalp hair to facial regions lacking density and fullness. [8] Hair transplantation is a surgical procedure used to treat baldness or hair loss. [8] Renal transplantation has become the treatment in early graft survival and long-term graft function that have made kidney transplantation a more cost-effective alternative to dialysis. [8] If you don't think the artificial brain would really be thinking when we fed your brain patterns into it, then you can suppose instead that we erase the patterns from some other human brain, and feed your patterns into that human brain. [36] Without this nerve, which could take about a year to grow back after it?s stitched together, a person would have to be on dozens of forms of artificial life support to survive. [38] Since there really isn't any details of this project (which isn't surprising since it just started and has 4 staff members), it's hard to say what level of AI they're looking at, or what they even mean by artificial intelligence. [41] Many technology theorists that assume that the essence of an individual?s conscious awareness and personality will soon be able to be uploaded? into a complex computer program, perhaps piggy backing off an artificial intelligence core program. [34] Billions of cells make up the human brain, and the most important thing in preserving it is keeping their connections intact. [35] It contains specialist stem cells, which produce the body's blood cells. [8] Regenerative Medicine – the UK Stem Cell Bank was the first in the world to store &amp; distribute stem cells; brain damage caused by strokes may be reversed by injecting stem cell into the brains; transplant may be created without being rejected by the body. [42] The new body would come from a normal transplant donor, who is declared brain dead. [43] Would the person be the same? If the person was the same, does that prove that our identity or individuality goes beyond the body and the brain? Would the person be different? Would the person have memories of the previous person? Would they feel the same? I know they would keep their own brain, but having the body of a completely different person would be quite something. [44] Italian neurosurgeon Sergio Canavero, from the Turin Advanced Neuromodulation Group in Italy, believes that surgeons will be able to transplant the head of one patient onto a completely different body by 2017. [44] It wouldn?t be the first time someone?s tried to transplant a head onto a new body. [45] During that time the patient would be given small electric shocks to stimulate their spinal cord and strengthen the connections between their head and new body. [43] The muscles and blood supply would be stitched up, before the patient is put into a coma for four weeks to stop them moving while the head and body heal together. [43] In 1970, neurosurgeon Robert White successfully transplanted the head from one monkey onto the body of another. [44] In 1954, a dog?s head and forelegs were transplanted onto a larger dog?s body by surgeon Vladimir Demikhov–the dog(s) only lived between two and six days. [45] BODY PARTS: Immigration is human trafficing and organ harvesting – New York Times- The FBI arrested 44 people. [10] This is where the geneticist works on manipulating the human genome, torturing monkeys, and clone a dead body or two during a shift. [46] The patient's head would then be moved on to the donor's body and attached using a ‘glue' called polyethylene glycol to fuse the two ends of the spinal cord together. [43] Creation of a computer model of the brain and human consciousness with the subsequent development of means to transfer individual consciousness onto an artificial carrier. [47] This development will profoundly change the world, it will not only give everyone the possibility of cybernetic immortality but will also create a friendly artificial intelligence, expand human capabilities and provide opportunities for ordinary people to restore or modify their own brain multiple times. [47] Cell Towers and Remote Control of Our Brains The Lily wave (named after John Lilly) allows you to bypass the resistance of the human mind (the brain) and you can transmit any emotion, any kind of information you want on the Lilly wave.Adams discovered they were using it through the power grid. [10] After the transplant, all of the heads had normal brain functioning, they were able to blink and move their whiskers. [44] Creation of an autonomous life-support system for the human brain linked to a robot, ‘avatar', will save people whose body is completely worn out or irreversibly damaged. [47] Dr Robert White has been able to take a human brain out of the body and keep it alive since 1963. [10] Scan people to find out damage levels (and location for brute/burn), some conditions, blood levels and some other info like body temperature. [46] Amount of blood left over in the body is visible on the Health analyzer. [46] Apparently, the trick is to get the spinal cords to fuse, and the fact that the body automatically rejects any new tissue makes this incredibly difficult. [44] A head transplant is planned sometime in the next few years, I kid you not, a real head removed from a diseased body will be attached to a healthy body whose head, obviously, suffered a fatal injury. [48] Body scanner is used to locate broken bones, organ damage, and internal bleeding. [46] Move patient to an advanced body scanner and locate the embedded object. [46] Treat brute damage on broken body part with either gauze or Bicaridine. [46] Powerful immunosuppressant drugs would be prescribed to stop the new body from being rejected. [43] The head and donor body are placed in suspended animation in order to extend the time that cells are able to survive without oxygen. The tissue around the neck is dissected, and the spinal cords of the head and body are cut cleanly, so as not to prevent nerve cells from being able to regenerate properly. [45] The recipient's head and the donor body would be cooled at the start of the procedure to extend the time that cells can survive without oxygen. [47] I think Arris has a much more likely prediction of finding the thawed out brains in dumpsters in about 30 years time. [48] I predict finding dumpsters full of thawed out brains in Australia in around 30 years time. [48] By shining it in patient's eyes, you can tell a few things from pupils' reaction – brain damage (different response speed between eyes), sleepiness (slower response time), drugs in patient's system (pinpoint/dilated pupils) or eye damage. [46] Factual scientific based evidence and the many warnings that the use of cellphones will damage our brains and kill us – is being ignored. [10] Most importantly, cells in the central nervous system–the brain and spine–do not naturally regenerate, which makes regaining motor control an impossibility. [45] All of which have been individually shown to possibly stimulate brain solar cells to death. [10] Any patient with an intact brain will be able to return to a fully functioning bodily life. [47] Causes brain damage to the occupant so should only be used when the patient is in critical condition. [46] Inducing a coma is usually a last-resort tactic, and carries risks of blood clots, infection, and brain damage. [45] By the late 2030's or early 2040's, Kurzweil said, the majority of brain function, at least in terms of information processing and thought processes, will be non-biological. [49] If he can take out someones brain and put it into a robot, then he should be able to pick up a 7 -10 split as well. [48] Robert J White?s Transplanted Monkey Head lived for 9 days with an artificial breathing mechanism. [45] Artificial eyes and hearts can be repaired during surgery with nanopaste. [46] Founded by Russian entrepreneur Dmitry Itskov in February 2011 with the participation of leading Russian specialists in the field of neural interfaces, robotics, artificial organs and systems. [47] Kurzweil, whose work at Google focuses largely on improving computers' artificial intelligence, is a strong proponent of singularity the point at which AI will exceed true human intelligence. [49] He told the BBC: The development of full artificial intelligence could spell the end of the human race. [10] While other brilliant minds like Stephen Hawking and Elon Musk have warned against the rise of artificial intelligence, Ray Kurzweil, famed inventor and futurist, and currently also Google's director of engineering, is taking a vastly different approach to technological innovations on the AI front. [49] Synthetic Biology – New methods have been developed in the UK to copy DNA up to 10,000 times faster; artificial leaves can convert sun into fuel; the number of steps required to create synthetic hormone has been reduced from 20 to 7; insects and the spread of diseases to crops can be controlled using DNA-based solutions. [42] The spinal cords would then be cut and the recipient's head moved on to the donor body. [47] Robotics &amp; Autonomous Systems – Robot arms are being developed to work in hazardous conditions; British autonomous submarines were the first to explore under a polar ice shelf; tiny robots can help pinpoint diseases within the human body while radar technology can enable cars to drive themselves. [42] How to perform a human brain transplant in 11 easy(ish) steps. [10] In just 15 years, Kurzweil believes, the human brain will become a hybrid of biology and technology, and we will put gateways to the cloud in our brains. [49] We plan to implement these breakthroughs as we work towards performing the first surgical prcedure of restoring and implanting a human brain to a new biolnic body. [50] Artificial Intelligence Could End Mankind Prof Stephen Hawking, one of Britain's pre-eminent scientists, has said that efforts to create thinking machines pose a threat to our very existence. [10] Dozens of scientists, entrepreneurs and investors involved in the field of artificial intelligence, including Stephen Hawking and Elon Musk, have signed an open letter warning that greater focus is needed on its safety and social benefits. [10] While the MRI-type magnetic transfer of your memories and thoughts from one brain to that of another human is probably science fiction, the closest we get to it will be presumably in 2016 when an Italian surgeon (Dr. Sergio Canavero) is set to perform a full head transplant from a Russian computer scientist (Valery Spiridonov) to the body of a brain-dead donor. [51] The talk, which took place in a mixture of Russian and English, focused on making it possible in our lifetime to conduct brain transplants, harvesting human parts from the body for cybernetic integration, and making self-aware brains comfortable in their new robot homes. [52] Since his brain is the seat of his mental life, the person with Spridinov?s head and someone else?s body would be mentally continuous with Spridinov and so would be him. [53] A head or brain cannot be transplanted into a newly dead body today, that's true, that doesn't mean it's impossible tomorrow (whether tomorrow be next year. or next decade or. whenever that sort of breakthrough may happen). [54] In the story Professor Dowell?s Head (1925), the Russian author Alexander Belyaev imagined a visionary surgeon finding a way to remove a subject?s head and transplanting it onto a new body while keeping the brain alive. [11] I agree with Soliloquy in that I'd rather go with either the stem cell fix, or maybe a cloned-body replacement (with non-functional brain on the donor body for obvious reasons). [55] To attempt to move a brain to a new body given what is known about the medicine and science involved, one would have to be out of one's mind. [54] The brain then gets reconstructed on the atomic and molecular level in a new clone body. [11] A human animal can arguably survive the loss of its limbs and most of its internal organs as long as its head and brain are kept alive and functional. [53] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (55 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) 1. (54) Uploading Human Brains to Computers – Boston Commons High Tech Related
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/cd7c9432-af90-31b8-ac39-1a7f0b269781" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-06T18:30:39Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:53:14.845Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/2016/01/brain-transplantation-into-an-artificial-body/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
