<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Kia shows off hybrid SUV concept in Detroit 19 minutes ago Author: James Fossdyke Kia has revealed its Telluride hybrid SUV concept car at the Detroit motor show. Were it to go into production, the boxy concept would sit above the existing Sorento to play a part in the premium SUV market. Kia Sportage 1.7 CRDi ISG 1 5dr Profile: 6+23 Mileage: 10k Miles p/a £189.35 Per Month, INC VAT £1436.10 initial payment View Details Personal Leasing Deal by: MyVehicleSource Ltd Using a plug-in hybrid powertrain, the Telluride combines a 270hp 3.5-litre naturally aspirated V6 petrol engine and a 130hp electric motor to drive all four wheels and achieve an American ‘highway’ economy figure of over 30mpg (equivalent to around 36mpg in British gallons). In a bid to compete with the premium establishment, the Telluride gets a luxurious cabin with dentist’s chair-style folding rear seats, leather in abundance, classy chrome details and huge infotainment screens. Aside from reinforcing Kia’s attempts to become a premium brand, the Telluride showcases a range of cutting-edge health technology, including so-called ‘Smart Sensors’ in the seats which log passengers’ vital stats and display them on panels in the door. The sensors also link with the ambient lighting system, which uses a huge bank of LEDs on the roof to display a therapeutic light pattern designed to combat jetlag and improve passenger energy levels. Other technologies include a swipe panel in the second row centre console allowing rear passengers to choose infotainment settings and a finger print-sensitive starter button. Kia claims it has no plans to build the Telluride, although it has claimed to take an 'interest in potentially offering a premium SUV positioned above the current Sorento' and is keen to point out that it 'has a history of delivering production vehicles that bear strong resemblance to preceding concept'. 'The Kia Telluride makes an aesthetic statement for the Kia brand as a bold, all-new luxury SUV with an abundance of advanced technology, focusing particular attention on the experience and comfort of second-row occupants,' said Tom Kearns, chief designer at the Kia Design Center America (KDCA). 'Longer, wider and taller than the recently redesigned Sorento CUV, Telluride allows us to envision what a full-size seven-passenger SUV from Kia could look like.'
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/b1a105e4-9ae0-38ff-9d6f-d6c36f89d131" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T13:00:41Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:42:41.184Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.contracthireandleasing.com/car-leasing-news/kia-telluride-hybrid-concept-detroit-2016/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
