<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. January 12, 2016 C O N T E N T S: Image Courtesy: link: http://palmbeachdrone.com/sales-service/agricultural-robotics/ author: palmbeachdrone.com description: Agricultural Robots KEY TOPICS The fact that someone can do a write-up and describe 27 agricultural robots speaks to how the space is developing, says Keay, referring to robotics analyst Frank Tobe's November 2014 Ag survey. [1] For these subsets of the overall ag industry they profiled DeLaval, Lely, Yamaha, BouMatic Robotics, Fullwood Automation and a few others. [2] Kinova designs and manufactures robotics platforms and components that are simple, sexy and safe under two divisions: Assistive Robotics empowers people with disabilities to push beyond their current boundaries and limitations while Service Robotics empowers people in industry to interact with their environment more efficiently and safely. [3] Arron Acosta CEO and Co-Founder, Rise Robotics Arron Acosta is the CEO and Co-founder of Rise Robotics, a company that pio-neers new, affordable ways to design and make robotic components without sacri-ficing performance or power. [3] We?ve been focusing on locomotion capability because that?s currently a missing component in robotics technology. [3] Coupled with the motivational component of training provided by a novel robotic gait training regimen, the H2 allows these participants to experience kinesthetic feedback of near-normal gait patterns in over ground walking. [3] SCHUNK designs and manufactures an unmatched selection of gripping systems including grippers, rotary modules, linear modules, robotic components, sensors and accessories. [4] Robotic ants developed by Festo AG can communicate with each other and work cooperatively to complete joint projects, such as moving a large object. [5] Robotic motion is controlled by Siemens 840D CONTROLLER software from Siemens AG (Munich, Germany). [6] Gene Mussel (left), Scott Kuechler, Ken Geiger and Matt Sherwood are in charge of expanding the use of robotic plastic injection molding machines at Plastic Components Inc. in Germantown. [7] Robotic plastic injection molding machines run with little human interaction at Plastic Components Inc. in Germantown. [7] Light constructions and material and/or component economising lead to more efficiency in aviation, transport logistics and automotive/vehicle technology, can increase performance and precision by providing higher dynamic efficiency in production and robotics, or can contribute to completely new solutions in design, functional integration and functionality itself. [8] One very good example here is the company Connova AG in 5612 Villmergen. Founded in 1983, and initially active in the areas of segment models and mould making for casting industry products, Connova AG has developed from a tool making company to an international specialist, and is in high demand for components and subassemblies for high-performance fibre-composite materials. [8] POSSIBLY USEFUL Bernd Wittman, Michael Krabiell and Erik Rig make up the Robotics, Handling and Automation team, bringing together years of knowledge and experience in creating robots, automation systems and high quality drive technology. [3] She is Director of Industry &amp; Start-up Relations at Robohub.org, a global site for news and views on robotics; founder of Robot Launchpad, a global robotics start-up competition; and cofounder of Robot Garden, a family-friendly community workshop promoting robotics and STEAM (science, technology, engineering, arts and math). [1] RoboScreen® technology, a patented invention by animator Andy Flessas of Robotic Arts in partnership with ABB, combines six-axis robots with the latest in LED display and media control technology to offer eye-catching video content and synchronized animatronics. [1] Open robot control software: the OROCOS project, in Robotics and Automation, 2001. [3] Development of a new humanoid robot WABIAN-2, in Proceedings 2006 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation, 2006. [3] As the trend towards developing more compact robots gains momentum, these Harmonic Drive® units are uniquely positioned to provide designers the affordability and flexibility to meet the increasing demands and performance expectations posed by the robotics industry. [3] Below are links and videos compiled to give persons involved with robot building and/or investigating careers involving robotics technology a list of internet resources that will help them achieve their goals. [3] Marco Mascorro CEO and CTO, Fellow Robots With 8+ years experience in robotics, Marco worked previously with BMW, Rolls-Royce and MINI, Singularity University, as well as in Japan to develop humanoid robots for rescue and exploration. [3] Richard Margolin Founder and Director of Engineering, RoboKind Robotics Mr. Margolin received his BS in mechanical engineering from the University of Texas at Arlington, and studied cognitive and computational neuroscience at Trinity College, Hartford, CT. Prior to founding RoboKind he was Director of Hardware for Hanson Robotics where he designed and built the world?s most lifelike interactive robots. [3] Collaborative robotics, where the safety function is allowing people and robots to work in closer cooperation, is enabling applications that were unheard of in the past. [1] She says these robots have implications beyond personal robotics and extend into professional service and even industrial robotics. [1] MASTER Robotics offers Preventive Maintenance service for your robots at very reasonable rates(volume discounts are available when 24 or more robots are scheduled for the same period). [3] Player 2.0: toward a practical robot programming framework, in Proceedings of the Australasian Conference on Robotics and Automation (ACRA 2005) (Sydney: ARAA), 145. [3] Robonaut 2-the first humanoid robot in space, in Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2011 IEEE International Conference on (Shanghai: IEEE), 2178-2183. [3] Excellent Technology for Evolving Industries Harmonic Drive actuators utilize high-precision, zero-backlash Harmonic Drive precision gears and play critical roles in robotics, semiconductor manufacturing equipment, factory automation equipment, medical diagnostics and surgical robot- ics. [3] The new expert teams cover all of the core sectors Harmonic Drive customers operate in, including Robotics, Handling and Automation, Machine Tool, Mechanical Engineering and Medical Technology, Optics and Precision Engineering, Aerospace, Defence and Special Environments. [3] Through this period of time, Bob has been involved with numerous applications of Harmonic Drive products in the field of motion control including factory automation and robotics. [3] Technology in Quality RoboDrives: the high-torque, precision drive for next-generation robotic applications As electric motors and drives are integrated into robotics systems, they are bringing new levels of efficiency and productivity to compact robotic solutions for medical, aerospace, and other applications. [3] I think personal robotics is probably the least of the areas that's going to be interesting in the next five years, even though it's one that people think of most when they think of robots, she says. [1] His robotics and AI practice includes workplace safety standards, privacy requirements, robot collaboration and human displacement, anti-discrimination law, and legislative and regulatory developments. [3] His company's Robotmaster® software for offline robot programming was featured in a previous article on robotic material removal. [1] We settled on ROS as it has a big growing community, built in support for OpenCV ( Bradski and Kaehler, 2008 ), is natively supported in Matlab, has a large selection of modules that we felt benefited Herbert, and has been shown to work successfully on numerous humanoid robots, such as NAO ( Gouaillier et al., 2009 ), Robonaut 2 ( Diftler et al., 2011 ), and the REEM ( Tellez et al., 2008 ) series of humanoids by PAL Robotics. [3] An example of a head designed primarily to look lifelike is by Hanson Robotics who developed a very realistic head used in the Albert version of HUBO humanoid robot ( Oh et al., 2006 ), which utilizes a high number of servo motors used to mimic human muscles and deform its rubbery skin so the head is able to display emotions as well as to articulate the mouth when it speaks. [3] There's been a lot of hype around collaborative robots, of which the Robotic Industries Association (RIA) has often led the discussion. [1] MASTER Robotics Robot repair and refurbishment You are using an outdated browser. [3] Collaborative robotics refers to human-robot interaction and was most recently covered in this article, The Realm of Collaborative Robots – Empowering Us in Many Forms. [1] Mask-bot 2i: an active customisable robotic head with interchangeable face, in Proceedings of IEEE-RAS International Conference on Humanoid Robots (Humanoids 2012) (Osaka: IEEE), 520-525. [3] Yaskawa, in collaboration with end effector manufacturer Robotiq, developed Kinetiq Teaching for robotic MIG welding, which allows the operator to hand-guide the robot to the desired welding positions rather than programming with a teach pendant. [1] Another trend that I think is really important and applicable to all sorts of robotics, not just personal robotics, is this new breed of social robots, she says. [1] The consumer sector is also growing: robotic vacuums and personal/social robots are examples. [3] The robotic entertainment system first gained prominence in 2010 when the robot troupe traveled the globe as main stage props for the Bon Jovi Circle Tour. [1] Ofer Shochet Entrepreneur, Technologist and Founder, Golem Robotics Dr. Ofer Shochet is an entrepreneur and a technology visionary, specializing in the development and successful implementation of future technologies in various companies at various fields of technologies. [3] In his role at MathWorks, he focuses on robotics product management, product marketing, industry marketing, and business development. [3] Through his passion for robotics, he continues to have an eye towards identifying new opportunity and driving business growth and requirements for product development. [3] Alan Ludwiszewski General Manager, Vecna, Inc. Alan Ludwiszewski, General Manager for Vecna?s Robotic Logistics Solutions, has over 20 years? experience in bringing innovative, multidisciplinary technology solutions to market. [3] After his graduation, he worked as the General Manager of a technology transfer and investment company before joining Kinova in its early days to develop the service robotics market. [3] Robotics and Automation Companies, especially smaller, start-up companies, tend to be more volatile than securities of companies that do not rely heavily on technology. [3] Robotics and Automation Companies may rely on a combination of patents, copyrights, trademarks and trade secret laws to establish and protect their proprietary rights in their products and technologies. [3] These risks associated with investments in Robotics and Automation Companies include, but are not limited to, small or limited markets for such securities, changes in business cycles, world economic growth, technological progress, rapid obsolescence, and government regulation. [3] Keay is Managing Director of Silicon Valley Robotics (SVR) in Pleasanton, California, a nonprofit industry group launched in 2010 by an alliance of Bay Area robotics companies, including founding members Adept Technology, Bosch, SRI International, and Willow Garage. [1] Aadhar holds a Bachelors of Science in Electrical Engineering from the Georgia Institute of Technology, where his focus was Artificial Intelligence and Robotics, and a Masters in Business Administration from the Harvard Business School. [3] In his current position with RoboUniverse, Richard is a catalyst for building community and introducing RoboUniverse events as end user focused open format world-class robotics business, technology and applications-focused trade shows. [3] He originated and co-chairs Littler?s Robotics, Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Automation Practice Group, providing legal advice and representation to the robotics industry, as well as employers deploying this technology in the workplace. [3] That figure represents more than the total global sales of all types of industrial robots in 2014! The Chinese government is encouraging the development of an in-country robotics industry because currently 3/4 of all robots purchased are from off-shore companies (albeit some with manufacturing and assembly facilities in China). [3] Provides a basic overview of the industry including development trends, competitive landscape analysis, and key regions development status – but only within the U.S. Covers vendors LG Electronics, iRobot, Samsung, Neato Robotics, Philips, Dyson, Panasonic, ECOVACS, Electrolux and 20 others. [2] Jon started his career in robotics and prototype development for the machine design industry. [3] He has served on the editorial boards of the IEEE Transactions on Robotics and Automation, IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering, ASME Journal of Mechanical Design, the ASME Journal of Mechanisms and Robotics and the Springer Tract in Advanced Robotics (STAR). [3] Design of the robot-cub (iCub) head, in Robotics and Automation, 2006. [3] Mechatronic design of NAO humanoid, in Conference on Robotics and Automation (Kobe: IEEE), 769-774. [3] Mike Beaupre, Director New Market Sales for KUKA Robotics Corporation in Shelby Township, Michigan, provides a glimpse into the advanced manufacturing technology deployed in Boeing's FAUB program. [1] Richard Erb Executive Director, RoboUniverse Conference and Expo Richard Erb brings more than 15 years of experience organizing trade shows in the telecom, information technology and robotics industries. [3] We're talking to some very large companies right now and demonstrating our technology, says Carl Vause, Chief Executive Officer of Soft Robotics Inc. in Cambridge, Massachusetts. [1] Carl Vause CEO, Soft Robotics Inc. Carl Vause is CEO of Soft Robotics Inc. Prior to Soft Robotics, Carl held a variety of senior positions in technology and medical device companies, most recently Vice President of Marketing at OmniGuide Surgical. [3] It's going to be a huge market, says Nicholas Hunt, Manager of Technology and Support at ABB Robotics in Auburn Hills, Michigan. [1] Nuzha Yakoob Product Manager, Festo Corporation Nuzha Yakoob is currently the Product Manager for the electromechanical, motion control and robotics products and solutions from Festo. [3] He focuses his practice on intellectual property counseling, particularly in the fields of alternative energy, medical devices, consumer products, and electromechanical engineering including robotics and control systems. [3] Prior to joining Neya, Mr. Stancil served as a project manager at QinetiQ North America where he lead the development of automated capability and control for several of the military?s fielded robotic EOD platforms including QinetiQ?s DragonRunner, TALON, and MAARS unmanned systems. [3] Brian has held numerous product development positions in an array of industries, including biotech, pharma, and now robotics. [3] Whether you are looking for new or used robotic spare parts, we can quickly provide you with a quote for even the hardest to find equipment. [3] Harmonic Drive gearing is used extensively in high-precision applications such as robotics and satellite antenna pointing. [3] For these reasons, harmonic drives are widely used in applications requiring precision positioning, especially in robotics and semiconductor industries. [3] I am interested in making a harmonic drive for small robotic applications. [3] Ideally suited for robotic applications, the new CSG-LW and CSF-LW gearheads are 30% lighter than previous designs without reducing the torque rating or significantly changing interface dimensions. [3] John holds a B.S. degree in mechanical engineering from the University at Buffalo and has publications in robotic manipulation, granular packing, learning algorithms, and machine design. [3] I really like the Universal Gripper (referring to Empire Robotics jamming transition technology first developed at Cornell University. [1] NASA is an organization that works in a multitude of Science and Technology fields, Including: Aeronautics, Human Exploration and Operations science, Space Technology, and Robotics. [3] Right now, the technology is primarily being used for arc welding, but it could be used in other types of robotic processes. [1] We're hearing the rumble of disruptive technology all throughout the robotics industry. [1] The improvement and technology evolution on the safety side of robotics is another key enabler, he says. [1] Combine Leap Motion with virtual reality technology, wearables, robotics – imagine the possibilities. [1] He is the founder of LocoRobo Inc., a technology non-profit whose mission is to advance programming education using robotics. [3] Covers the present and growth prospects of the global industrial robotics market in electronic and electrical industry during the period 2015-2019 and forecasts the industry to grow at a 5.43% CAGR through 2019. [2] Bill Culley Co-Founder and President, Empire Robotics, Inc. Bill Culley is an entrepreneur and engineer, and is cofounder of Empire Robotics, the company commercializing one of the newest technologies poised to have a significant impact across industrial robotics. [3] Bill Torrens Clearpath Robotics Bill Torrens joined Clearpath Robotics in 2014, charged with the responsibility to identify and manage opportunities in Clearpath?s industrial materials handling business vertical. [3] Prior to joining RMT Robotics, Bill was a Regional Sales Manager with Dematic Corporation, helping to foster integrated conveyor, ASRS and AGV based projects for Dematic?s industrial clients. [3] Eric Foellmer Marketing Manager, Rethink Robotics Eric Foellmer is the Manager of Product Marketing and Marketing Communications at Rethink Robotics, a pioneer in the Collaborative Robotics space. [3] Yanliang is the first product manager of MathWorks Robotics System Toolbox released in March 2015. [3] Jeff Burnstein President, Association for Advancing Automation (A3) Jeff Burnstein is the President of the Association for Advancing Automation (A3), the parent group of the Robotic Industries Association (RIA), AIA Advancing Vision + Imaging, and the Motion Control Association (MCA). [3] Automation, both with computations and AI, and physically with robotics, will take over some parts of what we do, but it will be the parts that we don't do well anyway. [1] ROBO-STOX is the first and only index tracking the global robotics and automation market. [3] In 2013 he co-founded Robo-stox? LLC (renamed to ROBO-Global) which developed a tracking index for the robotics industry: the ROBO-Global? Robotics &amp; Automation Index. [2] Dr. Murphy is a member of the IEEE Robotics and Automation Society Administrative Committee and co-founded the Technical Committee on Safety Security and Rescue Robotics and its annual conference. [3] Maccepa 2.0: adjustable compliant actuator with stiffening characteristic for energy efficient hopping, in Robotics and Automation, 2009. [3] Keay says soft robotics end effectors will extend automation into new areas. [1] Nathan's interest in robotics includes both the life-improving aspects that automation and smarter systems bring, and the fun side of things such as flying quadcopters. [3] Versatile modular electronics for rapid design and development of humanoid robotic subsystems, in Advanced Intelligent Mechatronics (AIM), 2014 IEEE/ASME International Conference on (Besancon: IEEE), 735-741. [3] Let Chronos and OPT help meet your goals for size and weight reduction, consistent with high performance, with a robust mechanical solution for your robotic application. [3] While it's primarily targeted at the robotic and semiconductor market, it will perform equally as well in other demanding high precision applications such as broadcast, aerospace and machine tools. [3] He also directs the robotics track of the AlphaLab Gear hardware startup accelerator, which he helped launch in partnership with Innovation Works. [3] Soft Robotics, the company, was founded in 2013 by Harvard professor George Whitesides and longtime collaborator Carmichael Roberts, along with their academic collaborator Dr. Conor Walsh of the Wyss Institute for Biologically Inspired Engineering at Harvard. [1] Provides the drivers and challenges for market growth, profiles vendors such as Fugro, Kongsberg Maritime, Oceaneering, SAAB, Teledyne, Atlas Elekronik, Bluefin Robotic, Boston Engineering and Palmarii Dynamics, and forecasts the market to grow at a CAGR of 20.65% through 2019. [2] MASTER Robotics provides quick, reliable repair of any part of your industrial robot. [3] Once industrial robots leave the factory floor and are commissioned for commercial use, they enter the professional service robotics realm. [1] Service robotics also involves human-robot interaction, but outside the industrial realm. [1] In addition to growth in Chinese industrial robotics, progress in the service robotics sector is also healthy. [3] Overall, 107 Chinese companies are involved in industrial robotics. [3] One, lower costs and increased ease of use will spur significant growth in industrial robotics over the next decade, according to a study conducted by The Boston Consulting Group (BCG). [3] When we're talking about a subset of industrial robotics, then collaboration takes on a different persona. [1] Where a traditional robotic manipulator may take months or years to develop a prototype, debug and market, our prototyping cycle right now can be as short as three days. [1] The entertainment arena is expected to grow considerably for robotics over the next few years. [1] According to the robotics industry experts Luo Baihui introduced in 2013 the Chinese market, sales of industrial robots near the Taiwan Taiwan, accounting for global sales of 1/5, with a total sales of more than Japan, ranking first in the world. [3] This report is skewed to reflect the growth of the service robotics industry in China. [2] Putting robotics at your service is a trademark of RobotShop inc. [9] She says her program is focusing on areas of development at the national and local levels, including robot-human collaboration and mobility, 3D imaging, end effectors and tactile sensing, and robotics in small to medium-sized businesses. [1] Most robotics companies I know are calling out for better, smaller, cheaper sensors, and embedded sensors, she says. [1] There are also companies like RightHand Robotics, she adds. [1] Profiles Hansen Medical, Intuitive Surgical, Mazor Robotics, Accuray, Titan Medican, Renishaw, Ekso Bionics, Varian Medical Systems, Stereotaxis and 15 other companies. [2] We have one of the largest robotics companies in the world with Intuitive Surgical and we have many small start-ups. [1] Whereas other robotic heads have been designed with the main aim of looking as lifelike as possible, so that the texture of the skin and the mimicking of the muscles are the most important aspect of their design. [3] Ofer is the founder of Golem Robotics, a startup in the world of Robotics, a lecturer at the COMAS Design school, serves as a Board member at Velo 3D Inc. and is an advisory board member at RoboUniverse Expo. [3] This report, with the same name as the Technavio one above, forecasts an 11% CAGR through 2020 and includes profiles of some different vendors (along with many of the same) including Deep Trekkers, Forum Energy Technologies, Subsea7, FMC Schilling Robotics, ECA Robotics and 25 others. [2] Technavio estimates the global robotics to grow at a steady rate of around 26% CAGR through 2019. [2] We gave Tobe a hearty nod in last year's inaugural forecast, Robotics in 2014: Market Diversity, Cobots and Global Investment. [1] MABEL, a new robotic bipedal walker and runner, in American Control Conference, 2009. [3] Messina expects collaborative robotics to have a significant impact especially on certain sectors of the manufacturing community. [1] She credits this phenomenon to small-batch manufacturing, rapid prototyping, crowdfunding, and angel investors, all making it easier to launch a robotics start-up. [1] To overcome the need for complex mechanical structures to display emotions and mouth movements, there is an emerging type of robotic head which uses the concept of displaying an avatar instead of relying on a complicated mechanical mechanism. [3] The changes that are happening in agriculture, logistics, and in medical and health robotics are really exciting. [1] One of the most transformative periods in the robotics industry is upon us. [1] RoboUniverse News Stay up to date on the incredible field of robotics! Enter your email address below to receive daily news about the robotics industry and updates on the RoboUniverse conference series, including show dates, announcements, exclusive discounts, and more. [3] Bottom line, all the reports are forecasting positive double-digit growth for most segments of the robotics industry. [2] One of the first industrial robots to grace the stage hails from ABB Robotics. [1] Common unmanned systems applications for our products include robotic arms, gimbals &amp; stabilized platforms, antenna positioning, and wheel drives for mobile robots. [3] Types of robots include industrial, service and mobile; components include hardware, software and services; market applications include healthcare, defense and security, aerospace, automotive, electronics, domestic and other. [2] A true visionary, Daniel has designed and developed several robots, including the Bear disaster recovery robot and the QC Bot logistics solution, as well as advanced automation components, such a biomemetic muscle and machine perception technology. [3] Many of the components that comprise a robot are intricate and costly, e.g., reduction gears from Nabtesco, Harmonic Drive and Sumitomo (all Japanese companies). [3] RT-middleware: distributed component middleware for RT (robot technology), in Intelligent Robots and Systems, 2005. (IROS 2005). 2005 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on (Alberta: IEEE), 3933-3938. [3] Does it sound like the harmonic could be damaged an then work for 5 months? There is a high sensitivity collision detect on the robot but I dont know how effective this is at actually protecting the robots components, Id apreciate your comments. [3] If I am asking the robot to move to one position (J(1) 100% CNT100) and then move away from it in the exact opposite direction (and with same 100% CNT100 command) would it be advisable to use an ACC command of, say 50, to slow it down (protect mechanical components) or should the standard acceleration be okay on the robots mechanical parts? Thanks. [3] This report is segmented by types of robots, components, applications and geography. [2] Application example: An actuator for adjusting business class seats in airplanes. 6 www.ConvergencePromotions.com RoboDrive and Pin-Ring Drives TQ leads a new generation of high-torque off-road eBikes High performance technology for Pedelecs and E-Bikes Under the trademark cleanmobile TQ develops and produces customer-specific drive systems and components for Pedelecs, E-Bikes and electric cargo vehicles. [3] Chinese companies that manufacture robots and their components are also growing. [3] A key component of this modular robot architecture in the PRL servo-electric. [3] The cost of the actuation mechanism is one of the most costly components on any humanoid robot. [3] Send your robot component repair to us with complete confidence knowing you are getting the best value for your money. [3] We work with customers of all sizes to provide both standard product and custom-engineered Harmonic DriveTM servo actuators, gearheads and gear components. [3] Structure of Harmonic Drive component product Flexspline Wave Generator Circular Spline Circular Spline Flexspline Tooth engagement The strain wave gear has a unique tooth engagement which results in a Zero-backlash gear mesh that provides high positional accuracy and high torque with a compact form factor. [3] Harmonic Drive LLC is a company that leads the high precision gearing and motion control industry with their servo actuators, gearheads and gear component sets. [3] Hackaday Here is another version using planetary gears to deform the flexspline: ORLIN Technologies Ltd How difficult would lit be to machine the components of a small harmonic drive (25mm dia)? I think the most difficult part would be the flexspline. [3] Harmonic Drive designs and manufactures high precision servo actuators, gearheads and gear component sets. [3] Available in a wide range of sizes, these zero backlash, 1 arc-min accuracy Harmonic Drive® gearheads enable design engineers to pass shafts, wires, tubing, or other components directly through the center of the gear. [3] Component Gear Sets Consisting of three basic components: flexspline, circular spline and wave generator; component gear sets offer ultimate design flexibility and can be tightly integrated in equipment sub-structures. [3] Many applications call for the need of lighter mechanical components example UAVs, aerospace ve- hicles, kitchen Aid equipment, house hold machines, etc. Apart from these applications, the reduction of size of gear box results in lower payload of aerospace vehicles, such as rockets, drones, aircrafts, etc.While considering weight reduction from a machine, the re- duction of weight contributed by gears will be a huge contribution. [3] Gear components and gearheads are available in many configurations including hollow shaft and differential gears as well as gearheads designed to quickly connect to any servomotor meet your specific application needs. However, the easiest way to reap the benefits of these high performance gears is to use one of our performance matched servo actuators. [3] China is making a push to manufacture these necessary components in-country, hence the interest in their new manufacturers Shaanxi Qinchuan Machinery Development Co., Ltd., Nantong Zhenkang Machinery Co., Ltd., Leader Harmonious Drive Systems Co., Ltd. and Shuaike Machinery Manufacturing Co., Ltd. The report forecasts a doubling of the Chinese production by 2016. [2] We have been able to identify 47 Chinese companies and 5 startups that call themselves industrial robot makers, and another 26 which offer to provide integration services and speciality equipment. 34 more provide ancillary services, sensors and components to the robot makers. [3] Their generous donation of precision aluminum welding services is an essential aspect of our rover, and provides us with the ability to make lightweight and strong components in configurations that would otherwise not be possible. [3] An option provides housings and components that have been built with pinned-in-place assembly techniques for the most demanding customer's applications. [3] MAG SOAR Company is already providing contactless mechanical components for space applications able to operate in a wide range of temperatures. [3] ADVANCED Motion Controls servo drives are compatible with ANY Motor, ANY Controller, ANY Feedback and ANY I/O which means you don't have to get locked into any particular component manufacturer when designing your system. [3] Headquartered in Clearwater, Florida, MICROMO Inc. is the North American source for the world?s smallest high precision DC drive systems, components, and controls. [3] Computer includes the following components: Antec 380 watt Power Supply Unit Zip Disc Drive(no cable) 2 Hard Drives Formatted(OS install ready) include: Primary: Seagate Barracuda 80GB and Secondary:. more Western Digital 30 GB LG Lightscribe DvD Player/Rewriter Plextor CD rewriter(included but don't know if this works; powers up) ATX Case Everything is in working order. [3] For your convenience we have compiled this list of 3 rd party component manufacturers that are known to work with our servo drives. [3] M axon Precision Mo tors, Inc. is a leading manufacturer and supplier of precision DC drive components. [3] Essentially the major components of the drive forces are due to structural damping and springiness of the flexispline deforming while the input rotates. [3] Harmonic Drive? servo actuators, gearheads, and gear components are very compact, yet deliver high torque and are capable of 30 arc-second position accuracy and +/- 5 arc-second repeatability. [3] The gearhead incorporates a Harmonic Drive gear component into an integral housing. [3] The limiting elements of conventional Harmonic Drives (teeth, flexspline and ball bearings) are substituted by contactless mechanical components (magnetic gear and superconducting magnetic bearings, ). [3] Harmonic Drive, LLC engineers and manufactures precision servo actuators, gearheads and gear component sets. [3] Harmonic Drive designs and manufactures all key components of our actuators including the motor, encoder, gearing and cross-roller output bearing. [3] Defined (by them) as autonomous robotic systems, this report examines collaborative, personal service, professional service and software robots and forecasts rapid growth of 19.22% CAGR by 2020. [2] In comparison to other robots, the development of humanoid robotic systems creates unique electrical challenges. [3] His technical focus is on integrated robotic systems including real-time sensor processing, mobility planning, and intuitive robot control. [3] Energid?s Actin software drives sensor-guided manipulation, autonomous grasping and straightforward control of complex robotic systems for medical, energy, transportation, and industrial applications. [3] Unlike other well-developed robotic systems, like wheeled robots where the controllers and sensors can easily be taken off-the-shelf and then integrated, developers of humanoid systems place a higher priority on compactness and weight. [3] I remembered watching my manager present the new robotic arm link solid model that was going to be used to automate the drive axle assembly? with a mouse and trackpad in hand. [3] Affiliated companies in, Japan (Harmonic Drive Systems, Inc.) and Germany (Harmonic Drive AG) provide additional manufacturing capabilities. [3] Keay also points to other standout companies in the Ag space, Blue River Technology and Harvest Automation. [1] The key focus of the Optics and Precision Engineering team is the move towards smaller high precision components, which places more demands on accurate machines and manufacturing. [3] Although a few of the startups are attempting to make reduction gears and other similar devices, the lack of these component manufacturers in China may put a cap on how low costs can go and on how much can be done in-country for the time being. [3] Silk Hat High Torque SHG Series SHG is a high torque, silk hat, component set gear available with a large hollow through bore. ?Dimensions HarmonicDriveComponentSet SHFSeries ?SHF Series Ratings SHF is a silk hat, component set gear available with a large hollow through bore. [3] CSG-2UH is a high torque housed component gear set combined with a precision cross roller output bearing flange. [3] Simplicity Gear Unit Non-housed component gearing combined with a precision cross roller output bearing. [3] Based on the proven reliability of our SHD component sets, this gear unit has zero backlash, exceptional position accuracy and repeatability. [3] All these supporting components have been important in the development of the complete system. [3] Figure 4 B shows different designs that have been tested in CAD using the finite element method (FEM) to compute the theoretical compliance as well as the strength of the component. [3] There are four main hardware components used to achieve this: (1) the projector; (2) the optics used to modify the light beam; and (3) the mask (4) the 3 DOF neck. [3] China is expected to become the worlds largest robot market in 2016, the amount will be more than 150 thousand units. even Nabtesco Plans to invest nearly 5 billion yen in new factories in China, starting in 2016, put into operation the core components of industrial robots, planned annual output of 100 thousand units, up to 200 thousand units in 2020. [3] David Askey Co-Founder and Chief Business Development Officer, Energid David Askey is responsible for strategic initiatives, guidance, and market development of vision-based robotic systems. [3] The Robotic Systems for Smart Manufacturing Program, within the Engineering Laboratory at NIST, develops and deploys measurement science for intelligent robotic systems used in manufacturing. [1] We're trying to avoid that, says Elena Messina, Group Leader, Manipulation &amp; Mobility at NIST, and Manager of the Robotic Systems for Smart Manufacturing Program. [1] I realize that you are probably looking for help on how to fix the gearbox but really if you are willing to spend 3k on the gearbox alone, a harmonic drive (works on a similar principle) might be a better option especially if you are building a robotic arm. [3] My goal was to implement the principle of the harmonic drive into a sturdy solid module that can ultimately be used for making a robotic arm. [3] Craig Tomita Area Sales Manager – West, Universal Robots Craig Tomita has over 25 years of sales and managerial experience in robotics, automation, and machine vision from top companies including: IAI, COGNEX, BOSCH-REXROTH, MINARIK, ADEPT TECHNOLOGY, and FESTO. He joined Universal Robots in the fall of 2015 as he saw collaborative robots as the next major leap in robotics. [10] MUSE brings robotics closer to companies addressing light industrial, bio-lab or service robot solutions. [4] Clearpath Robotics Inc. is a global robotics company dedicated to automating the world's dullest, dirtiest, and deadliest jobs with intelligent service robots. [11] He joined ABB in the Robotics Business Unit in 2007 in Shanghai, China as a Product Manager for the small robot portfolio in which he oversaw the launch of the IRB 120 robot. [10] Rainbow Robotics is a South Korean company specializing in the development of humanoid robots. [11] Opportunities in consumer robotics abound as price points for technology and innovation are bringing robots within the reach of everyday people. [4] From the food we eat to the cars we drive, robots help make our lives easier, more efficient, and simply more fun! The field of robotics is expanding at a rapid pace, and Texas 4-H is poised to help lead young people into this exciting field. [12] It helps to coordinate the distributed intelligence, provide synchronized movement or swarms, fuse the sensor data collected by a community of robots and ultimately provide a management structure for large scale robotics implementation. [4] Since 1995 when we launched the first Pioneer robot, Adept MobileRobots (previously known as ActivMedia Robotics and MobileRobots, Inc.) has grown to be a global leader in the design and manufacture of intelligent mobile robots. [11] This program uses Robot Virtual World Software which allows students to experience programing robots and viewing the robotics perform virtually. [12] The adoption rate of smart robots for personal applications such as vacuum cleaning, pool cleaning, robotic pets, and elderly assistance, among others has increased due to the increase in the urban population and per capita income. [13] The Robot Report is a web-based resource for news and links about the business of robotics. [4] After completing the robot, the students can enter the robot into the GEAR (Get Excited About Robotics) competition. [12] Most recently, Nick resisted the siren?s song of Silicon Valley and instead cofounded a company in downtown San Diego, Accel Robotics, which creates extraordinary robots designed to enhance the human experience. [10] Robolink is a leading robotics education company that makes robotics educational kit and instruct students how to make robots. [10] Harvest CROO Robotics was established in 2013 as a technology company focused on revolutionizing the agriculture industry with automation. [4] Prior to Iam Robotics, Tom co-founded OpenJAUS, a technology company that develops software for the Joint Architecture for Unmanned Systems (JAUS), an industry standard used by defence and commercial customers for ground breaking robotics programs. [10] Unlike GPS (the most widely used positioning technology for most existing autonomous systems) or various Artificial Intelligence technologies (also now widely used in robotic applications), 5D?s technologies work in any environment, including indoors, in large cities, underground, as well as in fog, rain, dust and dark. 5D also delivers positioning information that is significantly more accurate than does GPS, a requirement for many autonomy applications. [4] The company?s home robots help people find smarter ways to clean, its defense &amp; security robots protect those in harm?s way, and its remote presence robots enable virtual presence from anywhere in the world. iRobot?s consumer, enterprise and military robots feature proprietary technologies incorporating advanced concepts in navigation, mobility, manipulation, cloud robotics and artificial intelligence. [11] Universal Robots has reinvented industrial robotics with lightweight, flexible robot arms. [4] This 10 lesson online tutorial program is designed for students interested in building a robot on their own and provides explanations of robotics terms. [12] In 2010, he founded Hoaloha Robotics to develop autonomous, socially interactive robot companions for seniors and individuals who face the challenges that may come with disability and chronic disease, empowering them to live with greater independence and quality of life, and enabling them to continue to be active contributors in the lives of their families and community. [10] ECHORD++ is a joint project of Technische Universit Mchen (project coordinator), Blue Ocean Robotics, Bristol Robotics Laboratory, Commissariat l?. nergie Atomique et aux. nergies Alternatives, R.U. Robots limited, Scuola Superiore Sant?Anna and Universitat Politnica de Catalunya. [11] Overthrow Robotics is a startup that has invented an intelligent boxing robot. [4] Smokie Robotics, Inc. was founded to develop versatile, lightweight, and modularized open unit robots (OUR's) featuring low cost and high positional repeatability. [11] Or Let's get together and show off our robots and maybe create a local robotics competition. [4] The demand for personal robots for home cleaning, education and entertainment will be the fastest growing segment in robotics over the next decade. [4] The robotic skin – CellulA.R.Skin – demonstrated at IROS consists of multi-modal skin sensors, which can be adapted to any robot arm in order to improve safe human- robot collaboration and rapid configuration. [11] Business is our middle name; so here at Robotics Business Review, we believe that business, just as it has so aptly demonstrated since 1962, will ultimately be the force that drives all emerging robotics' technology forward. [14] RoboUniverse covers robotic innovation in agriculture, manufacturing, logistics, healthcare, AI, consumer, education, IoT, plus business, investment, technology, and so much more. [4] The expo hall allows networking opportunities with colleagues from 25 countries as well as 50+ exhibits from around the world. 80 + speakers provide coverage of industrial automation solutions, business, field and aerial robotics, healthcare, and consumer solutions and strategies. [4] Our mission is to rethink and deliver solutions for embedded computing and control systems to improve the future progression of robotics, industrial automation, special machinery, electric vehicles and the internet of things. [11] His group provides RD services in advanced sensing, industrial automation, and robotics for a broad range of industries and government agencies. [10] RoboticsTomorrow.com is a technical resource featuring Products, Companies, News, Articles and Events for the Robotics, Advanced Manufacturing and Factory Automation industries. [4] Known for our expert engineering and manufacturing, Harmonic Drive products are relied upon every day throughout the robotics industry. [4] Carl is also a roboticist with over fifteen years of advanced robotics and technical experience, including electrical and mechanical engineering, software development, machine vision, and autonomous navigation. [10] Prior to joining ABB Robotics he has been involved in business development for NVH testing equipment and software for LMS international. [10] ABB Robotics is a leading supplier of industrial robots – installing over 250,000 robots worldwide – also providing robot software, peripheral equipment, modular manufacturing cells and service for tasks such as welding, handling, assembly, painting and finishing, picking, packing, palletizing and machine tending. [4] Since its launch in 2008, Robotic Magazine has been one of the primary news sources on all areas of robotics, such as industrial robots, robot parts, software and AI, hobby, events, service robots, robotic vehicles, military robots, robotic toys and more. [4] He has nine years of technology experience including IBM and Clearpath Robotics and has worked with several startups such as The Funding Portal, where he saw the company from its launch through its first funding rounds. [10] Richard Erb Executive Director of RoboUniverse Global Events Richard Erb brings more than 15 years of experience organizing trade shows in the telecom, information technology and robotics industries. [10] In 2010, MobileRobots Inc. was acquired by the largest industrial robotics company in the U.S., Adept Technology. [11] To this end, NCCR Robotics is advancing fundamental insights in terms of technology, materials and control mechanisms along with offering unique opportunities for technology transfer towards high-tech companies and start-ups. [11] Currently, Transcend Robotics develops and distributes Articulated Traction Control (patented) technology, which enables robotic stair climbing and other obstacle maneuvering through a unique mechanical design. [4] The PAN-Robots project aims to improve the technology for the design and deployment of robotic fleets to the warehouse management in smart factories. [11] In business for over 20 years with over 40 ME?s along with a strong ecosystem of suppliers and contract manufacturers, Acorn has deep expertise in robotics and associated support infrastructure design. [4] Sessions in the Cognitive science track provide applications for building the brains of future robotic applications and involve emerging mathematical algorithms to not only solve common business problems, but also detect and predict future patterns. [4] In 2014, Nicolas moved to the United States to take on his current role as New Applications Business Line Manager in the Robotics Business Unit. [10] Following the concept of Sense – Reason – Act, 3D technologies such as object localization, recognition and scene analysis, robotic manipulation and application development complete the portfolio. [11] Jordan's current focus is transitioning Neya's mission management and data processing systems to cloud-based architectures, and supporting the development of new robotics programs using the latest web technologies. [10] Initially focusing on GPS-denied environments and multiple-UAV coordination technologies, Infinium Robotics has developed multiple patent-pending solutions in the UAS industry over the past few years. [10] RoboUniverse San Diego will feature a half day of tutorials, plus two days of conference sessions led by industry experts and demonstrations of the latest robotics technologies and services. [4] Build your robotic, IoT, security or other application using the machine learning, computer vision and other technologies within BrainOS, a software package that makes it easy to get the functionality that you need. [4] Tandy Trower CEO, Hoaloha Robotics Tandy Trower has lead the creation, marketing, and deployment of a wide variety of software and hardware products for over 30 years. [10] For the past three years, Craig has been the Director of Software Engineering for 3D Robotics and has lead the Open Source ArduPilot UAV project. [10] David Bruemmer CEO Co-Founder, 5D Robotics, Inc. Mr. Bruemmer provides leadership and vision guiding the development and commercialization of robotic software. [10] PAL Robotics is an R&amp;D company settled in Barcelona (Spain), focused on the development of robotic solutions. [11] Soft Robotics Inc. is a company focused on addressing the unmet needs of robotic manipulation through our proprietary and novel technology. [4] Robodub is a robotics company based in Seattle area which is creating high endurance gas powered rotary drones using patented technology. [4] Jervis B. Webb Company is a subsidiary of Daifuku North America Holding Company, a leading developer of innovative material handling technology such as Automatic Guided Vehicles (AGVs), Automated Storage and Retrieval Systems (AS/RS), conveyors, robotics, and baggage handling systems. [4] Mike T. Tolley Assistant Professor and Director, Bioinspired Robotics and Design Labs at University of California, San Diego Michael T. Tolley is an Assistant Professor in the department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, and director of the Bioinspired Robotics and Design Lab in the Jacobs School of Engineering at the University of California, San Diego. [10] Tom holds a PhD in Robotics from University of Florida and a BS in Aerospace Engineering from Embry Riddle Aeronautical University, with minors in Computer Science and Mathematics. [10] He has a BS in mechanical engineering from Carnegie Mellon University with a minor in robotics. [10] His Coordinated Robotics Lab is developing an array of clever vehicles to achieve maximum agility with minimal complexity, and is coming to the mass market with a number of small toy and educational robotic vehicles in collaboration with WowWee Robotics (their first jointly-developed product, MiP, recently was awarded Innovative Toy Of The Year by the Toy Association of America). [10] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (37 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) 1. (132) Hamonic Drive Robotics Components – Boston Commons High Tech Related Related Articles
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/eae679da-8c0f-387e-a4ae-b9c17fd6272d" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T21:18:37Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T12:04:27.226Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/ag-robotics-components/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
