<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Fiber Optic Connectors Market - Global Industry Analysis, Size, Share, Growth, Trends and Forecast 2015 - 2021 NEW YORK, Jan. 20, 2016 /PRNewswire/ -- Fiber optic connectors (FOC) are used to mechanically connect two optical fibers, thereby permitting light to transmit from the core of one particular fiber to the other fiber in order to link the fiber optic connection equipment. The global fiber optic connectors market has been segmented on the basis of types and applications. A cross sectional analysis of the global fiber optic connectors market broadly across five geographical segments has also been covered under the scope this report. The factors which are primarily driving the growth of the global fiber optic connectors market are increasing demand for high bandwidth in the telecommunication industry and increasing demand for transmission speed and data volume in the data centers. The key features of fiber optical connectors such as low power consumption, cost effectiveness and high data transmission among others. These features are expected to fuel the growth of fiber optics connectors in the next generation warehouse-scale data center networks. In addition, the increasing application of these connectors in medical sector is playing a significant role in pushing the growth of the market. Furthermore, large scale production and technological advancements of fiber optics is also driving the growth of the global market. The conjoint effect of all these drivers is therefore set to bolster the growth of the global fiber optic connectors market during the forecast period from 2015-2021. The rapid growth of the internet and cloud computing has resulted in bandwidth requirements for data center network. This is in turn expected to increase the demand for optical interconnects in the next-generation data center networks. Furthermore, advancements in fiber optic technology have led to the growth in requirement for <NODE id="1943" />optical sensors<NODE id="1958" /> and data links in several applications including defense and aerospace. By deploying the advanced technologies in this field, the manufacturers can utilize this opportunity to increase production in a cost-effective manner as well as satiate the growing demand for fiber optic components among consumers. However, phenomenal growth in the wireless networking system is hampering the advancement of fiber optics. Moreover, the high cost and low level of automation of fiber optic connectors might also restrict the growth of the global market. The competitive profiling of the leading players in the global market and their respective market shares across the five major geographic segments namely, North America, Europe, Asia Pacific, Latin America and Middle East and Africa have been covered under the purview of this report. In addition, the distinct business strategies which have been adopted by the key players have been included in the report. To provide a detailed insight into the market dynamics of the global fiber optic connectors market, market attractiveness analysis has been provided in the report. A comprehensive analysis of the market dynamics which include, market drivers, restraints and opportunities has been included under the scope of this report. Market dynamics are the factors which influence the growth of the market and thereby help to understand the current trends in the market. The market drivers have been analyzed from the economic, demand and supply side. Therefore, this reports offers an exhaustive study on the global fiber optic connectors market and also provides the forecast of the market from 2015 – 2021. Some of the key players in the fiber optic connectors market are, 3M (U.S.), Alcatel-Lucent SA (France), Arris Group Inc.( U.S.), Amphenol Corporation (U.S.), Hirose Electric Co. Ltd (Japan), TE Connectivity Ltd.(Switzerland), Furukawa Electric Co. Ltd (Japan), Hitachi Ltd. (Japan), ZTE Corporation (China), Corning Cable Systems LLC (U.S.), Sterlite Optical Technologies Limited (India), Avago Technologies (Singapore), Ratioplast Electronics (Germany), Sumitomo Electric Industries (Japan) and Diamond SA (Switzerland) among others. The global fiber optic connectors market has been segmented into: Fiber Optic Connectors Market, by Types LC SC ST MPO/MTP Others Fiber Optic Connectors Market, by Applications Telecom Industry Datacom DWDM systems Lasers Others Fiber Optic Connectors Market, by Geography: The market is broadly segmented on the basis of geography into: North America United States Canada Mexico Europe United Kingdom Germany France Spain Italy CIS Scandinavia Rest of Europe Asia Pacific China India Japan Oceania Rest of Asia Pacific Latin America Brazil Argentina Rest of Latin America Middle East and Africa (MEA) Saudi Arabia UAE South Africa Rest of MEA Read the full report: http://www.reportlinker.com/p03095692-summary/view-report.html About Reportlinker ReportLinker is an award-winning market research solution. Reportlinker finds and organizes the latest industry data so you get all the market research you need - instantly, in one place. http://www.reportlinker.com __________________________ Contact Clare: clare@reportlinker.com US: (339)-368-6001 Intl: +1 339-368-6001 To view the original version on PR Newswire, visit: http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/fiber-optic-connectors-market---global-industry-analysis-size-share-growth-trends-and-forecast-2015--2021-300207490.html Fiber optic
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1d561d47-c05c-3693-aee6-264e87208cb2" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-21T01:08:15Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:46:24.257Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/fiber-optic-connectors-market-global-221000118.html" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1943" endPos="1958" type="product-class" surface="optical sensors" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
