<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Cadillac of Arlington 2001 North Collins Street in Arlington, TX 76011 Learn More: http://www.cadillacofarlington.com/new/CADILLAC/2016-CADILLAC-SRX-43bf3d110a0e0a173be2a220a4c50690.htm Introducing the 2016 CADILLAC SRX. It features an automatic transmission, front-wheel drive, and a refined 6 cylinder engine. A wealth of standard features means that you no longer have to sacrifice. Like leather upholstery, a tachometer, power front seats, heated seats, heated door mirrors, a power rear cargo door, <NODE id="504" />blind spot sensor<NODE id="521" />, and seat memory. For drivers who enjoy the natural environment, a power moon roof allows an infusion of fresh air. Passenger security is always assured thanks to various safety features, such as: dual front impact airbags with occupant sensing airbag, front SIDE impact airbags, traction control, brake assist, a panic alarm, onStar, and 4 wheel disc brakes with ABS. Electronic stability control ensures solid grip atop the road surface, no matter how challenging the driving conditions. We pride ourselves in consistently exceeding our customer's expectations. Stop by our dealership or give us a call for more information. Tags: new,2016,CADILLAC,SRX,Luxury Collection,SUV,car,vehicle,automobile,Arlington,TX,76011,Cadillac of Arlington
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/0dae643d-e454-3179-9369-60b56d308aca" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-07T19:21:49Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:40:27.619Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V-LyZYZy0nY" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="504" endPos="521" type="product-class" surface="blind spot sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
