<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Tuesday, January 26, 2016 Last update: 6:03 AM FreshNews.com - Covering Large &amp; Obscure Tech Companies Since 1996 myDevices Launches Cayenne, the World’s First Drag-and-Drop IoT Project Builder Submitted by admin on 1/26/2016 @ 5:00 AM Companies mentioned in this article: myDevices LOS ANGELES -- (BUSINESS WIRE) -- myDevices , the Internet of Things (IoT) solutions company that simplifies the connected world, today announced Cayenne, its developer and maker tool for IoT projects, at the IoT Evolution Expo in Fort Lauderdale. myDevices developed a robust IoT platform that allows companies to efficiently connect devices, visualize data, apply sophisticated rules and interact with their connected customers. With the debut of Cayenne, myDevices is extending its versatile device and connectivity agnostic platform _ launched in October 2015 _ to the developer and maker community in the form of an easy-to-use, drag-and-drop tool. We are very excited to introduce the IoT community to Cayenne, our versatile developer and maker solution, first designed for the Raspberry Pi maker, said Kevin Bromber, CEO of myDevices. There are a lot of IoT platforms on the market, yet there are few IoT platforms that actually let the developer build a project without having to dig deep into SDKs and APIs just to get a simple proof of concept created. The Cayenne solution has revolutionary capabilities: automatic device and sensor discovery that enables Cayenne to be up and running in 7 minutes; drag-and-drop widgets that let the developer easily visualize real-time and historical data online or from a mobile app; triggers that allow one <NODE id="1638" />sensor<NODE id="1644" />, motor or actuator to invoke an action on another device; threshold alerts that send emails or SMS messages based on customizable criteria; and the ability to schedule specific days and times when lights, motors, valves and actuators turn on and turn off. With Cayenne, we have achieved our goal: engineers can now develop IoT projects in hours instead of months, Bromber said. On the business side, Cayenne can be used for cost-effective prototyping, improving business prophecies, and streaming workflow. In the home, Cayenne will allow makers to easily and fluidly control home automation, security, sensors and lighting, among other things. In addition to a seamless and intuitive user interface, the greatest benefit of the Cayenne solution is that makers will be able to undertake simple IoT projects and significantly reduce the time and expense of more complex IoT projects. It is like an easy-to-use website builder but for IoT projects, Bromber explained. Key features include: A mobile app to set up, monitor and control devices and sensors from anywhere Easy setup that quickly connects Pi to the Internet, sensors, actuators and extensions in minutes Rules engine for triggering actions across devices Customizable dashboard with drag-and-drop visualization widgets Scheduling of lights, motors and actuators GPIO control that can be configured from a mobile app or dashboard Instant remote access from phone or computer Attendees of the IoT Evolution Expo are invited to stop by myDevices' booth #1921 to see a Cayenne demonstration. To sign up for a free Cayenne account, go to: www.cayenne-mydevices.com About myDevices myDevices develops middleware platforms and application solutions for the Internet of Things that simplify the connected world. myDevices customized solutions allow companies that manufacture, sell and support connected devices to efficiently connect products, manage data, and interact with their customers. myDevices is the first platform of its kind to offer a back-end connected device solution for the enterprise and an interconnected front-end solution for the end user. myDevices is headquartered in Los Angeles and is a division of Avanquest. Copyright Business Wire 2016 Contact: myDevices Jake White, 310-702-4955 Vice President, Marketing bjakewhite@mydevices.com or Bospar for myDevices Hannah Ruark, 540-599-7887 hannah@bospar.com
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/2cdbd002-a1af-30c5-b7aa-dd267c2b4228" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-26T22:12:54Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:52:12.677Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.freshnews.com/news/1178113/mydevices-launches-cayenne-world-s-first-drag-and-drop-iot-project-builder" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1638" endPos="1644" type="product-class" surface="sensor" /></Entities><Relations />
</Document>
