<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Sat, Feb 6th, 2016 / 13:33 PM Advertisement 600 V E Series Power MOSFET Saves Space and Increases Efficiency Offered in the compact, fully RoHS-compliant PowerPAK® 8×8 package — 57 % smaller than the TO-263 (D²PAK) with one-fifth the height — the Vishay Siliconix SiHH26N60E features a Kelvin source connection to increase efficiency by improving the gate drive signal. Built on Vishay's latest energy-efficient E Series superjunction technology, the device features low on-resistance down to 0.135 Ω at 10 V for extremely low conduction and switching losses. VRPower® Integrated DrMOS Power Stage Solutions Offer High Power Density for POL Regulator Applications For next-generation notebooks, ultrabooks, and desktops, Vishay Siliconix SiC53x series devices combine power MOSFETs, an advanced MOSFET gate driver IC, and a bootstrap Schottky diode in thermally enhanced 4.5 mm by 3.5 mm PowerPAK® MLP4535-22L and 5 mm by 5 mm PowerPAK MLP55-31L packages. Offering a 45 % smaller footprint than utilizing discrete solutions, the devices provide continuous current to 40 A for computing platforms using the Intel® Skylake platform. Power Metal Strip® Resistor Saves Board Space With High Power to 0.5 W in Compact 1206 Case Size Offering twice the power of standard resistors in the 1206 footprint, the Vishay Dale WSK1206…18 allows designers to save board space and reduce costs by utilizing fewer or smaller components. The device features a Kelvin 4-terminal connection that reduces TCR down to 35 ppm and enables tight tolerances down to 0.1 % for increased measurement accuracy for all types of current sensing, voltage division, and pulse applications. Enhanced vPolyTan Polymer Tantalum Molded Chip Capacitors Offer Higher Voltage in New Case Sizes Vishay's extended T55 series features new devices in the D and V case sizes and higher voltage ratings from 16 V to 25 V. In addition, devices in the A and B case sizes have been enhanced with lower ESR. The capacitors are optimized for power management, battery decoupling, and energy storage in computer, telecom, and industrial applications. Schottky Barrier Rectifier Reduces Power Losses in Commercial, Industrial, and Automotive Applications Vishay will highlight a new surface-mount Schottky barrier rectifier in the compact 3.7 mm by 1.8 mm by 0.31 mm DO-218AB (SMF) package. The AEC-Q101-qualified Vishay General Semiconductor SS2FL4 combines high current ratings to 2 A with low forward voltage drop of 0.33 V at 1 A and 0.43 V at 2 A (both at 125 °C) to reduce power losses in high-frequency inverters, freewheeling diodes, DC/DC converters, and polarity protection. TransZorb® TVS Offers Tight 3.5 % Breakdown Voltage To protect sensitive electronics against voltage transients induced by inductive load switching and lightning, Vishay General Semiconductor SMBJXXD/CD series transient voltage suppressors (TVS) achieve ± 3.5 % breakdown voltage tolerance and very low reverse leakage current in the low-profile DO-214AA (SMBJ) package. Compared to previous-generation devices, the TVS offer excellent clamping features with higher peak pulse surge current and lower clamping voltage. High-Voltage Thin Film Resistors Enable Precise Voltage Measurement While Reducing Component Counts and Saving Board Space Vishay Draloric TNPV resistors are the industry's first thin film flat chip resistors to combine precision properties — low VCR &lt; 1 ppm/V, tight tolerances to ± 0.1 %, and low TCR down to ± 10 ppm/°C — with high operating voltages to 1000 V in the 1210 size and to 700 V in the 1206 size. The devices target industrial and automotive high-voltage applications, including inverters, electric vehicles, and battery management systems. Electrical Double Layer ENergY Storage Capacitors Increase Design Flexibility Vishay will introduce a new series of electrical double layer ENergY storage capacitors — ENYCAP — with high capacity and energy density in four case sizes. The Vishay BCcomponents 220 EDLC series is available in two versions: power and energy. The energy version is designed to provide high stability for energy harvesting and power backup applications, while the power version offers increased stored energy up to 0.029 Wh at +85 °C, lower ESR down to 12 mΩ, and capacitance up to +40 °F. 100 V N-Channel MOSFETs Reduce Power Losses and Improve Efficiency The Vishay Siliconix SUM70040E and SUP70040E ThunderFET® power MOSFETs feature a maximum on-resistance of 4 mΩ, which is 60 % lower per mm² than previous-generation devices. This allows the MOSFETs to significantly reduce power losses and improve efficiency in a wide range of applications, from solar micro inverters to charging stations for e-vehicles. The rugged devices feature a maximum junction temperature rated up to +175 °C. Schottky Rectifier Saves Space in High-Speed Switching Applications To reduce power losses, the Vishay Semiconductors VSKY20401608 commercial-grade surface-mount Schottky rectifier combines high current ratings to 2 A with low forward voltage drop of 510 mV at 2.0 A. Featuring low reverse current of &lt; 18 μA at 10 V, the device is offered in the compact 1.6 mm by 0.8 mm by 0.31 mm CLP1608-2L package. Metal Oxide Resistors Save Space in High-Voltage Systems Acting as bleeder resistors for dumping capacitor charges in power supplies, laboratory equipment, power control, and aeronautical applications, Vishay Dale RNX and ROX series metal oxide resistors feature high power ratings from 0.25 W to 28 W and working voltages to 45 kV in compact packages. Metal Film Resistors Deliver High Power Density Specially developed Vishay Dale CPF metal film resistors offer high power ratings up to 3 W in small sizes for industrial power applications. The devices feature a flameproof, high-temperature coating, excellent high-frequency characteristics, low noise, and a maximum working voltage to 500 V. Power Resistors Feature High Surge Capability Featuring thick film metal technology, Vishay MCB RCMC series resistors offer power ratings to 750 W at 25 °C and high energy capability at 100 J for 50 μs. The non-inductive devices are cooled by an external heatsink and offer easy assembly. NTC Lug Sensor Provides Accurate Surface Temperature Measurement For surface sensing applications in automotive equipment, battery management, and power electronics, the AEC-Q200-qualified Vishay BCcomponents NTCALUG01T features high insulation voltage of 2.7 kVAC and 150 °C long-term stability. The device offers a rugged construction and easy mounting via its ring tongue terminal. Single-Turn Inductors Offer High Current Ratings For high-frequency VRM 10.0 applications, Vishay Dale IFLR series devices offer high current ratings up to 50 A and low DCR values in four case sizes. Ceramic Disc Capacitors Provide High Reliability The Vishay Cera-Mite 440L series of AC-line-rate ceramic disc capacitors provides maximum capacitance to 20 nF for Class X1 (760 VAC) and Y1 (500 VAC) applications in accordance with IEC 60384-14.3, 4th edition. Optimized for across-the-line, line by-pass, and antenna coupling applications, the devices feature tolerances down to ± 10 % and an operating temperature range of -30 °C to +125 °C. Advertisement Tags: Electronics components , Events
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/1c878e26-bd5a-3d8b-8734-9fe6b618fc31" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-02-06T09:40:19Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T10:46:05.597Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://electronicsmaker.com/new-products-on-display-at-apec-2016" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
