<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Computer Aided Engineering for Batteries Project Posted By: Text Analysis Algorithm. All content footnoted with links to original sources. Featured image attribution at end of article. October 13, 2015 See up to 10 related YouTube videos at end. C O N T E N T S: KEY TOPICS The newly released Virtual Integrated Battery Environment (VIBE) is an integral part of the Open Architecture Software Framework designed within the CAEBAT (Computer Aided Engineering for Batteries) project. [1] Virtual Integrated Battery Environment (VIBE) developed at ORNL under the DOE funded CAEBAT (Computer Aided Engineering for Batteries) project was used to simulate the battery response employing different coupling between physics. [2] Above is a visualization of the battery modeling software from the Computer Aided Engineering for Electric Drive Batteries project. [3] Partners on the Computer Aided Engineering for Electric Drive Batteries project, supported by VTO, recently made three new battery modeling tools commercially available. [3] This project is part of the competitive Computer Aided Engineering of electric drive Batteries (CAEBAT) activity launched by DOE in 2010. [4] The Computer Aided Engineering for Electric Drive Batteries (CAEBAT) activity was initiated by the Vehicle Technologies Office (VTO) to create battery simulation suites/tools that enable acceleration of the design cycle as well as battery (cells and packs) performance and cost optimization. [5] As part of the CAEBAT (Computer Aided Engineering for Batteries) activities, ORNL developed a flexible, robust, and computationally scalable open-architecture framework that integrates multi-physics and multi-scale battery models. [6] Developing a simulation model database of commercially available cells to enable wider evaluation and adoption of computer aided engineering tools for the design of battery packs and cells. [5] NREL brings its predictive computer simulation of Li-ion batteries, known as a multi-scale multi-dimensional (MSMD) model framework, to the CAEBAT project. [7] Beginning in 2012, General Motors led a team working under a program administered by DOE?s National Renewable Energy Laboratory known as the Computer-Aided Engineering for Electric Drive Vehicle Batteries (CAEBAT) project. [8] Johnson Controls is an industry partner in the Computer-Aided Engineering for Electric-Drive Vehicle Batteries (CAEBAT) project, which aims to accelerate the development and lower the cost of next-generation electric-drive vehicles. [9] The Computer-Aided Engineering for Batteries (CAEBAT) program is funded through the Vehicle Technologies (VT) program office within the DOE Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy (EERE). [1] ACCELERATING DEVELOPMENT OF EV BATTERIES THROUGH COMPUTER- AIDED ENGINEERING ansys.com/92battery3 GM prototype 24-cell module featuring steady-state liquid cooling used for experimental validation GeneralMotors. [10] CADdoctor understands multiple computer aided design formats and product data quality criteria to easily translate and repair data as well as simplify geometry to reduce file size for more efficient computer aided engineering analysis. [11] TROY The Troy-based engineering technology developer Altair says Airbus Group, the European aerospace manufacturer, has signed on for access to Altair's software portfolio, including the HyperWorks computer aided engineering suite. [11] SOUTHFIELD The managed IT services provider Secure-24 has rolled out a managed, cloud-based engineering desktop for engineering firms that combines commonly used computer aided design resources into one service. [11] SOLIDWORKS is a suite of 3D computer aided design (CAD) software produced by Dassault Systes SolidWorks Corp. SolidWorks is a powerful, yet easy to use 3D CAD program that offers advanced features like design analysis, flow simulation, electrical integration and project lifecycle management. [12] CD-adapco, the largest privately held CFD-focused provider of Computer Aided Engineering software, announced that Dutch innovation company TNO and international energy consultancy Xodus Group have completed the first phase of a pioneering joint industry project (JIP) into the dynamic forces which affect the integrity of piping systems, in particular through multiphase flow. [13] Engineering being a vast field subsumes the field of computer aided design and simulation which form quite an integral part of engineering studies. [14] Beginning in 2012, General Motors led a team working under a pro- gram administered by DOE?s National Renewable Energy Laboratory known as the Computer-Aided Engineering for Electric Drive Vehicle Batteries (CAEBAT) project. [10] NREL is leading 11 industry partners in the Energy Department-sponsored Computer-Aided Engineering for Electric-Drive Vehicle Batteries (CAEBAT) project. [15] Dr. Jaber Abu Qahouq, an associate professor of electrical and computer engineering, is working with Mercedes to find out how some battery cells degrade faster than others, which is a problem because batteries are only as good as their weakest cells. [16] Dr Chacko is a skilled mechanical engineer with over 16 years experience in product development using analytical methods, computer aided engineering (CAE), prototype build and testing within the automotive, aerospace and nuclear sector. [17] After graduating from Purdue University, I was a principal engineer in the nuclear power industry for about two years with Impell and Surgent &amp; Lundy Corporations. ? Founded Modern Computer Aided Engineering Inc. (MCAE) in 1984 to develop advanced finite element analysis system. [18] Aditya Mohile of Friendswood High School was offered the opportunity to compete in the International Science and Engineering Fair for a Computer Science project, Computer-Aided Oral Cancer Diagnosis. [19] POSSIBLY USEFUL He received a CAREER award from the National Science Foundation in 2009 and four Best Paper Awards from the ACM/IEEE International Conference on Hardware-Software Codesign and System Synthesis (CODES+ISSS), the ACM/IEEE Design Automation and Test in Europe Conference (DATE), the IEEE International Conference on Engineering of Computer-Based Systems (ECBS), and the International Conference on Mobile Ubiquitous Computing, Systems, Services (UBICOMM). [1] CSDM staff in the Computational Engineering and Energy Science (CEES) and Computer Science (CS) groups are leading development of the shared computational infrastructure used across the program, known as the Open Architecture Software (OAS), as well as defining standards for input and battery state representations. [1] ABSTRACT: The Eclipse Parallel Tools Platform (PTP) project was started over 10 years ago with the goal of bringing best practices in software engineering to scientific computing. [1] The Vehicle Technologies Office (VTO) of the U.S. Department of Energy's Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy initiated the CAEBAT project in 2010 to facilitate the development of computer-aided engineering tools based on battery models developed by the national laboratories. [7] Johnson Controls is an industry partner in the CAEBAT project, which aims to accelerate the development and lower the cost of next-generation electric drive vehicles by using computer simulation to predict and detail the inner workings of Li-ion battery cells. [9] CD-adapco announced the successful completion of its development project targeting the automotive and lithium ion battery industries, enabling faster design and development of advanced electric drive vehicle power systems. [4] The initial award of the project was reported on July 7th, 2011 and the project team included CD-adapco, Battery Design Inc, Johnson Controls Inc and A123. [4] The design philosophy of the project will also be presented as well as how the n-body code problem is solved by the platform. [1] Majors in Engineering Design &amp; Production Technology, along with Sales &amp; Distribution spend 3 months learning from the company's professionals with the goal of becoming future employees. [9] The focus of the workshop was on assessing the needs of computational science software in the age of extreme-scale multicore and hybrid architectures, examining the scientific software lifecycle and infrastructure requirements for large-scale code development efforts, and exploring potential contributions and lessons learned that software engineering can bring to HPC software at scale. [1] The Software Engineering for Computational Science and Engineering workshop brings together software engineers and computational scientists. [1] The increase in the importance of Computational Science software motivates the need to identify and understand which software engineering (SE) practices are appropriate. [1] A multimillion-dollar investment by Johnson Controls includes 4 joint laboratories at the College of Engineering &amp; Applied Science, where the company's scientists, who are also adjunct professors, and UW-Milwaukee faculty and students work side-by-side. [9] Recent work in uncertainty quantification (UQ) has made it feasible to compute the statistical uncertainties for mathematical models in physics, biology, and engineering applications, offering added insight into how the model relates to the measurement data it represents. [1] Prior to the Eclipse Foundation, Andrew was Director of Engineering at Ingres where his team developed advanced spatial support features for the relational database and many applications. [1] BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION: Dimitri Mavriplis is currently the Max Castagne Professor in Mechanical Engineering at the University of Wyoming. [1] He obtained his Bachelor and Master's degrees in Mechanical Engineering from McGill University and his PhD in Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering from Princeton University. [1] In 2008 and 2013, he received an award for Excellence at the Student Interface from the College of Engineering and the University of Arizona. [1] Vivek became a member of the IBM Academy of Technology in 1995, the E.D. Butcher Chair in Engineering at Rice University in 2007, and was inducted as an ACM Fellow in 2008. [1] For electric vehicle makers, designing an efficient and robust cooling system for the battery pack is a key engineering task. [8] Ahmad Pesaran, Energy Storage Group Manager in NREL's Transportation and Hydrogen Systems Center, added, Continued progress developing and linking physics based models of batteries allows developers and designers to better understand the internal behavior of batteries in electric drive vehicles and explore new designs in a virtual environment, reducing the number of prototypes and tests required by a traditional build-break design cycle. [4] Each CAEBAT team is working independently to develop and validate modeling and design tools for EDV batteries, with an emphasis on integrating electrochemical, electrical, mechanical, and thermal physics. [7] This program, led by NREL and including industry and university partners, is developing computational tools for the design and analysis of batteries. [1] This program, led by NREL and including industry and university partners, is developing computational tools for the design and analysis of batteries with improved performance and lower cost. [1] Energy-dense power sources (Li-ion batteries) require careful design for normal use. [2] Industry partners on the projects used data from actual batteries to ensure the models are as accurate as possible. [3] The outcome of this project is expected to enable scientists and engineers to further improve the performance, cost, and lifetime of advanced lithium ion batteries in support of the DOE's EV Everywhere Grand Challenge. [4] The projects in question span advanced materials, batteries, nuclear fuels and reactors, nuclear fusion, quantum computing and many others. [1] Although electric vehicles with advanced lithium ion batteries have been introduced, further breakthroughs in scalable energy storage, beyond current state-of-the-art lithium ion batteries, are necessary before the full benefits of vehicle electrification can be realized. [1] Systems-level simulation energizes the virtual prototyping process for electric vehicle batteries. [8] As batteries are more fully incorporated into vehicle and stationary platforms they are increasingly pushed into use regimes that could result in less-than-safe operation. [2] Advances in transportation technologies, sensors, and onboard computers continue to push the efficiency of vehicles, resulting in an exponential increase in design parameter space. [1] A computer architect by training, he has chased parallelism up the software stack, having worked on alias and dependence analysis, parallel programming for GPUs, statically typed functional language compilation, and the design of parallel libraries. [1] Co-design refers to a computer system design process where scientific problem requirements influence architecture design and technology and constraints inform formulation and design of algorithms and software. [1] Co-design methodology requires the combined expertise of vendors, hardware architects, system software developers, domain scientists, computer scientists, and applied mathematicians working together to make informed decisions about features and tradeoffs in the design of the hardware, software and underlying algorithms. [1] Kenny has 220 U.S. patents issued and others pending, 180 scientific publications, and was awarded a 1998 R&amp;D 100 Award for one of the top 100 technological innovations of that year, for an advanced statistical pattern recognition technique that was originally developed for nuclear plant applications and is now being used for a variety of applications to improve the quality-of-service, availability, and optimal energy efficiency for enterprise and HPC computer servers. [1] One such tool is the COolant Boiling in Rod Arrays _ Two Fluids (COBRA-TF) computer code, capable of modeling the independent behavior of continuous liquid, vapor, and droplets using the sub-channel methodology. [1] His level set contributions include new level set calculus, novel numerical techniques, fluids and materials modeling, variational approaches, high co-dimension motion analysis, geometric optics, and the computation of discontinuous solutions to Hamilton-Jacobi equations; level set methods have been extremely influential in computer vision, image processing, and computer graphics. [1] Her expertise and experience is in the area of developing methods and computer codes for multi-dimensional reactor core analysis. [1] In support of the CAEBAT project, Oak Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL) is developing an open-architecture software interface to link the models developed by different teams into the CAEBAT suite of tools. [7] In the past several years ORNL modeling and simulation projects have experienced an increased need for interactive, graphical user tools. [1] It will cover both the robust, new infrastructure developed for modeling and simulation projects, such as new mesh editors and visualization tools, as well as the plugins for codes that are already supported by the platform and taking advantage of these features. [1] We will show how you can leverage it to accelerate your code deployment, use it to simplify your modeling and simulation project or get involved in the development. [1] Before joining ETH, he led the performance modeling and simulation efforts of parallel petascale applications for the NSF-funded Blue Waters project at NCSA/UIUC. He is also a key member of the Message Passing Interface (MPI) Forum where he chairs the Collective Operations and Topologies working group. [1] Prior to joining LMU as a Ph.D. student, Christian worked for several years in industry and academia as software engineer and project manager. [1] After a short 2 year sabbatical at Microsoft where he led a software group developing a next-generation virtual reality platform, he joined PNNL as the Director of the Center for Adaptive Supercomputer Software and Principal Investigator of a large DOD project in graph analytics. [1] I will illustrate with examples drawn from real projects, and from an existing and ongoing project, that details the state of software production in a large company, focusing on change data and how to use it to answer some of the questions posed in the preceding. [1] Recently it was announced that the Japanese Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology is intending to initiate a project towards an exascale supercomputer to be deployed around 2020. [1] In 2007, he integrated various benchmarks into the OSCAR cluster management suite as part of a Google Summer of Code project. [1] This project, which began in August 2011, is co-funded by the Vehicle Technologies Office in the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) and managed by DOE's National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL). [4] The project aims to provide energy storage technologies that go beyond today?s best Lithium-ion systems to provide five times the energy storage at one-fifth the cost in five years. [9] The topics of discussion during the executive session of the review included continued funding/growth of the program, task progression, and development of performance metrics for the project. [1] We present a way to project the model onto the low dimensional active subspace and solve the resulting problem using conventional techniques. [1] The QGE is a simplified model of the ocean, however it can be computationally expensive to resolve all scales, therefore numerical methods, such as the two-level method, are indispensable for time sensitive projects. [1] The computational homogenization scheme is here tailored to model the coupling between electrochemistry and mechanical phenomena that coexist during batteries charging and discharging cycles. [1] Accurate tests and models are critical for predicting and controlling the complex electrochemical, thermal and mechanical behavior of lithium-ion batteries. [2] With the growing use of automotive lithium-ion batteries in stationary energy storage applications, it is imperative to understand the safety of lithium-ion batteries after the first usage and before they are used in a secondary application. [2] Since their commercial introduction in the early 1990s, lithium-ion batteries have emerged as the most popular form of rechargeable energy storage devices in the portable electronics and electric vehicle markets. [8] Li-ion batteries are currently the preferred solution to store electrical energy. [2] We report on the progress in modeling and simulations of Li-ion batteries under abnormal conditions including external mechanical loading. [2] A state-of-the-art dry lab, the only one of its kind on a university campus in North America, enables work on the next generation of Li-ion batteries. [9] Topics addressed include: advanced batteries (including manufacturing processes) and electric drive R&amp;D; Lightweight materials; Advanced combustion engine and enabling technologies R&amp;D; and Fuels technologies (dedicated or dual-fuel natural gas engine technologies). [5] Michael Bauer is a sixth year PhD student in computer science at Stanford University. [1] BIOGRAPHY: Vivek Seshadri is a Ph.D. student at the Computer Science Department at Carnegie Mellon University. [1] He joined RIKEN AICS in 2012 after years at Hokkaido University, Japan, where he received a Ph.D. in Computer Science in 2012. [1] Dr. Lee received his B.S. in electrical engineering and computer science at the University of California, Berkeley and his Ph.D. in computer science at Harvard University. [1] BIO: Benjamin Lee is an assistant professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Duke University. [1] He did postdoctoral work in electrical engineering at Stanford University. [1] The Milwaukee School of Engineering's Rapid Prototyping lab enables Johnson Controls to quickly build and evaluate models of new battery parts. [9] The certificate in embedded systems, which is offered by the Department of Electrical, Computer and Energy Engineering and the Center for Advanced Engineering and Technology Education, with support of the Division of Continuing Education, offers students the hardware and software knowledge and skills needed to design and implement these systems. [20] Graduates will be situated in growing careers involving the design, development or support of electrical, electronic and computer hardware and software systems, software engineering, devices instruments or products, or will be successfully pursuing an advanced degree. [20] An instructor delivers information about selected computer software packages, and encourages teams to use computer-aided techniques to develop models for the processing and analysis of engineering data, through a series of assignments using these packages. [21] Electrical, computer and energy engineering is about the science and technology of information and energy. [20] The certification program was initiated by the Colorado Power Electronics Center, and is operated through the Department of Electrical, Computer and Energy Engineering and through the Center for Advanced Engineering and Technology Education (CAETE). [20] The following minors provide training in electrical, computer or energy engineering beyond the training usually received by science, mathematics and applied mathematics majors. [20] This is achieved through a sequence of required courses in these areas, culminating in a major design project incorporating realistic engineering constraints. [20] The Computer Skills taught and practiced in non-subject area-specific sections of EPICS 251 include advanced techniques in Microsoft Word, Excel, Project and Access, along with introductory lectures and practice in ArcView (GIS) and MathCAD. Students complete weekly homework assignments using these applications, and incorporate the techniques learned in the development and modeling of their design solutions. [21] Besides emphasizing computer hardware and software, the ECE curriculum also emphasizes design, integration, implementation and application of computer systems, as well as experience in software development. [20] COMPUTER SYSTEMS MANAGER (SYSTEM ANALYST SR) Description Conducts the analysis, design, estimating, development, documentation, testing, configuration and implementation of new hardware and software systems. [22] In addition to basic classes in mathematics, science and computing, the ECE curriculum includes a sequence of courses in analog and digital electronic circuits and systems, electromagnetic fields, probability, computer software and computer design and architecture. [20] We propose to develop and characterize a novel nanoscale memory unit that can store bit patterns and develop a computer simulation model of this unit that can be incorporated into commercial computer-aided design programs. [23] Realize Your Product Promise ANSYS is dedicated exclusively to developing engineering simulation software that fosters rapid and innovative product design. [10] We use ANSYS solutions to shorten the design analysis cycle, increasing the rate of design evolution while reducing test costs. - Andy Sadhwani, Senior Propulsion Analyst, SpaceX ONE ON ONE Semiconductor Engineering semiengineering.com, February 2015 The starting point of electronics systems engineering is no longer the system on chip (SoC). [10] The necessity for power electronics technology in these rapidly expanding areas creates a rising need for design engineers equipped with knowledge and skills to follow sound engineering principles and actively participate in multidisciplinary teams. [20] Master?s students may choose either an MS thesis option under Plan I or a non-thesis option of 30 hours under Plan II. The ME program is discussed in the College of Engineering and Applied Science general section on graduate study. [20] These minors also can broaden the training of students majoring in other engineering and applied science fields. [20] Students who wish to complete course requirements for medical (or dental, veterinary, etc.) school should add two semesters of organic chemistry to the ECEN/EEEN biomedical engineering option. [20] Students interested in biomedical engineering may receive elective credit for two semesters of biology if they also complete two bioengineering courses from the ECEN/EEEN offerings. [20] Students typically work in teams of four to five members to continue to learn and practice the fundamental skills of engineering. [21] We recruited Chris and John because we knew they could effectively steer our transportation team even further along in meeting the Energy Department's goals and the NREL mission, said Associate Lab Director for Mechanical and Thermal Systems Engineering Barbara Goodman. [15] Dual reflector antenna simulated with ANSYS HFSS ANSYS SOLUTIONS MEETING CUSTOMER NEEDS AT TIMKENSTEEL Industry Today industrytoday.co.uk, February 2015 TimkenSteel, a leading manufacturer of special bar quality (SBQ) large bars and seamless mechanical tubing, uses ANSYS simulation to solve customers? most demanding engineering challenges. [10] ANSYS advancements in MBSE and certified embedded code gen- eration drastically reduce development time for embedded software while meet- ing the highest safety standards, such as ISO 26262 ASIL-D. THE NEXT GREAT IDEA Simulation is not new to cars, but it has become such a crucial element of automotive engineering that visionary companies are making the paradigm shift of deploying a common enterprise-level simulation platform. [10] Can vehicle companies shift the paradigm from simulation-in-silos to deploying a common, scalable enterprise-level simulation platform that enables thorough systems engineering? GeometrycourtesyPTC. The latest ANSYS release assessed thermal effects of the engine and exhaust manifold on other vehicle components using a new mapped interface approach. [10] While a few battery cells may be sufficient for a phone or laptop, it is necessary to connect many hundreds of individual cells together as part of a much 2016 Chevy Volt battery For electric vehicle makers, designing an efficient and robust cooling system for the battery pack is a key engineering task. [10] For elec- tric vehicle makers, designing an effi- cient and robust cooling system for the battery pack is a key engineering task. [10] While these innovations intrigue consumers, they unnerve auto execu- tives who confront the rising complexity of vehicle engineering - along with its effect on time and cost of development. [10] This is accomplished by direct involvement of CU faculty, CET engineering staff and undergraduate and graduate students on the development of sensing systems to meet the observational needs of a number of government and industry sponsors. [20] Interested students are urged to contact the departmental biomedical engineering advisor for additional information. [20] PD teams can focus on engineering - not on running software - and engineers can collaborate and efficiently evalu- ate trade-offs. [10] LEVERAGING MODEL-BASED SYSTEMS ENGINEERING AND HARDWARE/SOFTWARE COSIMULATION Auto companies must go even further to address complexity, employing simu- lation that combines high-fidelity compo- nent analysis with holistic system behavior models. [10] The mission of the Digital Engineering Department is to enhance CAE technol- ogy in each of the company?s business groups by developing methods to solve typical product development problems. [10] STAYING ON TOP OF THE TRENDS: BREAKING DOWN THE SILOS The automotive industry was an ini- tial adopter of engineering simulation; it has leveraged this technology for sev- eral decades. [10] I've even picked up an engineering degree over the course of those years. [24] EPICS 251 is a three-credit course, where teams work on a design project from a pool of projects made available to them by their course mentors. [21] EPICS 251 _ Planetary : projects involve design problems in planetary science and exploration, for missions on the moon, Mars or other planets, as well as studies involving asteroids and comets. [21] Recent projects include the design and casting of sports medals, lithium-air and zinc-air batteries, and carbon dioxide sequestration. [21] Partners have contributed $7 million to the project, effectively doubling funding, and the first design tools were released earlier this year. [15] EPICS 262 _ EPICS II AutoCAD : incorporates semester-long instruction and practice in AutoCAD computer-aided drawing, with projects involving the use of AutoCAD in design solutions. [21] Recent projects include remodeling plans for the Ford Building, a solar tree house education center, an environmentally sustainable house, and new structural designs for use in Haiti following the January 2010 earthquake in Haiti. [21] In the last year, NREL has collaborated on sustainable transportation projects with partners including General Electric, the U.S. Advanced Battery Consortium, and all of the Big Three automakers. [15] The vast majority of people who took Ahmed's side did so because they read a news story that APPEARED to be about a teenager who invented a clock as a science project and was arrested and interrogated because his idiot school thought it was a bomb. [24] The successful candidate will work with a senior level forensic analyst, a project manager, and management personnel, as well as with attorneys and corpora. [22] DENSO intends to con- tinue to embed CAE more deeply within its global product development process and maintain its strong strategic part- nership with ANSYS through sharing visions and goals, as well as ongoing and future joint projects. [10] Graduates attaining the ECE degree will have comprehensive knowledge and experience in the concepts and design of electrical, electronic and computer devices, circuits and systems. [20] We'll just design everything in the computer, and use the computer to make sure all the pieces fit together before they're built. [25] Referring to the book I cited, until computer modeling was used, many concepts never made it past the coin cell proof of concept, and there was no attempt to validate a design at a working scale. [25] Posting Number S145PO Position Title Manager of the Open Access Lab and Departmental Computer Facilities Job Description The Manager of the Open Access Lab and Departmental Computer Facilities supervises a team of technical support specialists and works as a hands-on team member providing first and second level support services. [22] DDM paral- lelizes the entire simulation domain by creating a number of subdomains, each solved on different computing cores or various computers connected to a net- work. [10] Power electronics is a key enabling technology in essentially all electronic systems ranging from wireless communication devices, portable and desktop computers, to telecommunication infrastructure systems, renewable energy systems and industrial systems. [20] It is predicted that a density of 1Gb/cm2 of DRAM memory will be needed by the year 2020 if computers are to keep up with the current pace of technology. [23] Electrical engineering graduate programs leading to ME, MS and PhD degrees include the areas of biomedical engineering; communications and signal processing; computer engineering (including computer-aided synthesis and verification, software defined networks and embedded systems); dynamics and controls; electromagnetics; RF and microwaves; optics and photonics; power electronics and renewable energy systems; remote sensing; and nanostructures and devices. [20] The concurrent BS/MS program in electrical and computer engineering enables especially well qualified EEEN and ECEN majors to be admitted to the MS program during the junior year of their BS program, and to work simultaneously towards BS and MS degrees in electrical engineering. [20] The curriculum also provides opportunities for specialization in areas such as compiler design, embedded systems, software engineering and VLSI design, as well as in the electrical engineering specialties. [20] They are encouraged to participate in college and university activities, as well as in meetings of the two very active electrical engineering technical societies (IEEE and HKN). [20] Students are encouraged to develop interests outside their electrical engineering specialties by enrolling in nontechnical courses in other colleges of the university. [20] Course work in the ECEN/EEEN curriculum is coupled with specialized courses linking electrical engineering to such biomedical applications as bioeffects of electromagnetic fields, and therapeutic and diagnostic uses of bioelectric phenomena. [20] A graduating senior with high scholarship can finish a master?s degree in electrical engineering with about one additional full year of work at any of the nation?s major universities. [20] They understand the physical and mathematical principles underlying electrical and electronic technology and computer systems, and are able to analyze and solve electrical and computer engineering problems using this knowledge. [20] This option is described below under Concurrent BS/MS Program in Electrical and Computer Engineering. [20] For ECE majors, the requirement is for two of the three advanced core courses plus the Computer Engineering core: Discrete Math, Data Structures and Computer Organization. [20] We got some news that some new software has been developed to allow battery developers to run detailed simulations of everything from the cycle life and energy delivery of batteries to the nano-level chemistry changed going on within the cells themselves. [25] Dr. Xie takes a bottom up approach to this work by: clearly defining the need for clean energy from materials perspectives, designing nano-structural materials, developing the designed materials, characterizing the developed materials, and using these materials in energy conversion devices (i.e. fuel cells, batteries, super-capacitors, etc.). [26] Designers of safe high-performance batteries for electric vehicles are getting a hand with a new computational toolset created by a team led by Sreekanth Pannala and John Turner of Oak Ridge National Laboratory. [27] S ince their commercial introduction in the early 1990s, lithium-ion batteries have emerged as the most pop- ular form of rechargeable energy storage devices in the portable electronics and electric vehicle markets. [10] They understand the physical and mathematical principles underlying electrical and electronic technology, and are able to analyze and solve electrical engineering problems using this knowledge. [20] This course introduces the student to advanced engineering concepts using computer assisted design (CAD) tools. [28] Powers, L., Summers, J., (2009), Integrating Graduate Design Coaches in Undergraduate Design Project Teams, International Journal of Mechanical Engineering Education, vol. 37, no. 1, pp. 3-20 (ISSN 0306-4190). [29] A consultancy organization that offers engineering design, construction supervision, project management, institutional development, management information systems and training expertise. [30] The firm is a specialist engineering services &amp; solutions provider servicing clients across a range of engineering segments such as building, software projects, infrastructure projects, design automation etc. [30] In house engineering includes the design and fabrication of a battery management system, battery containment modules, structural framing for the mounting of the powertrain, as well as advanced data collection and analysis software. [31] Sen, C., Caldwell, B., Summers, J.D., Mocko, G., (2010), Evaluation of the Functional Basis using an Information Theoretic Approach, Artificial Intelligence in Engineering Design Analysis and Manufacturing, vol. 24, no. 1, pp. 87-105 (doi:10.1017/S0890060409990187). [29] Wetmore, W., Summers, J., Greenstein, J., (2008), Experimental Study of Influence of Group Familiarity and Information Sharing on Design Review Effectiveness, Journal of Engineering Design, (online-first) (10.1080/09544820802238217) on-line. (impact factor: 0.844). [29] Ostergaard, K., Summers, J., (2009), Development of a Systematic Classification and Taxonomy of Collaborative Design Activities, Journal of Engineering Design, vol. 20, no. 1, pp. 57-81. (DOI: 10.1080/09544820701499654). [29] Summers, J., Shah, J., (2010), Mechanical Engineering Design Complexity Metrics: Size, Coupling, and Solvability, Journal of Mechanical Design, vol. 132, no. 2, (doi:10.1115/1.4000759). on-line. [29] Hunt, B.J., Wiecek, M. and Fadel, G.M.,(2004), Matrices as Preference Modeling Tools in Bi-Criteria Engineering Design, Paper presented at the ISSMO MAO conference Albany, NY Aug 2004. [29] Topics studied include descriptive geometry, geometric tolerancing, and advanced engineering design concepts such as surface and solid modeling. [28] TROY The Troy engineering software developer Altair said Monday it had completed the acquisition of New York-based Multiscale Design Systems LLC, developer of software that models the performance and fatigue of composites and other complex materials. [11] WPI was the first university to offer and undergraduate program in robotics engineering and provides a unique project based curriculum that lives up to its founding motto of Theory and Practice. [12] In this REU project, we will work on an adapter design that allows step-wise adjustment of joint angles in prosthetics, starting by analyzing the state of the art, including the development of different design concepts, simulation and optimization of designs on the computer, production of a prototype (or prototypes) and ending with the bench testing (and possibly clinical testing) of such a prototype. [32] This project will develop dual-task gait analysis applications for the computer assisted rehabilitation environment (CAREN). [32] Dr. Samit Roy, the William D. Jordan Professor of Aerospace Engineering and Mechanics, is also using computers to quicken testing for an auto company. [16] REQUIRED BACKGROUND: Engineering preferred, specifically biomedical, mechanical or computer science/engineering. [32] Phelan, K., Wilson, C., Summers, J., (2014), Development of a design for manufacturing rules database for use in instruction of DFM practices, International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference, Buffalo, NY, DETC2014-34187. [29] Ma, J., Summers, J., (2011), Numerical Investigation of Effect of Membrane Thickness on the performance of Cellular Shear band based Non-pneumatic Tire, ASME International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference, Washington, DC, September 2011, DETC2011-47045. [29] Emphasis is placed on the use of computer assisted design (CAD) tools in the design and execution of site and foundation plans as well as topographical information and detail drawings of stairs and wall sections. [28] Topics include problem-solving strategies, classical representation methods such as sketching, geometric construction techniques, as well as computer assisted design (CAD), orthographic projection, and 3-D modeling. [28] Topics include coordinate systems, principles of machine processes and gearing, and the construction of 3-D wireframe models using computer assisted design (CAD). [28] The WALRUS Rover project team will be using SolidWorks for mechanical design and 3D modeling Learn more about SolidWorks at http://www.solidworks.com. [12] The team aims to educate people on the principles of electric vehicle design by engaging students in challenging and rewarding projects that cover a wide variety of academic disciplines. [31] The team?s main project is to design, build, and race a high performance electric motorcycle for competition in the 2015 eMotoRacing all-electric race series. [31] SCaD will have to facilitate teachers to create and clone classes, create different types of assignment, easily create and manage individuals and groups in class, multiple randomization routines that can match individual/group raters with projects, and most importantly allow commonly used design artifacts (video, cad models etc) be implemented into the webpage. [32] The goal of this project is to design and develop an assistive robotic manipulator evaluation tool (ARMET). [32] A company providing project management consultancy and design &amp; build solutions in the various asset classes such as IT/SEZ/business parks, hotels, A company providing project management consultancy and design &amp; build solutions in the various asset classes such as IT/SEZ/business parks, hotels, multi-specialty hospitals, high-end residential and data centers. [30] This course will introduce students to the principles, concepts, and software applications used in the management of projects. [28] This course introduces students to the use of simple and complex graphic tools used to communicate and understand ideas and concepts found in the areas of architecture, manufacturing, engineering, science, and mathematics. [28] The auto industry in our state can use us to understand the science needed to make engineering advancements in their products, said Dr. Gregory Thompson, a professor of metallurgical and materials engineering. [16] Morvan, S., Fadel, G.M., Virtual Prototyping Using STL files International Body Engineering Conference, IBEC 1996, Detroit, MI, Published in Conference proceedings, October 1996. [29] Sen, C., Summers, J., Mocko, G., (2010), Toward a Formal Representation of the Functional Basis Verbs, Tools and Methods for Competitive Engineering, Ancona, Italy, April 2010, #127 (podium presentation; invited for journal special issue). [29] Morkos, B., Palmer, G., Summers, J., (2010), A Comparison of Designer Familiarity and Centeredness During Customer Requirement Elicitation, Tools and Methods for Competitive Engineering, Ancona, Italy, April 2010, #53 (panel presentation; invited for journal special issue). [29] Caldwell, B.W., Mocko, G.M., 2010, A Representation of Artefacts and Interactions to Supplement Function, Tools and Methods for Competitive Engineering, Ancona, Italy, April 2010, (podium presentation). [29] TROY The Troy engineering software developer Altair Engineering has launched HyperXtrude 2015, a new version of a simulation tool for extrusion processes. [11] TROY The Troy-based engineering technology developer Altair Inc. said that Hamamatsu, Japan-based Elysium Co. Ltd. had joined the Altair Partner Alliance, adding its 3D geometry healing and translation software CADdoctor. [11] Worcester Polytechnic Institute was founded in 1865 and remains at the forefront of science, technology and engineering education. [12] TROY The Troy-based engineering technology developer Altair has announced a High Performance Computing Cloud Challenge using Amazon Web Services and Intel technologies. [11] Ma, J., Summers, J., (2009), Meshless Integral Method for Analysis of Elastoplastic Geotechnical Materials, ASME International Engineering Congress and Expo, Orlando, FL, Nov. 2009, in review (March 2009; Ma is corresponding author). [29] The move brings the Danish company's noise, vibration and harshness analysis software, Insight+, to customers of Altair's HyperWorks engineering software suite. [11] Altair said MDS' technology will bring important new composites expertise to HyperWorks, Altair's computer-aided engineering software suite including multiscale analysis, stochastic design, fatigue analysis, and multiphysics simulation. [11] Altair says the new software allows engineers on the shop floor for the first time to validate die designs using computer-aided engineering techniques directly from computer-aided design models which, the company says, is a significant workflow improvement. [11] This course focuses on engineering graphics introducing the student to symbol libraries, industry standards, and sectioning techniques. [28] The College of Engineering offers several auto competition teams that allow students to learn engineering through hands-on experience. [16] The firm provides building information modeling, quantity surveying, engineering and architectural detailing services. [30] Secure-24 says the company's new Engineering Desktops offering simplifies the management of engineering workstations used for 3D intensive applications such as AutoCAD, CATIA, Revit and Photoshop and secures high-value creative content by providing a virtual desktop with a dedicated, hardware-based graphics processor, in the company's secure data centers. [11] This course provides content for advanced networking engineering. [28] The aim of the challenge is to demonstrate the benefits of using the cloud for large-scale design exploration in the area of computer-aided engineering. [11] This project in the Tehachapi Mountains is proof of the success of using electro-mechanical batteries to store wind energy for the long term. [33] The frame that the team is using for the project was designed for use with an internal combustion engine, thus a separate sub- frame was designed to which the motors and battery modules can mount. [31] This project-based course focuses on the use of information technology to increase the effectiveness and efficiency of project management and integrated enterprise. [28] The Training of Trainers (ToT) Wheelchair Service Provision Evaluation is a project that uses a mixed methods formative and summative assessment to evaluate the impact of a wheelchair service training course on rehabilitation practices of trainers and their trainees. [32] This project-based, culminating course covers the management of a complete project in an authentic environment. [28] The firm provides consultancy services to Lead Industry and Lead Acid Battery Industry for Project management, Implementation, Production, Optimization and Maintenance. [30] A firm that offers project management consultancy, technical audit, cost management consultancy, preparation of bar bending schedule(bbs), quality audits and environment, health &amp; safety audits. [30] The intention of these projects is to provide both a more advanced learning experience for members, as well as a test bed for technologies that may be implemented on the electric motorcycle in the future. 4 SPONSORSHIP LEVELS Gigawatt Level Sponsor: $4,000 and Above The Gigawatt level sponsor receives a large logo that will be prominently displayed on the bike, as well as on team event t-shirts, posters, and our website. [31] This provides an opportunity for the public to gain awareness and engage team members in conversations about the contributions that you or your company made to the team. 6 PROJECTS ELECTRIC BIKES New members with little experience are introduced to the world of electric vehicles through electric bikes. [31] After this introductory project is complete, members move into working on intermediary development vehicles. [31] The proposed development project is the initial and critical stage for developing a TBI- specific EMA/ EMI using biomeasures for increasing behavioral self-regulation. [32] Project activities will include analysis of recorded neural data in Matlab, using a combination of pre-written and self-generated code. [32] The goal of this project is to develop a software program capable of collecting gait data in a clinical environment. [32] The REU intern on this project will develop fundamental abstractions for computationally customizable physical device production with the goal of enabling high-level control and testing of the semantics and properties of physical devices by end users; advance the model of service delivery by introducing mechanisms for ongoing iteration; and follow up which produce a more detailed understanding of AT use abandonment in comparison to more traditional AT provision models. [32] Through project-based learning, students will understand how to use the framework of initiating, planning, executing, monitoring and controlling, and closing a project in authentic situations. [28] Students will be responsible for planning, monitoring, controlling, and completing a series of smaller projects as well as a capstone project. [28] The modules undergo advanced computer simulation and analysis before they are put into use on the motorcycle. [31] This course is based upon the use of computer system diagnostic tools to read and diagnose computer codes in a variety of automotive types. [28] This course uses both CCNA Discovery -Introducing Routing and Switching in the Enterprise curriculum and CCNA Discovery -Designing and Supporting Computer Networks curriculum. [28] Hands-on activities for this course include the use of computer equipment and digital input devices. [28] This course includes the software skills required for installing and maintaining computers. [28] The intern will review literature for existing Wii balance board applications, write a computer program in Visual Basic (or other program) to simultaneously visualize Wii balance board data and video from a webcam, collect pilot data with control participants, and compare to a conventional gait analysis system. [32] Our primary goal is to develop new algorithms, tools, and computer assisted work strategies to catalyze on-line communities of skilled experts to dramatically scale up the ability of online communities to perform work, and apply these advances to making dramatic changes to the real-world task of producing customizable AT devices. [32] From left, Crimson Racing team members Cole Frederick, studying mechanical engineering, and Chris New, studying electrical and computer engineering, work on their car. [16] The three main subgroups of the team are mechanical engineering, firmware engineering, and electrical engineering. [31] Upon successful completion of the this course, students should be prepared to enter the workforce as an electrical helper and/or continuing education towards degrees in Construction Management or Electrical Engineering. [28] SUPERBIKE Battery Management System The battery management system is intended to effectively mitigate the risks associated with lithium ion batteries. [31] With batteries being expensive parts of electric vehicles, extending their lives could make the technology more affordable, Balasubramanian said. [16] In Year 2 of the project, the professional development will include learning opportunities for teachers on the use of Lab School classroom equipment; in year 3, the professional development will include learning opportunities for teachers on the curriculum integration of engineering concepts and advanced manufacturing technologies. (3) During the school year, a common planning period will be scheduled for the CTE teacher and science teacher to coordinate activities. [34] The Project LiveWire engineering team uses all of the latest design, prototyping, and manufacturing expertise that Harley-Davidson developed over the last century of building v-twin motorcycles. [35] The success of the pilot project inspired collaborators to develop the Summer Engineering Design Academy. [34] Karan Jerath of Friendswood High School was offered the opportunity to compete in the International Science and Engineering Fair for an Environmental Management project, International Oil Spill Remediation The Numerical Simulation of an In-Situ Subsea Separator Part II. Karan also won first place in the Senior division for Environmental Management. [19] Miriam Matney of Clear Lake High School was offered the opportunity to compete in the International Science and Engineering Fair for a Physics and Astronomy project, Energetic Particles from B and Li Fusion Reactions. [19] In initial planning for this project, collaborators from the Smithsonian and professors of engineering and education at the University of Virginia identified a trajectory of great inventions to teach science and engineering. [34] In addition to their own respective pathways, each student will be required to take a common course in which engineering and technology students work together, within and outside of their respective expertise, to complete group projects. [34] Justin DuPont of Clear Falls High School won fifth place in the Senior division in Electrical and Mechanical Engineering for the project The Effect of Coil Material and Size Ratio on Wireless Power Transfer as Applied to Implantable Medical Devices. [19] This exposure will be combined with the development of a high school curricular pathway, aligned with college and career ready standards, which allows students to build competencies in advanced manufacturing, design, and engineering. [34] Students in pilot middle schools will learn foundational engineering principles and advanced manufacturing technologies through the development and implementation of a semester-long engineering course based on reconstruction of historic inventions. ? Objective 1.2 Pilot Invention Kits in Science Teaching. [34] Critically, all assessments will reflect the Next Generation Science Standards, including the eight practices of science and engineering that the Framework identifies as essential for all students to learn and the three core ideas of engineering design in which students are expected to engage. [34] Joe Garofalo (Co-P.I.) will work with the team to coordinate conceptualization and design of science activities, identify correspondence of embedded mathematics concepts with mathematics standards and curriculum, and will adapt and refine engineering and science assessments. [34] Students in the engineering transfer pathway may enroll in several college-level courses such as Introduction to Engineering and Engineering Graphics where they will learn the design process, fundamental engineering principles for use in other courses, Matlab, and solid-modeling. [34] While students in both pathways will share a common interest in technology and engineering, the engineering transfer pathway will focus more on design and theory, while the technology transfer pathway will focus more on maintenance and other middle skills. [34] Students who elect to follow the engineering transfer pathway will, at the end of their degree, be eligible for a Level III certification equivalent to a design engineer. [34] It is designed to integrate engineering design into the middle school curriculum through advanced manufacturing technologies. [34] Support from the Investing in Innovation grant, leveraged with existing partnerships with higher education, nonprofits, and the private sector, will extend the work of the Lab School and Smithsonian partnership on a regional level through a middle school curriculum that provides exposure to elements of engineering and advanced manufacturing through integrated middle school science courses. [34] In the Senior or high school division, the fair is also a qualifier for the Intel International Science and Engineering Fair, as well as for scholarships to the Governer's Science and Technology Champions Academy. [19] This annual leadership summit brings together the leaders of ten national education associations, including the Association for Science Teacher Education (ASTE), the Association of Mathematics Teacher Educators (AMTE), and the International Technology and Engineering Education Association (ITEEA). [34] The other path will be for the student interested in pursuing an associate of applied science in engineering technology (technology transfer). [34] Students taking engineering electives develop demonstration apparatus for use in science classes. [34] Engineering students need tools to supplement their theoretical studies and that often requires the use of CAD softwares which brings me to write an article highlighting the best laptops for engineering students. [14] As an engineering student myself, I own a W541 simply because my work dictates the use of simulations and rendering that call for a quad core processor. [14] Occasionally I'll resort to Solidworks while providing examples and this is primarily due to it's burgeoning popularity among engineering students but rest assured all other softwares work more or less around the same principles. [14] Our core products are the technology-leading simulation packages, STAR-CCM+ and STAR-CD. The scope of our activities, however, extends well beyond CFD software development to encompass a wide range of CAE engineering services in fluid dynamics, heat transfer and structural engineering. [13] Our ongoing mission is to inspire innovation and reduce costs through the application of engineering simulation software and services. [13] Compare experimental and control classes for beta pilot in engineering classes Spring Semester 2016 ? Alpha pilot of Davenport electric motor and corresponding battery Invention Kits in the Laboratory School physical science classes ? Beta pilot of galvanometer and telegraph Invention Kits in Lab School physical science classes ? Evaluation 1. [34] National access to science and engineering resources U411P140316 Page 9 Objective 1: Develop Smithsonian Invention Kits and pilot in the Laboratory School for Advanced Manufacturing. [34] The teacher focus group protocol will gather information on the supports that teachers receive for implementing the new curricula as well as facilitators and barriers to incorporating engineering into the middle school science curricula. [34] Embedded assessments will be practicum-based such that students demonstrate mastery of skills and understanding of science and engineering principles, as well as how they interact. [34] U411P140316 Page 6 The introduction to engineering is based on an innovative method pioneered at Princeton by Professors Michael Littman and David Billington, who believe students can learn science and engineering through the coherent and engaging story of great inventions. [34] Designing and constructing their own demonstration apparatus for science classes presents engineering students with an authentic challenge. [34] The Lab School uses engineering classes as an innovation center to support science teaching. [34] Engineering education follows the model of the physical sciences in which detailed knowledge proceeds in an abstract sequence from general principals. [34] The instructions will be developed for levels of reconstruction including Hand Tools, 2D Fabrication and 3D fabrication, National Advisory Panel A national advisory panel will provide expertise in engineering, engineering education and science education. [34] The program teaches science and engineering through the reconstruction of great inventions. [34] Four of the technical electives should be chosen from within one of the following groups- Nuclear Engineering, Energy Systems, or Reliability Engineering, to create a structured degree program. [36] An examination of four central topics in wind energy engineering: the nature of wind energy as a resource for generating electricity; the aerodynamics of wind turbines by which the wind energy is converted into mechanical energy; the mechanics and dynamics of the wind energy system (tower, rotor, hub, drive train, and generator); and the electrical aspects of wind turbines. [36] This pathway will fill the gap of middle skill workers identified in the workforce plan, along with providing students planning to enter engineering fields at the community college or university level with practical experiences and the opportunity to earn credit through dual enrollment courses. [34] As with their U411P140316 Page 16 engineering transfer counterparts, these students will be gaining fundamental knowledge for use in other courses while also earning college credit. [34] This two-week curriculum would be further developed and modified for a classroom environment, ultimately becoming a standards-aligned engineering and physical sciences course of study composed of a series of active-learning explorations of early inventions from the Smithsonian collections. [34] Fab@School Designer is described in Appendix J. Objective 2: Develop methods for assessing learning outcomes corresponding to science and engineering instructional objectives. [34] Smithsonian Invention Kits will include resources to re-create these inventions, including a year-long science and engineering curriculum, 3D scans and animations, and online support. [34] Through examples of such thinking, students can learn ground-breaking engineering ideas without first having to know calculus. (Billington, 2006, p. xvii-xviii) The educational potential of early inventions inspired an initiative, American Innovations in an Age of Discovery, undertaken by the Laboratory School for Advanced Manufacturing in collaboration with Princeton and the Smithsonian Institution in 2013. [34] Students' scores will be compared to past students' scores as well as those of students in similar schools not implementing the new curriculum and between students enrolled and not enrolled in the engineering elective to better understand impacts. [34] Unlike the students in the engineering transfer pathway, these students will obtain a set of skills that can be used towards gainful employment in the manufacturing sector by the time they graduate high school. [34] They will also participate in a seminar on engineering education with Princeton University engineering educator doctoral students. [34] There is no doubt that Mac devices are well designed with equally stunning displays but when it comes to engineering softwares, majority of them are indigenous to Windows. [14] To continue the advanced manufacturing trajectory that begins at the middle school level, each division will create an advanced manufacturing and engineering centered high school curricular U411P140316 Page 15 pathway. [34] Central to the course is an extensive design challenge that requires students to integrate knowledge across topics while honing practical design and project management skills. [37] The experimental results thus far have given us new insights on how to improve the mechanical integrity analyzes of subsea templates, said Erik Nennie, Project Manager _ Heat Transfer and Fluid Dynamics with TNO. The outcome of the next phases will further improve the modeling tools for integrity analysis, as both design and operation of subsea templates can greatly benefit from these studies. [13] Kabir Jolly of The John Cooper School won fifth place in the Junior division in Energy and Transportation for the project Windmill Blade Design Creating More Electricity. [19] U411P140316 Page 14 (5) Technical skills such as computer-assisted design and soldering may also be required for implementation of project. [34] Matthew Caffet of The Academy of Science and Technology won first place in the Senior division in Energy and Transportation for the project Riding the Wave Energy in Motion II. [19] Ben Scarborough of The Academy of Science and Technology won fifth place in the Senior division in Environmental Management for the project Detecting Water Pollution with Bioluminescence. [19] Megan Alam and Juliana Steward of The Academy of Science and Technology won fourth place in the Senior division in Environmental Sciences/Analysis for the project The Macro Effects of Microbeads. [19] Andrew Kim of The Academy of Science and Technology won second place in the Senior division in Plant Sciences for the project Salinity Effects On Nannochloropsis and Haematococcus Enhanced Biomass Cultivation of Saltwater and Freshwater Algae Species. [19] Student Assessments, developed by the teachers and project personnel in conjunction with the evaluator and to include embedded (practicum-oriented) assessments will be used to understand how well students are mastering the science topics they are studying. [34] With that in mind, teachers and project personnel will consult with AIR when developing practicum-oriented assessments to measure student mastery of the science topics they are studying. [34] Zachary Bouthillette of McCullough Junior High School won fourth place in the Junior division in Plant Sciences for the project Maintaining Vegetable Nutrients in Cooking Methods. [19] Andrew Miller of McCullough Junior High School won fifth place in the Junior division in Plant Sciences for the project Growing Green Testing Algae Growth. [19] Evan Ree s of McCullough Junior High School won fourth place in the Junior division in Mathematical Sciences for the project What's Random About Rock Paper Scissors? [19] Joshua Gruener of Friendswood High School won second place in the Senior division in Earth Science for the project Impact Craters: What's your angle? [19] Ria Sur of Clear Lake High School won third place in the Senior division in Earth Science for the project Muscle Proteome Changes From Prolonged Space Travel. [19] Jessica Young of The John Cooper School won third place in the Junior division in Earth Science for the project The Holey Grail of Natural Gas. [19] Alexandra Boehning of League City Intermediate School won first place in the Junior division in Medicine and Health Sciences for the project Raspberries for Cancer: Hoax or Hope? [19] Anuraag Madabushi and Shomik Ghose of T.H. Rogers Middle School won second place in the Junior division in Behavioral and Social Sciences for the project Learning Styles. [19] Sueda Cetinkaya of Harmony School of Advancement won first place in the Senior division in Mathematical Sciences for the project Vascular Geometry in Tumors. [19] Praneel Joshi of Knox Junior High School won first place in the Junior division in Energy and Transportation for the project Measuring Efficiency of Different Battery Systems. [19] ACPS has significant experience managing federal grant awards, including the recent Safe Schools/Healthy Students initiative, a five year, joint project with Charlottesville City Schools and community organizations, which successfully met all project objectives in improving school safety. [34] Because a primary goal of the project is to develop student desire to pursue advanced STEM education and careers, it is important to measure the extent to which implementation of the program is influencing student interest and engagement. [34] Students will gain hands on experience conducting an energy audit project through assigned projects. [36] Student evaluation based on project specification, prototyping, integration, testing, simulation and documentation. [37] The elaborate computer model for LiveWire even included optimizations like balancing weight vs. structural strength and durability and advanced wire routing using simulation software and visualization tools. [35] This course will introduce students to the fundamentals of computer networks. [37] Matthew Webb of The Academy of Science and Technology won fourth place in the Senior division in Computer Science for the project Encrypting Reality. [19] Project includes building electrical devices and wiring of traction, control, lighting, and other components along with construction of adapters and devices necessary for the conversion of a vehicle to electric drive. [37] To ensure continuous improvement during implementation, the CMT and Project Director will use a Plan-Do-Study-Act (PDSA) model. [34] U411P140316 Page 18 The Project Co-Directors will work closely with a Core Management Team (CMT) of leadership from partnering organizations. [34] U411P140316 Page 17 C. Quality of Management Plan and Personnel Albemarle County Public Schools will serve as fiscal agent for the project. [34] Jennifer Lin of T.H. Rogers Middle School won third place in the Junior division in Cellular and Molecular Biology for the project Fighting Breast Cancer Using Anthrax Toxin. [19] Eight companies were involved in the first phase of the project: BP, Statoil, Total, Suncor, Shell, Lundin, Aker Solutions and FMC. TNO carried out the bulk of the test work at its facilities in The Netherlands, while Xodus managed the program and developed CFD schemes to be able to reproduce the measured results. [13] I learned about how the LiveWire team engineered and built their ground-breaking electric bike when I talked with lead project engineer Ben Lund. [35] Batteries are a key technology for todays and tomorrow?s electronic devices and electrical hybrid vehicle. [36] Discrete system simulations using MATLAB. Prerequisite: Electrical and Computer Engineering 280L(54L) and Statistics 130(113) or Mathematics 230(135) or Electrical and Computer Engineering 555(255) or permission of instructor. [37] RANKED SELECTED SOURCES (37 source documents arranged by frequency of occurrence in the above report) Related Related Articles
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/b91c70e1-6cc4-36b7-ad11-089f374754e5" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-12T14:35:43Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:45:32.002Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://bostoncommons.net/computer-aided-engineering-for-batteries-project/" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities /><Relations />
</Document>
