<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>PM Modi with President of Russia, Vladimir Putin, St. Petersburg, Russia, June 01, 2017
Saint-Petersburg Declaration By the Russian Federation And the Republic Of India: A Vision For The 21st Century
June 01, 2017
 
(Excerpts on India-Russia Civil Nuclear Cooperation)
Cooperation in the peaceful uses of nuclear energy has emerged as one of the hallmarks of the strategic partnership between the two countries, contributing to India’s energy security and energizing broader scientific and technological cooperation. With concerted efforts on both sides, there has been a series of steady and demonstrable achievements in our civil nuclear partnership, including advancing nuclear power projects at the <NODE id="703" />Kudankulam<NODE id="713" /> site and transforming <NODE id="736" />it<NODE id="738" /> into one of India’s largest energy hubs. We welcome the conclusion of the General Framework Agreement and Credit Protocol for Units 5 and 6 of the <NODE id="886" />Kudankulam Nuclear Power Plant<NODE id="916" />. We will work towards the implementation of the Strategic Vision for Strengthening Cooperation in Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy signed between the two countries on December 11, 2014. The future of Indian-Russian cooperation holds great promise across a wide spectrum covering nuclear power, nuclear fuel cycle and nuclear science and technology.
 
The growing partnership in the nuclear power sector between India and Russia has opened opportunities for developing advanced nuclear manufacturing capabilities in India in line with Government of India’s "Make in India” initiative. India and Russia commit themselves to earnestly implement the "Programme of Action for Localization in India” signed on 24 December 2015, and to encourage their nuclear industries to engage closely and foster concrete collaborations.
 

</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/iter03/84" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://dae.nic.in/" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="703" endPos="713" type="organization" surface="Kudankulam" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="736" endPos="738" type="organization" surface="it" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="886" endPos="916" type="organization" surface="Kudankulam Nuclear Power Plant" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="3" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="2" label="source" />
<Entity id="0" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
