<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Model <NODE id="6" />YX-FS60-II<NODE id="16" /> three colors tubes laminated plastic filling sealing machine fully automatic tube filler sealer أنبوب ملء وختم آلة designed and manufactured by our engineer team in cosmetic&amp;food&amp;pharma making and packaging machinery is widely used in the daily chemical industry like tubes filler sealer equipment and such like.We as a famous manufacturer moreover can design and produce the packaging machine according to the special requirements from customers. Use rotary piston way, filling precision, using light point control, heated sealing all work with high precision cylinder full stroke control, easy to adjust filling volume, the filling speed can be adjusted.  It applies to all kindsof composite tubes, plastic pipe and  metal pipe filling and sealing, date printing, cut the tail.  Sealing neat appearance, sealing strong, high accuracy, good stability.  According to the different material properties, Optional ingredients bucket  heating system, anti-leak filling head, Machine adopts imported PLC control, import the  original frequency control, <NODE id="1065" />pneumatic components<NODE id="1085" /> using (<NODE id="1093" />AIRTAC<NODE id="1099" />),  import original (<NODE id="1120" />SICK<NODE id="1124" />) <NODE id="1126" />photoelectric sensors<NODE id="1147" />,high stability, imported hot air flow meter  and the formation of hot air heating system.  Double Nozzle lip butter Tube Filling And Sealing Machine  Packaging materials and filling materials Scope:  1) soft tube, plastic pipe, composite pipe.  2) ointment, cream, gel viscosity fluids agents.  Double Nozzle lip butter Tube Filling And Sealing Machine Applicable industries:  Cosmetics, light industry (household chemicals), pharmaceutical, food and other industries  for enterprise product selection to the hose for the packaging container, the device suitable  for ointments, creams, gels or viscosity fluid filling, and then sealing the hose tail and print  code, the system produces the finished product.  Soft tube filling and sealing machine is mainly used for the packaging containers of plastic hose material  quantitative filling, sealing, this machine is widely used in pharmaceutical,  cosmetic, food, chemical and other industries packaging. Such as ointments, gels, adhesives,  AB glue, epoxy glue, skin cream, hair dye, shoe polish, toothpaste and other liquid or paste  filling and sealing materials.  Model <NODE id="2272" />YX-FS60-II<NODE id="2282" /> three colors tubes laminated plastic filling sealing machine fully automatic tube filler sealer أنبوب ملء وختم آلة: Voltage 220V/380v/50Hz/60Hz Productivity 80-100pcs/min Filling volume 3-250 ml(customized) Tube diameter 11mm-38mm(customized) Tube length  50-200mm(customized) Max power  7.5KW Water consumption  3-6L/min Machine weight  About 1300kg Dimension(L*W*H) n 2150×850×2100mm Working preceduer of tubes filler sealer equipment: Automatic tube feeding→ tube position (hose container) → automatic identification label  located on pipe → → filling quantity control test + + [hose internal cleansing (option)]  → filling →  heating the tube (inner heating for plastic tube, outer heating for compound tube) →  tail shaping and sealing → tail cutting → Print → finished discharge code  Our Factory since 1992 has been manufacturing the cosmetic&amp;food making and packaging machinery.In these field we have the experience rich enough to solve the questions encountered by our customers from both home and abroad.For more information about various high quality machinery like Model <NODE id="3366" />YX-FS60-II<NODE id="3376" /> three colors tubes laminated plastic filling sealing machine fully automatic tube filler sealer أنبوب ملء وختم آلة,please email via jackdu999@yahoo.com or browse our website http://penglaichina.com. Watch us on <NODE id="3588" />Youtube<NODE id="3595" /> :http://youtube.com/user/mrjackdu007 Follow us on News Center:http://www.penglaichina.com/news/ Skype us by :turnanewleaf Call us via:0086-15811882441 Whatsapp:0086-15811882441
</TEXT>
<Meta>
<feature featureName="id" featureValue="vico/bee1cef1-4d81-37c1-ad59-5977686251f3" />
<feature featureName="source" featureValue="sensor_corpus" />
<feature featureName="lang" featureValue="en" />
<feature featureName="pubDate" featureValue="2016-01-25T11:43:02Z" />
<feature featureName="indexDate" featureValue="2016-07-13T11:47:42.751Z" />
<feature featureName="uri" featureValue="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZIwf8nhJHUw" />
<feature featureName="solrEventType" featureValue="None" /></Meta><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="6" endPos="16" type="product" surface="YX-FS60-II" />
<Entity id="1" startPos="1065" endPos="1085" type="product" surface="pneumatic components" />
<Entity id="2" startPos="1093" endPos="1099" type="organization" surface="AIRTAC" />
<Entity id="3" startPos="1120" endPos="1124" type="organization" surface="SICK" />
<Entity id="4" startPos="1126" endPos="1147" type="product" surface="photoelectric sensors" />
<Entity id="5" startPos="2272" endPos="2282" type="product" surface="YX-FS60-II" />
<Entity id="6" startPos="3366" endPos="3376" type="product" surface="YX-FS60-II" />
<Entity id="7" startPos="3588" endPos="3595" type="organization" surface="Youtube" /></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="8" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="1" label="product" />
<Entity id="2" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="9" NAME="company_provides_product">
<Entity id="4" label="product" />
<Entity id="3" label="company" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="10" NAME="identity">
<Entity id="0" label="source" />
<Entity id="6" label="target" />
<Entity id="5" label="target" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
